It's David and on this appy cast I'm here with my mate Pat and he's got a
screenplay or a movie concept maybe even TV series we're not sure that we're
going to work through with ChatGPT and see if we can flesh it out into
something more real. The goal is actually to get a synopsis together, character
analysis and also to assist with the plot for a pilot episode of this show.
I've got I've set us up with a my map here and we'll build from here and I've
received this email from Pat called BlazedAnimized so let's just take a
copy of all this and we'll go into Visual Studio I've set up a folder here
and we'll just paste everything that we've got so BlazedAnimized, new
folder, new file, we'll call it scratch pad this is where we're just going to put
our raw information take it out of here put it into here and rather than me
asking Pat exactly what this is about I think this is where we'll start using
ChatGPT so we go into ChatGPT and I'm going to pick the GPT4 model for
today's session and let's give it some context. Today, comma, you are an expert
in creating screenplays, movies, TV series, full stop. I am going to need your
help to develop a project that has come through as an idea from a writer, full
stop. Just wait for the first draft and then give me a list of actions that you
think we should be looking into. Go with that, paste it all in, see what it comes
up with. So while that's going let's set up a blaster
while this is going I'm just going to play this to us so that we can hear what
it's told us to do. Hit play, hit play. Script development, the characters and
plot are well outlined but you would need to flesh out dialogues, scenes and
situations further for a full-length script. Consider hiring or collaborating
with a screenwriter to fully develop the screenplay. Character development,
Dex and Oz need further backstory to develop empathy among viewers and to
allow for further character growth. This could involve detailing their home
life, relationships and why they chose to study under Professor Allen. Create a
show Bible, develop a show Bible, which is a comprehensive guide that defines
your show's mission statement, character breakdowns, episode summaries and future
storylines. It's a key document to share with potential producers, networks or
streaming platforms to give them a comprehensive overview of your show.
Location scouting, start identifying potential shooting locations that would
suit the environment and aesthetic of your series. Think about where Dex and Oz
would live, where Professor Allen's classes would take place and where
Veronica Hartfield's office would be located. Assemble a production team, start
identifying potential directors, producers and a cinematographer. Consider
individuals who have a background in comedy or satirical work. You'll also
need to consider the post-production team for editing, music and sound design.
Casting, start scouting for actors who can bring your characters to life. They
should be able to handle both comedic and dramatic scenes and should have
chemistry together since Dex and Oz will spend a lot of time together. Storyboarding,
once the script is finalized, start storyboarding key scenes, especially those
that involve the clues and the detective work. Budgeting, create a detailed
budget plan for the entire production. This would include production costs,
cast and crew salaries, location costs, post-production costs, and contingency
funds. Legal aspects, ensure that all legal aspects are covered, including
copyrights for the script and music, contracts for the cast and crew, and
permits for the shooting locations. Marketing and promotion, develop a
marketing strategy to promote your series. This could include creating a trailer,
social media promotion, interviews with cast and crew, and sneak peeks of the
episodes. Distribution plan, research potential networks or streaming
platforms where your show could air. Prepare a pitch for these distributors
explaining why your show would be a good fit for their platform.
Okay, so this has gone too broad. So what we'll do is we'll just pop in the three
areas that I think make sense for now. And that's script development, character
development, and storyboarding.
So we'll pop in over to chat GPT and say, this information is way too general,
comma. What I need is a list of actions just to cover these three concepts.
I'll paste that in.
Okay, I'm going to take this. This is not quite what I want. I'll do one and two.
I think one needs a little bit more information in it. I think three is
premature. So we'll go back to our document and we'll create something called
script. We'll go with zero one. It's just the first concept we're working on.
And we'll say script development like that. We might go zero zero one dot mark down
and we'll paste this information in and we'll give them all headings.
Backstory and we've got storyboarding.
Looks like
I've missed that a little bit. So outline script development, character development.
So I'm going to undo this a bit.
So we have script development. We have character development.
And we have storyboarding. Let's make them all headings.
And wherever we've got a colon like this,
let's
move the text down and turn them into another heading like that.
I think we've captured everything we need. Let's take every variant of the three
hashes and make sure there's a space between them.
And we'll go to the top. We'll call it script development. So let's go over to our mind map
over here and give ourselves some goals. So we've got script development
and we've got backstory. Now the script development is break down the story into
access seams, write the dialogue, create conflict resolution, cooperate.
Okay. What I'd like to do, we'll go back to the scratch pad where we've got all our information.
Can you tell me in the 60 words or less the basic premise of this story?
Two neurodivergent stoners, decks and ores who despite their cluelessness
stumble into real crimes and solve them, unintentionally exposing hidden truths,
their humorous adventures and unique perspectives unfold within modern day setting,
offering comedic, spherical spin on traditional detective stories. That's about right.
Great. So what we'll do is we'll ask you the question.
What are five movies or TV shows that have a similar idea to this?
We'll go with that.
Okay. So I don't know broad city or dude. Where's my car?
Though I think I might have seen it, but the other ones, psych,
Bill and Ted's excellent adventure and pineapple express seem quite accurate.
What do you think?
I'd say Bill and Ted, pineapple express and broad city, maybe the closest.
Have you seen any of those?
I've seen psych, dude, where's my car? Bill and Ted's excellent adventures.
I haven't seen pineapple express or broad city, but the last three I've seen them all.
But just looking at the storyline behind all of them or five of them, I'd say that the first
one, actually the first one, number three, one and three actually are the closest.
Okay, cool. Do you know who the director or writer is for Jay and Silent Bob?
Kevin Smith.
Cliff.
Clerk, small rats. Okay.
Would you say that the way Kevin Smith approaches doing these sorts of movies
would be similar to what you're thinking?
It's on a similar vein to where we're going. It's on a similar path to where we're going with this,
but also like a more, even more modern satirical approach.
Okay. Okay, so let's just work through a couple of these. You like dude, where's my car?
Yeah, I liked it. It was a little bit too, obviously a little bit too crazy, but it was,
it was funny as hell at the time when it came out.
Too crazy, but it is funny. We got psych.
So you do, where's my car was more like a dumber and dumber thing? Whereas these guys are not done?
Don't really want to go the dumb and dumber
direction. Psych is great. It is funny. It is smart.
Yeah. But you said to me you wanted, like, there's some more stoners.
These are stoners. So what they're doing is that they're stoners. Do they think that they're solving,
they think that they're solving one crime, but inadvertently actually find real crimes?
Let's go with that.
Let's add in that statement. So these two guys think they are solving crimes,
but inadvertently find real crimes and are able to solve them.
Now Pineapple Express. Let's just type that in.
Good, bad or otherwise.
I don't know that I've seen it. So I can't give you input yet.
I'm not sure about this one,
as we have not seen it. Don't know about this, not seen it.
We'll say Broad City, Little Anteds, Excellent Adventure.
This is... That's pretty much on point. Yeah, on point.
That's perfect. Now you also mentioned Scooby-Doo and other stuff. So
why Scooby-Doo? Scooby-Doo because it's just because of the content where
they're a group of the age group. The age of the guys is around the same age as the Scooby-Doo group
and they're wandering around solving crimes. Okay, look, wonder around solving crimes, but also
they stumble, especially Scooby-Doo and his sidekick. Shady? Shady? Stumble.
Especially Scooby and Shaggy. Cool.
Was there another show? The Hardy Boys, of course, was too
young guys around the same age as well. I never saw that, but they weren't Stoner were they?
They weren't Stoner, but think of it's basically the same type of thing as Scooby-Doo. It's like
their ghost and supernatural mysteries that turn out to be somebody like a real person.
Okay.
Can I get five more shows that fit the positive examples within this list? In my opinion,
we've got two negative examples because we don't know about them. Sure. I just want to see if we've
got more. Harold and Kumar. Is that? There is a female Sleuth character that I'm thinking about
who is about 15 years old. What show would that be?
Don't remember it being Veronica Marce.
What about Nancy Drew?
Okay. I don't know though that Nancy Drew fits in with the style of thinking that.
No. It's more like a take the Hardy Boys and Scooby-Doo and cross it with Bill and Ted.
Okay. Take the Hardy Boys and Scooby-Doo and cross it with Bill and Ted and Jay and Silent Bob.
So that we get the fun loving Sleuth accidental Sleuths accidental detectives
with the irony of Stoners.
The one I'm thinking about, I just want to bring it in. Who is the female
Sherlock Holmes that is on Netflix?
Anola Holmes. Have you seen that? I haven't seen Anola Holmes but I've heard of
it but okay. It's a good it's a very good show so we could look into that. Yes okay.
Oh yeah that's a girl out of Stranger Things. Can you take the information that you just wrote
for us and also include Anola Holmes as an idea?
Okay. What I'm going to do, I didn't like the direction that just went so I'm going to come
up to our original question and alter it and that should then alter this in the shape that we want.
We'll just go with that. I don't know what else to ask. Okay. What I'm going to do,
that still didn't give what I wanted exactly so I'm going to copy that information. We'll
call this philosophy. So it's like the show. What's driving the show? Show philosophy
dot mark down and we'll take that line. We'll pop back one. We'll take that line.
We'll take
this information and we're going to come back to it and say I have some ideas
for the show philosophy comma. Some of the ideas overlap here but what I would like you to do
is break it down into five separate sections and an overview. Each section should describe
information relevant to the particular section comma. A section would be Scooby-Doo.
Let's see where we go with that.
Okay. This is pretty good. Let's just show philosophy all the way down. I'm going to just
pop it into this document here. Let's expand this out a bit and overview.
Get rid of those.
We can use this now as a second brain for driving a lot of content can be driven from
this particular information. The only other thing I would want to question is there anything from
Psyche that you want to bring into this? I like how the insight, I like his focus and intelligence
when it comes to the thinking outside of the box. Okay. Could you also bring in the good doctor?
The good doctor. Do you know the show? I don't know the show. Very interesting. So let's go to
YouTube. Go good doctor. So he's Asperger's I think. Good doctor trailer.
I met Sean Murphy when he was 14 years old.
Sean just act like a normal human being.
He was and he still is an extraordinary young man.
Autism. Difficulty in communicating. His high functioning. He's capable of living on his own.
Difficulty in using language and abstract concepts.
Does it sound like I'm describing a surgeon?
He's breathing. He saved his life. Who are you? I'm Dr. Sean Murphy. I'm a surgical resident
at San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital. You thought that this board wouldn't have any doubts about
hiring a surgeon diagnosed with autism. Justify your decision. He also has Savant Syndrome.
Genius level skills in several areas. He sees things. It's his heart. Adam needs an echocardiogram.
No, behave yourself or you'll be removed from the building. The echo is normal. Show them.
And analyzes things in ways that we can't even begin to understand. Again.
Again. Again. There. Looks normal to me. It's not normal. This kid was sprayed with glass
sharks. What if a piece of glass aired his bloodstream? What could be looking behind the heart?
You were right.
Why were you rude to me when we first met and now you want to be my friend?
Which time was it that you were pretending? He's got a serious deficit.
Child is alive today because of that deficit. And tomorrow one may be dead because of it.
We hire Sean and we give hope to those people with limitations that those limitations
are not what they think they are. That they do have a shot.
Never forget, you're the smart one. You can do anything.
I love the savant aspect of it where especially decks can
hone in on a particular thing and his divergency walks in on it and he's able to see things
that others can't. And Olin is often the guy who sticks up for decks knowing that
he's usually right. But I'm going to come back to that. Have you seen the Queen's Gambit?
Okay, so let's bring up the Queen's Gambit.
Queen's Gambit trailer.
Let's go with this one.
I'm going to come along and want to teach you things.
Doesn't make them any smarter.
You just let them blow by and you go on ahead and do just what and how you feel like.
Someday you're going to be all alone. So you need to figure out how to take care of yourself.
Tell the readers of life how it feels and to be a girl among all those men.
I don't mind it. Jess isn't always competitive. Jess can also be
beautiful.
You're an orphan, Beth. I'm fine being alone. I feel safe in an entire world of just 64 squares.
I'll creativity and psychosis often go hand in hand.
Or for that matter.
Genius and madness.
I feel safe in an entire world of just 64.
What I want to point out here is that what happens in the Queen's Gambit,
what happens in The Good Doctor, it happens a little bit in psych. I don't think it happens
in the mentalist too much, but it happens in these is that they are seeing things
that are not real, that give real meaning to the story. So for her, she lays down on a bed
and she sees the chessboard on the ceiling and she can just see where all the moves are.
In psych, he sees stuff like that all the time. In The Good Doctor, you've just always got him
seeing these things that are in virtual in his head that other people can't see.
So what I want to do is come back to what we've got here.
I need you to give me three more short sentences on these different movies,
comma, what we're really looking for is the savant capabilities within these TV shows.
So they're not movies.
So I say The Good Doctor, Queen's Gambit,
and we've only got two there. We could bring in the mentalist baby.
I'm going to say it, but the other one that comes to me is Limitless.
Limitless? That'd be more so than mentalist, right?
That, yeah, because limitless, yeah.
So go Limitless.
Let's see what we get.
Again, The Good Doctor and the Queen's Gambit make two statements that I think are relevant
is that there's this visualization. Visualization in 3D is how he does it.
She does the same thing. Visualize and plan, multiple moves ahead.
Okay, so let's get back to our document and add these in.
I'm going to take that out.
I'm not sure what those are. So let's, oh, that's from the previous area.
So let's just add this colon, colon,
add that, move on down, and we've got this.
So let's get just a general idea of, let's get a synopsis.
And what we'll do is we'll go back to our original document that you gave me.
We'll go to scratch pad and say using the original idea, comma, and show philosophies.
I would like you to come up with a 250 word synopsis for a show. Here we go.
Original idea like that. And we'll also say show philosophies.
Now we'll paste in the original idea here and we will go to the show philosophies.
And we'll paste them in here.
I'll just hit stop because it looks like I pasted it into the wrong spot.
Press edit, original idea is here.
Go down to the bottom, cut that out.
Okay.
As they uncover, as they uncover.
Okay. We'll just put that in there.
Press generate response.
Now that's about an hour into the session. I think we've got a good understanding of things.
What we'll do now is we'll play this back just to see whether it's what you like.
And then we might end up the session.
Sure.
Let's hit play.
Played and amazed is a vibrant and engaging television series that follows the amusing
and unexpected adventures of two neurodivergent stoners, Dex and Oz, as they unwittingly become
entangled in solving real crimes. The duo, reminiscent of a modern day hardy boys crossed
with the whimsical goofiness of Bill and Ted, bring a fresh take on the classic mystery solving
genre. Inadvertently, Dex's keen eye for patterns and Oz's unbounded creativity often
lead them to stumble upon genuine criminal activities within their seemingly mundane lives.
Taking inspiration from Scooby-Doo, their shenanigans often start as innocent fun
but morph into daring escapades. Enriched by the influence of Jay and Silent Bob,
their witty and lighthearted banter conceals their raw ingenuity and resourcefulness.
Dex and Oz's neurodivergence, akin to the brilliant minds and the good doctor and the
Queen's gambit, gifts them with a unique lens through which they view the world.
In the debut episode, their favorite professor, who channels existentialist philosophy reminiscent
of the philosophy of absurdity, is wrongfully accused of professional misconduct. Driven
by a sense of justice and loyalty, much like Enola Holmes, Dex and Oz put their eccentric
detective skills to the test. They embark on an adventure full of clever plot twists,
hilarious encounters, and moments of genuine heart.
Blazed and amazed masterfully weaves comedy, mystery,
and the untapped strengths of neurodivergent individuals into an enthralling tapestry that
captivates audiences from all walks of life. Through laughs, risks, and the unraveling of
enigmas, Dex and Oz prove that heroes come in the most unexpected packages.
I think we could convert this into a blog and just maybe have a landing page who knows,
so what we'll do now. Go to GoDaddy, I think.
Let's go Blazed and Amazed. Is that it? Yeah, Blazed and Amazed. Yep, press search.
It's available? Yeah. Okay. Do you want to also look at Blazed and Amazed?
What one would be easy, like if somebody was searching that, Blazed and Amazed or Blazed
and Amazed? Yeah, no, I'm gonna jump back and just say Blazed and Amazed.com.
Great. So I'll buy it? Yeah. Okay, so make it yours. We'll just press continue.
No domain protection for now. No professional email. Continue to cart.
Okay, why is it so expensive? Let's just do it for one year.
$16 Australian. I'm ready to pay.
Okay, we own a domain called Blazed and Amazed.com. If we go back to our mind map for a second,
we'll say domain Blazed and Amazed.com. Throw that in. If we go website,
give it a domain now. Blog. What we can do is take, say, these apicast videos and
create a chronological view of how we develop this. So chronological
show development based on apicast. Now, we've got a show philosophy at the moment,
or show synopsis, I think. There's a Y in there, I think. We've got a show philosophy as well.
We could develop it further. So come back to our documents.
We'll just say show philosophy needs more input.
Show synopsis. Looking good, in my opinion.
As we go in here, we'll just give ourselves some emoji marks. So show synopsis will be
good. Show philosophy will be okay. Domain name is done.
Okay. Now, let's just talk a little bit about next steps. Backstory, character development.
So we've got
Dex and Oz. Okay, that's cool. So we've got Dylan, Dex Richards, and we've got Alan, Oz, Cooper.
So we need to expand on these guys. Let's just throw in a few things. Let's go storyboarding.
For now, we need to do some mid-journey work to develop out these characters,
just how we think they'll look. We'll leave it at that. I'll have a read through everything. In
fact, you have a read through it all as well. What I'm going to do is share this mind map with you.
Okay. Press to music.com. You got edit capability on this. So we hit share.
So you can look at this. You can even expand on it if you want to. We'll take the script as it
stands today, and we'll hit the share button here. So we copy the link. We'll just see what it says.
Copy the link. And rather than sending it to you as an email, what I'm going to do is go
to the mind map. I'm going to create a concept called resources.
And I'm going to say chat GPT. And I'm just going to paste it in as a hyperlink for you. Okay.
So you can just go here, click on that, and it'll take you straight to that.
And that'll do for today.