Hi, I'm AppyDave, and the new voice mode has just come out on chat, GPT. And what
we're going to do is use it to create an application on the fly. I'm in the middle
of doing something else at the moment, but I needed a little bit of an automation.
I think we can create it in a few minutes using chat, GPT, voice modes. Let's get
into it.
So here's the problem I wanna solve. I've got 48 images coming through in Leonardo
at the moment. Now the 48 images are over six different categories of prompts. There's
two versions of the prompt for each category, and then there's four images and I
need to put these renamed into a particular folder quickly.
Now I'm in the middle of doing a video on the YouTube launch optimizer, and I've
already created a bunch of assets for the intro 48 in Told. And when I put in the
file names into this system, I actually had to do it all manually. I didn't even
think to automate it, but
Now I'm going to the outro where I've got no images, and I thought, why can't I just
write a script to solve this problem?
So I've got chat GPT ready to go. I can press the record button to get it into talk
mode and we'll have a conversation to build this software. I'm not geared for recording
these screens, so
it's gonna have to be done this way. So I'm hitting record and I'm just waiting for
it.
Are you listening to me? It's not saying anything
loud and clear what's on your mind.
I would like to write a script fairly quickly. Don't write in the programming language
just yet. Let's explore the idea and the problem I'm trying to solve. So I'm currently
using Leonardo AI to generate images and what you can do is you can enter in a prompt
and it generates four images and what I need to do is when I click the download button
on each of those images though end up in a folder on my computer as they arrive on
my computer, I need to move them to another folder. But let me describe the structure
of what we're going on. So I'm currently working through images in both the intro
and the outro of the script, where specifically looking at the outro today, and I
have six sections in the outro. Each section in the outro will have two prompts.
So in this case we'll have 12 different prompts, but every time we run a prompt we
get four images.
So are you with me so far?
Absolutely.
So you're generating 12 prompts for the outro and since each prompt yields four images,
you end up with 48 images in total.
You wanna automate moving these images from the download location to specific folders.
Am I following
You are, but there's a little bit of a grouping that you need to think about. So
there are six prompts of which there are two versions for each prompt. So let's say
we're working on the very first sentence of the intro or the outro. We would end
up calling that number one, but because it's the first version, we would want the
letter A to come after the number one. Then because we're working with the intro,
we might say dash intro and then as images get downloaded, the first one would be
one a dash intro dash one. The next one would be dash two, the next one, dash three
and the fourth one would be dash four. Then when I move on to the second row of images
for the same sentence, they would be one B dash intro dash one one B dash intro,
dash two dash three and dash four. Then when I get to the second intro,
the second intro video, I'd probably wanna say two a dash one intro dash one and
that'll just keep repeating. The only time things will change on this is that when
we get to the outro, I want to use the word outro and I probably want to use a different
folder. Does that make sense so far?
Got it.
You are organizing the images based on their position in the sequence and whether
they're from the intro or outro.
So for the first sentence, version A,
the second version of the first sentence would be one B intro dash one and so forth.
Then for the second sentence you'd start with two a intro one,
and for the outro you'd switch to names like one, a outro one and place them in a
different folder. That structure makes sense.
Great. So the other thing I normally I would do this as a file watcher so that it
can just run on automation, but I just need to get the code working. So a simple
script that I can run and what I'll probably do is I'll download four images at a
time. So we'll essentially be working with one A would be the example and I need
to with that script, which will run from the command line, just put in a parameter
one A. Sounds good to me.
and you'll be able to formulate the file names of say four that you find for different
images that are in the downloads directory. I will tell you what the
pattern is for those file names so you know how to find them and then you can just
move them over to the appropriate folder. It might be useful that in the script we
hard code both the input and the output folders, but the output folder should have
a sub folder as well, which can be the same name as that file name we were talking
about. So if we got one a dash intro dash one point
w, I'm not sure the format, we've gotta check what it is, whatever the format is,
it's going into probably a jpeg, let's just go and have a gander at that intros.
They are definitely,
JPEGs that it's going into and you'll move it into a subfolder called intro. If we're
deal dealing with the outro, you'll name it with the word outro, but you also put
into a subfolder of outro. Does that make sense?
Perfectly clear. So the script will take a parameter, like one a intro,
locate the corresponding images in the downloads directory and move them to an output
folder with sub folders like intro or outro.
The images will be renamed based on the parameter such as one, a intro, one jpeg,
and placed in the appropriate sub folder.
Now about the file pattern for identifying the images, how are they currently named
when downloaded?
Okay, that's a good question. Can you just wait while I check this out?
Take your time,
let me know what you find.
Okay, so what we're going to do is head over to
the Leonardo page. I'm just going to find one image here and download it. I think
I need to start from the bottom to get my ordering correct.
So we'll just press download
and it says that an image is going down into the downloads directory Right now. We'll
just bring up the folder. It says it's coming through as Leonardo. There's a big
long name, there's a dash one at the end and it's a jpeg. What I'm going to do is
pass in this or download the second file for you so you know what it is and the third
and the fourth. So these are all related to a particular prompt and they're coming
through in the format.
They're a little odd to be honest. So we've got a
dash zero dash one at the end of the jpeg. We've also got a underscore zero for some
reason. We've got a dash one dash one at the end and we've got
another dash or I kept saying dash, I meant underscore. So I think you just need
to look for JPEGs. That should be enough. I'll make sure there are no other JPEGs
in this particular folder, but apart from that, let's not worry too much about the
incoming name. You just need to change it to the upcoming name. Is that okay?
Got it.
The images have varied naming patterns, but we can focus on just targeting JPEG files.
The script will rename these files to our desired format and move them to the appropriate
sub-folder based on the parameters you provide, like one a intro,
this approach should work smoothly.
Great. I'm just gonna put it on hold and get things set up
sound.
So I'm just stopping that for a second and I'll pause the video.
So let's just take stock of where we're at. We've got this bunch of images that are
created and if we go down to the very bottom, we can see that the images match to
the prompts that are going through here. It goes all the way to number 10 and the
bottom row is a complex machine labeled previous video and next video. Is that what
it's saying? I'm not sure it is, which is great. So I think we can have a conversation
with ChatGPT now.
So we're just pressing the button. Are you listening to me at the moment?
Can you hear me?
However, I will also spend time hanging out with my friends playing Dungeons and
Dragons
whenever our schedules actually align
impulse control.
I'm a little confused. What have we been talking about in this conversation?
We've been discussing a script to automate the process of organizing images generated
by Leonardo ai.
You wanna download these images which come in a specific format and then move them
to designated folders based on whether they're for the intro or outro of your project.
The script will rename and sort these images into sub folders accordingly.
Does that help clarify?
It does. Look, I've got a little prompt that I want to give you. It's called Read.
And with the read I'm just going to give you the information you can do with it what
you want. I've given you the source folder so you'll know where to find the files.
I've also given you the four files that are currently in that folder and I've given
you an a few output folders. One is the main one where the assets go, and then two
sub-folders, one called outro, one called intro. And then under that I've given you
all the intro graphics 'cause this'll just help you understand the naming convention.
Now we are going to be specifically focusing on the outro folder. And what I need
you to do is create me one simple ruby script that can do this. Give me the name
of the file
CHMOD so that I can make it executable and just at one command line parameter to
run it. Does that make sense? Are you ready for me to give you that prompt?
Got it. I'm ready for your prompt. Once you give me the details, I'll help you craft
that Ruby script.
Okay, so I've typed that prompt into a, a different chat, the same chat window, but
on the computer. Hopefully we're not gonna have any confusion. Did that come through
to you? Okay.
I'm afraid I can't see messages or prompts from other chat windows or devices. Could
you please provide the prompt here and I'll help you out with the Ruby script?
Okay, no worries. So I thought,
we were using the same chat window on both the mobile phone and the desktop. Maybe
we weren't. So I'll just tell you what we've got. So the source directory is called
dash Tilda Sync, smart downloads, download images. Everything is in lowercase with
dashes except for the word sync. And let's not worry too much for the output folders.
I'll give you them later and I will let you know that the files are one a dash intro
dash one
jpeg.
Actually, we're stopping this conversation here.
Got it. So the source directory for the images is sync, smart downloads, downloaded
images.
We'll focus on organizing files like one a intro dash one jpeg.
When you're ready we can proceed with the Ruby script to handle this.
Okay, great.
look, can you just,
I'm gonna talk to my friends, so just hold on one second or you can listen in, but
just hold on.
So guys, you can see the confusion that I've just created for myself there. I'm having
a conversation on the phone, but I'm also having a conversation in the same chat
window over on the desktop and it didn't work. And I'm not sure why because I do
find that it's relatively easy to go from the phone to the desktop, but it hasn't
worked in this particular case. So with that said, let's just see if we do end up
getting a Ruby script that's going to move the files.
Okay, you've heard all that. Can you move forward with what we've gotta do?
Absolutely. Let's get into it. Here's a simple ruby script to move and rename your
files.
Images,
sync, smart downloads, downloaded images, all lowercase. Make sure to give your input
folders there so you're above the input directory.
And make sure to apply the map address of your download location here.
This script should be executed as a commands prompt. Set it up as simple as possible.
Prompt name, target, selection for the process and folder name.
Then you can run it with the command
pseudo transform up
rb,
run it as an argument
and call the appropriate location. And that's it.
This script should be executed as a command prompt.
Set it up as simple as possible.
Just to let you know, I'm running on a Mac, not on Linux.
Nope, that doesn't change anything.
The script I provided should work perfectly on Mac
Os.
Just make sure you have a Ruby installed, which is included by default on most Mac
OS versions.
Give it a try and let me know how it goes.
I'm just refreshing
the chat window on my desktop so that I can have a look at what's going on. I'm just
gonna put you on pause for a second. Is that okay?
Of course. Take your time.
I'll be here when you're ready to continue.
So it's come through and written a script here. What I'm gonna do is just copy all
that information and we'll head over to Visual Studio, I guess, and we'll just paste
it in there and I'll have a quick look at it.
So if we look at this,
folder, we've got a intro area where all the current intro images are. What we wanna
do is put in the outro
area. And one of the things we've gotta change is the folder looks wrong, it's not
downloaded, and that's definitely not the outro. I'm just gonna make a bunch of modifications
and just check this code out before I run it.
So I've added a whole bunch of debug code to this, and I'm really glad I did because
a problem happened and I didn't see it in the code, so I didn't run it with the moving
of the files. Let's see what happens if we do run this application. So I think it's
called Move images, the code that we want, the location that we want it to go. And
when we run this, we end up getting too many files. In fact, it's coming through
to 199 and there's only meant to be four. And the issue happens to be that it's going
down into the sub directories, underneath the assets folder, and there's a whole
lot of other stuff going on there. So what we'll do is we'll just get rid of this
and run it again and we should get about four different files that's looking about
right, if we bring up the folders,
We're looking to move these four files here, and they should move into this folder
just here. So let's just
run it. I don't think I've got the move turned on. I don't, so nothing should happen.
We'll just scroll down here and unco this file.
Clear it out. Run. Run it one more time and do, now we've got some files. We've also
got something coming in that we don't need.
Let's just go look at them. This is
Well there we have a live demonstration of the new advanced speech mode. In this
case, we were writing some software and it does work. I'm now going to be able to
go back to the video I was working on and create, download, and label a bunch of
files. I would've liked to have the speech,
tell you more, but that particular chat window went back to an older version of the
speech mode, so the more basic one, which works fabulously, but I couldn't interrupt
it as an example. So anyway, I'm happy Dave. I'll see in the next video where I'll
be talking about prompt engineering and agent workflows.