In this video, we're exploring knowledge driven development, an idea that fits under
the context, engineering or coding way of development. And we're doing it by looking
at a starter template that I'm putting together, which puts together next, Convex
and Cloudflare. But has the whole thing developed using AI agents using the Bmad
method?
Now, if you've been following vibe coding for a while, you might have come across
some repos such as Claude, Taskmaster, and Super Claude. Now, the one I've been following
a lot lately, and building starter templates and applications is the BMAD method,
which stands for Breakthrough Method for AI Driven Development. And if you want to
find out more about this particular technique, you can go over to BMAD code over
on YouTube. And he's got some great videos demonstrating how to use this.
Over the last couple of weeks, I've been doing a lot of videos around the context
engineering space. One in particular on the BMAD method is I retrospectives, which
is something you might do at the end of a sprint in software development. But I'm
now putting together a little starter kit, a full stack application
which is following an AI software development first approach. And as I was putting
it together, I came up with a stack that I wanted to work with. I wanted high performance
computing, I wanted reactive databases, and I wanted all the bells and whistles that
a modern stack would have. But the key difference that I wanted with this is that
I knew it wasn't going to be developed by me. Instead, I wanted it to be driven through
documents that an architect or an entrepreneur or a software developer could put
together and build the complete application.
Now. I started developing this application yesterday. So the initial commit happened
and then there was a bunch of documentation as I was developing the requirements
document, the PRD, the epics, stories and the architectural document. And then this
morning I sat and started creating the code for the first story. And this is the
foundation for the application.
So let's go and have a look at the code base in Visual Studio and what you'll be
able to see, especially in this area here is generally starter files that are needed
to get this project off the ground. And most of these were created in that last story
that you just saw. But what everything is being driven off is this documents directory.
And this documents directory was created using the Bmad method. Now up here we've
got the Bmad core. This is where all the agents and the templates the checklists
are. We've also got because I'm using Claude Code, to do this, a bunch of commands
set up for Claude that follow the Bmad method.
Now, as we look through the documents, the very first document that got created using
a particular agent called Mary was the project brief. And this was an overview of
what I wanted to build the application on. After that, I went into the architecture
agent, and I built essentially the stack that I want everything to work on the different
technologies. After that, we were able to combine those two together to build a product
requirements document, and the product requirements document started listing all
the different stages of the build. There's essentially seven epics, and each epic
has a whole lot of individual components that need to be built over time.
Now, if you don't know what an epic or a story is, there are ideas that come from
agile software development, which is designed for software development teams, and
the idea is that major areas of building the codebase are thought of as epics, and
then they're individually broken down into stories.
Now this information is really useful to the AI agent, but it has a problem in that
it's way too big. And so I was able to use the AI agent from the BMAD method called
the Scrum Master, and with the Scrum Master, I was able to do what's called sharding,
which is essentially splitting up all the files that are here into individual files
that we can work with. And I was able to do that for the PRD. I was also able to
do it for the architecture. So everything is in a much smaller unit of work
And so when you're using Cursor, or Claude Code,, you can easily find just the dedicated
piece of information that you need to effectively generate code.
So when I started building the application this morning, I wanted to start from Epic
one, which is get the foundation, the end to end development in place. And I needed
to work on story number one, and this is mono repo tooling and initialization. And
it would be considered done once it passes the acceptance criteria such as we have
a GitHub repository, we've got a package.json, we've got a few different folders.
But to do this, we need to break that information down into a detailed story. And
to do that, we use, in BMAD method, we use a particular agent called the Scrum Master.
And one of the capabilities of the scrum master is that they can create the next
story task. So the story task got created, and as you can see, it's quite a detailed
document. And this document was at one level at the beginning of the creation, but
after that, it then needed to go through development. And the development is done
by a totally different agent called the development agent.
and the development agent has all the skills of a software developer.
and when they're finished, they will come back to the story and fill in information
along the way of what they've done.
Now. The way you run a story against a large language model depends on the environment.
You're using Cursor, and windsurf or do it one way, but I'm using Claude Code, so
we're working very much in the terminal. And this was the terminal window that it
was processing. It all happened on autopilot. I didn't really need to get involved,
but once I got to a certain level and it had completed, I said, well, how do I test
this? How do I know it's even working? And what it did was it started giving me a
list of commands that I could run. And if we take some of them, we'll take the script
execution in this particular case,
and we'll head over to this terminal and run it. And it's just starting to show me
how to test and check that the code is working.
So I thought that was great. But one of the things I noticed when I looked through
the completion notes was that there were a whole lot of new concepts being added.
So when we look here, we can see that there's turbo because it's using turbo repo,
we've got prettier ESLint, we've got a Husky with Pre-commit
and we've got a whole lot of new directories. And that got me thinking. There are
documents that probably need to be updated to reflect all these new concepts. Some
of them might be just the basic directory structure, others
might be patterns
for command, lines
that you can use for different tools. And I thought, how do I get that back into
the main documentation
so that the next time I run an agent, it's aware of this.
So once I finished the story and I had everything committed with a nice commit message,
I thought, can I create some sort of agent or a technique that would allow me to
automatically update the document? And so I started a new conversation in Claude
over here on the right. And essentially what I did was
I said to
it,
I've done this new story, and there's a whole lot of changes that you've made and
you've documented them. You've told me what they are, but they're not actually stored
anywhere. And I said, how can we go about modifying the system? And I wasn't sure
whether I wanted to modify the BMAD agents.
I didn't know whether I wanted it to modify the template when it creates a story
or whether I wanted a brand new agent altogether.
and as part of that conversation, it essentially came up with a plan of action for
me.
and phase number one of that would be to look at the BM a D template and see if it
could be updated. After that, it would look at applying any of the changes and documents
that came out of that last story and putting it into the system. And the last thing
would be just to document it a little bit so I could tell you about it.
So let's first look at what it's added into VS code. So if we go down to Docs, we've
got all the architecture, PRD, and Project Brief that was originally created with
the
Bmad method, but now we've got these new folders. So one of them is called Examples.
So examples for the backend configuration and front end have not yet been created
because we haven't worked on any of that. But one thing we have done is the Monorepo
setup. So when we go in there, we can see concepts like the project structure, other
sorts of configurations going on.
if we reduce the examples and go into something like lessons learned, we can also
have a recording of lessons learned during the application development process. And
most of them are all empty at the moment, but we do have stories.
and what were the lessons learned in story one dash one?
And you can see a list of these ideas that are basically broken down into concepts
like context, challenge, solution outcome and recommendation. Or in this one problem
impact solution and how to prevent it.
Now, I think the most important files that this was generating were all the patterns
files. So what's the back end patterns? The front end software going to look like?
How do you do test now? At the moment they're all rudimentary because we haven't
done much of the application. But over time these will get extended. And so every
time it wants to create a new component in the front end, in the back end, or maybe
do some testing, we'll be able to have examples of what we consider the best practice
that it can use when it goes to write the code.
Now you might be wondering how do you get it for yourself?
Well, if you go to the repo and
you go to the docs and the methodology folder, I've put in a new file called KDD
Overview. Now, if we open that up in a markdown format, we can see it's the knowledge
driven development integration and
the problem that we're trying to solve is that after implementing a story, there's
a whole lot of new code and file files and folders, and the documentation isn't up
to date. So this came up with the idea of calling it knowledge driven development.
I thought this is a pretty good term. I wasn't sure whether it should be called context
driven development, but it doesn't really matter too much. Essentially, the integration
strategy that it's gone with
is updating the Bmad core templates. So there's new files going on there. We've got
a new KDD validation checklist. We've got ideas of where we're going to write information
into and keep track of stuff like the patterns, lessons learned and examples, and
you can add more over time.
And it's also gone through the story template, which is used as a basis whenever
a new story is created using BMAD, and it's just added in a whole lot of extra steps
to help propagate information back to the documentation system.
Now, I'll leave a link in the description if you want to find out the actual commit
that this was on, or you can come over to the repo, click on the commits that are
going on here. We're actually looking for the implementation of the knowledge driven
design integration with BMAD methodology. And you can see the overview of what it's
done here, but as you go through, you can see the individual parts that's added in.
For instance, if we look at this particular developer agent, so that's one of the
agents, it's got a new section in there to talk about the KDD pattern. And if you
scroll down, you'll see things like the KDD validation checklist, which is now part
of BMAD core,
the definition of done checklist, which is a really powerful tool that you can use
to make sure that everything that's in the story was actually done.
It's been updated with knowledge about the knowledge driven development compliance.
So go through this commit, there's 19 odd file changes. Maybe one day they'll get
added to the BMAD method itself. But I think the really powerful thing to note here
is that when you want to modify the BMAD method, it's really easy by starting with
something like
this KDD integration
overview document that I created and just running it within Claude Dev
and it'll make all the changes you need to the Bmad core and the different agents.
I.
Anyway, that's knowledge driven development using the Bmad method and context engineering.
I'm AppyDave, and if you want more videos on the BMAD method, or you want to see
more of what I'm doing with creating AI starter kits, then please like and subscribe
and I'll see you in the next video.