Last week an AI autonomous programmer was announced by Cognition. It's called Devon.
And in the week since a bunch of open source repositories are trying to replicate that functionality.
In this video I'm going to show you OpenDevon and how to install it.
The back end, the front end and the Docker container.
And then we'll talk about three different examples and the actual cost of using this product.
Let's get straight into installing OpenDevon.
And the way you can do that is navigate over to GitHub OpenDevon, find the repository for OpenDevon
and then just click on the code button.
From there you'll have three different ways that you can clone it down onto your computer.
I use the GitHub CLI tool, GH repo clone OpenDevon slash OpenDevon.
From there I went into Visual Studio just to have a look at what we've got.
To run this locally you're going to need a couple of runtime environments
and on my computer I use ASDF to manage programming language versions.
I've currently got Node and Python installed on my computer with different versions.
And I've also got Docker.
And if you run a Docker PS you'll see a list of containers that you've got on your computer.
Now the one we actually need for OpenDevon is called ghcr.io slash OpenDevon sandbox.
Make sure you do a Docker pull on that and pull it down to your computer.
Looking at the list of files in your code editor, what you'll want to do is copy the configtoml template to config.toml
and notice here that it's light gray.
It's also listed in my gitignore because we're going to put secret information in here like API keys
and we don't want that to be pushed up to a repo.
We can now configure a large language model to use with OpenDevon
and I've decided I want to use OpenAI so I've headed over to platform.openai.com
and gone down to the API keys, created a new one and just made a copy of it.
From there what I can do is go over to the config.toml and just paste the value in there.
You can also export it to your environment.
With three installation steps, the first being the back end.
What you need is a Python environment and from there we can do a pip install, pip-enf.
Follow that up with a pip-enf install-v and a pip shell
and what that will do is use the pip file that's already in the project
to make sure that the environment matches what works with OpenDevon.
With your environment in place, you can now use UVicon to open the back end on port 3000.
So long as you've gone through any troubleshooting sort of issues,
if you come back later on and you try to run this and you have errors,
just remember that you do need to activate the shell each time before starting the server.
Let's now look at the front-end chatbot which we will be running on port 3001 in this case
and if you go over to your project, there will be a folder called front-end.
You can just CD into that project and run an NPN install.
These installations we can now start the application
and what you'll see here are a couple of terminals where on the left I've got the Python back end running
and on the right I've got the Node.js front-end running
and you can see that it's running on port 3001.
Now before you write any prompts to create some code,
we do need to configure and make sure everything is working with the Docker container.
What you can do is start the application as normal,
run a Docker PS and you will see no containers listed
but the moment you start running an actual prompt to generate code, it will reach out
and from there you should be able to do a Docker PS.
You'll see the OpenDevern sandbox running.
Let's look at the example application that I wanted to create with OpenDevern.
Now recently I've been playing around with YouTube automation agents,
what I would call an army of workers and I've been doing that using CrewAI
and what I was looking for was if the agents are running in the background,
how can I communicate with them from the front-end and what technology would I pick
and I thought let's try and create an AstroJS application using OpenDevern.
Getting over to the OpenDevern workspace,
we can select a large language model to work with.
I'm using OpenAI so I'll go with GPT-4
and from there we just need to write a prompt.
Now the prompt I had was install a new AstroJS project named FlyVideo,
use Tailwind CSS and create a simple home page
for a SAS application for YouTube automation.
So I started running NPN Create Astro at latest with the parameters
that make sense for the project that I'm creating
and then starting to install NodeJS dependencies.
One of the things it did do was use the workspace variable
to create a new workspace folder within the project that is OpenDevern.
After that it started running and I noticed it was running for a little while
and didn't seem to be working, I wasn't sure what was going on.
I didn't actually investigate the issue too deeply that it couldn't install AstroJS
and what I did was make a bit of a clumsy mistake of thinking
that this was all running locally on my computer
because I've been using CrewAI where a lot of the Python work is local
and part of your local environment.
So I gave it this prompt saying I'm using ASDF, I'm using Node20,
can you do an installation doing that and I tried to do that and it failed
because what was going on was this is all running in a Docker container
and the Docker container hasn't got ASDF installed.
It should have worked but I couldn't figure out what was going on initially.
What this led to was a thought of is this costing me any money at the moment
and what I found out was that five minutes of playing around with this
had cost me $4.23 in open AI credits and I hadn't achieved anything at this point.
So I made a decision just to abandon this and go to a simpler solution
just using HTML pages.
Moving on to example number two which was just to set up a simple HTML page
around this YouTube automation army.
What I did was developed a fairly complex prompt
where I was talking about this agent framework
where transcripts from YouTube videos could be processed by different agents.
I needed a couple of fields, the title of the video, the transcript,
a list of agents that I would like to work with
and a simple start button.
When the start button runs the agents would run
and there'd be events coming back
and hopefully a bunch of results from the agents.
With that all in place I just pasted it straight into OpenDevon
and let's see what happens.
OpenDevon started running the new task
and it runs an LS command on the workspace folder
and it figures out that there's no files there
and you can see that it's empty here.
From here it then moves on to a planner
and starts writing some code for you.
OpenDevon is going to show you the code in a terminal here
and also tell you what it did.
So this current version of FlowVideo page has a transcripted title
it's also got an agent selection list and a start button.
After that it started going into a couple of errors.
I wondered what this was doing and this just kept going on.
If you go and look at the terminal
you can see that there's big prompts being sent
and this is step 12 at the moment
and that got me thinking is this costing me money?
I went over to the costing
and saw that 92 cents had been consumed at this point.
What did we get for it? We got this HTML page.
You can see the form here
and it tells us the information that it's got going on.
Now normally with a page being created like this
what you would want to do is go down to the bottom
and type in a new prompt
but I just stopped the server at that stage
because something wasn't working
and we were in a repeating loop that could be quite expensive.
The last example is a continuation.
It's updating the page
but what makes it a little bit different
is that in the past we had a workspace with no files
so it knows how to create new applications.
In this case there are files
so it can assume that it's just taking the work that's there
and updating it further.
Tape the prompt that we had before
I just made a couple of modifications to the text.
I said I've already created the HTML page
and I told it what sections had gone right.
I just added in down below
where I'd already had this information
told it this is the next section
that I want you to add into the system.
Now what it's done is said
OpenDevon is starting the new task
of reading in the index.html in the workspace
and it's figured out that it needs to create
an event log and a GPT output sections.
What it does is try to work with a file
in a sub-direction called workspace
and that was a bit of an error
but it self-corrected
with now editing the workspace
slash index.html.
We've got a bunch of HTML
the first section being the event log is a table
the second section GPT output
is a couple of rows just showing some JSON.
We look at the old form
and the new form is now added
event log and the GPT output.
If we look at the costing for this
we can see that cost 36 cents
and it was quite successful.
For evaluating whether this is a good product to use
we need to look at the costs.
So how much did this cost
and for me the first project
which was a bit of a failure the AstroJS
cost me $4.23
and I never got an output that satisfied me.
The second one was a success
but then it went into a little bit of an infinite loop
and I stopped it at 92 cents.
The third one worked
there was one error during the process
but it self recovered and that cost me 36 cents
so all up this was a $5.50
using OpenAI GPT for credits.
OpenDevon is very promising
but it needs to be guided at the moment
otherwise you could incur some big costs.
I look forward to seeing what they're going to do
with this over the next few weeks
it could be a worthy contender
and alternative to DevonAI.
I'm Appy Dave.
If you like videos on chat GPT
coding with GPT or prompt engineering
then like and subscribe
and I'll see you in the next video.