OpenAI just made projects available in ChatGPT. Plus, in this video, we're going
to check it out and see how useful it really is.
Now projects is a capability that I've been looking for from ChatGPT plus for a while,
because if you look at my chats over here on the left, you can see this A68 A67.
Now they represent for me video codes for videos that I've put out on AppyDave. And
then we've got other sorts of conversations that I've been having. We go through
September and we've got dozens and dozens of different chats. And the problem I always
have is trying to come up with a naming convention so that I can find them again.
So one of the things I sometimes do with my chats is I give them a prefix. So I kind
of understand and remember where they came from. So if we look at two of the chats
that are going on here, fly. This is for a video asset management software that I'm
building for myself called FliVideo. So that's one of the first projects we want
to identify, find the chats and put them into that project.
Moving further on, I can see that I've got HCL, which stands for KlueLess. The clue
is to do less. This is a programming language that I'm developing using GPT. Further
on, we've got anything that starts with an 'A' and a number. These are videos that
I created in a particular month for AppyDave. Anything that starts with AWB is my
Agent Workflow Builder software that I'm developing. And then a bit further on, we've
got Kozi, which is a cafe idea in Thailand that I'm developing as a podcast.
So we come to the very top. You can see new projects, and what we'll do is we'll
just create a couple projects to get started. So the first one we'll do is FliVideo
for the video asset management tool that I've created. And then the next one, if
we go and click on this add button, we'll just type in AppyDave and we'll put that.
We might just say videos actually, because this is where I'm going to put the videos.
And while we're thinking of that we'll add in one more, which would be the AppyDave
tools. Now what I'll do here is I might put a dash between it so that I can see it
visually. Now, one of the things that happens if you do this is you might go, I want
to rename this. So if you come and click on here, you won't have the ability to rename
it. So if you go and click on it directly it'll come up here and you can rename it
here. So I'm going to just put in a dash right there and we'll press save. And now
we've got three projects ready to go within ChatGPT.
Now, if we look through the left here, I've got four different chats that I know
are obvious that I need to put into videos, and that's because I code my videos in
a sequential order, and I put a bit of a label after it. So what I'm going to do
is just go through and click on all of them, and you see them start getting added.
Now, if I do a refresh, they actually disappear from this list and they should be
available here.
Now I'm going to take a quick opportunity to rename these as I go, because while
codes I can find my videos would be easier if I could see visually what this video
is about. So recently I was using a pair programming tool called Aider, which allowed
me to automate documentations and presentations. So now this is all listed under
my AppyDave videos.
Now what I'll do next is I'll click on FliVideo. And this application that I'm building
has a logo which is green. So what I might do is just change the folder color as
we're going. And at the moment we can drag them up here like we've seen. But as I
go further down we won't be able to see this project. So the other thing that you
can do is click on the little options here and we can move it to FliVideo. And I
know that the damn code, which stands for Digital Asset Management, is also part
of FliVideo. So as I click through to them, they're just adding here on the right.
Now. One capability I'm really looking forward to is this new one called Add Instructions.
But we should just revisit custom instructions so that you understand what they're
used for. So I have some custom instructions. They're quite simple. Basically, I
want to limit how big the response is from ChatGPT by saying say ye if you understand,
and then it just replies with yay! Or if I just want it to read the information and
absorb it, I say read. And if I want it to create an image, I just say create image
followed by the prompt and it creates the image. And so these are simple general
purpose instructions that I use for all my chats.
But what if you need project level instructions? Well, that's what we can do when
we look at the add instructions.
So let's have a look at the custom instructions for affidavit videos. And before
we do, we'll change the color to Brown, which is my brand color. And from there we'll
just go and quickly look at the affidavit channel. Now here, I've got this more and
I've got all this information about who I am. So this is branding information, but
the way I usually put this into my videos, into my YouTube descriptions is I use
the agent workflow builder and we will create a project for that in a second. And
one of the things I do is I automate all of my launch of a video using chat GPT.
and one of those areas is down where I write the description and there's probably
information for the brand. And generally I'm just pasting a whole lot of branding
information here, but it'd be nicer if this was automatically going into my chats.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna head over to add instructions, and I'm gonna say,
this is information about my brand.
And I'll just paste in what I currently would paste into my custom gpt.
Now I have all this information that I would put into marketing and YouTube descriptions,
but it's a little bit too verbose for an instruction. So what I might just say is
about me, and then I'll just paste this information in. We've got my name is David
AppyDave, a list of my channels, opt in and stuff like that, and a list of my skills.
So I spent about 20 minutes just doing a little bit of grouping, and let's just go
through some of them to see the things that I'm thinking through as I start grouping
projects. So the first one is five, five, five, seven websites. So essentially this
is a manifesto that I built with ChatGPT about 18 months ago around the idea of building
550 videos over 55 weeks on five channels. It's not something I've done, but it is
a goal. And there are actually seven brands that I've been building all around this
concept. So I want to keep this global overview of what I do all in one location.
So next we can look at the two major applications that I'm building. One is FliVideo,
which is about achieving that goal is around the automation of myself and tools like
that. And then Agent Workflow Builder, which is another way that I automate everything
by having GPT workflows that solve different challenges, especially in the YouTube
automation, but anywhere in business.
Next time documenting in a podcast some due diligence around setting up a cafe in
Thailand. And that's called Kozi Kafe
Then I thought I'd do an image creation project because I have lots of images that
I tend to do on a video by video basis, but then I can never find the images that
I specifically want. So in this particular case, I was helping a friend get a logo
together and we were just playing around with ChatGPT and Dall-E three to generate
the images. So I'll probably end up having one project purely for the image ideation.
Now there's only a limited view of the projects here, but you can click on the see
more. So if we go to a company that I work with where all the software architecture
guidelines and best practices are being dealt with. If we go down to AppyDave videos,
this is where I'll keep all the scripts and my analysis of the scripts. And I do
all of this with Agent Workflow Builder. And the videos you can see are all listed
I then have a open source project that I'm putting together called KlueLess, and
this is where a custom tag seemed to make sense. So firstly the tag lines. The clue
is to do
Or even you can code even if you're clueless. This is a programming language that
I'm putting together for interacting with large language models.
Now, I mentioned FliVideo as a YouTube automation tool. Well, where that's being
used is AI-TLDR, and AI-TLDR is a channel that I put together. It's got about 80
videos over the last six months. It's growing quite well, and what I'm really going
to need is to keep track of a lot of the files. And you can currently see that there's
a bunch of videos over here, and they are mapping to the files that are over on this
system. So recently when we did the Sora video, which is just here, we've got the
basic metadata and the script and all that being put together.
And so what I can do with this is come over and click on the Add files. And I think
the two that we want is the Readme file and the affiliate file. This is where a list
of information is. And I should just be able to drag them in and they've been added.
Where this will end up being really useful for me is that there was a video done
recently called Compose Quickly, and one of the things going on in it is an affiliate
code. Now, this is just an incredible SEO friendly blogging tool, but if I want that
information, I can go over to my conversation in ChatGPT and there's an affiliate
file and that'll be listed there. So it'll be really easy to pull that information
into chats that I'm doing in the future.
Anyway, I'm AppyDave. That was a quick look at the ChatGPT projects and how I plan
to use them. I usually do videos on prompt engineering coding with AI and Agentic
frameworks. So if this is something that you're interested, please like and subscribe.
I'll see you in the next video.