In this video, I'm going to show you how to create 10 different games using WebSim.ai
It's a follow up to the video I did last week on building a component for a GPT Agent
framework. What we'll look at are classic games like Tetris, asteroids, and Wordle,
but also more modern style of games that might be useful in an AI agent framework.
I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Head over to Google and type in WebSim.ai and when you click on the link, you'll
be brought to a screen like this. And down below are a bunch of games and applications
that people have already created.
Now, last week in my first looks at WebSim.ai I took an application that I have a
GPT Workflow engine and I was able to add in this new component
and it allowed me to go backwards and forwards by clicking here and ending back on
a workflow screen. Now all of this took me about 20 minutes just using WebSim.ai
to do the work.
So from here we'll head back to Web simm ai, and this is where you can start a new
application just by writing a prompt. One of the things that you can do is select
the large language model.
I'm just going to work with Sonnet 3.5. That's what I used last time and it worked
quite well.
But let's work out what it is we're going to build. So if we head over to ChatGPT,
I've written this prompt here that says you are going to help me to create 10 different
games. The game's gonna be written in HTML in JavaScript, and that they're going
to be using online artificial intelligence tool called WebSim.ai So one of the things
I've asked it to do is do a search for WebSim.ai so it understands how this tool
sort of works. And I've also said I want the prompts to be fairly simple and clear
when we are doing this. So I'm trying to find software products or applications from
the past games that have been
relatively simple to create. And what it's done is given a list of 20 ideas that
we can work with. So I've just enhanced that prompt a little bit further so that
we can get two different examples for each of the 20 games. So got things like Pong
and breakout from back in the seventies,
and Tetris from 1984. So what I've done is then just asked it to give me a short
list. Currently it's given me nine, and we'll see that I will get it up to 10 at
the end. But before I did that, I thought let's get some images together to see how
these could look. And so these are the images I'll use on the thumbnail. We've got
Atari, we've got missile command. We may make that one. We'll see. I think S Space
Invaders would be a great game to CR create. And then we got on the Nokia. There
was a snake game when I asked it to do number five, which was Pacman. It said there's
a content policy issue, so I just asked it to rename it to GPT Man. And so we'll
create some sort of Pacman clone,
followed by a tower defense.
then we can finish off with Asteroids, Wordle,
and Tetris. Now that was the original nine it came up with, but I thought I'd love
to see Donkey Kong and hopefully we can round it out to 10 different games in this
video.
let's work on the first game. It's the Atari breakout game, and what I've done is
created a little prompt. If I wanted to describe the creation of the game breakout
as a short requirement, spec, and also a separate chain of responsibility, prompt,
how would I do that? Now, what we've got here is a pretty clear list of requirements
for the breakout game. We've got game elements, mechanics, graphics, and design.
The only thing, technical requirements using H-T-M-L-C-S-S and JavaScript and responsive
may not be needed because this is kind of the default that WebSim.ai would do anyway
as a chain of responsibility. This is the sort of stuff you might do if you wanted
to run it in something like Anthropic or ChatGPT,
I don't know that I need to worry about it for this particular case. So I think what
we'll do is we'll take everything from here all the way through to here, and let's
just test it out in WebSim.ai
What we'll do is head over to WebSim.ai and we're just gonna paste all the information
that we let ChatGPT create for us and we'll hit go. And I don't know that this will
work. This is probably a little bit more complex than the system would know how to
work with, but let's see what happens.
So we've got this breakout play. We've got score up in the left hand corner. Let's
just see. Whoa.
Now
it worked though. I couldn't get the actual paddle to work,
I think we can just go in and change the prompt and see if we can add left and right
arrows to the movement mechanism. So I've just added a prompt. Can you make the paddle
respond to the left and right keys so that I can control movement left and right?
The paddle should not go beyond the left and right edge of the screen and we will
just press go on that and see what it creates. Now one of the things you'll notice
is that the code is being generated and can sometimes be seen up in this blue bar.
So we've got a little help message down here. We'll hit play. Oh, look at that. And
that's working.
And there we,
wow. That's impressive.
heading back to GPT, I just asked what are the classic colors for the game? We've
got red, orange, yellow, green, and blue. I also asked if if there was ever a missile
or bullet system that said there was in a game called asteroid. So I said, give me
a short prompt
what it's come up with is modify the existing breakout game, add rows with bricks
in the following colors, introduce a power up, ensure that the power up is visually
distinguishable and can be activated once per game. So we'll just take this information
right here, we'll head over and paste it in, and we press go and it'll start regenerating
the game.
we'll press play and look at that. We've got colors. This is looking good. I'm not
a very good player at this
and the space doesn't do anything.
So the first attempt at altering the game to have colored bars worked fine, but one
of the things it didn't do was allow the power up to work from the space bar. So
I added in a prompt, the space bar is not firing. Can you fix this? What it did for
me was added in this new power up, that right here it says Space to shoot when the
power is active, but it wasn't active and I couldn't figure out how to make it active.
So I just added in one more prompt
and that prompt is here. Can you make sure the power up is active at the beginning
of the game?
let's just test this out and we've got it working. Looks good.
I just pressed the space button and we saw a bullet come through. So three or four
minutes and we've got this game of breakout. We should be able to
put a bookmark against it. We'll keep that. And the other thing we can do if we click
here is we can download the HTML to our computer.
So we'll head over to Visual Studio and we've just opened up the HTML page that we
downloaded. There's a bunch of CSS going on, little bit of HTML and elements all
being dealt with in JavaScript. So the game itself is relatively simple. If we right
click on it and view it as a live server,
our gamers come up locally, we hit play. And let's say we wanna change the red to
pink. What we should be able to do is just change the first set of colors here. We'll
just make that pink and we'll hit save. And it's refresh the page and we'll hit play.
And we now have a pink line up the top. So, so easy to create a game. It's only a
few minutes, and then you've got all the code and you can edit it the way you want.
Now before we move on to game number two, let's just make an alteration to our username.
So at the moment, I'm light butterfly and a number, and what you can do is move over
to the left here.
there is a little icon here that when you click on it, you can go and change your
username.
I've just said a AppyDave, I've changed my avatar picture here. Other things that
you can change is use a custom API key and the default large language model that
you want to use.
just press save
we now have a username and logo going on here.
So let's try and create the next game missile command.
we've got is the original prompt that we did for breakout is just here, but if we
move to the bottom and alter it a little bit, we'll say the game missile command
as a short requirement spec. Now we didn't use the chain of responsibility, so I
think we'll just leave it at that and press play and see what happens.
And we've got our requirement specs.
We'll head over to web sim and just pretty much paste everything and see what happens
with the generation.
We'll get a little initialization. It's still writing code at the moment. It's looking
very similar to the last game we created. Looks like it's finished. We'll just hit
play.
Now the first iteration of this, none of the keyboard controls have worked, but what
we do have are five cities down the bottom of the screen and we've got three missile
silos.
let's head over
ChatGPT and we've got our original,
prompts that we use to come up with the requirement specs. And if we focus in, you
can see I've added this new area. Can you create a separate chain of responsibility?
Prompt, which is what I said I didn't need this time around, but it seems I did.
And what that's doing is giving us a list of actions that you could go through one
at a time, which may be the better way to build games at the moment. One of the areas
here is the game play mechanics, and this is how we should control the different
sprites on the screen. Now it doesn't give us any information here about keyboard
or mouse, so I'm just going to extend it a little bit. Give me the gameplay mechanics
and include keyboard or mass controls. Make sure you specify which keyboard,
controls to use.
we've got 'em listed
and we got As and D to work from the different missile silos. They're the green ones
here. We're also going to support the mouse controls.
should be able to do is just copy the information that's here,
and I've just pasted that information directly into this area here. We've hit play
and I've already done this. So what you can see is that we've now got an A to launch
from the left S to launch from the middle and D to launch from the right. It should
also work with the mouse for aiming and left clicking.
let's give it a whirl.
So we'll just hit play and from this point we can use the mouse to just fire, or
if we use a, it comes from the left, s from the center, and d from the right.
so this game is working and it's taken two prompts in about five minutes of work.
At the moment, we're two down eight to go. What we can do is head over and you've
got these areas for bookmarks, and one of the things we should be able to do is publish
'em and make them live.
and we'll come over to this one and press the edit button and we can publish that
and we should be able to open that one as well. So here's the first one. Here's the
second one.
Everything seems to be
working here.
Now, just for your information, there may be a little problem you'll run into. I
just ran into it now. So at the moment, this is the correct version of the game and
it's all working, but when I bookmarked it, I actually had an older version of the
application open when I did the bookmark and I couldn't undo it. I kept coming in
here and pressing the unpublished republished, see what happened. But there's this
little button up here that you can press called Updated, and that will just bring
it up to, I believe, the URL that you are on. So if you have an issue where you've
accidentally published an older version and you wanna change it, it's this little
button here called updated that will update the actual URL to the latest version
of your game.
So let's move over to the third game,
So I said, can you describe the creation of the game Asteroids as a short requirement
spa in two sections. Number one is just the look and feel and the general game requirements.
And number two is the gameplay because we're finding that if we do them both together,
the gameplay doesn't get done anyway.
we'll see what it produces here.
section one looks good. Let's just copy from this area down to here and later on
we'll come back and look at this.
Now if we go back to the last game we were working on, you can get back to the home
by pressing this little button here
and we'll just click on the prompt and paste it in and see what happens.
Now it's starting to generate the game here.
Neoclassic asteroids, we've got a play button. It's still loading at the moment
it all looks ready. Let's see what happens if we hit play and do we have any, we
do already have some controls, so that's a good thing to know. We may actually be
working right now.
let's go back to the GPT that we had, and I'm still going to add in some extra information.
So we'll just click on this
and
just see what happens if we expand it. I think the main thing that I'm looking to
get this time through is just what the controls are going to be shown visually on
the screen.
we've now got three lives. We've got a high
score zero.
got a little bit of a fire coming out of it now. Oh, let's get out of there and
look. It's working just like the original asteroids. One thing we could do is improve
the graphics a little bit, but other than that, this looks great. In fact, let's
just try that and we'll just test with the idea of can you make the graphics a little
bit more realistic?
at this point, we've got a new name for it. It's called Hyperrealistic Asteroids.
There's a little bit of a font change going on. We're still loading at the moment,
and that's finished. It takes about 30 to 40 seconds to generate, but let's see if
it's actually working.
So this uncovered another issue to be aware of. So I had it not work and I said the
game has stopped working. And what I didn't notice was that there was the word continue
here. So kind of like ChatGPT, uh, might just stop
midway through a generation and you can press continue.
we'll just press continue here
and it's finished. We'll hit play and
there we go. It looks a lot different than before. The graphics are a little bit
better, which is what we're after.
And
fantastic.
So the thing I learned here is that it worked with the original requirement spec.
I didn't need to do the gameplay controls. This time around when I made it more hyperrealistic,
one of the things I didn't take into consideration is that sometimes the generation
of the game can take a lot longer than expected and it will just say continue. And
you've gotta just look out for that. Press the continue. And here we have the updated
game is got better graphics, but essentially it's the same game.
heading back over to the fourth game and we've got the Nokia Game Snake, and what
I've done is altered the prompt a little bit. Can you describe the creation of the
Game Snake as a short requirement spec? Now, I haven't split out into two sections
so much because the controls are really easy with this game. Anyway, include the
game, look and feel, general requirements, game mechanics and keyboard controls needed.
I also wanna make sure from now on that we get the keyboard controls printed on the
home screen. It didn't happen with the last one, but it has happened with others.
So I'm just being a little bit more specific in this particular case.
Now, this time it's gone really detailed and broken everything up. Now we've never
tested this as an idea,
I like to do is test things out. So we'll take everything. I generally probably would've
made this a simpler prompt than what we're seeing,
head back to WebSim.ai. Just click on the home button, click in here, and we'll just
paste it all in and we'll see what comes up. Game is being generated at the moment.
We're seeing the how to play controls going on here. So we've got up down left and
right and play to start. Now it's still loading,
So we will kick it off. And I'm meant to be eating the food and I missed it.
And we are now longer,
and it's getting longer as we go. So it looks like the game is working. Okay. This
is awesome. So this actually happened in one prompt. I didn't know how to use it
straight away, but this is going well.
So one of the things I've noticed here is that when you right click on areas, you
can do this edit. So how about we take this and we'll click on edit and I'm going
to type in
change the words, classic snake two, buymeacoffee.com/appydave and we'll press okay.
What happens here is it starts regenerating the page again, and hopefully it's just
gonna focus on that one area. So now if you want to help fund this channel, then
check out buymeacoffee.com/appydave.
Now let's move on to game number five. And one of the things that ran into was this
issue with using the term Pac Man when it drew the image. And I think we'll deal
with that in the game generation as well. So if we head over to the requirement specs
that we've got here and we can see that, can you describe the creation of the Game
man as a short requirement? Include the game, look and feel, general requirements,
game mechanics. Make sure we've got the screen controls and that they display on
screen.
I'm also going to get it to rename the game to GPT-Man, and we'll just press go
We've got the game look and feel. General requirements, I think whatever it produces.
We're just going to go with one more time
so we get the retro style graphics. This is all good. The one thing that's a little
interesting in here is that we've got the power up to allow GPT Man to eat enemies
for a short duration. So we'll have to see whether that works. The controls are pretty
much the same as we've seen before, so we can just take that information, go back
home to start a new game, and then just paste the information in and press.
Okay,
so we'll hit play and see what's going on. And the first thing to notice is it's
very fast, so we might wanna slow it down. In fact, let's do that.
Just see if we can go, can you slow down the speed of movement by half? See if that's
something that'll work. It's generating it here and it's finished. We'll hit play
and things are going a fair bit slower now. Now at the moment, the other characters
aren't moving, so maybe we've broken something in doing this.
So I've just mentioned that the opponents never come out the box and that they're
meant to come out like in a regular game of Pac-Man. And that's kind of delayed so
they don't all come out at the same time. So it's just finished. We'll press the
button and one of 'em is out. So now it's starting to feel a lot like
And it killed me again.
So that's great.
we'll just come back here and we'll right click on the GPT man.
So we'll just change GPT, man to API, Dave, and let it rerun.
and now we've got the YouTube channel AppyDave as the heading here on the game.
So let's move on to the sixth game tower defense. And at the moment, they're only
taking about two or three minutes to get each game up and running in a basic form.
So we'll just go with another prompt that we've got. Can you describe the creation
of a tower defense game? It's the same prompt, just with the words change. You've
got things like cartoonish graphics coming through,
green landscape with defined path for enemies to follow.
towers placed along the path. Let's look at the user interface. So we've got play.
We're gonna show the keyboard instructions at the beginning of the game
and the enemies are going to come in. Waves. We've got up, down left, right? We've
also got tower placements, so apparently they can be five that we can use and we
can start and pause the game.
So we'll head over to web sim, we'll paste it in and press go.
Apparently initializing the code here and starting to render some sort of game.
we've got our scores and currency and lives up here,
hit play.
And it's a very bright color going on at the moment.
It's so, so far it's not working. I've just said currently I see a red line across
the screen.
we'll just regenerate the prompt and see if we can get this up and running.
We got clearer instructions showing here,
click to place a tower. Maybe that's something I didn't do before and space bar to
start or pause the game
and something's moving. So
are they meant to shoot?
it looks like it's starting to work, but we don't have any bullets coming out,
I'm just saying no bullets are coming outta the towers. Hopefully this is enough
to get it going.
We'll try one more time
and it's, oh, look at that. There's a bullet coming through now.
I put in a new prompt here that says, when we get to each new level, can you reset
the screen and draw a different path?
And so here we go.
So I've been testing a few different prompts here. And this latest one is, when we
get to a new level, can you reset the enemies to the beginning and draw a new path?
So we have a path going on here. We're on level one
and we've just gone to level two, so we should just be able to click and create new
items
only. I ran outta currency, so this is interesting. There's things like currency
that allow you to buy different towers.
we went to level two, we had no towers, so it started again. I don't know that we'll
get to level three. This is a little bit more finicky to get going with this particular
game,
But the control of the application generation is still pretty spot on. Each time
I make a change.
Moving on to the next game. We've got Wordle here and it's in the middle of just
generating a prompt based on Wordle. And we are just going to copy it. I'm not even
going to read it this time.
We're head over to WebSim.ai
we insert the prompt and let it run. And now let's have a look at what's going on
here. We've got a five by six grid where players input their guesses. We've got areas
like incorrect colors, correct letter, wrong position,
correct letter, correct position, and it's still generating over here. The letters
A to Z are the input letters for the current guess and enter. To submit the current
guess, we can use the bat space key to delete the last letter from the page. So what
happens if I press a,
we press play and then
a
B.
Let's do that and press enter.
Now we've got two that are the right letters, but in the wrong location.
So we'll try the word karma,
press enter. We've got the A correct in the second position,
the word naval
made an assumption with the first two A, that there would be two A in it, but that
might not be the case. And it's not, it's happy is the word.
so looks like the word will. Game worked the first time.
So we've got this game, we can hit play on it and we'll just type in happy, I think,
and something is correct here. Let's try
dance.
And we've got it on the second go. Now, what might be useful at this point is, can
we just right click here and see the words that we've got available?
So I've just put in, can you give me a list of the words that are available as a
sheet?
I did it by right clicking down near the play again.
hopefully we're going to see a list of information behind the scenes and we have
it here. So let's try another word.
in jumbo, that was down the bottom there. And then we can go with
dance again.
Now it looks like it's gonna be cactus, but that's not a five letter word, so I'm
not sure what's going on here. Let's try that.
And it works. So there's a bug in the software, but apart from that, this is all
working pretty well.
we'd need to do a little bit of playing around with the code. I.
we're nearly through the list. We're up to Tetris here. Then we've got Donkey Kong
and I believe there might be one other I need to do, but let's just head over to,
can you describe the creation of the game word or, and we'll just change that to
Tetris
and that's going through and generating a new requirement spec for us. So the graphics
are going to be blocks,
Tetroaminos with different colors. We've got clear and easily distinguishable blocks,
smooth animation for falling and moving. That's pretty cool.
Standard sort of game elements that we've seen before.
When a row is complete,
filled in with all the blocks, it disappears and the player earns some points. Game
continues until the blocks stack up to the top of the playing field.
got the arrow keys going on, including space bar to drop a block instantly. So as
per usual, just paste it in. Press go. So we have start of the game. Tetris Mandala
Align. The pieces align your mind, and we've got the controls going on here at the
moment. It's still generating the page.
A little bit of an animation has kicked in, so we'll hit play. Whoa, that is fast.
So I've just added, can you please slow down the blocks to a quarter of the speed
and we'll try pressing play. And now what? Is it too slow?
Oh, yep. Okay. It's working but it's too slow. But at least we can test it down.
Arrow should take it
space bar to drop it to the bottom. Okay. Move it over Space bar.
Press the up arrow. I think what we can do
is maybe drop that in here. We can do that.
And the next one comes through. How are we going to test at this?
And hopefully we will see two lines disappear with this one.
And they did.
And the last bit to look at here is the score. It's currently a hundred, so as soon
as this goes into place, it should change for us
one 40. So the game's working straight away. There is an issue with the speed. Firstly,
it was too fast, too slow. We can change that pretty easily. But very simple to create
the game of Tetris.
So far, we've built eight games pretty quickly with WebSim.ai. From the list that
we've got here, we've done everything except for Space Invaders, and I was going
to work on Donkey Kong, and one of the problems I found when I looked at it was that
it came out looking pretty poor, and I couldn't get the gameplay to work in an easy
fashion. So I thought, why don't I change tact and go off on a new direction now,
because I do a lot of work with AI agent frameworks, I thought, could there be a
couple of games to make agent frameworks a lot easier to use?
So the game idea I'm thinking of is Influencer Village. As a YouTuber, I need to
create YouTube titles and descriptions. Sometimes a LinkedIn post or a tweet, and
I use GPTs to solve the problem.
we make a game that solves this in a more visual aspect? So I started designing some
graphics in Dali three. We've got pixel art style here and low poly style and veto
graphics, as well as top down 3D. So the image I think I'm gonna go with is this,
and we'll develop a requirement spec.
Now through a series of prompts. We've got this
Influencer Village who play a YouTube influencer navigating through a Village to
complete necessary tasks for publishing a YouTube video. Each villager has a role
like keyword researcher, and these are essentially going to be GPT agents that do
individual tasks. The way I think it'll work is that I'll move around from villager
to villager using the arrow keys, and when you encounter someone, it says, can you
help me with a task? And sure, what task would you like help with?
these are the inputs I need. So something like a YouTube prescription needs a transcript
to write it correctly.
Now, because I'm going to use an image as the background, I need to know the coordinates.
So I've also asked it to put in a debug option so that I can turn it on and off to
see what the coordinates are for each villager
got a bunch of other general sorts of information, but the last area is also the
list of the villagers and their roles and the sort of input that's needed.
Let's head over to WebSim.ai, and we've pasted in our technical requirements, and
we'll just start it off
and things are starting to render right now. We've got the positions where the villages
will be, so hopefully we'll get a little bit of a debug screen here. I
updated the prompt with where is the debug chart and the controls, and now we have
a debug
chart that we can turn on and off. Unfortunately, it's also one of the arrow keys
in this case, the right arrow key, so we could change that, but I'm not so concerned.
I'm more interested in knowing these numbers for when we put a image behind the background.
I'm also looking to add, when I move to a villager, I do not get an interaction and
we'll just put the information that we had in our requirements document and see if
this improves things.
And now we've got this E two in interact with the villager, so if we move over, we've
got press E to interact with the title creator, we'll press E, and we've got information
showing up that would be a Q&A with that particular villager. So I think let's go
and create a graphic and make it in the background.
looking through the graphics we've got here, my favorite would be this one, but I
think the one that'll fit the shape the best might be this one. So I'm just gonna
click download on that.
to keep the hosting simple, I'm just gonna drag it into this product called Post
image. And what that'll do is upload the image and make it available as public URL.
We should be able to use that from our application.
here's the image and we'll go and click on the direct link and head over to here
where I've started. Can you add the following image as a background and we'll just
paste that in
and click go. And we're getting a regeneration at the moment.
there we go. So in theory, we should be able to move up to different people, interact
with the title creator. We get the word title here. Now this image is generated in
Dali three, so it's got a whole lot of text issues, but it's still a working idea
transcript converter, which would be the transcription manager right here.
Now I mentioned that the coordinates could be off. So we've got this coordinate here
and we can press the D and notice that
the social media manager, which is down here, is a hundred pixels to the right and
500 pixels down. And what we might wanna do is move it to 250 pixels to the right
or something like that. Now let's go and download this application actually and do
that manually. So we'll
click on the download button that's just here, and we've got the HTML on our computer
and we'll open it in vs code.
So I've got the game running locally from this JavaScript and HTML file that's going
on here. So we can see the JavaScript around the positioning of the different villages
and we can see the image that we just uploaded being read into the background. So
all of this we can alter. So I'll just press D and we've now got our coordinates.
And if we move around to different places, this says social media manager on the
villager profile, but here it says transcript converter. So that's the wrong position.
And the one over here, which I think is the social media manager, is what we pretty
much want over here, maybe about that position.
go and change this value to two 50 and this one will change to five 80. And we'll
hit save
page refreshed. The numbers should be different down here they are. Let's just move
to the right and this will be the social media manager, which is great. This will
be the transcript converter. And let's test the E and see what we get.
So
we'll just press
Sure I can help you with a LinkedIn post conversion.
Now where I personally see a game like this being really useful in the sort of applications
I build is as a new interface to the GPT workflow tool that I've been developing.
So the idea of the tool is to isolate the different GPTs that you would call into
a sequence or a series. And last week using WebSim.ai, I developed this landing page
where you could easily see the different phases of A GPT workflow and navigate to
them.
so what we could do now is take a screen like this, put it in the location that this
one was going, and instead navigate around. And when you press E to interact, you
can start communicating with the GPT in a more gamified approach.
The last game that I wanna develop here would be a YouTube script automation factory.
And it'll work in a similar fashion to the influencer village. But rather than moving
around different areas of the village, you would just move sequentially down a production
line to build a YouTube script.
what I've done is developed a few images that I like, and I'm either gonna go with
the one here, or probably this one. There are others that have been developed over
time,
and the way I see it working is that you would start from a type of video that you
want to create. You'd be doing things like script writing, quality assurance, getting
a basic fact sheet. Now this is something I do all the time. And so when I'm working
with a GPT workflow from basic ideas, selecting an idea, building a fact sheet about
a video, I want to do video ideas. And I have the ability to navigate to each of
these different ideas. And I use this for creating actual videos on a faceless channel
that I'm developing now. The channel's only a month old.
so started off with this Ideogram video, but basically every script that you've got
here has been generated using a simple GPT workflow. And funnily enough, one of my
first videos took off 700 views a couple of days ago. So what I'd like to do is develop
a requirement spec. And now that I look at it, I think this is the image we'll use
as a background, and we'll see if we can automate or gamify the creation of YouTube
scripts.
we'll start off by downloading an image. Now this is the image I like the most, but
from a straight line perspective, which will be easy for the coordinates, we'll work
with this one instead. So we'll just click download within DALE-3 here.
I've headed over to post image and I've uploaded the image we've got and we're just
copying the URL.
Here's the requirements document for the YouTube Automation Factory.
we have the, in the YouTube automation factory, your character is navigating through
an assembly line, completing tasks,
necessary for creating YouTube videos.
then we've got a list of stations within the factory. Now, they're not the order
I do them, but this is just the idea of creating the game. From there, we've also
got the image and we'll make sure that we've got the proper URL when we include it
in the requirement spec.
We got the debugged feature that we did before we, so that we can align the stations
with the coordinates.
this time I'm just keeping the characters movement to left and right keys. We down
the bottom, we've also got a list of stations that we can work with.
head over to WebSim.ai, we can just take all the information we've got,
We've got it generating all the HTML and CSS behind the scenes.
we've got the background has kicked in
and we've got the stations. Now, obviously they would need to go down in this angular
format,
and the D for the debug is working so we can see all the
coordinates. So they look a little odd. I don't know,
Maybe it's on just one vertical access. And so these are just the positions left
and right. So we're probably gonna need to put in a Y and an X coordinate. Now let's
just see if the arrows are working
and it looks like
And next, can I help you with a fact sheet? And then there's sort of secondary question
coming up. So I need the expanded fact sheet from which to work on.
So I'm just gonna bookmark this last one. And all the games that I've been building
the, I got the bookmarks in the YouTube description below.
we'll do right now is just download this to the.
So here's A-H-T-M-L that we've got for the page that you're looking at and everything
works okay, but there are two problems. One is that it's only got a position coordinate,
so it doesn't have a Y access that we can configure. And the updating of the character
position also does not actually follow the elements or the stations on screen.
is added? Two prompts. Can you modify it so that the Y coordinate is configurable?
I also want the person to move to the next station.
let's have a look at the code comparison.
here we have the old on the left and the right is the new. And you can see that the
coordinates are fixed on the old version.
And in the JavaScript configuration, we now have an external Y coordinate rather
than position. Also, the coordinates are being used when calculating locations. So
let's see how this looks.
So here's our YouTube automation factory, and we've got in the top right hand corner,
the task completed zero seven. If we press the D for debug, we should be able to
see the coordinates for the different stations in the factory. And if we use the
right keyboard, we should be able move forward and see, hello. You can help me with
determining the video type and we just keep moving through the different tasks all
the way to
The best thing about this workflow is like most of 'em, it takes about 10 minutes
to recreate this particular application.
So that was building 10 games with WebSim.ai. Eight of them were classics. Two of
them were the sorts of games or workflows that I might want in my GPT workflow engine.
So if you are interested in ChatGPT or Prompt Engineering or different AI tools,
then please I can subscribe or leave a comment down below and the video over here
on the side
point you to the WebSim.ai demonstration that I did, building a component for A GPT
workflow.