Welcome to the Future of YouTube in 2024.
I'm excited to unveil seven Custom
GPTs designed to transform your
YouTube channel and introduce the GPT
store that makes all this possible.
Discover how these GPTs revolutionize
content creation with stunning
B roll, engaging outros and SEO
enhanced YouTube descriptions.
We'll also highlight three social
sharing GPTs to boost your digital reach.
Let's delve into how GPT is set to
reshape content creation in 2024.
Hi, I'm AppyDave, and the intro you
just heard was created by one of
the GPTs coming up in this video,
but we'll get into that later.
I.
When you open up the chat GPT store,
you have access to GPTs created
by open AI and by other people.
Let's head over to my GPTs and you'll
see that there's a bunch that I've
created and many of these are related
to YouTube content automation.
What I'll cover in this video are seven
different GPTs that I use after I've
recorded the bulk of the content, and
that includes the intro and outro script,
B-roll, which is about generating images
that match the words that I'm saying.
There'll be the YouTube description
writer, which creates a really nice
SEO friendly YouTube description
with affiliate links, social links,
and key highlights pulled out of it.
Then lastly, I need to share the
videos that I do, and I use LinkedIn,
Facebook, and Twitter, and these
bots will be designed to generate
content or posts that make sense
for each of the different platforms.
Before going into detail on the seven
YouTube automation bots, there's one other
bot that we should have a look at First.
Whenever I create my YouTube intro or the
SEO friendly description, or maybe even
the daily three B-roll images, I like
to create everything based off exactly
what I said in the video and the script.
abridger is an expert in summarizing
transcriptions and making abridgement.
If we click on the commands, basically
there are two concepts that I like
to get out of a full transcription.
Going into detail, the role of
this bot is to summarize and
condense video transcriptions.
Now it can use natural language
processing to extract structural
information from a transcript, or it can
summarize it without losing the detail.
What this means is I can take a 30
minute video that I've recorded and
summarize it from, say a few thousand
words, down to a couple a hundred.
Now, it can do it either as a summary
where it condenses, but keeps the meaning,
or it can do it as an analysis where
it gives more of a structural point
of view, and both of these sorts of
outputs can be useful for future bots.
Say an example.
Let's take this 200 lines of
transcript from a 30 minute video
that I did earlier in the week.
If we compare everything side by side,
you can see what the full transcript
over here on the left is 2,330 words.
Now, if we go over to the summary,
it basically says close to the same
thing, and it does it in 127 words.
There's also the analysis, which gives
more of a structural view of what the
document has, and it's in 270 words.
Now both the analysis and the
summarization of the transcript make
for really useful inputs into other
bots that might generate a description
or generate graphics for an intro, and
it's as simple to use as typing over
the summarize or the analysis command
pasting in your long form transcript,
and then just letting GPT do its work.
as it goes, we can see that this
video features a scripting enthusiast
demonstrating the use of a custom
GPT agent, the shell script helper.
As we move through the seven YouTube
automation GPTs, we're going to find
that the summary or the analysis of
the transcription, it's going to play
an important role for each of 'em.
The test case for each of the bots
that we're working with today will be
around the Shell Script helper video.
Now, this video came out a couple
of days ago and a few things
to note as you look through it.
Is that there's a detailed SEO
friendly YouTube description with
keywords and links to various assets.
If we scroll down and click on the
transcript, you'll see that there's an
intro that was written by one of the bots.
We'll look at how I use GPT
to generate YouTube titles.
But also look at the text that it
can create to go on a thumbnail,
which is quite a bit different
to the text in a YouTube title.
We'll also look at the Dali three
images that can be generated or what I
would call elements of the thumbnail.
And if I get a chance, I'll even touch
on how Dali three instructions can be
generated directly off the transcript
to produce B-roll images that look
exactly like what you're talking about.
Most of the videos I create are from
five to 25 minutes in length and once
recorded, I take the transcription and
I put it through the transcript abridger
to get my summary and an analysis.
From there, I then go and generate a
YouTube title using a chat GPT bot.
That preliminary work out of
the road, I'm then in a position
to create my YouTube intro.
And to do that, I use the
YouTube intro generator.
Now, the role of this bot is to
generate tailored YouTube intros.
The overview is that it can work
with a transcript directly, or it can
work with a summary or an analysis.
the main guidelines is that it
creates concise, informative,
and compelling intros.
The marketing frameworks, which in this
case are either PAS or AIDA, are really
just psychological triggers to get people
engaged with your content pretty early.
So we've got the problem agitate solution
framework, or we've got the attention,
interest desire action framework.
Now, from a structure point of view,
we have concepts like problem solution,
which is one of the ones I like to
use, where there is a problem and I've
got a solution that I've de developed.
I'm also fond of the Q and A
style, but other people might
like more of a storytelling style.
And the idea of the bot is that you would
configure it with the niche, the topic,
which might just be your YouTube title
some keywords, and then basically the
marketing framework and structure that
you want using this sort of configuration.
And the transcript helps
you then generate the intro.
Over to my GPTs, and we'll click
on the intro maker, create engaging
educational YouTube intros, and
we'll just click on the commands
to see what we've got available.
And you can see, we can configure it.
We can create an intro based off a draft.
We can also get some definitions
around the marketing framework and
the intro structures if you need.
So I've just put in the config command.
I've said ChatGPT for coding.
That's what the video
happened to be about.
The PAS marketing framework,
Q&A style, and let's just see
what this comes back with.
So this is working on the idea that
the niche will be ChatGPT for coding.
She the problem agitation, solution
framework, Q and A structure.
The tone will be authoritative and
engaging and you can run a configure.
Command again, if you wanna change
what it says here, but for that,
we can now move on to create and we
just type in, create like this, press
colon, and then we paste in all the
information from the transcription.
I also like to put in the title, so
the title should be there as well.
We got title, unlock the Power of
GPTs, and we just press enter and we
see what we get on the first attempt.
It's written an introduction for us,
and the one that's here is hello and
welcome to today's video where we're
unlocking the incredible potential
of GPTs focusing on a unique tool.
The shell script helper for ChatGPT,
and then it goes on from there.
Now the intro it's created in
this example is quite accurate,
but it's also way longer than I
would want to do for an intro.
We have a little bit of
configuration with that GPT agent.
You can get an intro that follows
the style and pattern that you want.
And the one I went for that video
was, do you wanna simplify the
way you build terminal scripts?
Join me on this unique scripting
adventure where I'll be using
custom GPT shell script helper.
So this little intro, it's quite
short and to the point, and it
was generated out of that bot with
a little bit of extra tweaking.
Let's move on to A GPT agent designed
to generate your YouTube outro.
Looking at the YouTube outro generator,
the main role is that it can create
an engaging outro for your video.
Now, the overview suggests that it's
about creating viewer engagement.
You want people to like and
subscribe, to do comments.
Maybe you want them to click on an end
card and go to one of your other videos.
Like the previous agent, the outro
creator has a configure command
where you can put the capability
that you wanna see within the outro.
And the main ones that I like to use is a
call to action, maybe like and subscribe.
I definitely like to do a recap of the
video and have some sort of video end card
that people can click on to go to related.
Content and you can do that
all through the configuration.
Before you worry about creating the outro.
It will come over to the GPTs and
we'll click on the tube outro writer
craft engaging outros for YouTube
videos based on summaries and
settings, and we can have a look at
what commands we'd got available.
We can do a configuration, create an
outro, or look at the capabilities
and we'll just run that one command.
We're not going to give it any input,
we'll just see what it comes up with.
So we have a pretty extensive list.
Call to actions, end cards,
and you could configure each
of these pieces of information.
But we'll go for something quite simple.
We'll just go brevity and thanks.
So I'll put in config with brevity.
Thanks with like, and subscribe.
I also added a configuration for AppyCast.
At this point, we can just do a create
and do a paste, and what I've done is
like, before, I've included the title of
the video and then the full transcript.
In this case you can do it with
both transcripts and summaries.
I find for this one, I like
to do the full transcript.
So it's gone through and created
everything that we wanted.
I will read it in a moment, but what
I'd like it to do is just the script In
this case, it's also given a few extra
instructions that could be useful for the
video editor, but I just wanna read it.
So what we got was that's wrap on
our scripting adventure with Shell
Script helper so it understands
the context of the video.
Big thanks for joining us on
this journey to simplify shell
scripting with GPT Technology.
If you loved diving into the Tech
with Us, show you support by hitting
the like and subscribe to AppyCast.
So this is basically following
the guidelines that we did when
we configured the capabilities.
I just played the outro that was on
the video I created two days ago.
Wouldn't it be great if the words
that you're saying in your transcript
automagically turned into beautiful scenes
generated with, say, DALE3 or MidJourney?
I.
If you've ever used Nvidia AI or
maybe Pictory you've already seen
this in action because what these
tools do is take the transcript and
match it to images that it gets from
stock photography and stock video.
Created this video about a week ago,
and if you look at the transcript,
there's ideas like creating a
custom instruction in chat GPT.
There's the ability to look at video
files that are put into a project folder,
and I'm talking about this and what I
want to do is make sure that the images.
That come up as I'm talking,
match what I'm saying.
So this is creating a
custom GPT instruction.
Here I am programming a YouTube
video application and putting the
recordings into a folder structure.
So everything that you're seeing
here is generated directly
out of Dali using A GPT agent.
Let's have a look at the
individual images first.
So the creating a custom chat
GPT instruction was created from
this particular prompt here.
And as you go through, we've got
depict person demonstrating video file
organization on a computer screen.
visualize a user working with
eCamm Live Stream Deck and Hazel.
the video that those images were
related to was about this software
I'm creating called FliVideo, which
takes all my recordings and runs them
through various GPTs to solve the
problems in a more automated fashion.
if we head over to GPT and look
at an agent that I've created
for analyzing the transcription.
You'll see that I've got a bot
here that looks at transcriptions
in the form of scenes.
So scene one, and it goes from three
seconds through to 50 seconds, and this is
the words being said in the transcription.
Then scene number two goes from 50 seconds
through to one minute and 34, and this
is a regular file format for subtitles.
What I've been able to do
is take that information.
Keep the numbers in place so the
numbers haven't changed, but instead
prompts have been generated to
replace what was actually said.
from these prompts, they can be
taken over to chat GPT, where
you can just create 'em manually.
Now you may not want to create 'em
manually, and that's the reason why
I'm creating this software FliVideo,
and I'm just going through the various
episodes at the moment while I build it
out so that I can automate the B roll
creation, whether it be images, which
is great with DALE3, or maybe you could
use runway ML and generate B-roll video.
The GPT agents that we've just
looked at, were all around content
creation, whether it be the YouTube
intro, the outro, or B-roll.
The next agent we're going to look
at is around the publishing of
your YouTube video, where you've
gotta fill in information like
the description and the keywords.
Let's take a look at the description
from a video I did a week ago, and
the video is called Build YouTube
Automation App with chat GPT.
And the way it starts is join me
in the first episode of Build a
YouTube automation app with chat GPT.
So it's written an intro here in the
description that matches the title.
From there, we have four sections.
We've got what's inside episode
highlights, useful links including
affiliate links, and stay
tuned for more, and it finishes
off with a bunch of keywords.
Let's take a look at the GPT agent for
YouTube description writing, and the role
of this agent is to craft engaging and
informative YouTube video descriptions.
The basic overview of this is that
it specializes in creating YouTube
descriptions for videos, focusing on
SEO viewer engagement and compliance
within the YouTube guidelines.
So with the additional guidelines around
hashtags, links, and discoverability,
we should be able to start using
this GPT to create a new description.
the primary command for this particular
GPT is create, and usually I would
provide it with a title and a summary.
I might also have some special
instructions if I need it, and I
often include extra metadata such
as affiliate links or branding
links to my social media channels.
Heading over to my GPTs, we've got
a video description wizard, which
is a friendly yet professional
YouTube description expert, focusing
on SEO engagement and compliance.
Now what we'll do is we'll click
on the, I will give you a title,
transcript and special instructions.
at the moment it's just waiting for input.
Select the analysis and the
summary as we scroll up.
There's also the intro that was used
in this video and the title, and
we'll take it a little bit further
and just copy the brand details and
just put that into the clipboard.
type in the word create with a colon,
and just paste everything that we've
selected and see what it creates.
It's got a title, which has
unlocked the power of GPTs, and
then we move into the description.
So I would be copying from
this little emoji all the way
down what you'll discover, key
highlights, and stay connected
through some social media channels.
There's a call to action to
like, share and subscribe, and
following up with some keywords.
Let's have a look at 3 GPT agents
to share our video on social media.
we'll look at the tweet composer,
the LinkedIn video post writer,
and the Facebook teaser.
When I created the shell script
helper video, I tweeted it and
it goes dive into the future of
scripting with shell script helper.
Watch as I transform shell scripting
with ChatGPT and we've got a
link and a couple of hashtags.
Now looking at the Tweet composer,
GPT Agent, its role is to create
tweets for YouTube videos.
It emphasizes on capturing the
essence of videos in tweet format.
when you use the create command,
which I've set up for this one, it
expects a YouTube title, a link to the
video, and a couple of key highlights
we could also pass in the summary.
Let's head over to the tweet composer
and we'll see that it specializes
in creating engaging tweets for
YouTube videos, and we'll click on
the commands to see what's available.
The primary command is create,
which will create a tweet.
paste in the information we
have from earlier, which is
a little bit of metadata.
We've got the title of the video,
and then we've got a summary.
we could also use the analysis, which is
got more structure, and they would both
produce different but useful tweets.
So let's just click on
that and see what we get.
Here's our tweet.
Dive into the world of GPTs with AppyDave.
Discover how the shell script.
Helper GPT transform shell scripting
from complex FFMPEG commands to
chapter base video compiling.
we've got a couple of hashtags in here
and we've got a link to the video.
It may be a little bit
too long for the tweet.
It may still need a little bit of
refinement, but it does a pretty good
job of creating a tweet for your video.
This GPT will work with your how to
video on YouTube and convert it into
a LinkedIn post in a way that'll
extract the highlights and make it
engaging for LinkedIn professionals.
Diving into the GPT agent.
Let's look at the a LinkedIn post that
was generated a week ago The video itself
was build a YouTube automation app, and
I was doing the technical design for this
tool that I'm creating that mixes in the
GPTs that we've been talking about with
the transcriptions from the videos that
I record and just automates the process.
But the interesting thing about the
LinkedIn posts that it generated.
Was not only did it pull out the useful
information for YouTube content creators,
but it also isolated that there's
an area in here about a programming
language that I'm developing for GPT.
So this is a GPT meta language, maybe an
advanced prompting language, and it's been
able to pull that information out as well.
So from a LinkedIn.
Post generation point of view.
This was a one-shot post.
I put in the transcription, the summary
and everything, and it came out.
We've got areas like the
hashtags, and then I just
added the thumbnail at the end.
Looking at the LinkedIn video post GPT,
we can see that its role is to transform
a video transcription to a LinkedIn post.
The key guideline of this bot is to
extract key highlights from the video.
Include relevant call to
actions and insights that
adhere to LinkedIn standards.
Heading over to the GPT store, what
we can do is go to the tube LinkedIn
transformer, and what this does is
specialize in transforming video
transcriptions into LinkedIn posts.
there's a couple of starter conversations.
I think the one we'll work with
is use special instructions
plus title and transcription.
Here we have the summary and the
structural analysis from the transcript.
we can use one or the other,
or we can even use both.
They essentially say the same thing
they just said in different ways.
if I copy all this information,
I've also included the YouTube
title and a little bit of metadata.
it's just finishing off the article
at the moment, but if we move up,
we've got unleashing the potential
of gpt in Shell scripting a case
study with shell script helper.
Then we've got a couple of hashtags
and some sort of introduction and
we can go and watch the video.
Let's actually see if that works.
Looks like it's loading up.
That's great, and it just goes on to
talk about this video based on the way we
use either the summary or the transcript
analysis or even the transcript itself,
you'll get different outputs, but
usually this is a one-shot prompt for me.
I put the information in, I get it
out, and tiny little bit of tweaking.
It's ready to go.
This next GPT agent is to
create a teaser on your Facebook
profile for your YouTube video.
Let's have a look at an example Facebook
teaser that I've done for the last
video, which was the Shell Script helper.
And some of the things that you notice
is there's no YouTube title as such.
There's just a statement unleashing
the power of AI in Shell scripting,
which is more Facebook like, and
it's made really good use of emojis.
It's got a couple of hashtags going
on and then a link to the video.
Now, this is in contrast.
the two videos I did just before
episode one and episode two in Building
FliVideo where I've just manually
written this sort of stuff, it's okay,
but it's a lot better when we use
concepts like emojis and hashtags to
make this searchable and more engaging.
I hope you found the insights from the
seven YouTube automation bots useful.
We dived into how each GPT from an
intro writer to the Facebook teaser
is simplifying content creation.
Remember, it's all about making
the process more efficient and
your content more engaging.
Don't forget to check out the GPT
store for these amazing tools and drop
your thoughts in the comments below.
I would love to know which GPT
you are most excited to try.
And if there is a GPT that you want
me to create, you can dive deeper into
custom Bots with this playlist featuring
detailed discussions on each custom GPT.
Thank you for watching.
See you next time.