I used NotebookLM on one of my projects to create this table of content, where I
went through a bunch of the files I had and it created this nice structure for me.
Let me show you how I did that.
So here we have a docs directory. And within that folder we've got a whole lot of
requirements documents in markdown format. And what we want to do is create a table
of content for the fly video application.
Now. I wrote this simple prompt for the outline and the Toc, but before I did that,
I dragged all the files into the sources. We can see them on the left, and then we
just see the brands and the breakdown of brands. We've got the command line interface
and the breakdown of that, and all this information can now be copied back into my
requirements document.
I'm AppyDave. Check out the link below on how I'm using NotebookLM.