I recently added buy me a Coffee as a fundraising mechanism to my YouTube channel,
and in this video what I thought I'd do was take you through the complete process
of set up everything that I went through, the areas that I love, the areas that I
don't specifically need, but you might find useful.
I'm a content creator with a small YouTube channel that's currently not monetized,
but over the last 12 months that I've got this channel going, I've had a couple of
breakout videos. One in particular got 21,000 views, but I didn't have anything in
place to potentially financially monetize that traffic. So in this video I wanna
show you how you can set up and use buy me a coffee to solve that particular problem.
So why would you use buy me a coffee? Well, basically it's designed for people like
myself who are content creators or YouTubers can be used for entertainers, musicians,
anyone that's trying to promote themselves. And they're still quite small and they
want a simple and easy platform. So what makes it beneficial over something like
Patreon is that it's got a little bit cheaper fees and it's easier to set up and
compared to something like the Super Likes from YouTube where they'll automatically
promote it to your subscriber base, which is great, but they take 30% commission.
So it's a lot more beneficial to you as a creator.
Now, I was talking to a mentor of mine about how do I turn YouTube into a business
and based on a bunch of influencers and this mentor, he said this would be a simple
way to get started. So I thought I'd just take you through the process that I'm going
through right now to set up buy me a coffee for, in this case, the username AppyDave.
When you go to the create account page, it already saved Buy me a coffee.com/ and
for me, I just used my YouTube handle AppyDave. And from there, just start filling
in the standard signup capabilities. I'm using a username and password here. Now
this will take you to the profile setup screen.
So very simply fill in your brand name.
in this case, I've put in a little bit of an About us and a link to my website. After
that, I just took my standard brand image and uploaded it.
Now next it'll ask you how you plan to use Buy me a coffee. Now you can use it as
a membership system, a shop, a blog posts that are exclusive to your members. We've
also got the email list and marketing. Now for myself, I'm only looking as a support
platform. Just
some extra income that comes through. And the reason for that is that I'm using Kajabi
in my day-to-Day business work.
So when you press next your door asks you to start setting up your payment.
here I've set up Australia in my particular case and it's taken to me to this area
about setting up Stripe.
I've filled in a username and password that I had for Stripe, but I haven't used
Stripe in about four years.
it took me through a bit of a process here and I'll show what I went through.
firstly it said, welcome back, try to sign in.
I did that and it said, verify that you own this account and it required some serious
documentation, passport
photos and QR codes. But once I got through all of this, it said, you're all set.
We can get going.
then I was able to set up two factor authentication, which would be really important
because this is a banking system. Money is coming through to you. So make sure you
do that.
then it takes you to the dashboard.
I have 57 cents available for me from what looks to be six years ago back in 2018.
Coming outta Stripe, we come back to the homepage of Buy me a coffee. And from here
you'll see that there's a link called View page right here. And there's also another
one over on the right called share page. And if you click on that, that'll take you
to the public page that your supporters will see. And what they would do is generally
fill in this particular form, and once that's done, they'll end up as a supporter
here in the list page.
One of the things that makes buy me a coffee so brilliant is that you don't pay for
this platform yet. You have access to capabilities like recurring income through
the membership system, and from this, you can make content of yours available to
people that are your members. On top of that, you can also set up a shop, so you
don't need to pay for Shopify. You can have your own e-commerce platform up and running
where you can sell some of your merchandise.
lastly, you've got a blogging platform, so you don't need to set up Wix or WordPress
or anything else like that. You just come in, create your posts. Again, you can make
these available just for your subscribers. Now, I don't use this. Instead I'm using
Kajabi and I have a video in the link if you wanna find out more about Kajabi because
it's great for me as a course and content creator where I'm marketing courses.
but if you just need something affordable to get started, then buy me a coffee. Has
pretty much all the capabilities you need.
when it comes to marketing, they've got you covered here with graphics and buttons,
images and shareables.
you can put a website button on for buy me a coffee. We've got the widget where people
can interact and select the amount of money that they wanna send you. You've got
the stream alerts, so when you are streaming and someone pay you some money, that
you can use these sorts of graphics directly in your live stream. Or if you wanna
make it simple for people, give them access to a QR code.
Now when it comes to workflow integrations, they've got you sorted here. So when
a buy me a coffee comes in, you can have a tweet sent out to your X account automatically.
You can give people in your Discord server different roles and capabilities. It can
be integrated into WordPress, and if you just need full flexibility, it works with
Zapier as well.
Now let's go on to setting up being paid out. So the first thing you do is head over
to settings. You can set a goal and one of the areas you can do is set up your payments.
From here we select the country that you're in. In my case, I'm in Australia and
we need to enter in our bank account details. So I've put in my email address and
my phone number After that, set up the legal business entity that you're using. I
don't have a A BN just yet, so I'm just going to get it started and fill that in
later. After that, you just need to verify your details. So we've got my home address,
we've got legal name, and from there we can set up the bank account where you want
money to go. So I filled it in, had it all confirmed. It asks you to review and submit.
Once you've done all of that,
It'll say connected to payout account for your name, David.
now, when anyone ever goes to your buy me a coffee, personalized URL, they'll be
taken to a screen like this with your name, your picture, what you're about, and
the ability for them to buy you a coffee.
So that's the setup process for Buy Me a Coffee. It's great for any content creator
who wants to start monetizing their channel. I'm AppyDave I do videos on ChatGPT,
prompt Engineering and various AI tools. Please like and subscribe and if you've
got any comments, drop 'em down below. Otherwise, I'll see you in the next video.
That'll probably be on an AI tool or prompt engineering.