Would you like to automate or script your AI pair programming?
In this video we're going to look at ADA, we're going to install it and test out a couple of use cases.
I'm Appy Dave, let's get into it.
Now you can access ADA through GitHub on ADA-AI slash ADA.
And if we scroll down we'll find the Getting Started where we'll work through this to install the software.
A little bit further down you've got the documentation which will take you over to a page like this
where we can look through some additional examples.
Now I've just opened up a terminal, I'm running Python 3.12.5.
We're just going to click on the install for ADA chat and let's paste it in and see what happens.
From here we'll do a new terminal and we'll just type in ADA help
and you'll be able to find all the command line arguments that you can use here.
I like to just copy these straight into ChatGPT and ask it questions but it's all available here.
Now the next step in the ReadMe is change to a directory.
So what we'll do is we'll make a directory and go there.
It's also talking about using the Anthropic Key or the OpenAI API key.
Now I have both of those exported so I'm not sure which one it's going to run and then we've got ADA.
So what we'll do is we'll go down to a terminal, we'll make a test directory and we'll cd into test
and then we'll just type in ADA and see what happens.
So it's firstly asking us to create a repo.
We'll say yes and from there it's telling us which model it's going to use.
So it's got Claude 3.5 Sonnet, 2024, 1022.
Now when ADA starts you're straight into a terminal with chat capability already enabled
so you can just start writing a prompt.
So we'll start off with a simple prompt, make a HTML page in Tailwind CSS.
We'll add three fields, we'll go with name, description and URL.
We'll add a little bit more called plus two text areas and I'm just going to press yes
and see what happens.
It'll start writing some code for us and we've got Tailwind CSS.
What I'm hoping to do is have three fields on the left and two text areas on the right
and I'd like to create a template engine where the fields on the left are merged with the template to create an output.
So here we've got some information come up.
It would like to create a page.
Let's do that.
We'll say yes and it's also got open index HTML.
Let's see what happens if we try to open it.
So it's generated a new page.
We've got it looks like Tailwind to me.
We've got name, description and URL and we've got this template and where the output would be right here.
So let's say we wanted hello name.
This is how I would think it should work.
And then we can say the description is and we could put something like description.
And lastly, we need the URL.
So I'll say URL and we'll put in the URL.
And what I'm hoping will happen is that this information will get copied down here, but these values will be altered with whatever's going on here.
So if you look at the terminal, you can see a couple of extras.
So we've got a commit message and it looks like it's using semantic labeling.
So it's got a feat for feature and it said create a HTML page with HTML CSS.
What I think we should do is just go down to this terminal and we'll do a git status and there's nothing going on in there.
We'll do a git log and there it is.
We've got this feature create HTML page with tailwind CSS.
So if we go back, we could undo it, but what I'd like to do now is extend it with JavaScript capability.
Now what I think we should do now is go over to VS code and let's have a look at the code in the terminal.
And so we've got all this HTML.
There's the tailwind CSS.
Looks all pretty simple.
So let's add a new prompt.
So I've pre written a prompt and it says, can you enhance the page with JavaScript?
We're basically going to watch the field names on the left and the template and we're going to use interpolation.
And I've said, can you use square brackets?
We'll spell that correctly and we'll take a copy of that.
And if we head over to the terminal, we should be able to just paste it in and see what happens.
Now, hopefully as it goes through, we're also going to see some JavaScript changes either in the HTML file or as a new page.
So it's finished with instructions.
If we come back over and we look at the HTML page, we now have a whole lot of JavaScript down the bottom.
Let's also read this a little bit further.
If you type in template area, that's the sort of information you can then fill in the fields.
And this is how it should interpolate.
And lastly, it should be able to open it.
And we also have the commit message going on here as well.
I'm just going to press yes and we'll let that run.
And while that's happening, we'll bring up a web page.
So we've got the little HTML page up.
Let's put in Dave and let's just see what happens if we start typing name and this last one should change.
It does.
It changes to this.
We'll say we'll put in a description and we'll say URL URL like that.
And for the description, we'll paste this in for the URL.
We'll paste this in.
And we've basically built a prompt templating engine in about two prompts.
Well, to recap, we've installed Ada.
We've got it working and we've created a little HTML page and added some JavaScript.
And it's taken only a few minutes to finish this off.
I'm happy Dave.
In the next video, I'm going to take this process a little bit further.
I'll see you soon.