Imagine building a self-editing application. What that means is that you could talk to it and it
generates all the data in the back end or you could ask it to visualize it and html pages suddenly
materialized. In this video we're going to use the Agent SDK from Claude Code to do that and we're
going to build this application using the BMAD method. I'm Abbey Dade, let's get into it. Now
this video is a step-by-step tutorial so if you want to move ahead or go backwards and forwards
check out the chapter links in the description. Now what we're building today is this self-editing
application. We're going to use the Claude Agent SDK and the BMAD method. Now if this all works
what we'll be demonstrating is the idea of creating a bunch of products building out a product listing
maybe even a details page for it adding a home page making some of those products featured and
then adding more products along the way. Now the magic of a self-editing application is firstly this
human experience so we'll be able to talk to the computer have it generate features have it generate
data and we'll be doing that using vibe coding sort of techniques but the technical reality of
this is that we're going to use context engineering using the BMAD method and tools like the Agent SDK
to make this application a reality. So our Agent SDK application is built and this is what it can
do for us. So we're going into the chat bot where we're going to enter in some products we should be
able to view those products and see that they're being stored in the back end at any time we should
be able to create a HTML page notice that there's a live activity there's also live pages if we click
on the pages we should be able to go and see the products listing at any time then we should be
able to add a new product or update it and it should come through instantaneously. If we need
a home page we should be able to add a link and create a home page at the same time when we go
to that home page we should be able to navigate back to the products and at the end of the video
there's a complex multi-page workflow demonstration. Now let's just talk a little bit about the
planning ahead of time so I've already got a planning folder in place for what we're going to
do. I've got some preliminary tech stack stuff but I want to run all of this through the BMAD
method. Now which version of the BMAD method should we use? Should we use version four which
is the current or should we use the version six alpha nine? Now I tried a video yesterday on alpha
eight and I don't particularly believe it's ready for use just yet for this sort of project so we're
going to work with version four and that means what we're going to do is use this command here
npx BMAD method in store. If you do want to use the version six it's all available. Now the problems
I ran into with version six I've already communicated with Brian from BMAD and he's aware of it and
he's talking through the changes that are coming in place related to those issues but for today
we'll keep it simple and work in version four. Now in the repo that we're building all this which is
07 BMAD Claude SDK you can go to the bottom and find the links so here's the link to the version
for BMAD and if you scroll down a little bit we'll go and select our starting command. With that
selected we can go over to our terminal and I've already got some pages here. The readme that you
were just seeing is in here at that location and I've got a planning phase in my documents directory
already. So we've cleared the screen and putting in the npx BMAD method in store and that's going
to walk us through a wizard. So let's work through it step by step and the first thing is the folder.
Now it's opened it up to an npx directory so what I'm going to do is put in the directory
where we're building this application today. After that it's talking about different frameworks of
BMAD that we can install. This all changes a fair bit in version six we've got better games
set up in that particular version. For now we'll just go with the Agile Core. In version four when
it comes to the PRD product requirements document and the architecture document you can shard the
files meaning that they can be split up into individual files after generation. This changes
a little bit in version six but for today we'll say yes and then you can decide on what agent
coding system you're going to use. I'm using Claude Code so we'll just select that and in this example
we're not going to use Gemini or Codec so I'm going to say no to those models. Now it started
off with this idea of reading the user guide so we'll take a copy of that and head over to
Visual Studio. Now let's have a look at what I already had in place. So I already have a docs
folder with just this planning directory so there's a fair bit of spikes and examples
of how this application could work. We'll draw on that when we're building our product brief.
We've got a Claude file in place we've got our Claude subfolder and you'll notice that there's
an area called commands so all the BMAD methods have been set up within this area and then the
rest of BMAD is in the BMAD Core where we've got different workflows, teams, templates for working
through checklists, we've got our agents and we've got this little user guide that it told us to
read so let's pop that up. We've got a user guide for the Greenfield project so this is a brand new
project. Brownfield is for if you've already got an existing code base and we can start with a
project idea. We've got an optional analyst research now we don't need that because I've
already done all the planning but we might just work through it temporarily to see what it does.
Then we've got to build the brief so with the brief we're doing the product requirements
document, we'll do a bit of UX design, we'll do a little bit of architecture design and then at the
end we'll make it all cohesive and with the cohesion in place that's when we'll start using
a scrub master to design stories and a developer to actually create the code for those stories.
So let's start with our terminal and we're going to use Claude code and I'm going to run it with
the dangerously skipped permissions. Now it's fresh context and we've just added a lot of
context from Claude so I'm just going to run and knit on this. I'm going to give it a little bit
of extra information. We've got this planning folder but I don't want it to take too much over
with the Claude file. I want it to be referenced, I want it to maybe use it as a guideline for what
the project will be about but the main focus of Claude should be on the BMAD method and whatever
it decides to create. So with those two statements what we can see is that we're
improving the Claude MD to prioritize the BMAD workflow. So what is Claude MD?
That's essentially the system prompt so it's available every time we do a prompt that anything
in this file will be used and we want it to be hyper focused on what it does. So anything in red
has been removed and that's a lot of the stuff that I did in pre-planning before this video. We
can see that my folder hierarchy that does exist has been removed from the system prompt
but the important stuff that it's a self-editing application is in place, that the core of the
server should only be about 200 lines of code. It's got a very clean understanding of what the
BMAD workflow is. So we've got the workflow primary path, we've got step one which is
installation. Now we've already done that. We've got step two which will be the analyst agent
doing a workflow init and it just keeps going doing this hyper focused system prompt. So we'll
start off by having a fresh version of Claude and we'll put in a slash command and the one we're
going to go with is analyst and analyst will load up Mary. Now there's a lot of things that
Mary can do. For this session mostly we're going to focus on creating a project brief but she's
one of these agents that you can spend a long time in just doing all sorts of planning and research.
So we just go back to Claude code and we'll have create a project brief by reading an existing
document and if we put in the at sign we can start putting in project reference and we'll select it
and we'll see what she can do with that particular document. So the create project brief is going to
read from our project reference and what it does is it uses commands like the create doc which is
based on a template already in the BMAD core and for this we're going to work in the interactive
mode. So we'll just press one. YOLO would be the fast way to do it and with my project documentation
it could just work out perfectly but I want to be pretty sure with this. So notice that the output
file is going to be docs brief and we can see that it's working through many to-dos. Currently
it's written the executive summary for it and I've read it through. It's all pretty perfect.
I think the target market says it all. It's developers learning AI agent integration and
self-modifying systems. It's for technical educators. That's what I do where I want to
generate systems that are a bit flexible and dynamic pretty quickly. That's also rapid
prototyping. That's what we're doing today and then we've got the BMAD method practitioners.
Now one thing is to know that I'll be testing this with version 6 BMAD and if there is anything you
want me to test it with let me know in the comments below but for now we'll just proceed
to the next section and the good thing is it started writing the brief so we'll just bring
up Visual Studio and click on this file here and so as it goes we can keep track of what's going
on the left hand side but let's have a look at this problem statement that it's come up with.
So reading through the problem statement everything's pretty good. One of the things I
notice is the database. This is where this application will be a little different to a
lot of applications. It won't have a database. Instead it's just going to have JSON documents,
JSOM. They're going to be stored in the server and for saving them it's just going to be committed
to a repository. Now this is not a normal application that you would run in the cloud I guess
but for me it allows me to rapidly create tools that I use locally on my computer through a web
interface. So I think we can just move on to the next section and what it will start doing is
writing an updated brief. We should see it pop in below. It's updating so we can see a whole new
green section and here it is listed in the markdown document. Now if there was anything
out of whack with it rather than using Claude to change it you might just manually come in
and alter the document here to have it to rectify any flaws that you notice. It's important also
that you do rectify flaws because these propagate through. If you fix it now you have less issues
in the future. So the next area we're going to work on is the proposed solution section. So it's
written the proposed solution. If we go over and have a look we can see that it's going to use an
express JavaScript server. Embedded into it will be a Claude Agent SDK back end. Some of the tools
that we'll have is the ability to read and write JSON files and also to write HTML files. The main
front end technology is that we'll use React with socket IO so that we can stream information live
and we're going to use BMAB method version 4. There's also a little note here about using
for the user interface. We might also use the Versel AI elements. Now the back end is meant
to be simple. Just about 200 lines of code and one of the key requirements is that I can just
use it with my Max account from Claude. I don't need to go and pay any API costs with this
particular tool. Now while that's been happening in the background it's been setting up the target
users. We'll get it to start writing that brief for us. Once it's done the target users section
it should move on automatically to the goals and success metrics. All I've had to do each time
is basically say the next number for it to save the file. So the target users have been
updated. It should go directly into the next area but if we have a look at the target users
we can see that it's a learning system for developers but I would argue that it's for
anyone that wants to learn context engineering which is partly about building applications but
it's about building any system in a business or in your personal workflows. This is also an area
that you could pull out because I think anyone should be able to learn this. One of the things
about what we're doing is that we're not writing any code ourselves. Everything is just understanding
a little bit of architecture, following a plan and using natural language processes the entire
way. So now it's about to create the goals and success metrics. We've already written
all the target user information. It reads the brief each time, does what it needs to do and
then writes the brief again and you might be wondering what does it need to do? How does it
know to do that? And this is just one of the internal mechanisms of the BMAD method. So now
the KPIs or the key performance indicators have been updated. We can go look at it while we move
on to the next section. One of the things I would suggest is in this case they're not that useful
for me. I don't really care about these numbers here. 1000 developers clone or fork the repository,
not important to me. Content amplification, if people use it I'd be really happy about that.
I guess if anything was important is that people are using a sound content engineering system which
is BMAD method. But quite frankly this section is a bit of fluff today for us but the next area
is really important and this is the minimum viable product. And so as a must have it's working on the
idea of it having three epics. Now this is not normal by the way, this is not the normal area to
put in epics. Usually we do that after we've done the architecture and the PRD and it comes later.
But I put this specifically into my planning documents because I'm thinking of this as a
simple application with three different areas that we need to do. We need a foundation, that's the
server, the client, it just needs to be set up. After that the back end is the main area that we
want to work on. For the Claude Agent SDK implementation I've already done what's called
a core loop or the event loop documentation and essentially this is just a human readable list
it should work no matter what target language this system is built for. Now we are going for
JavaScript and so hopefully that'll translate pretty readily. And then the third area is that
we're going to have a beautiful user interface so this is basically using the Verso and ShadCN and
Tailwind CSS and just getting it to talk to the back end with streams. And as that information
hits the SDK perform any data creation or web page designs as we go. And the next section of
the MVP is what not to do. So we don't need a database, we don't need multi-tenancy, multi-user,
we don't need authentication or authorization, we don't need model context protocol. Good thing
about using BMAD is that I've used it for enterprise applications really effectively so it can do all
of these but we're keeping it out of the example. So after that we're going to build the post-MVP
or the post-minimum viable product vision and we can see that it's already come up with most of
that. It's got different tools that we might want to add later on and additional areas like multi-agent
workflows, production release. Now quite frankly I could maybe delete all of this and be happy
because I'm not planning to go further with this particular project. It's going to be the foundation
for other tools that you'll see me creating using the BMAD method. So it's gone off and now
thought about the technical considerations they've all been set up. It feels that we need to use
React version 19 and if we look at it in the mark down it's TypeScript and Vite, ShadCN, Tailwind,
CSS. This is all for the front end. If we look a bit further we've got the back end which is an
express server. We've got an installation of the agent SDK planned. We're going to communicate
between the two systems with socket IO and we're running it on Node. For our database it's just
going to be some JSON documents in the data directory. Future we could use a database if
we like and the hosting is it's just planned to run on localhost. So with that we can go and look
at the next section. It's currently working on the constraints and assumptions so this was a big thing
for me. Is it going to cost me anything? No, I want it to hook into my Mac's account and that
should be how it works. Developer time 40 to 60 hours for the MVP. Let's go and look at the
risk and open question and this is really useful. I've never done the agent SDK so it is a dependency
with high risk for me when I'm doing this video. The constraint, I think that the statement here
could be true but I don't think it matters. It's not that I have to do it in 200 lines of code,
it's just that I don't want it to be complex. That's kind of why I'm doing the constraint.
I will talk about this section briefly. I took out a section called the BMAD quality gates.
What I wanted to have happen is that rather than pure vibe coding where the user says I would like
a new home page, I wanted it to actually create a BMAD story on the back end. Now I think for this
demonstration it's maybe a reach goal, maybe we'll do it but this would be a really powerful
idea that users could just sit on the front end and say I want a new capability and BMAD
at the other end hears that and says well let me create a story for you and then the developer
can go off and create it. But for today I've taken it out. So that's the docs brief finish.
You notice it's now saying to go on to the next agent. It's got everything written. What we're
going to do is exit out because what I'd like to do is have a clean context the next time we start
but while we're looking at that let's just see what that last section was. So we've got the next
step immediate action is we're going to create the product requirements document. We're going to do
that by loading the project manager agent and running the create PRD command. Let's also look
at what we've got in our system. So everything that you see on the left in planning is stuff I've
done ahead of time. So the only one document we have in the system specifically created by BMAD
is the brief. Now I'll just take a moment out to suggest that if you want a little bit more
hand-holding or just seeing day-to-day operations on using the BMAD method context engineering to
produce applications or other sorts of business systems then you might want to check the link in
the description where you can go to my school community where I'll be talking about this on a
day-by-day basis but next let's go and look at creating this PRD. Now to do that we're going to
have a new agent and the agent we want is the project manager. So we load the project manager
in with the slash PM command and John comes into existence with a whole lot of capabilities. Now
the one we want is the star create PRD. So we just paste that in and let's see what comes up
and you notice that the way BMAD works is it works with context documents so we've got the create doc
dot md there was also a template going on which we can see here and a bit of configuration yaml.
Now in version 6 a lot of this stuff still happens similarly but they've made it a lot more
flexible. Now you may notice when you start with a clean cloud code is that the context is empty
and so certain things it doesn't know about. So this idea of do you have a project brief which
we just worked on is something it doesn't currently know about. So I'm just going to put in one that's
what we want to do and I'll put in the app sign and start typing brief and we'll just press enter
so it'll use that as loaded context. So it's read in the brief I've read it everything seems okay to
me so I'm just going to press one and continue on that. Notice as it goes it creates a change log
so we've got version one which is the initial PRD created from the project brief and now we get into
the hearts of what a product requirements document is we're coming up with the functional
requirements as we go so FR1 would be the first functional requirement so it's listing all the
basic capabilities that this application is going to do and then after that it does the non-functional
requirements which is all abstractions or ideas that the system's going to work on such as the
line limit on the server the fact that we're going to use Claude auth to log into the system.
Now like with the interactive mode with product brief we could just move on to the next section
but it's got a couple of areas needing validation is 200 lines realistic and should we have pre-built
examples. So I'm just going to make a simple adjustment here it says the 200 is a suggestion
what I'm trying to do is have the actual event loop of the agent be fairly small and contained
there's not a lot that you need to do there but this is a guideline it's not a limit at all what
I wanted to ensure that it does is not create complex structures as it builds out this system
because there's nothing complex about the Claude code event loop the other thing I wanted to talk
about is this area of should we have a pre-built example application no we shouldn't this is all
vibe coding that we're going to ask people to do but we may actually create some examples later
on so we'll just press enter on that and so the functional requirements have been updated we've
removed a concept and we've done slight updates and so this is a lot more important than in the
brief to get this right so we'll move on to the next step but the idea is that this is what's
actually going to get built. Now the user interface design guides have come through I've read through
all of this and most of it was good except there was one area and probably the core area
which is these screens and this is not working the way I'm thinking so the first thing it says is
chat interface primary screen full height chat with message history input field streaming indicator
and example starters love that that is the only thing that I saw this initial application having
it's then got concept of a status panel shows active story recent file operations quality
gait status now that's more complexity than I need my thoughts were that as soon as you started
typing stuff in here you could generate html in the back end and now that doesn't necessarily
mean the menus would work but the actual pages should work I had a plan for this particular
application that be mad stories would get generated that's what the quality gates were but then I've
taken it out made it a future thing so if we go to the very bottom I said this section here doesn't
make sense anymore and then I've said the next two steps which are these ones down here which I've
copied from above are too complex and I've given it a little bit more clarity on what to do so
we'll just run with that again it's so important in this area that you actually get it stating
exactly what you think you want to see so it's come through red is what it's changing green is
what it's changing it to you can see it's continuing with simplified user interface but
we can also go over to visual studio and have a look at the document like before here in a simple
markdown viewer so be mad Claude self-editing application we've got our functional requirements
kicking into place here and we can see some of the modifications like the slash chat and the
products as examples so we go back to our conversation and this makes a whole lot more
sense we've got the application presents as a minimal chat interface we know it can generate
concepts like products and blogs even though there may not be a navigation menu in place
the one little bit of styling we'll have is that it can do dark mode and light mode and so we can
move on to the next step there is one big issue in here and this is the issue of anyone using
coding is that this application when we build it will allow us to change our backend server
now that's both a security issue you wouldn't do this on a public website this is an internal tool
but it means how do we manage those changes and i'm assuming in my setup that i'm going to use
git commit so i should be able to roll back but that's not necessarily the most technically
easy thing for people to use but for this example that's how i'm planning to do it now here what
it's done is come up with the technical assumptions they're all based off the project brief which is
great i've read through all of them and they're all very accurate this is exactly the way i see
it happening but i thought i'd point out one area so where did this all come from it came from
something called the storyline app now i think it's important that we look at the storyline
application because the catalyst for building this project was could we generate stories
dynamically on the fly so if we head over to a web view and we're looking at what is a client
and server sort of system so currently we are connected to the server and it's using the same
technology we're about to build and if we go and have a look at our project files we've got something
called the boy and the baker now the boy and the baker is a five minute video that we've created
and when you look at it you can see that it's the story and the story starts off with an elderly
baker what's into his shot to seize a boy being beaten and bullied by some younger children so we
can see pictures of this baker along the way now if we go and toggle the image display we can see
that we got an establishing shot we've also got other versions of the shot available so as we
move through this story and it goes for five minutes all of these images are character
consistent their theme and style consistent and so we build our movie by using the image prompts
with tools like dali3 and so on and we use the animation prompts along the way for doing the
animations in halo or vo3 the interesting thing is that everything that you're seeing is based
off this one narrative so we've got a little narrative it creates setting the ambience characters
the description we got the image prompt and we've got the animation prompt and i've been going
through and refactoring this so that this is a lot more deeper but really i just want to type this
into a text box and have all of this extra information generated for me automatically and
that's what this application is meant to do we should just be able to save something into a text
box and have complex data structures form around that information so let me give you a glimpse of
what the application we're currently building can be used for and it's this storyline application
that generated this movie we've got character consistency scene consistency and everything was
generated using clawed code in the background to generate the data structures so as we start
asking questions like can you create three products that will generate complex json documents behind
the scene well that's what's happened with the storyline application but instead there's a simple
narrative that converts into image and style guides now if you're interested in seeing the
five minute video around the boy and the baker by vos then check out the link in the description
below but for now let's get back to john our product manager so i just press one to move
forward and we've got our epic list and it looks like there's going to be three epics which is what
i'd suggested it to do anyway so we've got the mono repo set up with basic client and server npm
workspaces we're going to express server minimal html client so that looks good after that we're
really working on the back end which is the agent sdk integration it's going to have the three tools
that are talked about and then we're going to polish up the communication with the front end
chat interface here so then we've got our sequencing logic i think the good bit is the
story count it's listing three to four stories per epic there isn't a lot of work in each section
and then it's listed its rationale and decisions i read through that this all seems to make sense
for me so at this point we've got many stories already set up for different epics the first one
is mono repo set up with a client in the server so the basic application structure for the front
end talking to the back end next we have epic number two which is essentially setting up the
clawed agent sdk so that it can communicate from server through to the client and when you look at
the goal there's also tools included such as talking to jason and html files and the final epic
number three is all about building a react front end and using libraries like shad cn and tailwind
css now if we go back to the top of the epic we'll see that every story follows a common
formula that's designed for agile development so firstly we've got a story number so in this case
it's 1.1 then we've got a simple title for what the story is going to be about this is initializing
the workspace and the mono repo so the idea of a user story is this three-part formula that says
as a particular person using the capability what do they want to achieve that's the i want
and if they did achieve it what would they get then there's an acceptance criteria so this story
is considered complete when all of these items are checked off and this concept is going to
repeat through every story in the epic so what i'll do now is i'll read through every story
headline and then we'll see pretty quickly that there may be some flaws in the way that it's
come up with so the first thing it wants to do in the epic is initialize the npm workspaces and
mono repo that sounds really good then it's going to create an express type script server
after that it's going to get a very basic html client up and running and finally we're just
going to have a little bit of an end-to-end test and mainly that'll be worked out by starting both
servers and checking the browser logs checking the console logs so so far epic number one looks
pretty good we'll see if it needs any changes when we look at the next step epic so now we're
moving on to epic 2 which is all about setting up the anthropic clawed sdk and it talks about
let's get it installed seems like a good first step after that is trying to implement one of
the tools which is the read json then it's going to do the right json and the right file and then
after all of that we're going to integrate socket streaming and we're going to do it both for the
server but we're also going to have the chat messages working with this and then after that
we're going to implement the full event loop now it's this particular epic that i'm having a few
challenges with and i'll go over what they are soon and how i can change them pretty quickly
but let's look at the third epic now the third epic is all about setting up a react application
as the front end so when we look at 3.1 it's initializing react with vite application
then 3.2 is setting up shad cn configuring it with tailwind css after that we build the chat
interface using the verse cell ai elements and lastly we're just giving it a simple light mode
dark mode now we've got all sorts of rationale being listed we could move on from there but
like i said i think there's a problem in epic 2 and the main issues i can see is that after
installing the sdk it starts going into setting up tools but we haven't defined yet where they
fit into the event loop we don't even know whether the event loop is going to work and
communicate correctly with the client and so as we work through all the stories in epic 2 we're
going to be pretty blind to whether they're working until the very end of the epic where
it all comes together in a big avalanche so to resolve this problem i could have a conversation
here but what i find easier is to just start selecting the context we need and what i've done
is copied all the way up to when the epic first started at this point i just select that put it
in the clipboard after that i just like to open a new conversation which i've got down below
and i've started it with the statement i want to read and absorb the following information
and then wait for me for guidance and that complete epic list has been pasted in so that
new conversation knows what we've got i've got it highlighted in blue and i just tell it that
you're going to help me build up an instruction that we can put back into the previous conversation
so the goal of this conversation is purely to build a prompt to paste into this conversation
but before we get started i ask it to do a bit of a q&a session with me to get clarity around
the problems as i see it i tell it that i'm pretty happy with epic 1 i think it's good but i think
there's stuff that we're going to talk about in epic 2 that will impact it so i just prepare it
to know that it can change epic 1 even though at the moment it's pretty good after that i went
through epic 2 and each of the stories and i just gave it this long diatribe now i was just dictating
directly into the microphone it was writing out everything as we go and so the good thing about
this is it can make it more readable for me so the first thing it does is start to unpack the issues
that i had addressed figured out that stories 2.2 2.3 and 2.4 can't be properly verified until we've
done the event loop it also worked out that the event loop is not a single story there's both a
beginning and an incremental development of it before it finishes it identified from my
conversation that what was called story 2.4 was actually two different concepts one was the
streaming client area the other was the same streaming client but specifically for the agent
sdk and this also led it to understanding that 1.4 might need some modifications now because i asked
it to do a q and a system it actually came up with four pretty solid questions but one of the
things i noticed while reading them was it kind of suggested the answers as it went so it's a
question of is it asking me questions or does it already have good recommendations and i just need
to sign them off so i just told it that the questions it's asking i already thought it had
the answer could you just give me the recommendation it just saves me a lot more time than actually
engaging in the q and a and so it wrote these recommendations so the minimum viable event loop
after 2.1 becomes this idea of create a basic event loop and there's no tooling no streaming
there's just the fact that it can receive messages from the sdk at the moment at the end of epic one
we're just doing http requests but it thinks that it might be useful to put in some socket
functionality at that point it now feels that the event loop that we're building is a bunch
of capabilities that can be done as multiple stories and we can move the tools that we want
to do into 2.4 to 2.6 and when i look at that i realize that even before we move on to epic three
if i want to build in other capabilities like clawed skills this epic will be the right way
to go because it's designed in such a way that each cross-cutting concern or aspect
can be added one at a time later on if needed so it's already figured out a much better plan
but remember that the initial part of this conversation was can you create the instruction
for me so i just tell it down the bottom here and i'll press enter that this is perfect i love the
way it's thinking what it needs to do is now create those instructions that we want to put
back into the top conversation and just so you know that top conversation is this one that's
here we're going to take whatever comes out of this conversation and drop it straight into here
to modify it so here's our detailed instruction set we can just go all the way to the bottom
with this we'll make a copy of it come up here and paste it in 203 lines of information just
by asking a couple questions so it's already started working on things one of the interesting
things is it's also playing around with the product requirements document right here so the
changes we asked for have been implemented we've got a change to story 1.4 and we've got a whole
new re reordering and breaking up of epic 2 and what the number of stories really tell us is how
many development sessions are going to go on because we'll get the scrum master and the
developer to work on each of the stories sequentially starting from one and going through to number 14
so quickly looking at the prd we've got the new epic list it's the mono repo set up the agents
or the server in the back end and the front end client and then we've got all the details coming
through one story at a time these are just simple stories they'll be converted into full-blown
stories with the scrum master and then add streaming and logging as we go and then after
that we can do the tools and then finally connect it all up to the react front end so with the very
complete epic list in place we'll come back to our conversation and just move on to the next step
which is the checklist so what the checklist has done is just read the prd now this is from a
product owner or product manager's point of view so this is all the business cases have been covered
we haven't yet gone to the tech stack or the software architect's point of view that's the
next area but when we look at it it says it's 92 complete there's problems with it but it's
mentioned that the user research area isn't really that relevant for a demonstration like this so i
won't worry about it and so everything else has passed except for this area in the mvp so any
blockers to moving forward well there's none identified are there any high level issues that
we should be aware of i think this is one we might address but we'll do it asking a recommendation
rather than actually taking the time to define it because the ai will probably do a better job
than me at coming up with an answer anyway these medium level issues don't really matter to me
like the target user doesn't matter and the success metrics don't matter in this particular
project now my background has been software engineering software architecture and even
for a time a scrum master so these numbers that you're seeing here the 23 days to get this
application written are legitimate numbers this is about how long it would take to do a project
like this if you were doing it in an enterprise system but at the end of the video i'll tell you
how long it's taken to do the documentation and to do the coding so we'll see what numbers really
come back so i've just dictated a little statement about the outer scope area like what does it
suggest we put in there and i've also said that for the logging i don't want to use a logging
framework but i wouldn't mind some simplistic patterns predefined before we get started and
this is perfect this is just what i didn't want to actually type in myself so we're not going to use
database and persistent authentication authorization isn't needed it's not for
production testing infrastructure is not important in this process advanced features like quality
gate hoops all this sort of stuff was all out of scope for me it doesn't need to be a polished ui
though i hope it'll be pretty good with shad cn and tailwind css logging and monitoring is also
really good it's come up with just a simple javascript logo platform it's not trying to
use libraries or anything like that so i'm just asking it to update the prd with all the changes
the only little change i mentioned is that the hot module reloading which is a developer experience
changes like modifying a bit of code and seeing it updated directly in the client is a really
nice capability to have in the application so we're all complete with our prd at this point
it's suggesting that we hand off to the architect we could do it in this conversation
but what we'll do is we'll just exit out of clawed and and start a new clawed session because we
want to have a clean context to get up and running with the architecture now i just want to point out
some basic maintenance that i like to do with working with clawed so i've just put in this
little prompt here and the reason is that we've created a brief we've created a prd but my initial
system prompt or the clawed prompt is pointing to the planning phase of the system but now that
bmad method has done these great documents i want to ensure that my clawed file knows about them
and so it's taken some old ideas like the planning documents and the bmad execution guide which are
now this one's not relevant anymore and this one's just lower priority so it said we've got the brief
we've got the prd and then we've got the planning guide now a lot of changes have been made but if
we go down the bottom and have a look at the summary we can see that our system prompt has
a very clear understanding of everything we've done right now one of the other things i noticed
is that it knows that the next step is going to be the architecture so if we come down and we will
clear out again and start with a new clawed context we'll go straight into the architecture
agent let it load and we can move into creating things so we don't need the back end architecture
and front end individually we just need the full stack architecture so we'll just paste that in
and kick it off so the architect is going to generate our architecture at this location
in the dots folder it's read the project brief it's read the prd we have a basic introduction
and it's worked out for starter templates that while it's based on a different idea there is no
starter template so for us it's just going to put in a changelog and we can move on to the next
section which is the main architecture so it's written out a lot of information i've read through
it all it's pretty much just restating a lot of the stuff we've already got we've got a technical
summary we've got the platform and infrastructure one of the things that it notices is that for an
mvp we don't need any complexities like a platform or infrastructure service approach we've got some
interesting graph that's going to show up in our markdown document and a list of the architecture
patterns and the rationale at that point we can just move on to the next section which is building
the tech stack so it currently hasn't written the markdown documents a lot of this is a little
unreadable but we've got the full tech stack table going on and again we've got rationale summary
including the key technology choices we've got the trade-offs of not having concepts like caching
and the database we're going to use version pinning so should be recording what version it's on
like react 19 and these ideas could be important if we're using an mcp to go and get documentation
around react or express it needs to know what version to work with now if you are actually
coming from a point of view where you don't fully understand all the terminology going on remember
there are other ways that you can deal with this documentation so you can use chain of thought also
secure day sort of stuff i understand generally the technology going on so i'm just pressing one
to move forward so now it gets into the data models and this is just the transport or usage
of data in the system so the first idea of the chat interface and the fact that it might have a
id such as the user or the ai bot content and status this is all great the only thing i'm a
little concerned about is does it match with the verse cell ai chat bot got a section on the tool
calling so the reading of the json writing of the json and then just messaging between client and
server so it's only identified three different objects that we need the chat message tool call
and the socket event so with that i'm just going to move forward so we can now just move on to the
api specification the only thing i was looking at here which i thought interesting is that we
are using this bio directional communication pattern now i don't know how much i'm going to
be changing specifically on the server that i need to send back to the client because i know this was
based off a different application the storyline app that i talked about where a lot of that would
happen but i think this will work pretty cleanly so now it's just working out all the different
components where it thinks the files are going to be as it builds out the application one of the
interesting things about doing it this way is that when we go back and look at the prd we may find
out that the order of doing things which the prd will list might be in conflict with some of the
architecture decisions now in version 6 of the bmad method they deal with that with a section
called solutioning i don't think it existed in version 4 so we'll deal with that ourselves
when we get to it we can also see here that there's a big component diagram being created
that we can go and look at a bit later so it's pretty good it's come up with the idea that
there's a data directory and that's where it's going to put json documents based on the ideas
i've already told it about it's got the concept of products it's got the concept of blog posts
maybe it needs some configuration so if we needed to do a home page and it had a logo or a theme
that's where that sort of information could go it's given a sample file structure talking about
the idea that files should be in kebab case and that it's essentially just an array of json objects
though we can see with that one that that's more just a general object now there's no scheme of
validation so this system could be brittle or fragile in the real world but i think for the
use cases we're doing it'll work pretty well and if we did want a more strict rules system we could
introduce something like zod or some sort of schema to make sure that any data being written
or read from always follows a certain format so we'll just move on to the next area one of the
things we can see here from our trade-offs is that this is not designed for big systems
it's really just a little internal tool that i want to use it for at the moment so it's come up
with a plan for our front-end components we've got the chat interface we've got some generic ui
controls we got the idea of the sockets it'll just be a single page application no router involved
and a bunch of static html pages i think the big issue we might have there is keeping style
consistency when we generate things and we haven't catered for that but we'll see how it
goes when we start running the application so plenty more examples coming through so we're
nearly done with the architecture we've just put in the system backend we've got the agents how
they're all going to work we got the tools that we need to work with a couple of utilities plenty
of example code coming through more diagrams being added to the system so we can see here
it's going to have a native npm workspace we're going to have three packages so we've got the
server client and the shared types going on now the full workflow from the command line has been
listed like node npm we've got the clawed auth this will allow us to hook up our agent sdk to our
local clawed account it plans to have a single line to get it all up and running just npm run
dev we'll start both the server and the client and now we're on to the remaining sections so
we've got the deployment strategy coming through we've got a continuous integration continuous
development pipeline but it's very empty there's nothing really going on just yet conversations
about environment we've got security coming through we've got performance metrics we've got
all the testing approaches just documented as future they're not in place just yet but we do
have sample code of what it could look like in the future and then we've got the error handling
strategy we've got a diagram and we've got sample codes to work with now we've got a two and a half
thousand line document created it's quite extensive if we jump over to vs code and look at it we can
see it's got concepts like the high level architecture we've got diagrams being generated
we can see that the plan is for the user to interact with the browser and for that to talk
to the agent event loop the agent event loop should then be doing any tool calling that it
needs to do and returning information back to the chat gpt stream we've got the ability to write
different files as we go a whole lot of architectural patterns we've got the defined tech stack very
extensive data models are defined and clearly written out using typescript we've got the custom
utilities which are integrated into the sdk right here then we move into components related to the
front end and how it communicates with the back end because the shape of data on both the front
and the back end can be the same we've got a shared types to transport that data and then we
get a visualization of the components on both the front end and how they communicate through to the
back end and we can see a little bit of where the shared components meet now we've got a sequence
diagram that's showing us the way data flows through the system and this is based on the
happy path meaning what happens when nothing goes wrong we've then got examples of the tool
invocation this is the writing of jason then the error handling workflow so this is the unhappy
workflow now the thing with web sockets is that they can stop working so we've got a reconnection
workflow coming through and examples of if i had the product catalog working what it would all look
like the writing of the product jason as an example then it talks about database schema well
we don't really have one but we do have a storage architecture it's just going to be files and samples
of what in this case products could look like blog posts and the configuration for the system and just
how the files are going to be laid out then it's documenting what we're not going to have so we
don't have schema validation we don't have index and performance sorted out we're not using caching
we'll just the data that we store will just be version controlled in github then we've got a
full list of what the front end architecture is going to look like followed by component templates
so when it needs to write a component it can use the component template to start there we've got
the state management architecture up on the client so this is examples of how the client can talk
to the back end and this has all been listed through here we've got the routing organization
now remember we don't have a router this is just a single page application but we do have concepts
like dealing with static html and then we move on to the back end architecture we've got the files
that are planned to be created we've got an example template for what a controller could look like
storing of data we'll use the repository pattern but it'll be file based persistent and then we've
got authentication and authorization flows which is really just the clawed authentication
for the sdk kicking in simple little middleware guard but generally we don't have any authentication
going on and then we've got the full unified project coming through right here so with all
this information done the next thing to do is just to confirm that our prd that we've created
is actually going to match with the architecture that we've got now in version 6 of be mad method
they have a section called solutioning which takes care of that but we'll do it manually today
now i'm just going to go into the pm and we're just going to ensure that we've still got alignment
between the prd and the architecture because the prd was created before the architecture
so i've just told john the pm to check that the architecture document and the prd are in alignment
main thing i want to ensure is that the prd is still in the right order based on the architecture
i also want to see if any of the stories or the epics or anything needs to change based on what
we did with the architecture if you're using version 6 of the be mad method this is called
solutioning it's just something i tend to do manually because i found it effective in the past
so it's finished the alignment with the architecture document it's listed a bunch of areas i've read
through them all and they're very minor so i think the main thing that we can do is just apply number
one which is the recommendations to the prd can be applied right now so those minor alignment issues
are now being fixed between the prd and the architecture what we're going to do now is
change over to the po the product donor and this is because we want to shard the documents now if
i just jump down to this view here sharding is the idea of splitting up a big document into little
documents and a few of the agents can do sharding but the one that's designed to do for both
architecture and prds is the po and that's why we've jumped over to there and we can see
the command here it's called shard doc followed by the document we want to work with and the
destination that we want to put it in so we'll start by typing in shard doc and i'll put in
the at sign and type in the prd and after that we'll put it into a file that doesn't currently
exist which is why i haven't used the at sign it's docs prd now while that's doing that we'll
head over to vs code to see what's going on so it's this big document that we've got going on
here and we're moving it into this folder and you can see everything being split up and there
should be a little index that points to where all the different parts of that file exist
so with that done we go back and we run the shard doc again this time we're going to click on
architecture and if we head over we should get an architecture folder being generated and we've got
all the indexes pointing to each individual file as well now we're about to get into development
but we should have a look at what our dots look like so we have the brief that was generated
we've split the prd out into individual files we've done the same thing for the architecture
but i haven't gotten rid of those files i've moved them into an archive directory and i've
left the planning document because that's got a lot of detailed files that we can lean on if we
need to at the time of generating the stories so now we're ready to start developing our application
so to get started we need the scrub master and the scrub master will read through the epic and
create the first story for us and that can be done by using this command here called draft so what
we'll do is we'll type in draft and we could say something like draft first story in this case
so i've got draft first story from first epic and if we go over and have a look at the epics list
the first one is the mono repo set up with the basic server and client so we can see it starting
to gather architecture context here we've got all the different documents that we've created
in the architecture folder being read as needed it's ensuring for the first time that we've made
the stories directory now i've already done that manually now keep in mind that from the epic point
of view it's only got this basic information to start with so it's drawing from that followed by
all the architecture documents and we now have our first story in draft mode and we can see that it's
grabbed from the epic the story card and the acceptance criteria and from that it's just
developed a bunch of tasks and sub tasks to work with it's aware that there's no story to start off
with this is the first one it accesses the tech stack we've got the project structure that it's
meant to be creating we understand the workspace that we're in and it's gone and prepared some
shared types so it's grabbing a lot of this information from the architecture document
setting up the naming conventions and the coding standards and it also understands how to set up
the type script configuration it's filled in an area for testing which at the moment we don't
have any testing and so at this point we could start doing development now the normal flow in
an application would be to read through this and check everything is okay for now i'm just going
to change this from draft to ready and hit save and then we can go back to clawed where we can
start doing our development now it needed to be in that ready mode so we've done that so we'll just
switch over to the development agent and we can just type develop story now i'm going to put in
the 1.1 because it'll make it easier for it to find the correct document without having to look
through documents and now it has a plan of action of what it's going to work through so it's going
to set up our package.json create the workspace directory structure for us move on to configuring
type script create the workspace package.json and create the shared types we'll do the git ignore
and then finally it will verify that the mono repo has been set up correctly so it's finished
developing all the code it makes a statement that everything is in place it's a little bit hard to
test because we don't actually have any source code just yet but when the story has been updated
we have a lot of check boxes of the work that's been done when i personally run the build i got
a couple of errors but they're actually listed here so that's okay all the files have actually
been created so at that point we can close off this store now you might notice at the end of
the story there's an area for the QA agent so what we can do is go back over type in slash QA for the
quality assurance agent now this is not an agent i would normally use in my own projects what i
have are custom agents more for story acceptance testing and that's about generating a document
for the human to work through and test different things that would be visual in nature but for this
video we'll use the QA agent and we'll just do a review on 1.1 i mentioned that i'd normally do a
story acceptance test plan now that doesn't preclude doing normal tests as well so usually
when you're developing an application you want to have unit tests you might want to have end-to-end
tests but definitely you need some sort of a test plan at the end of the story that says these are
the things that you have to go and look at and in a more complex application i like it to actually
walk me through and say first click on this menu filling this piece of information and all of this
information can be derived from a story and if it was something i was doing with this project the
way it would look is that it would create a new file right next to the story so we've got 1.1
dot story but i would have a 1.1 dot story dash sat and in that would be all the guidance and
instructions for me to go and visually check that everything's working now currently we can see that
the qa agent has come in it started to update the document so we now have our overall quality
assessment in place everything seems to be okay and one of the interesting statements is this one
right here so it's just talking about future considerations that'll be important with new
stories now if we go back to our vs code we can see that the story has been updated with all this
extra quality assurance checks so with our first story down we'll do a commit and we can see that
there's all the new configuration and setup for the mono repo plus there's all the architecture prd
and the initial story has been added as well we'll set up a new claw code and the first thing we need
to do is make sure we're on the scrum master and we'll type in draft story 1.2 and let it go and
build that new document for us now like before it goes through a template loads in information from
the epic that we're on story 1.2 loads in all the technical architecture documents also reads from
the previous story so it knows what's already been done so story 1.2 has been drafted i just had a
quick look through the document so i've set the status to ready but we've got our acceptance
criteria we've got all of our subtasks in place so now it's time to develop we just go back i've
already set up the development agent and we'll just type in develop story 1.2 and let it run
now while that's running i'll just talk about the idea of working with multiple projects at once
one of the things i love about being mad is that if you are generating two different applications
you've got a fair bit of time while the development is going on so you saw what i
did i set up the story then i switched over to the developer agent and i kicked it off
at that point i'll go to another terminal where i've already got the mad running on a different
project and goes through the same process now personally i can't do three projects at a time
because usually the first project has finished and i've got to go back and manually review it
but the good thing is that you can be working on two different applications at the same time
so we'll just come back and have a look at what it's doing and we can see that as it goes it's
signing off on tasks that it's done and it just keeps working through them so it's finished the
development the definition of done has been filled in we got some new files what we'll do is we'll
jump over to the quality assurance agent so again we're going through a number of code quality
metrics and we can see a list of the changes that wherever it says this story and we can go and have
a look at the code over here now if you're a developer this is an area that you probably
spend a lot of time looking i work more as a software architect and so while it would be smart
for me to check all the code i usually don't check the code and that's an interesting thing about this
i've built complete enterprise applications and i spend more time working on the documentation
to check the code quality than i do in actually looking at the code now the agents i use for that
i'll talk about in future videos at the moment we're just trying to build a simple application
so all the completion notes have been filled in we know the files that have been changed and now
the qa has come in so if we go and open up qa and look at the quality gate number 1.2 we can see
a yaml file on the changes though it's a lot easier to see it back in the clawed context window now at
this point we could be moving on to 1.3 but i suspect there might be something in this code
that we could test that we can see if it's working but the problem is that we don't have a list that
we can check so i've gone and set myself up a new window this is a conversation i have with a second
brain and the second brain has knowledge about things like be mad version 4 and version 6 and
i've had it just construct for me instructions for creating a story acceptance testing agent
now i'll just point out behind the scenes what's really going on is that if we do a tree you can
see all the different documents that i've got available on clawed so we've got the sdk here
we've got clawed code we've got skills and you can also see stuff on be mad method we've got
mostly v4 but we've also got information on v6 as well and it's true having access to that information
plus the project we're working on that we've been able to build these instructions so what i'm going
to do is just take all the information down to the bottom and we'll just go into our current
conversation and say can you create a new agent for me within the be mad system i'm going to paste
the information in so that's coming through and we'll paste all that information and let it go
now if this was version 6 of be mad you would have access to a system called bmb which is the
be mad module builder and if we go back to our second brain you can see where i've gone that
information there is this bmb folder that allows you to create agents for different workflow modules
but because we're in v4 we don't have access to that module and so i've just let it come through
so what i'm going to do is select the command we've got i've copied it into the clipboard
and it says that if we run it we should see some blue time stamp iso 8601 format so what we'll do
is we'll jump over to a terminal we'll paste it in and see what happens when we run it and yep
certainly does we've got some line console items here so the good thing is we can see what the
application is meant to do based on what the story says it should do now this is a little bit
different to a user acceptance test because this will change from story to story something that
would have been a uat in say 1.1 might now be defunct and not useful in 1.3 so it's not quite
the same as a uat which is generally for the life of the application this is only for the life of
the story so now we'll come down to ac4 this is about checking the health of the server apparently
if we hit the api health endpoint we should get a status okay so i'm just coming up to a terminal
and we'll run it and yes it's saying status okay so that's just a quick demonstration on how you
can create your own agents at any time it's easy to just say model it after something give it a
little bit of instructions on what to do one of the things i find with that particular agent that
i did is that some of those commands like was the terminal blue is not something i need to
visually check but i could get the ai to do it so i tend to split it up into two groups those that
i have to go and check out myself like entering in a form did i see an error message versus the
ones that could just be tested by clod code itself but hang on you might be saying what about play
riot or end-to-end tests could you set them up and the answer is yes you can you probably should
but i find that they're quite hard to get going they're very fragile so they're always breaking
and you spend more time wasted around in debugging them where then all you really want in this
particular case is do the forms work the way the story said they were going to be implemented
and i need to test it visually anyway i can't purely rely on e2e testing and this is where
the sat agent is really good so at that point i've just come back to clod code and what we're
going to do is just do a commit and push this up so what i've done is started a new clod code
we've gone over to the scrum master we started drafting story 1.3 so it's finished creating the
story let's head over to visual studio i've already set it to ready i think after it gets
through the tasks the main thing that we're going to want to look at is the fact that there's now a
html page so we should be able to see something apparently there's going to be a little bit of
javascript going on so let's go back and start developing so i'm just letting it load up the
developer and once that's done we can just develop the story 1.3 so now the development is finished
it looks like we're going to have an index file that we can go and look at or do the sat soon but
let's just go over to the qa bot for a moment and we'll run our review on 1.3 while that's running
we'll just do a quick check of the document it says all the tasks done there should be a public
directory we've got the html index we've got script tags coming through in a moment we should
see an update to the qa results so the qa results are in we've got a new gait file we can see the
story we will check an sat soon there's updates to the packages the client application now has an
index html page going on so let's go and test our story except in a spot we should be able to type
in sat and we've got sat so currently taylor is loading into memory we've got a create sat command
available we've also got an update sat command now we'll kick off the create and this command
this one here that we haven't used yet is just in case i don't like the instructions that the
current bot has we've got the ability to update the bot so this is reading our sat is reading the
story that's going to be the source of truth it's also looking at some of the code that's been
created like the client index html and at the end of this we should have a new file just sitting
next to 1.3 story so it's just created it let's pop it open so the story itself was about creating
a basic html page and the human test that we can do requires us to run the server which i've just
done and then it wants to go to the chat window and we should see a blue header called client
server communication test let's just bring it up that looks like it and it's also got a text input
box saying enter a message optional yep that's in place and a blue button labeled test health endpoint
it's also saying gray response area with test response will go here i wonder if it works now
we'll come back to having a look at our form we've got some things around styling i'm not that concerned
about that what's this form submission without a page reload should just say server response status
is okay and apparently there's no page reload so we'll bring up our website and we'll click on test
endpoint and there wasn't a refresh but we did see the server response update there's a bonus
visual test we can stop the server which i've just done and if we click on test health endpoint we get
failed to fetch make sure the server is running so that's really cool i wasn't planning to create
the sat agent as part of this video but this is the idea of it is that you don't have to think
about what the code did it tells you what has happened and tells you how to reproduce it which
just saves you a heap of time when you're using the beam add method to develop an application we'll
come back to our terminal where i was running that server and we'll just clean up after ourselves so
we'll do a bit of a commit right now and we've got a great commit message everything's listed
so for story 1.4 i've just run everything at once i haven't done any testing yet we started off with
bob the scrum master he created the story i went a little bit premature into taylor for the story
acceptance test because that can be derived from the story but it should also be done after
the development so i needed to do a bit of an update later i also ran james to develop all
the code and then did quinn to do the quality assurance so the new documentation files are
that we have a story we have an sat and we have a q and a document and from a code point of view
we got new files plus a little bit of an update to the readme so we can see the end points that
we want to test but if we go and look at the sat plan we've got a little bit of console logging
that we should see in chat and we should see some server responses if we type anything into
the chat window apparently it can also handle a disconnection so let's go test them out so here's
our web application will hit refresh and it's saying that we're currently connected let's just
say appy dave here press enter and we're getting a response received i've just asked it to kill
the server over in clawed code because i think it's running in the background over here i didn't
actually start it and look at that it's starting to say that it's disconnected what i'll do is
restart it from the terminal myself and if we come back to our web application hopefully it just
automatically reconnects so at this point we're right at the very end of the epic so number one
is done we've done stories one two three and four from the epic now at this point we might want to
do a retrospective this is something that you would do in agile development i recently talked
about that in a video so this video here how to make your ai coding partner smarter was an ai
retrospective that i did a few months ago on be mad this has now been implemented into be mad so
you'll see that in the version 6 once that's available otherwise you can watch this video
to see how it works but for now we will just move straight on to epic number two so at this point
we have finished our first feature our first epic in the system we have this client and server
application it uses socket io and has bio directional communication meaning that we can
type something in the text box and it immediately hits the server or if the server was to want to
communicate with the client it could do that as well now all the code and prompt sequences are
available up on the github repo if you want to access that there's a link to my community down
below now next up we're going to work on epic 2 which is the clawed agent sdk and what that's
going to allow us to do is put the equivalent of clawed code into our server so all the sorts of
stuff you've seen me doing with be mad which is creating code writing documents doing research
hopefully we can do that from our own application so that we can build html pages and we can generate
product and blog post content so we'll head back to clawed code and we've got our scrum master
set up and we're going to draft story 2.1 and so we have our story created it's as a developer
i want a clawed agent sdk installed and authenticated so that i can integrate the
agent-driven conversational capabilities into the application now we'll do one extra step this time
and we're going to go over to the product owner agent and with this we're going to run this
validate story draft 2.1 and what that'll do is run a validation on the story that we've
already done and what it's really attempting to do here and this is an optional task is just
ensure that there were no hallucinations or mistakes made in generating the story now i
don't normally do the validation system because it slows down my general workflow but sometimes
what you notice is that code goes off the rails and if you'd have done the validation you would
have saved yourself a lot of headaches so let's have a look at what the validation system is trying
to do so firstly it's an anti-hallucination protection is going on what it does is a qa
against just inventing stuff then what it does is make sure that all the documentation it needs
is internally stored within that story and then finally a whole lot of checks and balances on the
template and the sequence of the story so use the product owner agents validate story with
discretion like when you think something's complex because this will save a lot of future headache
if things go off the rails during the development cycle now so far we've gone through a full epic
without any issues so i didn't really need to do it but i thought i'd just throw it in so you can
see what it does so after that we go into developing the 2.1 task and everything was going really well
created all the code that we needed ran the definition of done checklist and this is when
a bunch of warnings popped up so you can see here that there's an external dependency that we need
which is to authenticate into Claude so we'll just open up a new terminal window and we'll paste
that in and see what happens so i ran into a couple of problems doing authentication and
apparently i was on the wrong version of Claude so what i've done is an update and i'm going to
take you through the workflow as it stands i've just logged into 2.0.42 and i'm just going to do
a log out so this ensures that we are now out of Claude and down below i've created a little test
SDK script and we're seeing an SDK test fail because we're not logged in so what we'll do is
we'll come back up here and we'll run the login function and we'll say yes and yes we're using
our browser subscription so we can just come up and click on the authorize button we'll come back
to the terminal it says we're signed in so let's clear this and try it again and it's just going
to say hello in exactly five words and hopefully it gets something back and so now we can see that
our SDK is actually working so at the moment the 2.1 story is finished if we go and look at the main
story acceptance test that we need to look for it's just that we've got colored timestamp with the
agent SDK running successfully if we go down to our terminal we can see that entry just here
so from a terminal point of view the server seems to be working all of our acceptance tests have
worked and the little test tool that was created is also returning valid data that the authentication
is working now for story 2.2 the basic agent event loop i've run this ahead of time as i said we'll
go straight into testing it so here we can put in a message i'm going to say can you help me with
the Claude SDK we'll press send to agent and you'll see a message coming through here and
currently it's saying processing and we've got this great formatted HTML response i'd be happy
to help you with the SDK however i need to clarify that i'm a HTML application building bot
and the messaging that's here happens to be because of a system prompt that was created
in the last story so let's go and check out the flow that we did in conversation and you can see
that we started off with the scrum master and we just asked bob to draft story 2.2 and with the
story created we can see that it's about doing the minimal event loop for communicating with the SDK
and we can already see from the success criteria that we were able to send a message see it logged
and then see it displayed in HTML now the main file created will be the agent event loop and
we've got this solid readiness score and we've also got a list of things that the developer could do
but we'll notice at the bottom that it does suggest that we could use a validation we don't
really have to with this sort of story but i've run one so we look at Sarah the technical product
owner we can then validate the next story now it's just comparing the story to other documents
in the system previous documents goals making sure that everything's in alignment everything's
great there's one little yellow flag here so we'll go have a look at it there's a slight
little question here but we won't worry about it in the story or rectifying it because the development
agent will figure this out pretty easily and so next we just install the dev agent which is
james and then we can just run the develop story command as james gets all the work done it's all
being marked off on the task list the story document is being filled in along the way and
we're seeing a little bit of a state change in the document just making sure that it's now ready
for review we see confirmation of what was either created or modified and so with the code complete
i just now need a plan of action written up for me so the story acceptance test is what will kick
off this is that new agent we created we've loaded it up taylor is in place and we just run the create
story acceptance test for 2.2 so new document is created and that helps us understanding things
like what are the new files or the modifications going on if we want to go and have a look at the
code a write-up of what the code is plus a little bit of key implementation details just to help
just so that you can understand it a little bit easier so we'll go and have a look at that document
we've got the acceptance test guide with the prerequisites how to set it up and then we go
straight into the human tests and we started all of this off by running this particular test where
we saw the information coming through we saw the log messages coming through now you got to see the
happy path if we put in hello can you help me we'd get some sort of clean response coming back from
the agent sdk so what i did for the acceptance test 8 happy path is i pasted in the console log
with a little bit of a message saying that i don't see anything suggesting that this actually got all
the way through it said that i probably need to do a hard reset on the html so i did that and i
started getting a response this was very good except what i was seeing was object object all
the way through the response so i just asked it was it expecting that that was all we were going
to get because i didn't go in thorough enough reading the story to know whether i was going
to get clean data it said no it's not right so when it made some modifications to the code
it first started by suggesting what those modifications were and then it made the changes
automatically and that brings us to where we are at the moment where we can now put in a message
we'll say what do you think would be a good application to build with the clawed sdk and
we've got a conversation stream that makes a whole lot of sense and remember that this agent
is paired with a system prompt which is about building web applications so we clean up the
end of the story by just using the qa agent which is quin and we ran the review story to build this
quality gait document so we have this audit trail of things that have happened including that the
initial implementation did have a failure in it now i've just implemented 2.3 which is real-time
streaming and one of the interesting things is i was also able to create a beam add workflow
to do all the work for me in one sequential flow we'll look at that in a moment but for now let's
just test it out so i've created a bunch of testing prompts that we can work with the idea
is that i want to see chunks come through the system so we go and select this particular one
and come back to our web form now i've made a minor change to the system prompt so that it
has a command called test what i want it to do is ignore the idea that it's a web application
building agent and we'll just paste this information in and it's starting to write some information
you can see here it's saying processing at the moment and all of this has been done in one chunk
so the interesting thing about the Claude Agent SDK is that you can't stream word by word it is
done in chunks so it's a little bit slow between updates but you can see that the streaming is
working between where my initial message came through and then the agent got involved we'll
try a different version where we're testing of reading the package.json we've got i'll help you
read the package.json so we see chunk zero coming through right here and now it'll do an analysis
md and we can see the three chunks coming through over in the console log so the last test is what
would happen if we bombarded it with ideas so i'm going to put in number 10 and we'll press enter
then we'll paste and we'll put 20 and we'll paste and we'll put 100 and then we'll paste and we'll
do 10 again and we can see that counting to 10 this is what it's come up with count 20 it's done
that for us count to 20 and notice things are starting to get a little bit out of order so it's
basically as the information comes in is when it's written to the stream and what i notice about this
is that it works very much similar to how Claude code would work which is different to ChatGPT
where you actually have to wait for each response to come through now i don't personally know whether
the way with Claude code if i was to rapid fire prompts like this they kind of get aggregated
you can put in an idea and then follow it up with a change of idea and it takes it into account
don't think that's happening here but we've got the rudimentary ideas of what you can already do
with Claude code all working now let's get back to the workflow because i created a custom workflow
to build all this out so that it could just run without too much input from me and it's called
the AppyDave workflow what it does is it starts off by asking a question what story do you want
to have so we did 2.3 at that point it started creating the story and it did that by starting
up the scrum master and running the draft story command and as per normal we got a detailed story
written it's in draft format at the moment and it's as a developer i want to stream responses
so that the end users can see information progressively now we've seen that working
so we know it's all going on it wrote the initial plan of what the code should look like in the
story and then it gave me this status update so we can see that it's in draft acceptance criteria
is there and it's got a couple of questions do i want to continue do i want to skip or exit so
we got a final summary of the creation of the story we can see that it's in draft mode at the
moment and it's asked me do i want to continue on the validation or skip now i said that the
validation is optional but i decided to just press continue and we can see that it's now going into
to the product owner and validating the information in the story against other documents now we're
onto story 2.4 which is all about reading the json document and you can see that i've done
a basic test here we can see the conversation finding information on the computer it's got
three sample products in place and if we jump down to the conversation it started as usual with the
new abby dave workflow we've got 2.4 being the story that we want to run it created that story
and then i just typed in continue this moved on to validating the file that gave a 9.5 out of 10
and the little issues that were there were all dealt with pretty cleanly during the development
phase so we didn't need to do anything once i then set the status to develop we were able to come
in and click on the develop story it also set up some sample data automatically so we had some
test products in place we also have broken data which we haven't done a test test on just yet
next it built the story acceptance test based off the story and the code that we've developed it
also ran for me all the automated tests that it could do anything that was to do with the terminal
or something that could be run from a command now during the sat generation it also generated a
couple of files that were very unexpected there was this human test there was also a quit test
so what i had to do was let it know that the sat agent that we had created earlier in this project
probably has some flaws and if it could go through and rectify them at the same time as cleaning up
these files and putting them in the correct location and this is the sort of bespoke issue
that you can get from time to time as soon as you see something out of the ordinary with the bmad
method it's important that you probably fix it in the moment and let the system know either through
learning documents or you clawed md or in this case an agent's file that it's not quite right can
it go and update itself so we can see right here that the create sat task has been updated with new
instructions and the cleanup of unnecessary files has happened right here now when i went to read
the json using the ai agent there were a couple of problems that needed to use the development
agent to fix the first one was a little permission issue it rectified that really quickly based off
documentation then there was the rom folder it got that fixed up as soon as i gave it an example
of where it was trying to read and where the files actually were and then lastly which was the hardest
one was that we were implementing this concept of read json but it didn't have any ability to
figure out what json documents were available or to discover the one you actually wanted so it
suggested and then quickly built two extra tools the list would show any files that were available
and the preview would let the agent interrogate the files to figure out which one you actually
wanted so let's go and test the read system we've got our little products document and we've also
got a broken document and we'll just head over to our site and we'll say can you get me a list of
products we'll send that to the agent it's processing at the moment i'll help you get a
list of products first let's discover them i've found some products let me read them and it's
got the file and look at that it's got the api dave on school so it's got that file that
we just updated and we'll see if this test against the broken json document will work we'll say can
you get a list of items from broken and it's doing some processing at the moment it's found that we
have a broken dot json document let's read it and this is perfect it's giving a nice message that
the data is malformed and the system is not falling over just finished story 2.5 which is
the ability to write information to the different data files i've done a few use cases but let's
go through the individual changes that have happened so from the api dave workflow point of
view there's a little bit of an improvement because on load it has a look through to see what the last
story was that was done and suggest the next story to go and write so i've just put in 2.5
here so it's created the story really quickly but the challenge i had with the last story
was that we added a couple of new tools that was the lists and and the preview json and so what i
did at the time of validation which is the next thing i then gave it some extra context by talking
about the list and preview json from the previous story and also giving it a little bit of a use
case so i was able to talk through the capabilities it could already see with adding json but then it
went on to document a bunch of critical gaps which is exactly what we want we want it to pick up old
ideas bring them into the new story and make it available for the development so it gave me a
bunch of options i went with number one that's just fix or update the story so we're seeing new
information being added to the story and that allowed us to go into developing with the new
capabilities thought of along the way and then when it wrote the sat plan one of the things
that did automatically this timeness because i'm gradually improving agents and workflows as we go
is that it did the automated tests of the terminal commands but i did ask it to run it
lot one more time and just give me a summary of what's going on so we can see the eight tests
that are from the terminal are all working and then it started listing eight different tests
that i as the human could go and test and the steps to work on them now the first one actually
failed and the failure was simply that it wrote the json document out in quote marks so as a
string so i let it know that there was an issue there quickly found and rectified that particular
problem then i ran into a new problem which didn't end up being a bug but just a gap in the
requirements and you can see the basic idea here is that i had a conversation that said add sugar
for 50 cents now i said that statement after a prior statement of looking in the products table
so i assumed contextually it would just work and the issue is that it had no conversational memory
each time it went back to the sdk so it suggested we could either fix it or create a new story
so what i've done is added a new story to this epic called 2.7 just based directly off the
information right here so the ability to have conversational memory is something we'll do in
two stories time so let's test the idea of adding and updating files in the data folder we've got to
test products we can see the information that's here we've got one broken file as well and we'll
come over and say can you add a product we want sugar and we want it to be 50 cents after that
we'll go down to our use cases and we've got this create an electronics json document under the
catalog folder so it'll be a nested file and it's saying it will do it with a laptop and a phone now
we'll head down to our json document we can see that this is expanded to have sugar at 50 cents
looks like we've got our new file let's just drag that in we've got an electronics catalog and we've
got multiple items coming in here and they're quite detailed now let's try out a couple of
discovery commands so we'll go what json exists in the data directory let's see what comes through
we can see the broken and the test products we don't have the catalog so it hasn't looked
deeply but what we'll do is we'll add a category field to the test products table so click that
center agent it's telling us it'll add a category now it's done it and if we head over to vs code
we can now see that on products we've got these categories so we've got groceries over here and
there was a couple of other interesting use cases that all worked which i didn't even think of it
just created these and the ability to create a file outside of the data directory was blocked
creating a file with circular references and the last useful example is to just add five items and
array to a new table so here we have five sites added so what we're seeing now is this really
powerful mechanism where we can read we can write we can update we can work with subdirectories of
files back on our server now these are data files next we'll be looking at how we can do html files
but the whole idea of this is more for an internal tool i wouldn't it's not the sort of tool that we
would use up on a public website where it can write to your server but if you're trying to
build a little application for yourself and you want the ability to dynamically update data just
by talking into the microphone then this is a perfect technique that we can be using now with
story 2.6 our conversational bot is now starting to get really powerful so what we'll do is we'll
start off with a simple question and that's what html files exist in the public directory
and you can see here it's saying that there are currently no html files in the public directory
and if we head down to vs code we can confirm that so we've got our data directory from the
last session available but in the server when we click on public there's nothing there right now
so the full conversation for this workflow was that we started with the appy dave workflow it
figured out that it had done 2.5 and that it could move on to 2.6 and so it was able to start up the
scrum master and create the story for us now because we'd made a lot of extensions within the
2.4 and this 2.5 story i decided to let it know that it was modeling these two stories except
rather than for data it was going to be for html and so while there were major differences like
the type of file and the location that they were going to be the actual tooling was pretty much
the same and so i suggested that it have a look at the 2.4 and the 2.5 before updating this story
with new capability from that it was able to notice all the critical gaps that were in place
and come up with four separate tools to implement before that it only had one tool which was writing
the html now to show that this was an extensive change we can see as we scroll through that
there's a lot of green and reds a lot of stuff been taken out a lot of new stuff being added
and the public directory is the 2.6 story so then we changed over to the development agent
everything pretty much went off without a hitch there were two different problems that i did need
to address and you can see them here the first one was that it wasn't actually serving from the
public directory i was able to test all the html but not from the application so that was a bit
of a problem the other problem was that when i was trying to display data that we created in
the previous story it also wasn't showing through so i did a little bit of prompt engineering just
to get the code working it was really easy to do because clodcode gave me option a b and c and i
just said let's go with a and c and it just wrote all the code that we needed so with our chat agent
set up to story 2.6 we'll just put in a simple prompt that says can you create a html page for
and along with that question i'll just paste in a little bit of information i just copied from my
website and we'll press enter and see what it does with that now you'll notice as it's building it
that we've got this concept down the bottom of pages so i've also added a little menu to the
bottom of the chat box to show any public pages that are being created so it's just come back
with i'll create a page let me check i'll create it and it looks like a bunch of stuff's being
created and we can see this little index let's click on that and see what we get we've got abby
dave and this is actually a whole lot of information from my main website we'll just pop over and have
a look at that and we can see master ai and prompt engineering different projects and down
the bottom different channels so if we come through and look at it here it looks like it's
all the same information all it's done is created this little html file for us and it's put all the
colors in there let's see if we can do something a little bit more complex and we'll do a prompt
that says can you create a html page called cat dash dog and do it talking about a pet store that
is about cats and dogs and let's go with the colors of brown yellow and green so we'll just
let this prompt come through as soon as it's typed in so we'll send that through to the agent
and we can see all our product data down here we can see our cat dog and our html file so what
i think i want to do now is create a new html file we'll go with a css file as well so the prompt will
go can you create a html file called aitldr.h and can we create a css file to go with that can the
colors of that css be light blue dark blue and white and can we make sure that we're displaying
a whole lot of products can the products come from our test products and document so i'll just
let that prompt come through there it is and we'll press enter so there's a couple of typos in there
but it looks like we're going to create a html file matching css file perfect now let me check
what pages exist and while that's happening what aitldr is is one of my other channels this is a
faceless youtube channel where most of the focus is on youtube storytelling so we've got something
coming through they're not necessarily the colors we normally use but let's go and click on this
and see what we get aitldr product catalog and this is really interesting from a few points of
view so the actual widgets that are in the product listing abby dave on school sugar
this has all come through but we've even got the html links so we can get to the home page can we
get to the cat and dog we can get to the cat and dog what about products that's taking us to where
we are and if we go back to the chat interface so at this point we've almost achieved everything
i wanted with this project it was the ability to create any sort of data we want let's go and
test the idea of updating data can you go and add three different products about nail polish
let that come through and send that to the agent and what i'm hoping it'll do is it'll come up
with three interesting products it should be able to add it to the only file we've got which is the
test products i probably should go and rename that well let's just go back to this it can see
the file it's now apparently added things oh look at that it's showing them as well
so we'll go and click on the aitldr page and see what that's showing okay we've got five products
now our page hasn't updated but if i go down to visual studio we can see that three actual
products have been added so my assumption is it's not reading from the javascript and it's
not it's actually been hard coded so maybe we can modify that so we're going to work with the idea
of can we update the html of aitldr so that the products are actually just reading from that url
so we'll send that through while that's doing its thing we can have a look at the url this is the
data that's available to us it says that the page is working let's go and click on it and look at
that we've got eight products we've got three new products added so yeah we're using our chat
interface to both create data update data delete it well we don't know whether it can delete
and to actually modify the html so let's see if we can do one more compound idea so we'll go with
the idea of can it delete widgets from the test products table the json document can we also go
to the aitldr css and we'll start changing the colors to be a light pink blue and yellow we'll
send that through to the agent we should see it coming down the bottom here so currently it's
doing a search broadly for the css files it's found them it's now going to read the full
content from them it's found widget abnc which it's going to remove from the json then it's
going to go and update the css and it looks like it's done that and what we'll do is click on
aitldr and look at that we got pinks blues and yellows and we've removed the three widgets
moving on to story 2.7 which is a new story that came about because we encountered a bug
where if you typed in a couple of messages it didn't understand the previous messages
so we've put it in place and what i thought we'd do is test it by maybe changing the title of this
particular website and at the same time also change the price of just cats and we'll do that
in two separate messages so here's our first prompt can you change the title of the cat dog
website so that rather than saying cat and dog pet store it just says pet store so we'll kick that
off and then we'll start the next prompt can you go to the cat dog website and change every product
that is related to a cat so that it is 100 more and we'll just press enter on that one now if
we look at the current website it says cat and dog pet store now i've done a refresh on it and
we can see that the pet store has been updated we want to see if the 24.99 becomes 124.99 and
they have changed so there's the new value and we've got the old value as 24.99 and cat and dog pet
store so from a conversational point of view it was pretty much the standard workflow we started
off with the appy dave workflow we created the 2.7 story we validated it the minor change here was
that i asked it to go and read the documentation around the sdk and we have a second brain of
information around that particular tool the basic findings from that were all listed and updated the
story we then just did our standard development phase we did an sat there was nothing in there
other than to run the two commands that i did and so we just finish off with a review from the qa
agent so that brings us to the end of epic 2 and what we can now do is we can add products or any
sort of data that we like we can update it we can also play around with html css javascript and we
could call this a complete application but if we look at what epic number three is going to be
about we'll be able to give the chat interface a much needed upgrade and we'll do that by going
to react where we'll use vite shad cn tailwind css and we'll use the versel ai elements to give
a really clean chat interface now it's a fairly simple epic we're going to initialize the react
application then we're going to install the shad cn and configure tailwind css then we'll build the
chat interface again using versel ai elements and lastly we'll implement a simple dark mode light
mode toggle so one of the things that we have to do before we actually start the first story for
epic number three is we just need to do a little bit of a retrospective so i've got a basic question
just asking it to think about what it would need to do a retrospective and it's come up with a
long list of tasks that it should perform to build up that particular document i've specifically told
it to think deeply and i've also given it as much time as it needs to do a detailed job and so it
goes through and it writes this long document and we don't have to read the document but it will have
information from here that it can pull on when generating the stories for epic 3 so story 3.1
is finished there's not actually a lot to see there's a little bit of console logging we can
see now that it's using react and bite and from our front end point of view all we've got is hello
world be mad claude sdk and the fact that it says bite connected and we'll just check that the hot
module reloading is working that's working okay so we have a foundation now for the react version
of the chat client let's move on to story 3.2 now we are on story 3.2 and there's not a lot to be
seen just yet we've got an installation of shad cn and ui and if we pop it up what we'll see is
this user interface with the basic typing area in place we've got to click me and we've got some
buttons and the styling is very ordinary at the moment and according to the component verification
that's exactly what we want to see at the moment we've just completed story 3.3 and we're really
close to the end of building the application and what you can see now is that it started to come
together quite nicely we'll demonstrate where it's at in a moment but i'll point out that this is the
14th story that we've done and every story we've done up until this one just came across without
a hitch it was able to be created it was validated it was written by the software developer we were
able to do the story acceptance testing and we were able to do the qa afterwards and everything
was really quite quick this is the one story where everything changed so i'll do a little bit of a
post-mortem analysis of it as well after i've demonstrated where we're at so let's test out
our new chatbot and what we'll do is we'll search for products first so can you tell me what products
are available and we'll let this prompt come through we'll press enter and so we can see this
little bubble coming up here that's what the user has said this is what the agent stk is responding
with at the moment and there are our products we've got some groceries we've got some beauty
products nail art sort of stuff so let's create a little website can you create a little html
website called beauty and joy can this be a nail art sort of store can we get both a html page
and a css file and we'll let that kick off and in a moment it'll come up with a plan of action
and here it's starting to happen and what we can also do is just head over to vs code where we can
see what we currently have we have a couple of websites here cat dog index and ai tldr and if
we come back and we look at these little pages here this is where we can see this and look at
that it just created beauty and joy so maybe that's already started let's go back and see
whether it's created here yes we can see it we've got a css file and a html file and that's why that
came about so let's go and click on that and see what we get okay we've got a interesting looking
nail art shop i think we can do better styling than that so what i'll do is i'll bring it back
here and say can you update the css styling for the beauty and joy website and can you
use this basic guidelines so what we'll do is we'll just go down and paste some extra work
and hopefully this will show up cleanly here we go we've got soft modern feminine we got some
primary colors coming through and it should be updating the css very soon and it looks like it's
finished it's actually created a different html so if we go up we now have two we have beauty and
joy and we have beauty let's look at the old one here's the old one and the new one is looking a
fair bit more elegant now ideally i would have liked that to actually update the original website
but for a first pass add a chat bot that can create data read data and also use it for websites
this is working really well now i said that this story wasn't actually as successful in the coding
as any other story that we've done but let's have a look at what it was originally it's build a chat
interface with versal ai as a developer a chat interface using the ai element patterns so that
users can send messages and have streaming agent responses now that's working and so pretty happy
but let's have a look at the postmortem and this is where a number of issues happen now part of
the issues happen because i think when i was doing it i was really tired so i wasn't paying
attention to different things going on but the main issue which i seem to run into every time i
do tailwind and totally forgot about it in this particular case is that it got configured with
v3 syntax but it was a version for tailwind and you might have noticed in the last story that
there was styling that looked pretty average and i said well that's actually how it's meant to be
well that's not the case and the reason is that the tailwind styling was misconfigured and took
a little while to find it out another issue that was happening under the hood for me is that one
of the servers there are two in this was meant to be running on 5173 but claude was actually running
a separate one on 5174 and so i was trying to see updates and nothing was coming through and i kept
saying to claude this is not working and he kept saying i've fixed it but i wasn't seeing anything
visually now again a lot of that was me tired at the time but this is one of the realities of having
ai agents that can run the servers for you is that if they've got a conflict with your current server
then it's just going to spawn a new one on a different port then it had a bunch of issues
with the bubbles and the drop down menu that we saw going up showing up underneath the bubbles
now the reason i actually wrote this document wasn't just so that i could show you the sort
of challenges that you can run into but because once you write a document like this you can make
it a part of your documentation system so if any other issues happen in the future and you notice
it you can say can you go and read other documentation or lessons learnt that were
done in the past and this can be a perfect way of training the ai model to you to write code the
right way if you see a certain problem showing up again and again now we're nearly at the end
and about to demonstrate this system all working so the 3.4 planning document ended up getting a
fair few changes this became a little bit of a conversation to deal with different issues so the
first thing we did was we added in the light mode dark mode and that's working we've got an activity
slide out panel that's actually working really well clicks happen everywhere it's all using socket
io it had nice status checks on when files are added deleted updated when i went to use the system
there were a number of issues just with the system prompt so i kept feeding the conversations back
in and asking it to update the system prompt it now works really well and so now i've set it up
for four different demonstrations now there's only two in the video the first one is the little
example at the beginning of the video is essentially based off these prompts here and the full session
that we're about to demonstrate is the creation of the bookstore and we can see all the prompts
that we're about to run now we have our chat application created using the be mad method
it's got the clawed sdk as a backend some of the capabilities is that at the moment we're seeing
no pages but as we add pages they'll appear automatically there's also an activity log
showing every file coming through so if we just start off with our first creation we're going to
create five bookstore products we've set the prices one of them is out of stock now it's created a
file and automatically created products dot jason we can see five products created here next we'll
create a products html file now as that comes through it should automatically update this to
show one product at which point we'll be able to click on it and see a menu so we'll go and add a
few more products and if we pop up the website hopefully we're going to see it dynamically load
because of the socket connection which means that any updates on the server will automatically
come through to the client we're seeing that right there if we don't like the style we can ask for it
to create a product css file this is going to go with a professional blue and gold color scheme
now this probably won't update the html because we're only asking for it to create the css at
the moment and nothing has updated so we'll just say update the products html so it uses the css
while we're doing that we'll have a look at what it's created so we got a bunch of css created
right here and it's just started writing the file and a refresh is showing the blue and gold coming
through on the website now there's a little home page if we click on that we're going to get a
file not found so what we'll do is we'll come back to our chat client and put in create a html
file this is the index we also want to feature a few products on the front page so let's bring up
page and we'll click on the home see what we get and we've got a shop now and a chat with us
and it looks like we've got some featured products on the beginning let's go back to shop now and
we're taken back to the products at this point it might be useful to create some blog posts so
we'll start with a little bit of data and we can see that it's creating it with a title author date
content and tags so it's very much related to the bookstore if we click on the blog post we can see
the information coming through here and here so we'll create a html page we're making sure
we're using the sockets if we bring up the page started writing the page now i think it's created
the blog page but when we look there's no link on the products there's no link on the home page
so what we'll do is we'll just jump down and put in a can you add a link on the home and the products
page if we click through we can read our blog articles here this looks good we'll click on
home we'll come back to the products and we've got the blog here as well so the three articles
we've got golden age of reading building your personal library and we've got philosophy in
pages let's go and add another blog post to the blog post jason it's in the middle of writing
and we have creating your home library so at that point it might be good to think about it's
coming up to christmas can we have a design that makes sense so we'll apply a christmas
styling to the product css with snowfall animation and festive red green colors it's started to come
through there's styling bugs and we can't currently click on the blog post if we go over to the blog
we can see the tinsel coming through here one thing you might notice though is that there were
a number of attempts to get this working so we started with apply christmas styling to the
product css and had to follow it up with five different prompts to get it working across all
the different pages it had a recommendation to go with scalable vector graphics so that was the
recommendation we went through now since it's christmas i think we should take the sold out
item and do an article about promoting some of it so we'll write a blog post announcing that
there's a special that the product has gone from 32 to 22 but there's only 10 left now the article
has been written but we better go and update the products so that it's in stock and we have a price
for it we'll click on products and this is the product that we're looking to see change and
there it is it's changed through it might be useful to change the color as well
just asking for it to be highlighted at the moment and there's our holiday special slightly
misaligned but we'll leave that for now and let's make sure the home page has a product for the
holiday special exclusive and we should be able to view it in the catalog so that brings us to
the end and what we've been able to do is build this complete application just with natural language
prompts and we did that using context engineering that's with the be mad method and the backend
system that we've built is using the clawed agent sdk so this is giving us all the power of clawed
code within our own web applications so the demonstrations we did was that we were able to
create html pages json documents css files make sure all the links go from page to page now all
the code is available you can check it out in the repository and if you want to join the community
we have more of a discussion and teachings each day on prompt engineering now if you're loving
the power of be mad in the next video we're going to use be mad again but this time we're going to
recreate an orchestration framework just like be mad we're going to call it poem which is the prompt
orchestration and engineering method and the whole idea of it is so that we can create and test prompts
in a technique very similar to be mad i'm happy dave i'll see you in the next video