I love Ecamm Live, but what I absolutely hate about this product is setting up my desktop
for a new stream recording.
In this recording, I want to work through a few different steps that I've been taking
to get my windows into the correct position so that every time I change scenes, a window
is nicely positioned within a frame.
I work through three areas.
Number one is getting the windows into the right position and the right size.
This includes the aspect ratio and location on what in my case is a very big monitor,
a 5K monitor which is the size of two 27 inch monitors.
After that, I'll go into the process that I use so that I can replace all those windows
whenever I need by just pressing a button.
And lastly, I will set up a bunch of scenes and layouts within Ecamm Live and talk about
the challenges that I regularly have in this area and how I'm managing to overcome them
at the moment.
Now, I just want to reiterate, I love Ecamm Live, but this part of the process has been
really challenging for me over the last two weeks that I've been using the product.
I thought I'd start by showing the problem that I'm trying to manage and what you're
looking here is my entire screen, two 27 inch monitors in size, but it's a 5K monitor.
And what that means is it has 5,120 pixels across and 1,440 pixels down.
It's not got your normal 16-9 aspect ratio, which is the size that you would be watching
if you were watching a regular YouTube video, instead it's equivalent of two of them side-by-side.
You also notice that there's a lot of windows on my screen and that's because the usage
of Ecamm Live for me is generally around prompt engineering and GPT or software development
and using GPT to write software or YouTube automation.
So I have three channels, they all focus on those three individual niches.
And in ApiCast, which I'm on right now, this is where I try and figure out problems.
This is where I work through behind the scenes solutions.
And today we're going to work through how do I get this all laid out so that I can have
an efficient Ecamm Live process.
But let's quickly go through the windows that I'm dealing with on a regular basis.
So here in this big window, we've just got a web page and I often do my mind mapping
and organization of thoughts here, but I might have other things like Logo Pony.
I was playing around with logo creation software and I want to teach people about these topics.
The next window, which is sized in a vertical orientation is chat GPT window.
So I'm doing a lot of prompt engineering.
I want to be able to talk about that.
Quite often need to control the computer from the command line.
So terminal is very important and when it comes to terminal, there's almost always a requirement
for some sort of software development and it's a big 16 by 9 screen.
Most of these are 16 by 9, but at different sizes.
And lastly, the other big window I use is mid journey.
So mid journey, I don't want to show the whole window.
I really only want to focus on the section where the pictures are.
And I'm also often using the finder window and all of these windows that I've just talked about
need to show up in my Ecamm Live in different scenes.
Sometimes it's just one.
It might just be the visual studio code is the focus or it might be two.
It might be that I've got visual studio code to show some code being created and chat GPT
over on the right or on the left so that you can see how the two connect with one another.
And pretty much every window you see here is either single focused or paired focus.
And on the odd occasion, there might be three windows being shown.
Let's have a talk about window management and window size set up.
I've got this product here called Moom, which does part of the job I want.
But then there's the issue of actual layout.
So if we look at this little image of the Internet, you've got all these windows and some of them are
bigger than others.
And the idea is that some might be taller, some might be wider and they're definitely in
different positions.
Another thing that's interesting is that if I just open is that if you look at this image
of windows, there's no other.
Another thing to be aware of, if you look at this image of windows, there's no overlap
and overlap in Ecamm Live has been causing me a bit of issues.
I'll show you the problem a bit later on in this video.
So I have this need to have windows of different sizes, but I also have a need for them not
to overlap where possible.
And that can be challenging.
Let's have a look at how I manually position and measure my windows.
And what I'm doing is I'm using a Chrome extension called Window Resizer.
And what it allows you to do is set up a bunch of presets in which a Chrome window will become
a particular size and at a particular position.
Now, this is not very useful to the other windows in my system like Visual Studio or
the terminal, but I use it more to find these positions and get a window into location.
And then I might put the Visual Studio over the top of it or the terminal over the top
of it.
Are there better ways of doing this?
Probably, but I haven't come across it at the moment on the Mac and there's definitely
going to be stuff available on windows.
So what I'll do is I'll just demonstrate it in action.
At the moment, we're looking at a window and we click down here.
And if I put this to what I've called Ecamm, because this is laying out my Ecamm setup,
GPT narrow, it will move over to the right here.
And the thing is it's totally out of alignment with any other windows that might happen.
And the thing is it doesn't overlap any other windows the way it is.
So if I create a new window and go to 1080p, which is my normal web view, it's sitting
over here on the right and it doesn't overlap the one on the left.
We can then take the window that I would usually have for the terminal and put one of these
windows up here.
So we'll click on here and go for 10, 1280 by 720.
It's a 720p high definition display.
Click it and it pops up into the left right there.
And another position I have is a 520p and it will move down.
And another position I have is a 520p and it will move down to the bottom right of my screen.
And I often will put my finder windows down there.
So just like if you were scrapbooking or doing something with woodwork, you might put down
a piece of paper to guide things.
That's what I'm using this for.
So I can then take this window, which is a finder window, and put it into place.
Or I can get this into place and size by clicking on here, going up to the 721 should take it
to the right.
It does.
And then I can just move this into position over the top of it.
So this is how I'm currently getting my windows into position.
It's a little time consuming, but it was better than just the random arrangement that would
often happen.
It's also not a perfect setup because there's still some overlap going on.
So if I bring up the Visual Studio, it doesn't overlap with the ChatGPT window, but it does
overlap a little bit with the terminal window.
I could maybe make this a 520p rather than a 720p and not have as much overlap.
And again, that'll be a problem because as the mouse moves around over the top of the
terminal window, it's also moving over the top of the Visual Studio window.
Even though when you lay out your Ecam live, they might be totally separate from one another,
but the mouse isn't.
The mouse is actually in the same place.
I don't know whether that's a bug or whether it's just something that they can't resolve
because it's with windows, but it's a little bit of a challenge.
The other issue that you can see is that the web view is totally over the top of the Visual
Studio view.
So if I pop it up, they cover one another.
There's not much I can do, even though this is a massive monitor.
I don't have more room.
And there's also another problem you have when you do have windows that are out of your
sight line is that when you look to the right, you're now not looking at the camera.
Now, I do plan to have more cameras set up, but that's also a little bit of extra work
that we've got to set up to get things just working nicely.
Now, let's look at Moom.
And Moom is a Mac product.
I don't know what the equivalent is on Windows.
And it's a Windows management tool, Windows layout tool.
I currently use another tool generally, but I use this tool just for one feature.
Let's look at what you can do with it.
When you hover over the little green icon here, you get this little square and you can
say, I want it, I want the window to be that big.
So now it's that big.
We click on it again.
We hover over it again, and we might say we want it to be on the left hand side.
So it takes up half the screen on the left.
Now it's not bad for what it does, but it's not very accurate, especially when your screens
get bigger.
It only supports this concept of nine by nine.
And I want to have precise windowing positions, but it does have another capability, and that's
the ability to save arranged windows.
And what I'll do is I'll right click and I'll go into preferences here.
And you'll see that I've got this configuration set up on my F13 key, where all the windows
that were on the page have been saved as a snapshot, whatever their location and sizes
has been saved.
Now a really important thing to get right when you do this is to turn off ignore obstructed
windows because you might remember that the Chrome window was over the top of the visual
code window and the visual code window overlaps a little bit on the eye terminal window.
And if you don't turn this off, they just won't get saved.
And that was one of the frustrations I had with this tool was that I'd try to get them
back into position and some of the windows wouldn't move.
And I go, why not?
And it's because they were obstructed and not being saved.
So what we can do is I won't show you exactly how to use this.
And in fact, what I will tell you right now is that if you do want to learn more about
eCAM Live, there are some really great people on the internet to learn from.
I think these two guys run eCAM Live.
They do really good tutorials.
I've found out about eCAM Live from Justin from Primal Video.
I probably have an affiliate link in the description because he's someone that I learned
from.
I learned a lot of my YouTubeing from him and a couple of other people.
But another two people that I thought were really good with their teaching is Adrian
Salisby.
I get the impression he works for eCAM Live, I don't know, but he does really good videos
on the topic.
And I've late the person that I've been learning a lot from is Alec from TakeOneTech.
Now I'm probably going to join his program as well because great learning there.
If I do, there'll be an affiliate link in the description.
But these are people that you can just learn great stuff around using eCAM Live and especially
with Alec, other sorts of automations and stream decks sort of work.
Anyway, I've got a little bit off track there.
Let's go back to using Moom to position things around.
Now I will state up front that sometimes I've had problems with this and I might screw things
up and have to start again.
But what I'll do is I'll move this window down a little bit and I'll move this one to
the right and I'll take the Discord window and I'll move it over here and I'll take this
window to here and we'll move this one down here and I can press F13 now to resize or
reposition everything.
It's also available through this here and that's where the F13 is.
But I'll just press F13 and what happens?
Pretty much perfect and this is what I mean.
If you forget something, it won't be perfect and what I have actually forgotten is that
the finder window down in the right hand corner of my window, I mustn't have saved it.
So what I can do there is see if I can find it.
Here we go.
Notice this is called Ecamm Layout Hell but we'll move it, I'm going to leave it at the
size it's at actually and I'm going to move it down here and then we can just go to any
of these, right click, go to preferences and you can update the snapshot.
I believe this is the right button to press.
So we'll click that there, replace the snapshot or merge.
I don't really know the difference between the two.
I'm going to go with merge, get out of there and let's do this again.
Move that out of alignment, move this out of alignment, this one, this one and this one
and we'll get the i-terminal out of alignment and then from any of them you can just arrange
windows. This time I'll click on it rather than pressing F13
and we are looking very good. Just make sure that the Visual Studio Code window is in position
as well. So the first part of this was about measuring where your windows are going to be,
what location, resizing them and being able to do it manually but with a bit of efficiency
using the window resizer tool. The next thing is once you've got it all set up,
use something like Moom to record all those positions. Now I don't believe it brings the
windows into play. I think you've got to have them loaded on your screen but it will
lay it out for you that way.
Let's just test one other idea because this is probably what will happen to you, this is what
happens to me all the time. We'll just firstly put everything into position, it's all in position
but what we'll do is we'll delete a window, we'll take it off the screen so there's no finder
and there's no ChatGPT window, we've got this out of alignment. Let's see what happens when
you're missing windows and you try to do this arrangement. So it all works well except the
two windows are not there. What we might be able to do is grab a window and go to GPT Narrow so
it's here, we'll call that ChatGPT, we'll open one finder window, new finder window wherever it
happens to be, it's currently on the downloads directory and we'll try this one more time and
see if magically it gets things into position. I don't totally have high hopes of this working
because it won't necessarily remember the exact window but we'll try it.
Look at that, very good. It's just nice that it does that. I don't know what it would do if we
had two finder windows but we can try that as well. Always testing so we'll throw out two of them
and we'll just put one on the download images directory and try this one more time.
Great, so we've got download images there but the other one magically moved up there so that's
very odd. It's not necessarily gone where I want and so while Moom is really good at getting things
back into position it's not totally the best and so sometimes you need to manually rearrange
your windows which is why knowing about the resizer or window resizer is also a useful option.
Now in this next section I'm going to go through the scenes and the overlays
on ECAM live and I'm going to start setting them up for these windows that I've created.
Now before I do, what we should look at is the stream decks that I'm using so you can see these
two little windows down in the corner and I'll just focus in on them and the first window I've got
says finish and pause so at the moment I'm recording and this is a pedal driven stream deck
so it's three buttons and if I press the middle one I can change context so I've got things like
I can change profiles so let's just do one they might not be looking good but they should
still work and if I go to the left I'm back to the one I was just on, keep going left I'm on a
different profile so I can use the pedals for changing profiles I don't usually because I usually
use that for recording and pausing and stopping and stopping recording. The next one is a setup
and where that would be relevant is that if I didn't have the window for my stream deck open I can
just press the left button and it pops up so now let's talk about this second stream deck it's a
stream deck excel and this is where I make mistakes I just press the right foot and shortcuts came up
and I was actually meaning to press pause and so usually when I'm recording I don't ever come off
this particular one so I can hit pause and we're back up and running and the reason I did that was
I was about to cough so let's have a look at this stream deck here and you can see that I've got the
concept of front facing and when front facing is on this is the view that you see and I'll go back
to the one that we're looking at but I also have my GPT view when I just want to see the GPT window
but if I also want to see the GPT window plus visual studio or plus iterminal then I can do that
or if I want a web page or a web page plus GPT or if I want visual studio plus GPT
terminal plus vs code or mid journey plus the folder that the files would save into
and we've got this desktop one which I've only put on for today I don't usually do my desktop
but this is so that you can see the whole screen for these examples
now just set up the recording so that you can see the overlay windows the scenes and all that
it's not something that you can normally see when you're recording on a cam live but apparently
there's a setting so give me one second to find it so exactly one second has gone by
that's one of the awesome things about these pause buttons is that you can go off and do
other stuff and resume where you're at and what I did was I went to the Facebook community for
a cam live it's a great resource to get answers to your questions and I found out that you can
press command shift D which I'm pressing right now and we go into demo mode so at this point
things like the camera which you'll see because I might have a window going that doesn't become
available when you're in demo mode other than what's showing on screen but we now have things like
the various windows that are available to ecam live so for the rest of this section I'm probably
going to be in this mode okay so let's tackle these layouts one at a time the first one I'm
just going to go through this is what we get so the issue I've got here is that it's not pointing
at the right chrome window I will press the edit button here I find this is the easiest
way to go you go to chrome and then you can pick one of the selected windows so it looks like we
want the chat gpt and we have fairly good layout there this is a layout I did earlier before but
now the windows move so it all gets out of whack I don't want to display the little message at the
bottom of the chat gpt and I don't want to show the tabs or the address bar so we're pretty perfect
now I would consider this bit done now as I move on to the plus visual studio code which is here
we can see that the chat gpt is not quite right and definitely the visual studio is not right
now the one of the things that I've had a lot of problems with this
is because I might move windows about and they don't actually have a proper aspect ratio so they
might not be 16 9 maybe they're 16 10 or maybe they're 15 8 or whatever they are I believe and
this is what we're testing out today that if you can get your aspect ratio exactly 16 9 for most
videos for most windows then it should fit on any ecam live layout because the idea of a video
that I'm doing is the 16 9 so even if it's smaller proportionally it should be right now we did that
by going to visual studio we've got it sitting right here and I am going to press edit on this
and it's definitely on code which is what we want to see and I have a wide layout so how
do I solve this problem firstly this is where I get a bit confused myself using this I'm just
going to click the zoom to app window and we're pretty good but there's a whole lot of space
on the left and right now I think I'm going to step forward and try and resolve this window
before I resolve this because I do have a different way that I can tackle this I believe so let's go
over to edit on this window and we'll set it to chrome to chat GPT this is great I'm going to come
back to this one let's move to item so this is chat GPT plus item and we will go into the edit mode
on this one and set it to the window chat GPT so this is fairly good it's not perfect you can see
there's a little bit of stuff going on at the top now one of the things you really can't do once you
layout your windows is you can't move them around like if I tried to move this chat GPT
window around I might get it looking well in this layout but then I'd screw up another
layout so that's just one of the challenges you have to think about so what I'll do is I'll hold
the option key down and I'm just going to move this down a little bit and I think we're pretty good
there now we could move on to the terminal but again I would like to now deal with things like
vs code the website and and terminal in the buttons that are that are just solving that problem
and I'll show you why so as a recap so far we've got this GPT working fine we've got the GPT
aspect of vs code working fine and the GPT aspect of item working fine we will I'm going to jump over
to visual studio code now and I press that button and we have a full view of visual studio and this
is supposed to take up the majority of the screen now I don't know why this is a this is a live preview
I don't know that I need that but we'll leave it there and I almost want to start again with
this one but let's just press edit we'll go into we'll just say entire screen kind of
wrecking whatever happened to be there then wide is probably fine I do like to change it around
just to make sure the things are working cleanly it's a little challenging and then we go to
wide mode again and I'm going to select code so code is in place but it's not it's kind of cropped
in on the window and it could be now that I think about it that this window has been moved before
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to start again with this one by just deleting it so we come
over to VS code here and click the little delete button there we'll add a new thing we'll call it
VS code and then we can click on this little button here and what it's done is reset all the
orientation we won't go with entire screen we'll just go with code and we'll set the aspect ratio
to wide and we're looking good we can then make this a bit bigger move it up this way
move it up this way at this point the VS code window is inside of our frame I don't want any
of the background I don't want the desktop I certainly don't want the button bars down the left
along the bottom or even the tabs across the top so at this point I will crop this window in by
holding down my option key and just dragging down and we'll go that far and this far and this far
and over on the right if I bring it all the way in I might get a better view here but
I tend to find that when I'm using multiple versions of VS code layouts that it's just
better that they're the same every time because what you can do now that you've got this is
you can copy it back to some of these other layouts where we had problems so I'm just
going to move this up into the top left hand corner and down into the right and we better just
center it a little bit and if we drag the window window here
now the webcam is sitting on top and this is the thing that I often will move from time to time
another thing I find very useful especially if you're using a full page sort of layout
is to lock it now if you don't lock it and you've got this window that you can move around
but if you accidentally drag on the thing it moves your overlay rather than the window
but if you right click on it and say lock overlay now when you drag it drags the whole window
now you have to do it for each element this one is not in place and by the way if you do
screw up and you go I choose how do I get it back to the original location just press command z
that's the undo key so it's back where we need it and we could lock that one as well and now it's
draggable from that point of view but let's unlock it one more time click on it and I'm going to
press copy and I'm going to do that by pressing the and I'm going to do that by pressing the command
c button so it's copied and we'll move back over to our chat gpt plus visual studio
and just delete the visual studio overlay that's here and paste in the one that we just copied
from the full screen vs code there it is and rather than trying to rearrange that vs code
window it's just easier to go from a full source one like you saw we do need to drag it down it
is meant to be under the chat gpt window the primary focus with this particular button and
we are on this orange one here is that chat gpt as a focus plus you get to see vs code now
I don't need to do any other modifications on this vs code this was a gpt application that I was
just doing some work against and the very top of the code window is where it says require and the
very bottom of the code window is where it says allow client so all the code is visible and I'd
be quite happy with this now we have gpt gpt plus vs code working and we have vs code working what
I'll now do is do the other individual windows so that would be web item and mid journey which will
be a little different because its aspect ratio is different the orientation but let's do item so
I'll press the item button see what we've got we have a pretty good window but as I saw before it's
kind of better just to delete it and start again so we'll click on it and press delete and then
what we can do is drag in a new window somehow
that was a mistake on my part you don't drag you just click it just one click we'll do and from
here we can click edit go from entire screen to item we now have more of the application
go to a wide view we're now quite focused expand the window up
on three of the corners like that and then crop as we need to so I'll get rid of this
brown at the bottom I'll get rid of the address bar or the title bar get rid of the right hand side
and then there could be just a little bit of extra laying out that we can do
with that in place we'll just drag it down so it's underneath the webcam and the webcam is okay
looks like one of the things I've been doing at some stages I've changed my border border radius
I probably need to fix that in the ones from before I don't think there's a global way of
changing this so we'll bring this back up to five it's a little bit fiddly by the way
there we go and we will copy it because we're going to use this aspect ratio the way we've
got it back on what I would call the GPT plus item so I go press that on the stream deck
and we're here and we can just delete this window
delete button doesn't work so you do actually have to come in and press this little delete button
here and we can paste and it's good just too big and we'll find a spot that be like it
and because the aspect ratio was set correctly on the full view the aspect ratio fits quite well
here we could maybe make things a little bit bigger just for to give more real estate
one of the big challenges that I've always been trying to do with how-to videos is not to make
stuff too small you should be able to see it even if you're running on a mobile phone so
being a little bit pedantic and particular about this I feel is important we'll hit
we'll go over to the web view and it's probably okay but I might just remove it as well because
I will copy this to other windows soon so we go to the screen share we delete it we click the button
I think we need to drag it down one we can then press edit go out of entire screen and go to
google but this time it's the other page involved this is looking good we can then press
we'll press the wide gets it at least close to where we want and expand it all the way up
and cropping now with this particular window I could almost call this my mine
myster window rather than a chrome window because I like to get rid of the little
controls that are around the mine myster window and I don't necessarily want to do that on other
web pages we'll keep it there and now if I want to recenter the middle of this I can do it actually
on the web page I can move it around to where I need it to be and I often do that because I might
make this fairly big from time to time and
I go with the idea that the most important aspect is at the top so if it's an orange
one the most important concept is GPT plus say item or web web plus GPT so
this is how I've been thinking it through that primary focus is at the top line secondary focus
if you need a second item is the second third and fourth line
now I'm going to move on to this blue vs code plus GPT and the thing is I've already got an
orange GPT plus vs code and I'll show you what I do here I come and make a copy of both windows
go back and paste it in there we have the vs code we can go back and now click on the GPT window
we'll copy that go back and we'll paste it in as well and you might be going well why would you
do that why would you have a GPT plus vs code or a vs code plus GPT that are looking the same
and this is where this which one is the major focus becomes important to me
so since this is the one where GPT is secondary focus I might just make it smaller
and just put it up in the corner like that and this is just how I'm thinking about laying out
these windows we'll just move over to the iterm plus vs code what I'll do is I'll just quickly
put the copy the originals into these spots and there it is we're the terminal taking up the
major focus with a little bit of code this is a very obvious area where I might actually get rid
of all this black space on the visual studio and cut it up into a little square but it's more that
idea that people can see some program running and also see the code at the same time but it's
not the primary focus and the very last section is the mid journey so as I've done before I will
just delete the existing mid journey window we'll add on a new overlay and that's a folder so we'll
add on a new overlay delete the folder make sure that when we edit it we go to discord is
where mid journey is in this particular case and we want a tall one this time so we go tall
and we're looking relatively good I think bring it down into there and we can just use the option
key to zoom in on what we want probably we'll want the message bar don't want any menu bar
don't want that top section and that's probably okay as well
we'll copy that and drag it more to the center so because it's so narrow it gives the opportunity
for the webcam to be a fair bit bigger it would be nicer if I could show more of this but
that's about where it's at one of the ways I can make it a bit bigger is to crop in even further
but I don't like to do that in this case because you might want to read what's going on down here
and we can just copy this one because if we move to the next one which is mid journey plus folder
we can delete them both again and we'll go mid journey is gone download images is gone we just
paste what we had from the other window and then we add one more which will now be the folder the
file finder I guess so we just click on finder and go to wide aspect ratio so so long as you
crop in in this case down to here and I'll just show you something while we're here is that
as I've been recording this video I've been doing it in sections so each we're at a
the section where recording right now obviously isn't in the folder but when I hit the save button
which is just on my case the left foot pedal for finish it will write a file a video file directly
into this directory for me and then I can just change the file name and I've kind of got all
these videos in order but for now we'll just move that to there and in a different video I can show
more of how I create videos so that it's efficient to create content and not have to do a whole lot
of post-production editing which is what I've found to be the most exciting aspect of e-cam live
its ability to make editing almost a thing of the past now it's not quite that simple but
it does so much of the post-production work for us I think we're done let's just go there's
desktop view desktop plus stream debt we've got our mid-journey plus our folder we've got our
mid-journey we've got our iterm plus a vs code we've got our vs code plus a gpt no webcam we could
add one we've got our web page and we've got our web page plus a gpt and then finally we've got our
gpt plus vs code plus iterm and our front facing camera
now at this point I would call that a wrap we are done setting up all our layouts
hopefully I'm not going to have any troubles with them one thing I didn't talk about is that I did
send off a support request last night and I dropped a couple of fbombs in the video
to them because I've found this layout process to be tedious that's the main thing you
it takes a long time to set up and any sort of movement in your screens screws it up I can see
how things could improve over time and hopefully we'll see them in improve some of the issues that
I think are there may not actually be related to ecambut just more to the way windows and the
windowing environment works on the Mac in my case but this is the process that I think is going to
work well for me to keep my layouts the way I need them to be
finally I'm doing videos on chat gpt for coding chat gpt for prompt engineering
and youtube automation so if there's anything that you're interested in seeing how
seeing the behind the scenes how it all works just hit me up in the comments