In this video we're doing a local install of N8n using Node.
So let's install N8n locally. I've come over to the GitHub repo for n8n, and if you
scroll down, you'll be able to find access to various documentation. The one we're
looking at at the moment is with NPX, which is one technique we can use. The other
is using NPM and the -g command. So why would we use one over the other?
or whether we would use the docker version. So the docker version is what you would
normally run locally. But if you wanted something like GPU acceleration and you're
on a mac, which I am at the moment, you don't have access to that using the Docker
version. So that would be the reason to come back and use one of the node versions.
But then why NPX? Now with NPX, what it'll do is it'll just get it down, get it running
for you, but not do a global install. So this is really useful if all you want to
do is test out the idea of running it locally. So this is where we'll start. And
then after that we'll test the npm version.
So quickly. Just come up to this little button, copy it to the clipboard. Once you've
done that, you can go down to your terminal and just run that and follow the prompts.
So we have N8n installed. Now we can see that it's running on port localhost 5678.
Now if we head over to a browser and we'll just paste in that URL, we now have n8n
running for us. The good thing about this version of it is that if I run the same
command again in one month's time, it'll give me the latest version every time because
it hasn't been installed globally. But each time you run it, it will be a bit slower
because it does have to go and check and potentially download a new version.
So we'll just do a quick little test on this. We'll set up an owner account with
this.
Go through the quick customization and we'll skip this section because I already
have a key.
Now I've opened up a new terminal to use the global npm install. So if we do which
on n8n, it'll say there's nothing there. So if we type in npm install and we'll type
in n8n and we'll type in g n8n and start the process there.
So it's finished installing. If we want to try testing it, we can type in N8n and
see what happens when we run it. And it tells us that there is a port conflict going
on with the version that's running over here.
So what we'll do is we'll just set the port in an environment variable. N8n port
is 5900 and see whether this runs. And here we have it. We'll take a copy of the
URL with the 5900 at the end. Now here we have the older version that's running on
NPX. If we do a refresh, everything should be running okay. And we'll just open up
a new browser window and start a new version. And this time it's asking us to sign
in.
Now we're entering the credentials that were used on the other version of this, running
on a different port, and it looks like we've signed in.
So what we'll do is
we'll click on the add first Node. We're just going to go with the trigger manually.
We just want to make sure this is all running.
And we'll press the execute workflow. And that looks to be working okay.
Now to be interesting, to know whether we can run this on the other port. We'll just
pop back to there and we do need to sign in. So this is the NPX version. The other
one is the NPM
g version and it looks like it's all available. Let's see what happens if we click
through here and we press Execute Workflow. We can run it from both ports. And it
is sharing the information.
So that's a local install of n8n using either the npm or
npm g command. In the next video, what we'll do is
we'll install it locally again, but this time using Docker. I'm AppyDave. See you
in the next video.