Have you been hearing about Vibe coding and wondered, could you build an application
for yourself? In this video, I'm just demonstrating an application that I built this
week using Claude Opus 4.5. What it allows me to do is double the productivity with
my own recording schedule as a YouTuber. It's allowing me to do short segment
recordings, put them directly into a folder, and named correctly. I can then add
images directly and have the images labeled to match the recording that they're part
of. I can also create thumbnails and add them against the video recording, and then
at any time change to a different project.
Now, let me give you a little bit of context. We are looking at the application.
There's a bunch of what are considered bad takes, which are all the white area and
potential good takes in yellow, and what is probably the good take in green. And
I'm using ECammLive. So what's good about using ECammLive is I can press buttons
on my stream deck and I can go to pre-configured scenes. So if we wanted to look
at the coding that's over here on this monitor right here, I can press this button.
There's a coding going on. If I'm having conversations with a requirements document
that's building the application, I can look here.
Now another thing that I've got going on is I've got a little strand deck pedal.
Now if I press the right pedal right now,
I can pause the video long enough to reset up the scene with a prop as I've done.
And if I press the button one more time,
I could put the prop back on the shelf.
Now another thing I could do is use my voice to create an image prompt and then have
that image put right here.
And the way this is happening is through the software that I've built that helps
me automate these workflows.
this little application that I've vibe coded using Opus 4.5 from Anthropic.
So let's go through what this application can do and maybe along the way fix a few
things. And I think the first thing we need to fix is that the last recording that
you just saw me doing is 122 megabytes in length and it's actually got a lot of errors
in it. I was pausing, re-recording, pausing, re-recording, and that's not a normal
workflow for me. I don't like having to do that because I really don't like doing
video editing. I like to solve the problems in pre-production, not in post-production.
And this is where e ECammLive has been
such a beneficial piece of software. If I want to change my scenes, like to this
one, I just go down to the stream deck, I press it. I want to go back to the scene
that we were just looking at. It's really quick. You're seeing animations. There's
absolutely no editing going on in this.
But where ECammLive falls down for me is
when it saves a file to the hard drive, it does it as a date timestamp. Now what
I really want to do is put it into a chapter. Maybe I'm recording the introduction.
So that's chapter one. And maybe there's going to be a few parts to the introduction.
Maybe there's a scenario, a call to action or hook, anything like that. And I wanna
make sure that every time I do a recording, not only does the file name change automatically,
but it also goes into the correct project. It would be really good if I could record
two different videos at once
and quickly just switch from project to project by going to a bundle light projects
and going, we are now working on this particular video, or we're back at this particular
video.
And so that's why I created this software. And now the actual requirements document
for building it is nearly two years old,
But recently I did a video and you can find out more about that right here. And that
video is about how I used Opus 4.5 for the first time
to build the initial part of this application that you've been looking at.
Now at the moment, on my e ECammLive downloads directory, I have two video recordings
in place. They're both quite big and the one that we had earlier for 122 megabytes
is not really part of the intro of this video, but it's more a scenario. So what
I'm going to do is I'm going to come up here and create a new chapter. It's going
to automatically become chapter two, and it's gonna reset the sequence to number
one.
Now I don't have any predefined areas called Scenario 'cause if I click on that,
this will just fill it in. But I can type in whatever I want.
So we'll type in the word scenario here, bring up our folder structure, and we'll
just do a rename of that and it moves over. Now it asked me do I want to delete remaining
files? And in this particular case, I wanna say no. Normally I would have a few bad
tapes. I want to get rid of them, but this particular file here is also part of the
same scenario. So I'm just going to press rename one more time.
And so now I've got two videos in chapter two on scenario already recorded. Now what
I'd like to do is maybe do a little bit of vibe coding right now just to fix a little
problem. So I'm just gonna hit save.
And restart the video and show that this part is also part of the scenario. So in
theory, I could do a rename, but what I'd like to know is how long is that in seconds.
Now to make the modification to this using Vibe coding, I'm using a tool called Claude
Code. So what I've done is just gone down to the base folder on my computer where
this application is running, and I'm just going to type in Claude. And in my case,
I'm going turn on the -dangerously-skipped-permissions, which means it has full control
of my system if it wants it.
And I'm just gonna ask it a simple question, what are we doing here in this folder?
And you can see that it's got a couple of folders. And these folders are nearly two
years old of this particular application in its earlier form. And I used the requirements
that were in there the other day to build the application we're about to see. So
I'm now asking it what is going on in the file-namer folder.
And you can see here that it's some sort of React, node js application that's being
built. It's watching the e ECammLive directory. Now this could be configured for
something like OBS if that's the streaming software you are using.
then there's this idea of dealing with thumbnail images for my videos, images for
B roll.
so when I pointed to the screen here, what was happening was an image was generated
and it was just going to get put into that particular location.
So I currently have three different terminals running The bottom terminal is the
actual application.
so it's running and it's listening to the ECammLive directory and just sending information
directly to the website. In here, this is my software architect or my product owner
conversation.
this is where I'm building functional requirements or non-functional requirements.
The difference is, is it visible and is it something that the user does, or is it
something under the system like maybe communicating with a server.
and I recently asked it to create this functional requirement, which is, can you
tell me how many seconds the video's actually going for? And what it did was write
all this information in green. I don't tend to read it. I know this is working very
effectively and it's created a non-functional requirement, number seven for us. And
it's asking, do I want to hand this over to the developer? So I'm just going to say
yes. And all it's doing at the moment is creating for me a little instruction set
that includes the non-functional requirement it just wrote, and an instruction to
put it into a different conversation window.
So it's finished writing that instruction. And what I can do is just select all the
information down to the bottom, put it into my clipboard, and I just head over to
the second conversation I've got going on in this system. And this is the developer.
So all the requirements are done in the other conversation. This particular conversation
is showing the developer. And so the developer is off writing code. We can see them
side by side if we want to.
I could even come over to the functional requirements area and start preparing the
next bit of work to be done.
but the main thing that I'm work hoping for is that when it gets to this area of
updating the file card, it'll come over and will automatically see a new time sitting
right next to this 71 megabytes.
We can see that the last section where I was making all these changes actually took
four minutes.
Now you might be thinking that's not how long the video is on YouTube. And that's
because I will do some post editing
because not every bad take I do, I stop the video if I've already got a really good
starting part to that section and then I have a bad take,
all I do is use my right foot to pause the video, compose myself,
and then record the next part.
Now let's integrate these two into the main video. So this is a new chapter, so we're
gonna go number three. We're on sequence one, and what we've been doing
is vibe coding using Opus 4.5. So I'll just press rename on this particular one.
That'll be number one. We will not discard and we will do another rename. And so
both of those sections are now into my main video recording project.
Now I did mention that a lot of files were also discarded, so were they deleted?
And the answer is no. So one of the things going on in my video project is I do have
a backup in the trash can of all the recordings that I said I didn't want, just in
case I do want to go back and use 'em.
But another thing that happens once you are recording a number of videos is that
the list of current files here starts to get a little bit long.
So let's start working through the capabilities that are in the recordings area.
So what the recordings area is showing is the same videos that we were just looking
at. If we press the folder button, we can see them right here. And we also have this
little toggle called safe. And at the moment that's not doing anything because nothing
has been marked as safe. But what we could do is take the intro because I don't really
need to refer to it anymore, and we'll just say Safe. And what that's done is moved
it into a new fold
right here. And if we click on that, we'll see that the three intros are living in
this position. Now, if we want to do
the same thing for chapter two, which is the scenario, we can press that button there
as well.
I've also put some quality of life features into the application.
what this will do when I click on it is open finder
and it's opened a second one for us, but it's opened it right where the recordings
are.
And I have this capability throughout the system. So if we go to the configuration,
we can see where the ECamm files are.
So they would get saved into here. In fact, let's stop the video.
And then we restart the video and we can see that there is a holding file going on
right now. We can go to the project directory. We can also go to the downloads directory.
Now the downloads directory won't make any sense until we get to assets. This is
where we can attach images to our videos, but what we'll do is
get this little ECammLive file over to our main application. Now we're not on the
demonstration of Opus 4.5, so what we'll do is we'll just create a new chapter
and we'll call this section the opening finder. Now, one of the uses of labeling
my videos this way is that I use large language model to help me automatically generate
the chapter links in the YouTube description. So when you go down and look at this
video from a YouTube description point of view,
you're going to see links that are based on the context of the transcript, but also
around whatever this name is.
We know it's two minutes, 57 seconds, which is that new capability. We know it's
68 megabytes. We'll hit rename and it's just moved over for us.
So we'll come back to our recordings and we'll turn off the safe because I don't
really care about that. This is where we're up to in our video.
So I've just finished that so we can see it updated
and we're about to go onto assets.
So currently we've got our asset assignment, and this is where we can label things
correctly. We've got our incoming images and that's in the downloads directory. I'll
just click on that button right now
and we can see that it's popping up here and there's nothing in there at the moment.
We haven't downloaded anything. And we do want to get our assets from the downloads
directory over to our video. And the last area we've got
is where the assets get assigned to.
I'm just gonna go over to a chat GPT window. And this is from another video and I've
got a bunch of assets that have been generated using just prompt engineering and
a style guide. And we'll just pick the bottom one. So we'll click on it and we'll
press this little download button right here.
And if we go down to our downloads directory, or in this case finder, we can see
that the image has just gone into this particular location.
Now, I didn't produce this image for this video, but let's say it was meant to work
with the oh four dash one open in finder.
What I can do is come over to our application. It's now automatically shown in the
incoming images area.
come up to our asset control and say, let's assign it to one of the videos.
Now I can control things from different locations. I could say it's part of chapter
three instead, and it'll do that chapter two, or I can just go to the end.
there's a hover effect and we can make it small, medium, or large
But the only thing we really want to do is come up and press this assign button.
And we're expecting the video to move out of the downloads folder
and whatever location it goes into, that should be the name. So I'm going to press
assign and it's disappeared from the download.
called images. We'll click in there and there's that image.
Now, I may not wanna waste my time during the recording of the video of doing the
images.
I might instead just want to come up with a prompt for an image and ask my video
editor if he could generate the image.
so what I'm about to dois use Ito.AI. Now I do have a link to a video on what is
an awesome tool and another one of those productivity enhancements. But what we're
gonna do is write a prompt here.
could you do some sort of infographic about the quick brown fox jumping over the
lazy dog?
it's just written that information into the text box. Now when I press save here,
we still get a file, but it's not a .png this time. It's just the text that was actually
in the prompt.
And that text is actually recorded in the assigned assets. So we've got a section
down the bottom here
We've also got an oh four one opening finder with a natural prompt.
I've just asked chat GPT to look at my previous infographics for style guidelines
So it's generating some sort of infographic at the moment.
Now it looks beautiful. There's obviously some typos going on in this,
what we wanna do is get it into the incoming images right here.
I might just leave it that way and do an assign on it. It should currently be in
the assets folder.
With the hover effect. We see the size of the file, the date and time,
and when we head down to our folder, we've got that new image.
Now let's move on to the next step. And that's dealing with thumbnails for your video.
So I was able to vibe code this little thumbnail section, and currently there is
a zip file there. We'll just delete that.
I'm going to click on this field, which is all about the assets. Now, I did do a
little error, but this is the one we're going to rename. And when we rename it it's
going to end up in this location. So we'll let that happen. And it's also asking
do we want to discard the error video. We'll say yes to that
And we will come back and look at thumbnails. So firstly, start a new chapter. We'll
call it thumb.
I've just come into Canva
we've got some thumbnails going on here. We can click through and see what they are.
I would like to have these thumbnails in my video.
I can come up and click on the share button, go to the download,
make sure it's on the jpeg, and then select which images I want. So I'll turn 'em
all off. I'll take this little blue area, we'll go number 2, 3, 4, and five, and
we'll hit done. And at this moment, we're saving it to the system.
so let's go back to our application. And what should happen is once it downloads,
it should just pop up
if we click on preview here, we can see the five images.
let's go take that,
and import it. And so now we've got our images right here, but it might've been smarter
if we came back, made a couple of modifications if we wanted to. And then when we
shared it, do a much more focused set of images. So we'll get rid of that thumbnail
area and we'll get rid of number five.
And we'll do a download. And then when we come back to our application here, we should
get a new zip file being created.
We'll click on delete. We'll click on this one where we can do a preview
these are the images that we want in our video.
come down to our assets. Notice that we do have a thumbs folder from before it has
the three that we had, but we're about to click, import the selected. So we'll click
on that, and now they've been updated for us.
So what we'll do is come back to our incoming area,
make sure we're on our recordings. We'll just do a rename of that. So this is number
six thumb. We can also go back to our recordings right here.
I don't currently have a restore all but I can restore them one at a time. So we'll
click on that one, that one and that one.
And our safe directory is now empty.
And so as I get towards the very end of the video, what you can see is that we've
got the final set of files they'll need to be merged. I'll use Gling AI to do that.
I've got all my chapters here. So the intro, the scenario, how we vibe coded, a little
feature with Opus 4.5,
how we pressed a little icon to open in finder, how we looked at the assets management,
the thumbnail.
The thing is with videos, when you're doing an intro or when you're doing an outro,
there are other components of it. So we'll click on there. And what we've just done
really is the recap.
what I'm gonna do is click on recap, and so when it saves this video, I will know
that the chapter is outro. But the very specific area within the video is the recap.
So what we'll do is we'll stop the video right here.
Start the video and rename that segment right there.
what we're going to do is go into the call to action.
I'm AppyDave if you enjoy learning about coding prompt engineering, context engineering,
then that's what I talk about all the time on this channel. If you want to join my
school community, there is a link in the description. And this is where you can find
prompts and different projects that I'm working on. You can find a really cool image
about whatever the school community looks like right about here.
And so now what we can do is come back to our play here. We'll press.
Stop and the video has appeared.
So the things that are in yellow like that, they're only because we're on the outro.
So if I go to summary you won't see them, you will have custom. I could put in AppyDave
as an example. If I just want something tagged in the video,
Come back to the outro. Know that I just did a call to action, but I did a specific
one. I did one to the school community,
hope you enjoyed that. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in
the next video.
Now in the next video we're going to extend the recording system and what we're going
to look at is the recordings themselves and as they come into the system, automatically
transcribe them.
it'll be able to suggest when we need to do calls to action things that we need to
talk about automatically. It will be able to generate the assets that we were looking
at
by generating prompts for us automatically based off the transcript.
We'll be able to put the timestamp where they're at, and then easily create the chapter
links in the YouTube description.
So check out the link to that video right here. I'm AppyDave.