Would you like to automate or script your AI pair programming? In this video we're
going to look at Aider. We're going to install it and test out a couple of use cases.
I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Now you can access Aider through GitHub on Aider. I Aider and if we scroll down we'll
find the getting started where we'll work through this to install the software a
little bit further down you've got the documentation which will take you over to
a page like this where we can look through some additional examples.
Now I've just opened up a terminal. I'm running Python 3.12.5. We're just going to
click on the install for Aider chat, and let's paste it in and see what happens.
From here, we'll do a new terminal and we'll just type in Aider help, and you'll
be able to find all the command line arguments that you can use here. I like to just
copy these straight into ChatGPT and ask it questions, but it's all available here.
Now the next step in the readme is change to a directory. So what we'll do is we'll
make a directory and go there. It's also talking about using the anthropic key
or the OpenAI API key. Now I have both of those supported, so I'm not sure which
one it's going to run. And then we've got Aider. So what we'll do is we'll go down
to a terminal, we'll make a test directory and we'll CD into test, and then we'll
just type in Aider and see what happens. So it's firstly asking us to create a repo.
We'll say yes. And from there it's telling us which model it's going to use. So it's
got Claude 3.5, sonnet 2024 1022.
Now when Aider starts you straight into a terminal with chat capability already enabled.
So you can just start writing a prompt. So we'll start off with a simple prompt,
make A-H-T-M-L page in tailwind CSS, we'll add three fields. We'll go with name,
description and URL.
we'll add a little bit more called plus two text areas. And I'm just gonna press
yes and see what happens. It'll start writing some code for us. And we've got Tailwind
CSS. And what I'm hoping to do is have three fields on the left and two text areas
on the right. And I'd like to create a template engine where the fields on the left
merged with the template to create an output. So here we've got some information
come up. We would like to create a page. Let's,
do that. We'll say yes. And it's also got open index, HCML. Let's see what happens
if we try to open it. So it's generated a new page. We've got, it looks like tailwind
to me. We've got name, description and URL and we've got this template and where
the output would be right here. So let's say we wanted hello,
name. This is how I would think it should work.
and then we can say the description
is, and we could put something like
description.
And lastly, we need the URL. So I'll say URL. And we'll put in the URL. And what
I'm hoping will happen is that this information will get copied down here, but these
values will be altered with whatever's going on here.
So if you look at the terminal
you can see a couple of extras. So we've got a commit message and it looks like it's
using semantic labeling. So it's got a feat for feature. And it said create a HTML
page with HTML CSS. What I think we should do is just go down to this terminal and
we'll do a git status, and there's nothing going on in there. We'll do a git log
and there it is. We've got this feature create HTML page with tailwind CSS. So if
we go back we could undo it. But what I'd like to do now is extend it with JavaScript
capability.
Now, what I think we should do now is go over to VS code, and let's have a look at
the code in the terminal. And so we've got all this HTML. There's the tailwind CSS
lots. All pretty simple. So let's add a new prompt. So I've prewritten a prompt and
it says can you enhance the page with JavaScript. We're basically going to watch
the field names on the left and the template. And we're going to use interpolation.
And I've said can you use square brackets. We'll spell that correctly and we'll take
a copy of that. And if we head over to the terminal we should be able to just paste
it in and see what happens. Now hopefully as it goes through, we're also going to
see some JavaScript changes, either in the HTML file or as a new page.
So it's finished with instructions. If we come back over and we look at the HTML
page, we now have a whole lot of JavaScript down the bottom. Let's also read this
a little bit further.
if you type in the template area, that's the sort of information you can then fill
in the fields. And this is how it should interpolate. And lastly it should be able
to open it. And we also have the commit message going on here as well. I'm just going
to press yes. And we'll let that run. And while that's happening we'll bring up a
web page.
So we get the little HTML page up. Let's put in Dave and let's just see what happens
if we start typing name. And this last one should change it. Does it changes to this.
We'll say we'll put in a description
And we'll say URL URL like that. And for the description we'll paste this in.
for the URL we'll paste this in
And we've basically built a prompt templating engine in about two prompts.
Well, to recap, we've installed Aider, we've got it working, and we've created a
little HTML page and added some JavaScript. And it's taken only a few minutes. To
finish this off, I'm AppyDave. In the next video, I'm going to take this process
a little bit further. I'll see you soon.