In this video, I'm going to
use ChatGPT to create a class
to anonymize people's names.
Here is the scenario.
You have content that you're trying to
create and you are using real names and
questions from the internet, and what
you wanna do is take the names like Dot
Stroop Andy and Christelle and change 'em
to another name that's still realistic,
but doesn't identify the original person.
I'm just gonna take you over to Visual
Studio and you'll see that I have a data
file here with people's names in it.
We've got Michael Dot, and Andy.
And from them there are also more detailed
data files with other people's names.
these are people's.
Names that would've replied to a question.
what I wanna do is take every name and
run it through an anonymization routine.
But the other thing I want to
do is I wanna vet the names
that are coming out of it.
And if there's a name that I
don't like, I want to be able to
refresh it on a regular basis.
the way I want to go about that
today is to just use ChatGPT
to create this class for me.
Let's head over to ChatGPT and look
at a prompt that I've written and
it starts off with, I need a class.
I need you to anonymize people's names.
The way I want to use it is that
there'll be a dictionary of some
sort with the original name.
Name followed by the anonymized
name, and one of the things
is a flag called refresh.
And the idea of the refresh flag is
that if I set it to true, I should
be able to get a new name generated.
if it gets set to false, it'll stay fixed.
if the refresh flag is
true, it means that I'm.
Not happy with the new name, and it can be
recreated if you receive an original name.
So this is a name that
you've already seen before.
You will add it to the dictionary
and set the refresh flag to true.
You only add names that
you have not seen before.
I will need some sort of lookout function
on the original name so that I can
get the anonymized name and I want the
information stored in a JSON document.
I don't really care how it names it.
One of the reasons I do that is because.
I find it's pretty good at coming up
with the right names, and since naming
is an incredibly important aspect of
programming, let's take it out of our
hands and let the computer do it for us.
before you write code, I would like you
to describe the structure of the class
meaning what methods and properties.
the reason that's important to me
is that I don't necessarily like
every bit of code that GPT writes.
So I want to have a look at what it
thinks is a good way of going about it,
and then I might tweak that a little
bit before I get it to generate code.
I.
Want this in Ruby.
That's programming language I'm
using for this particular problem.
ChatGPT has come up with this idea of
a class called Name Anonymizer, and I'm
pretty happy with that as the name, and
it believes it will need a dictionary to
store the information I guess the person's
original name will go into this location
and the mapped name or the anonymized
name will go into this location.
I assume it's going to work on the
idea that if refresh is true, it would
regenerate the name before persisting
it back into the JSON document.
it has a concept of a file name and
it defaults to name mapping JSON.
I'll be happy with that.
It has a constructor, an initializer.
There's nothing mentioned here about it.
Taking the file name as a parameter,
so maybe you have to in instantiate it.
Then set the file name if
you want a custom one, and
then work with the functions.
But we'll see what it actually generates.
This has the concept
of anonymizing a name.
let's say we give my name David Cruwys,
and it comes back with Bob Smith.
The thing is that it will check
for my name in the dictionary.
If present, yes, it does.
Then set the refresh flag to false.
It returns the anonymized name.
That might be the right flow, if not
present or if the refresh flag is true.
It generates a new anonymized name.
if it comes back with Bob Smith
and I don't like that, then I
can set the flag to true and.
Just call my name again to
get a different name back now.
Then there's a method here
called refresh, anonymized name.
I guess this is the method
that's going to do the work.
What's it say?
Sets the refresh flag to true for a
given name so that a new anonymized
name can be generated next time.
it's really just setting
the flag in this case.
I think this name is not necessarily the
best name 'cause I, I got the impression
it was going to do an action, but it's
actually only going to change a state.
if I wanted to give a bit extra
instruction to ChatGPT, that
might be the area that I do it.
But quite frankly, it's probably
gonna be easier just to change
it in code after the fact.
But we'll just see what
else it's got here.
the next one is look up
with an original name.
this is the main method that would get
called each time returns to an anonymous
name, based on an original name.
Then there's a save to file and a load
from file additional considerations,
the anonymized name generation process.
You could use simple naming
patterns or integrate a more
sophisticated name generator.
What I think I'm going to do is suggest to
it that it uses a ruby gem called Faker.
Instantiate, the class which loads the
existing directory or creates a new one.
Not necessarily what I wanna do.
I probably wanna have a little bit
of control there, but we'll see.
Call lookup to get the anonymized name
for an original name and optionally
call, refresh anonymized name if you
want to refresh flag for the name.
Maybe this status name is, okay.
We'll see once this generates.
does this structure align
with your requirements?
It's close enough.
I've decided to do a
couple of customizations.
The first one is, if I look at the
refresh anonymized name, it's actually
a pretty good calling technique
to work this way, but it wasn't
the way I was planning to use it.
My plan was that if the JSON
document on the server changed.
Then the next time that this
method is called the getting of
a new anonymous name, it would
just go and refresh at the time.
what I'm gonna do is rather than even
coming up for a name for this method,
it's really interesting when you struggle
to find the right name that ChatGPT may
actually be able to solve this problem.
So we'll just write this little prompt
and I've already pre-written it.
I think the name refresh, anonymized
name does not match the intent.
This name suggests that the anonymous
name will be refreshed, but really
it's just setting a state flag, which
will only ever need to be processed
the next time the name is requested.
Give me five names.
That might be better.
Let's see what it.
does it's come up with
five different names.
They're all pretty good.
mark_for_update, set_refresh_flag,
and schedule_name_refresh.
this is probably the most obvious one.
I know it does not conform to RuboCop,
which is a linter in the Ruby language.
They do not like using setters and
getters like that, and that gets
me thinking that I might just get
it to go with mark_for_update.
here's the class that it's generated.
It's called anonymous name generator.
I don't believe that's what it came
up with before it said NameAnonymizer.
I'm gonna copy that 'cause I prefer
this name for what it's wants.
It's.
Got requirements for
JSON and file utilities.
I believe the project, I'll use this in
already have that so it could be removed.
It's then got an attribute accessor
for the underlying mappings.
how about we go through it quickly,
then come back and look in detail.
an initializer, which calls a method
called load or initialize mappings.
There's a method for getting anonymous
name and one for mark for update.
That looks good.
There's the ability to save
a mapping and there's the.
Ability to generate anonymized names.
This is not actually what I wanted to do.
I guess I forgot to use the Faker
gem as part of the requirements.
I think we'll end up regenerating
this, but let's look a bit.
Further, and then we've got a
private method called mkdir_for_file.
And what that's doing is taking the file
name, looking at any path that might
be related to it, and then making a
directory if it does not exist, if we use
it here, and this is how we would use it.
generator equals anonymous name
generator with the name of the file.
then you can get an anonymous name or
you can mark it for update as I look
through this, a couple of things.
stand out this.
Should be private.
This is not a public method.
It's making the directory.
returning an empty hash if
the file does not exist.
Otherwise, it's loading it and passing
it from JSON into a hash, and it's
been called in the initializer,
but really that's a private method.
I might tell it to do that.
when I look at this section of.
Code.
I wouldn't necessarily write it this way.
We've got this name mapping
to the original name.
So let's say the name is David Cruwys me.
It would be at name mapping David Cruwys.
that's been called three times
here and then returned here.
maybe a variable might've
been a better technique.
If it does, Find it,
that's what gets returned.
Otherwise, it generates a new one.
What we've got here is checking
for the mark for update is false.
if it was true, it would keep moving down
and get the anonymized name, and then
we build up the structure that we want
to store against the original name, save
the mapping, return this anonymized name.
I think all this code would work.
The only thing I wanna change
is the name of the class and let
it know to use the Faker Gem.
I've just created a prompt that I'm
going to use to generate this class.
And one of the things I did was I did
read through all of this again and
picked out a couple of little tweaks
that I want to do to the instructions.
One of them being that I wanted
to use Mark for update, and what
I'll do is we'll paste it in here.
because I know some of the
names can have three words in
'them, or two words or one word.
I don't really care what the
source name is, but I do wanna
make sure that, the generated name,
is always the first and a last.
I've made that statement.
I want to take any Relative
path, qualified file name.
So my belief is that I would use this
and the JSON file might be in a sub
folder from where it's being called.
I want to make sure that it can
handle concepts like config.
My names JSON.
Or my custom name, JSON, or if nothing
is provided, and that's important to
say, if nothing is provided, so that it
realizes the Initializer needs an optional
parameter and to use name mapping.json.
the folder name might not exist.
can it pre-create it if it's there?
I haven't actually stated
pre-create the file.
I think it's gonna get it.
use the mark for update flag.
Write this code in Ruby.
we'll hit go and we'll see
what it starts writing for us.
Now I've just gone and created a prompt
just to make a couple minor edits.
to be fair, you probably just changed
this code yourself, but the good thing
about ChatGPT is that you can get it
to do all your work, if you like, and
learning the skill is really important
as we move forward and it gets better
and better at doing this sort of stuff.
Can you rename the
class to name anonymize?
that's what I liked.
Can you make a particular method private?
there's these constant lookups
against the dictionary, which
could either be used in a variable.
I think it was only in that one method,
or there could be a Memoized helper.
let's just press enter and
see what it comes up with.
The initialized code is not in this
position anymore, we've got these two.
Public methods and then the load is now
private and we've got a memoised helper.
and it's given us a description that it's
reducing repetitive dictionary lookups.
So I'm pretty happy with that.
Let's see how that got used up here.
here's where it gets called.
It's say, mapping entry based off the
original name, putting it into an entry
variable, and then it just works with
that entry variable wherever it needs to,
except when it's creating the new one.
I just had a look at this method and
This is not a memoized pattern, where
you go off and do a long-winded process,
and then you store it in a variable,
and then the next time you go to get
it, you just use that variable again.
Here it's just doing the process every
time, so it didn't really understand that.
I'm not even going to
try again with ChatGPT.
I'll just write the code myself.
these are the little things that
you do need to watch out for, it
probably doesn't matter at all.
This is just a dictionary
look up on a small file.
So performance never is going to be
a big concern with this particular
class, if you have the opportunity
to do it right the first time, you
can do it right the first time.
what we can do is go through this
code, make a couple of tweaks if
needed, and we'll test it out.
the first thing I'll look at is this
generate anonymized names, and what I can
do is just take this code and replace it.
Basically with the Faker gem, I'm
going to get rid of all the comments.
I don't really need comments
for things that are obvious.
I like to use single responsibility
methods and the method names
really match the intent.
As I said, this is not a memoed helper,
but one thing I did notice when I looked
back over the code I'll show you that this
is probably still the right way to go.
what I noticed is that the calling
through to this method both here and
where's the other one there, is just
being stored into a variable anyway.
Now, if I.
I'd done it the way I'd I
was suggesting to ChatGPT.
Then I would've had to call this method
with the original name over and over
again in this position, and this position.
this is still a better technique
I'll hit save on this file.
I'll get a copy of the class name and
head over to a unit test harness it
would be useful if we bring up a terminal
with unit test runner already to go,
basically I've just using it more as an
integration test to call this method.
The method is here and I've set
up a couple of names the goal will
be that this file will update.
the first thing we look at is that we
have an anonymizer we will loop through
all the names, which are here, call
the anonymizer.anonymized_name with
that name and get a new value back.
While I'm not using this as an actual
unit test, there is an expectation that
the anonymized name will not be the same
as the regular name, so that should work,
and that it matches the concept of having
two words with capital and lower letter.
Does in it.
And lastly, I just wanna print out
a key value pair to the console.
I wanna take the original
name and the anonymous name.
if I hit save, we get David Cruwys
being mapped to Nina and App
Dave being mapped to Chet Flatly.
that looks good.
And we've also got our values here.
Here in the Matt file, and
they're not marked for updates.
if I call it again, and the best way
to do that right here is just hit save.
It'll run it again.
And we get the same values as before
for both David Cruwys and API Dave.
what I'd like to do is test this, update
who, and we'll work with David Cruwys.
what we.
Can do is put my name into
this particular parameter.
If the parameter exists, then call Mark
for update with that particular value.
what should happen is that value
would become true when this is
called, and then when it goes and
loops through all the people here.
when it gets this anonymous name,
it would update this value and then
set this from true back to false.
I think it might be useful if we see that
timing delay so directly after I set that
true, we'll put in a one second pause
before calling the new anonymous name.
there it is there, and I'll just hit save.
If we've got our terminal running,
it should just work correctly.
This is true.
The name changed it's back to false.
If we keep doing that, it
becomes true for a little while.
The name will change
and then back to false.
if I wanna do it for API, Dave, I can just
go and select that value and now it'll be
the second one is going to change here.
Chet Flatly becomes Jonathan.
Schoen.
I think one last thing to test is that if
you wanted other names in there, I might
just put in @flivideo, @winningprompts,
@appycast and @carnivore 90.
Now, this code I'm going to be using
for presentation capabilities within
this YouTube channel, but these are
various YouTube channels that I use.
But here I'm just going to use the
values to change 'em to people's names.
I'll hit save and hopefully we.
End up with four new
entries in the system.
Now, every time I refer to fly video,
for instance, I will always get mosh mhy.
if I hit save, that value does not change.
But if I want fly video to change in
this case, we'll just say @flivideo,
hit save, and now it's been updated.
To Didre now, that's an example
of how you can create a class
from scratch using just ChatGPT
and if you're interested in various
automations that I create using prompt
engineering and the GPT APIs, then maybe
click one of the links in the description.