In this video, we're going to be talking about my upcoming personal project, the Carnivore 90 Challenge.
This is an endeavor to improve my health and well-being by following a carnivorous diet over 90 days and
documenting the process on a new YouTube channel. As the name suggests, the diet primarily
consists of eating meat, following the natural diet of carnivores, as some call it, the lion diet.
Before we dive into the details, I'm Appie Dave and I welcome you to the planning phase of the Carnivore 90 Challenge.
Today, I weigh about 100 kilos and I'm 177 centimetres tall and I have several health issues that I am looking to improve
during the 90-day challenge.
This includes psoriasis on my arms,
constant heartburn. I also have fluid in my ears.
I'm having a lot of issues with energy, needing to go to sleep during the middle of the day,
brain fog and memory.
I'm pre-diabetic, overweight, a lot of visceral fat around the middle and
currently checking my PSA levels that have been elevated for the last three months.
I also have sleep apnea and I use the CPAP machine.
The primary goal of this challenge is to get healthy, to improve my cognitive function,
have more energy and improve my mental health, especially depression.
Another goal is to monetize the challenge. I plan to share my journey on YouTube and
possibly derive some sort of income from it. For the last six months,
I've been living in another country and I've just come back to Australia.
I'm in Brisbane and on the 1st of July, I move into a new apartment.
So that is the date that I've scheduled to start this 90-day challenge.
It's in about seven days time.
Now, I need to find reliable meat suppliers, I guess butchers in my local area.
It's probably going to be organic meat.
And I need to learn some recipes, something that's tasty and easy for me to do.
There will be a learning curve for me as I delve deeper into the carnival diet.
I need to gain a better understanding of the impact on my health.
I also need to research people that are against the carnival diet.
I want to find out what the opposing point of view is.
This is the very beginning. This is my planning phase.
My primary goal is to get healthy.
My secondary goal is to document the process.
Hey, I'm Matthew David.
Let's get into a vidcast on the Carnival 90 challenge.
OK, in this video, I want to explore a new project that I'm about to start.
It's a 90 day challenge on using the carnival diet.
So let's have a look at the goals that I have.
So my main reason for this is health.
I'm about 100 kilos.
And that's my weight, but there's a bunch of health issues going on.
So let's say I have psoriasis on my arms.
I have a chest problem, heartburn, I guess.
It's constant. I had hearing issues.
I'll expand on that later.
Energy and energy issues with brain fog.
Overweight, visceral fat.
OK, let's use chatGPT.
I'm just writing a quick prompt into chatGPT
and pasting in my current issues to see what it comes up with.
Well, that's going, let's explore this hearing issue.
So the hearing issue is not that I can't hear.
It's that I have fluids in the ear canal.
Now I've had a look into whether I can get tubes put in to drain my ears.
But the issue is that my ear canal or the entry is too narrow for that.
So I suspect that this is an inflammation issue.
That's just me doing a little bit of Google doctoring,
not actually having any real understanding.
Energy, this is incredibly challenging for me.
I have an effective work day of about four hours.
That's when my brain is all switched on.
Let's bring this into brain fog instead.
I need to rest middle afternoons.
The heartburn is at the esophagus.
Essentially, it happened for seeing wrong chemicals about 10 years ago.
It causes a cough.
When I talk, psoriasis, my strength, strength is an issue.
You just say general fitness.
Look unhealthy.
Ah, yes, definitely high blood pressure.
It's all right.
Cholesterol, maybe.
I'm about to have a check on on that.
Diabetes, I'm pre-diabetic.
Rectal, not prostate health.
This is PSA is getting that checked in a moment.
PSA is elevated vision.
So yes, I've always had some vision problems,
but they've been getting worse over the last four or five years.
So we just note that down as something that's happened.
Osteo, not that I think of mental health, lots of them.
Sleep issues.
Yes, sleep apnea.
This is the one on a CPAP machine, which is a lifesaver really.
I think this is where a lot of the brain fog
and other sorts of issues came from was the sleep.
Declining testosterone.
Oh, maybe this, maybe this is the issue, including fatigue.
They're changes.
I don't know.
I know, in fact, I'm not going to put it down because I don't know.
Weight gain, definitely.
Let's just put that as weight gain.
Looking unhealthy, visceral fat.
Lots of that.
Cognitive decline, nutritional deficiency.
So that's worse than I thought.
Let's just pop that over here.
Health.
Let's put in a goal.
Yeah, OK, so what is the goal of the challenge?
I want to get healthy.
Improved cognitive function, more energy.
Mental health improvement, so depression
and since I'm going to record this challenge,
I do want to monetize it.
So monetize the challenge.
We'll put in monetization here.
Let's also have an action plan.
It is 2023, July 21.
Let's start on the first July two, oh, two, three.
On that date, I move into a new condo, move into a new condo.
I need to find butchers,
moving directly into South Brisbane, find suppliers.
I know of one out at Nanda.
There's also one in West End.
Market in Brisbane.
On Saturday, I know it's on Saturday.
Brisbane Projects Market.
Rockley, that's it.
So I need to go check out Rockley.
Let's find out where that is.
Rockley, zoom out.
So I have no idea.
So Bunny was Rockley.
Where am I?
I'm in Nanda and I will be moving into South Brisbane here.
And Rockley was down here somewhere.
Rockley Markets.
That's the screenshot.
And throw it into.
OK, next thing to talk about is monetization.
But before we do that, we need to get into storytelling.
Because if I'm going to do this,
storytelling is going to be important as well.
Build our stories.
Look, it is so affiliates, for sure.
Now, the obvious one to me is the meat suppliers that I use.
Meat suppliers, if they sell online.
Now, this generally would probably just be a local affiliate
sort of concept.
So I'm going to have to find them for each state in Australia, I guess.
The other big thing for me is probably to do recipes.
So I don't want to do that until after the challenge.
This is my mindset or point of view from this is that I don't want
to worry too much about monetization during the 90 day challenge.
All I want to do is do it.
So I have no knowledge of whether I'm even going to complete it.
Do I have the discipline?
Is it healthy for me?
I don't really know.
That's a good question.
Health implications.
Where were we?
So recipes.
It would be nice to have some sort of recipe guide for carnivores
that I create and maybe market it on Etsy or my Shopify store.
So just a little bit of income for the project.
Who are my partners?
I have a partner.
I'm going to go with Jim and Jim is a friend of mine who gives a lot
of emotional support.
She is a good video editor.
She does more storytelling video editing.
This project is obviously for my health benefits, but from a monetization point
of view, this is a shared monetization strategy.
Let's just for now put question marks about affiliate.
We got recipes and what else could we look at?
Monetizing kitchen equipment might be a yes for one if I'm using that
sort of stuff, maybe stuff on Amazon.
Now the storytelling, certain routines that I follow all the time.
Luckily, I'm living near the river, I guess.
As I ride near the river in the morning, there should be great scenes
that I can use for B-roll.
For my physical health, I plan to do swimming every day and to also
go dancing three or four nights a week.
What I can probably do from a B-roll point of view with swimming, have a
little bit of time lapse photography, I think.
Jen will give me more guidance and direction on what she wants to see here.
Different shot angles.
So we better spring in equipment.
What equipment am I going to need?
I'm going to need a gimbal.
I am going to need a tripod.
I have one of those.
Most of my other equipment is in Thailand at the moment.
So I might need to buy some new stuff.
Don't need lighting, not for this particular project, I don't think.
Dancing.
So I'll just throw in the main dance styles that I'm likely to be doing
over the next few months.
I guess I'll be doing bachata, salsa.
And definitely end a little bit of West Coast tweet.
Now, the reason they become important is that they're not all
going to add much to my health stuff.
They'll all help my mental health, I guess.
Little health and vitality.
So because Zimba is slow, it doesn't really give much fitness.
But Zucchata, salsa and West Coast swing, especially salsa, will
give me a lot of cardio sort of workout.
Now, I haven't got strength training in here and partly it's
because I just hate it.
I like that Dan and I can't currently do yoga because I have
a upper high tool, hernia.
An action plan.
I've got to reinstate my private health insurance here in Australia.
Cooking.
Let's put in cooking.
Let's put in loaning.
So this is a big thing that's going to happen over the next 90 days.
I'm going to learn a whole lot about the carnivore diet.
Let's just go to YouTube for a second.
Carnivore diet.
Had Joe Rogan talking about it with Jordan Peterson.
Then we got this guy called Dr. Ken Berry.
He says to be the big proponent on this, but there's another doctor.
I don't know whether it's Dr. Gundry.
This guy is, he's just been growing over the last few months.
He had some sort of lifestyle channel on his farm or something like that.
And then, well, seven days ago, 85, so it's just over 90 days.
He's been recording his progress and podcasting with different people.
Grown a pretty big following in this area now.
I don't know how big his following was before he started, but this is partly
the inspiration for doing this is that not only are people getting healthy,
but it's a good way to build your brand and your profile and stuff like that.
Here's another important person for me to follow.
Dr. Berg.
I've been watching this girl a fair bit.
She's, how does it hurt?
Yeah, I think it's her and there's another one.
They're being great to listen to.
They've got some diet plans or recipes, I should say.
So I should look into that as well.
Uh, that looks like Michaela.
So yeah, that's Michaela Peterson.
So Jordan Peace Peterson's daughter and it was listening to Jordan Peterson
and Michaela who were doing it not for white reasons, but because of auto
immune disorders.
And I just think as I get older and having had a shocking seven years of depression
and darkness and letting myself go physically.
I've created a whole lot of internal problems that I'm trying to reverse.
Learnings, learn about me, die, learn about health, observe, observations.
So one of the things that I'm about to do to get blood work done.
So observations and measurements is important.
Cooking, we need recipes.
I'm a lazy cook, so this is going to be painful for me.
Okay, I think I've got enough information to move on.
So this is my pre-plan for the carnival 90 challenge.
One more thing that just occurred to me.
I need a domain name slash channel name.
Let's go to the content.
We'll call it content marketing.
I throw that.
Where am I going to promote this?
So the main place is YouTube.
I think I'm going to use shorts stories, which is a new concept that I just found
out about and long form probably only a few times.
So the long form will be the end of the 90 day and the 90 day challenge.
Stories should be daily from my point of view.
Maybe they're, I don't know, whether it's shorts or whether the horizontal videos
that they could happen, depends on how long they are.
If they go over a minute, you can't really do it as a short.
So then it becomes a short horizontal.
This is where I'll rely on Jin to do video editing.
Before and after.
Cheese for after.
I have to take some shameful photos of my body.
I need a name for different milestones.
So one of the milestones or at least weekly goals.
I'll call fat fuck Friday to YouTube.
I'll probably have to call it that fork.
It's a funny movie from years ago that used that rather than fuck.
And why what I want to do is look at my body shape, composition, whatever you want to call it.
On a weekly basis.
And see the progress.
So I need a channel name or a domain name.
I like carnivore 90 or carny 90.
I'm not sure if they're available and we'd better use chat sheet PT to come up with a variety of names.
The good thing is we've got this really good second brain
in the form of all this information.
So if we just copy it, jump into Visual Studio, paste it all in.
We've got a hierarchical concept here.
So let's go back to chat sheet PT.
I am starting a project for a new video channel on YouTube, which I think I would like to call carnivore 90.
And essentially, it is a 90 day challenge on the carnivore diet to see what happens to my health and document the journey, comma, here is the information I have collected in a mind map.
Can you just read it and say, yeah, do nothing else?
Perfect.
I just had a big coughing fit and a little bit of flame in my throat.
So if we just go back to my issues, we're adding flame.
Go over to chat sheet PT and say, I need a domain name or a YouTube channel name for this project.
Can you give me 10 that you think might work?
A couple of those look good.
Let's just pop in here.
Meet and transform 90.
No carnivore journey 90 90 days of meat.
I like that carnivore revival 90 meat powered 90 carnivore challenge journey 90 day meat makeover.
Not bad carnivore life 90 90 days.
Let's get rid of the dot com.
Command shift L select more, copy all that out, paste it in, split it into topics.
Let's find a bulk domain.
Can I stop?
Of course not domain name.
Check out.
This is the one we want.
This one I've used before.
Copy.
Go with that one.
Search domain names.
So six domain names are available carnivore life 90 90 day meat makeover.
We've got 90 days of meat and we've got carnivore 90.
I think of all of those.
I only like carnivore 90.
Let's see what was unavailable.
So the domain name I really want carnivore 90 is already taken platforms.
Definitely YouTube.
Red, which is a Chinese social media platform that Jin will help me utilize.
I'm assuming Instagram.
Don't know yet.
And reels.
So short list is that, but we can also do carnivore 90.com that.
So when available, we have a good handle for social media channels.
And the fallback would be at carnivore 90, which is also going to be a great domain name.
So that's my action plan.
I get enough information to get started in about a week's time on this diet.
The main goal is to get healthy.
But I'll document this on various social media channels and a website as I go.