Hello, how are you doing?
I'm good.
Come on in.
Welcome to my home and welcome to the studio that's taking up half my living room.
So I've just moved to Brisbane from Thailand and I've brought some of my YouTube equipment
that I use for Abbey Dave and it's all set up and it's ready to go.
This is my lounge area, it's actually where I sit and use chat GPT from my phone whenever
I'm writing code.
I'd like to actually sit in comfort.
Let's have a look at some of my YouTube studio that I've set up in the last week.
So when I came from Thailand, all I've brought with me is this little Mac 2 mini, got a little
hard drive going on and all the cabling.
If we look underneath, you'll see down below there's this stream deck pedal and this is
what I'm using to record all my videos.
The other stuff that I bring with me when I move overseas back and forward, just these
little mini key lights.
So recently I had to buy some additional equipment for this set up.
So the monitor has been staying in Australia with a friend and last time I had a YouTube
studio, I actually built this wooden structure to hang all my cameras off.
Probably with that was it took me a couple of weeks to do and it was fairly expensive.
I've just recently bought this newer frame and it's working out perfect.
You can see at the top that it's got places where I can hang the key light minis and if
we rotate that around, these are on remote controller run them from the phone.
And across it, I've got a couple of racks where I'm sitting the speakers and we'll come
into this little bit of metal because this is part of a new feature that I'm going to
be building soon.
And across the front, I've got my camera and it's actually that piece of metal that we
were just looking at is going to be a new platform for this.
But generally when I'm doing my YouTubeing, I'm sitting down in front of this big camera
and if we just pull over the Ecamm Live, which is my tool of choice and I've got this little
stream deck that I use and essentially what I can do is I can look at individual windows
on this 50 inch monitor.
So we'll just press the GPT window and now here I am down in the corner.
Now this time around, and I haven't used the Dino video yet, so I have the Ecamm Live set
up and we're currently looking at the chat GPT window and one of the other things that
I'll often do is maybe go over to a web view or a code view or sometimes a combination
of different views.
But one of the other things that I've just recently put in is my friend Jim and so hi
Jim, thank you for recording.
I've also set up another camera giving me a different angle and I've yet to use it
in any of the scenes, but we'll see how that works.
And the other thing that I've brought from Thailand is this HyperX microphone, it's a
Cartoid podcast microphone.
I love it.
And recently I bought this eight dollar piece of wood.
So what I've recently bought this week is this little microphone scan.
I got it from Yilanze and it's proven to be good.
When I first got it, I thought I was going to attach it to the table, but I didn't realise
that the angle that this goes up and down wasn't going to be big enough.
So I've now mounted it to this piece of wood.
Now, originally, I also used the stand that this comes on and I sat it on the wood, but
the problem I was having was that I wasn't quite close enough to the microphone.
So now I can bring it in nice and close and it sounds quite good.
The other thing I bought last week was what's called a cheese grate rail.
Bought it so that I can currently hang the camera.
It's sitting on this ball joint and we've also got this clamp at the top.
Now at the beginning of the week when I recorded a video, I actually hung my camera upside
down off this and it works okay, but I was having problems with different software needing
to rotate the camera right here.
And we can just see that rotation in Ecamm Live.
I can change it for different angles.
So when I had the camera upside down, this would be the rotation I have, but now that
it's up the right way, I can go back to the normal looking field.
This then goes into what we're looking at at the back.
Currently I've just got a couple of staged items being a tripod.
I've got my little gimbal here and I've got this little tripod as well.
The gimbal is something I'm using out in the field for a little bit of morning recordings
and I'm yet to do much with that, but that's coming along soon.
I've also got this teleprompter which has not proven to be all that useful to me.
It's actually a bit of a challenge to set up every time I need it and as you can see
when you look at my current camera, it would cover too much of my screen, which is also
my existing problem.
Now, I do want to talk about this little piece of metal that I've just recently bought
for about $5 from the local hardware store and what I'm going to do is bend it at two
different locations so that I can create this Z sort of shape and the bottom of the Z is
where I'm going to mount my camera and the top of the Z is where I'm going to mount
it to this ball joint here.
And what that will allow me to do is be able to move this up and down like this.
The camera will have multiple degrees of movement, but the other thing is that I'll be able to
lift my camera up and give more visibility to my screen because one of the problems that
I'm having right now with this screen is that the camera takes up so much real estate that
I have to stick my head around to the left or the right to have a look what's behind
it.
So this will be next week.
So that's my in progress YouTube studio and I say it's in progress because while I was
recording this came in, it's got a small ring, people just open it up.
And what this is going to do is be another optional way of mounting the camera.
So what I should be able to do is take this clamp and put it onto the pole and then lock
this into position with my camera just the way I need it.
The other thing that will come into the YouTube studio in the next day or so is the
green screen.
Now I'm going to build it, it'll be a DIY sort of job.
You can see some of the challenges that I'm trying to solve with my YouTube setup.
If you've got any comments on how I should improve the YouTube setup, I'd love to hear
your ideas.
Anyway, I'm Appy Dave, I'll see you in the next video.