Cool news alert! OpenAI's moderation tool.
Gets an upgrade! Hey there, young techies! OpenAI has some awesome news for you!
On August 25th, 2023, we're giving a boost to our OpenAI moderation API.
What's that, you ask? Well, it's a tool that helps check and sort out
messages and texts on the internet. This new version will be even better
and smarter than before. The best part? If you're using it, you don't have to do
anything. It'll upgrade all by itself. But if you like things the way they are,
there's another version called Stable that won't change.
Stay tuned because we'll keep making it cooler and smarter in the future.
Thanks for being awesome with us. Your pals at OpenAI.