Okay, this video is to showcase how you can automate video creation of things like
these tables. And it comes because this table showed up on the AI-TLDR channel.
you can see the little animation of tools appearing. It's very much based off a social
media graphic that you see all the time, the top 10 XYZs,
and they all show up. And you notice that there's a little bit of image misalignment
going on, and it's because of the nature of how these slides were created in Canva.
So what happened was at different times, slides were duplicated, more information
was happening, and somewhere it shifted a little bit to the left. We can also see
some misalignment in these two bars. So this is actually quite time consuming to
do in Canva. And it's not the prettiest. It's pretty good. It's is like it is Canva.
You can do some pretty good stuff, but what if we could take that to a much greater
level? And that's what I wanna show with Remotion.
So here we have Remotion. It looks like a video editor, a timeline video editor,
and it looks like that 'cause it is. But what makes it very different to any video
editor you've ever seen is that it's a programming language based video editor. So
everything that we see here is just little micro applications that have been,
built. And they've got things like color controls that we can do and we can play
around with different settings. We could change the text, which I've already done
once and we'll just change that.
Hello from David. So this little hello world application,
came with the Remotion studio, but I built a bunch of other graphics. So I think
the first one we're gonna look at is the top 10 reveal. So if we come back over to
the video that we're seeing here from AI-TLDR, this is a top 10 AI tools,
reveal where we've got categories down the left and we've got AI tools down the right.
So what I ended up doing
was going into ChatGPT and describing different,
micro apps that I wanted to create. One of them is
the O one top 10 reveal.
And we can see the,
requirements docs here.
We can change information, stuff like that. And through a little bit of extra prompt
magic, I went in and turned it into a complex structure for video animations within
this Remotion Hello world. And so let's go and actually have a look at
the top 10 AI reveal tools for 2025. And we've got number four, number five, number
six. And these are all coming through in red. That is actually changeable. If we
wanted, we can go with that, but we'll leave it at red because number one, two, and
three are all now about to pop in. And the good thing about this animation is I could
go and click the render button down in the bottom right and turn this into a video.
Now that's one sort of animation, but I saw another variation of a animation online
that I thought I wanted to do for myself. So what I did is I just went over to my
GitHub username. It's got some 88,
code repositories in this.
I wanna see this information in an animation. Now, as I was building it, I did misalign
the names a little bit.
so we are going to see this in the tweet type on is where we're going to see the
GitHub repository. So here it's coming through. Let's just change the size of it
so it's a little bit more readable and we'll get rid of the property grid over on
the right. And what we are now seeing is an animation around my guitar programming
repository. We can put my name in there, the name of the repository. We've got the
pinned repositories all just typing across as we go and we can see the contributions.
And all of this was done in a one shot prompt. So then let's look at the next one
I did, which was really a tweet like what happens if we, and that's
when we click on this particular thing, we've got an animated Twitter post. So we
see AppyDave AppyDave just shipped a new feature, sometimes the smallest optimizations.
And we've got all this information coming through. Now all the data is all configurable,
as you can see over here on the right in the property grid. And all of it was generated
in one shot prompt based on
a little prompt structure that I put together for Remotion.
Now for the last one, I wanted to,
look into an idea that I've had on my channel a
year and a half ago, and it was animated YouTube outros. Now it doesn't look like
what I want, but most of the information is there. So what we're seeing at the moment
is the sort of thing that I kind of say at the end of a YouTube video. Usually I
say,
I'll do a little bit of a recap. I'll talk about what the next video is. I'll ask
for a like and subscribe.
I'll
maybe suggest people,
comment down below and tell 'em what's coming up next. So here it is AppyDave, we've
got the number of subscribers. Here are three videos that you might find interesting.
Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video. And then the next video
can pop up like this and that could be what it is. And I could also tell people about
the chapter codes. So all of this animation, again, was a one shot prompt.
and it built it all. Now it's just a case of tweaking it to make it look pretty.
So this is using prompt engineering, Claude code and promotion to generate any sort
of animation that you want, where you're doing infographics and information like
that.