I have a script that I can say in 60 seconds and it took me about three or four hours to
write.
I did it for a competition and I've just found out that I need to say it in about 30 seconds.
So what I want to do is see if I can create a prompt that will maintain the value of this
script but cut it in half.
Here's the idea, can you take an awesome script, cut it in half, keep it awesome.
I've already created a video and here's the transcript from it.
Now the main things that are in here that are making it go a bit longer is that I'm
talking about this 555 manifesto both at the end and at the beginning.
I also talk about the journey of five different YouTube channels that I've worked on and
the problem is I probably go into a little bit too much depth on each of them.
The idea is could we get ChatGPT to rewrite this script for me in about 30 seconds, currently
it takes 60 seconds.
To get started let's paste in a little prompt that I've just prepared.
I need to take this 60 second script, get five variations, I want to test them all by listening
to them using AI voices but I want each of them to be 25 seconds or less.
This part of the prompt is essentially setting up the goal of what we're trying to achieve
but there's one thing that's missing because if I run this prompt on its own it won't take
into account what I think is the important and I've already stated that the 555 manifesto
is not actually important.
So I'm going to write another prompt and we say before you proceed can you make sure
to ask questions about what is important.
We might even add to that.
Just added this section here, keep asking me questions about what is important until
I say write script.
So I need it to interrogate me, have a look at the script and then come back with a set
of questions, I'll answer them and when I'm ready then I'll ask it to write the script.
Now we can just check it all, it looks all good, let's hit go and see what we come up
with.
Now I like what it's come up here, it's talked about having five different questions that
it needs to ask me, what are the key milestones, are there any specific channels to highlight
which is not the case, I don't have any, they're all important.
How essential is it to include details about followers, speed of monetization, it's important
but I can get rid of it if that makes sense.
Do you have a preference for mentioning certain achievements?
Not really, it is the essence of 555 manifesto important, not at all because that I can do
in a different video.
There is one thing that I also need to add to this is that it's done for a competition
by video ranking academy, it's a course that I'm part of and I'm trying to create this
30 second video to submit to that course.
I better try and include something like that.
Let's see what we can add as answer to these questions.
Now looking at the questions, what I've done is written five different answers and we'll
go through them.
The first one which is about milestones or key points and I guess the main thing is because
it's a competition for video ranking academy which is where I learnt a lot of my skills
would be good if it could be highlighted somewhere.
Then the next thing is that all five of the channels are important.
I think maybe they're not but I believe they are so I'd like to list them.
The main thing is I've separated them out into three tech channels, one channel that
is just a personal challenge for me and then the last channel which is my podcasting where
I actually create most of my content to disseminate to the other channels.
Then number three, how essential is it to include followers of the speed of monetization?
It's not really that important from this sort of video point of view but number four it
would be nice if I could highlight the one channel and the one video that just blew my
mind because I was able to capture a trend.
I used concepts like trend jacking and clickbait keywords and unique concepts, unique content
points of view to monetize a channel really quickly.
So I think it's important that it tries to capture that detail but we'll see.
Lastly the 555 manifesto which is really a future project is not really needed within
this so let's just press enter and see what we get.
GPT has written five different variations for me.
One of the things I asked it though was to wait until I said to write script so sometimes
it doesn't follow the instructions but let's have a look through the five variations.
Normally what I like to do is get the computer to read them to me either using 11 labs or
a re-voicer or one of the other text-to-speech tools that I have.
What we'll do today is I'll just read through them all because most of them are off a little
bit on what I need and I don't yet have what I consider a final script.
Variation 1 through Video Ranking Academy I mastered the art of content full stop.
That sentence just feels dead, it just dies really quickly.
It then talks about the five channels 3 being tech, 1 being a personal project with my heart
truly lying with Abby Cast.
That last statement feels a little bit wrong to me, it's not the way I would want to say
it.
I will want to change this if I go with it.
The idea of gaining 2,000 followers in a week is just a highlight, it's an all right statement.
The problem is it doesn't relate to the channel where it happened which is Appy Dave so we
may need to play around with that.
Let's have a look at Variation 2.
A Variation 2 feels a lot better from SkillsHound at Video Ranking Academy I diversified into
five unique channels, Flow Video, Winning Prompts and Appy Dave, catering to tech.
Well Carnivore 90 is my health diary but Appy Cast is where my story is truly unfold.
So that whole sentences, that feels pretty good to me.
This last statement did I mention 2,000 followers in a week, a little bit of context there might
be important.
Let's move on to Variation 3.
Now I've just read through number 3 and it's okay but it has a lot of similarities to Variation
1 from my point of view and I can almost say no straight away.
Let's look at Variation 4.
This one has a starting structure that's similar to 2 and probably okay for me to go with.
Thanks to Video Ranking Academy I ventured into five channels, Flow Video, Winning Prompts
and Appy Dave for Tech, Carnivore 90 for Health and my dearest Appy Cast podcast.
I don't really like that last statement.
The rest of it didn't really make any sense to me that the context is a bit vague.
Let's look at Variation 5.
This one starts off really good.
My journey began at Video Ranking Academy leading to five dynamic channels, Apply Video,
Winning Prompts, Appy Dave for Tech, Enthusiasts.
Carnivore 90 as a health diary.
It may be a little incorrect.
My journey didn't begin at Video Ranking Academy.
They've been a major player during my time creating videos.
The intimate conversations at Appy Cast, that's also incorrect in that what I'm doing right now
is more of behind the scenes.
This is where I figure out how to make Tech do what I need it to do, where I get AI to do what I need it to do.
To call it intimate conversations is off the ball.
But I do the last statement.
Being monetised in nine days was a cherry on top.
OK, so that to me might be a better statement than the 2000 followers in a week.
There was also that idea of getting 4000 watch hours and I did it really quickly.
And so far I've been a one hit wonder.
I haven't been able to achieve that since.
But I learned a lot going through that particular process.
So it'd be good to highlight that having read through this.
So I have a prompt here that I've filled in.
I basically like variation to and I like variation for the section about Appy Cast.
I've got a preference.
So I basically say when talking about Appy Cast, I prefer a statement similar to.
And then the last thing is from an achievements point of view, these two statements.
But I only want one.
I don't want both.
So I think we can finish this off with.
Can you make five scripts using these new criteria for guidance?
And we'll hit go and see what it comes up with.
That GPT started writing some pretty good scripts.
But I did restart it again and I'll just show you why.
And one of the things that you can do at any time is restart a conversation by clicking
on this little button here.
And we'll look at the second one.
Essentially, I wanted it to note that the achievement was with Appy Dave.
It started writing new variations again.
And in particular, I really like variation to now you can read all of them if you want to.
But essentially, variation to it's kind of the sweet point for me.
Thanks to video ranking and Academy.
I've entered into five channels, fly video, winning prompts and that day for tech, carnivore
90 for health and learning with Dave at Epicast.
Oh, and a quick brag.
Appy Dave was monetized in just nine days.
To me, this feels the way I would say things.
And I'd be happy to go with this as a testimonial video.
The only thing that might have been a little bit nicer is if I included dive into behind
the scenes trials and errors at Epicast, though, as I say it, it doesn't really roll off my
tongue.
I think I've got a winner with variation to and this is the script that I'm going to
submit for a little competition.
See how I go.
Personal note, I've been a member of Video Ranking Academy for over two years and I didn't
actually get started until November last year.
But if it's something you want to follow up on, then I've left a link in the description.
It's an affiliate link.
On the other hand, if what you want to do is learn techniques around chat GPT or automating
your YouTube influence, then check out one of the videos that I have up here in the corner.