Two days ago, OpenAI released Swarm. Now what it is is an educational framework for
developers, and it's about building multi-agent workflows. What we're going to do
today is we're going to come up to the code and click on clone and bring it down
to the computer. After that, we'll look through some of the documentation, see how
it works, look at it a little bit of code. And finally we're going to go through
the examples. So they've got a bunch of examples available inside the code base.
And we'll test them out on the system I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe. Let's
get into it.
The Swarm project is focusing on execution and coordination, and it has two different
concepts within it. One is called agents and the other is handoffs. And with agents,
what we're looking at are instructions and tools with the handoffs. If we go over
to the document related to this, there's a cookbook orchestrating agents routines
and handoffs.
it's defined as an agent that hands off processing to another agent.
Now, the Swarm project is essentially an area to explore patterns the patterns for
lightweight, scalable, and highly customizable design. This is not a replacement
for Crew AI or other sorts of frameworks like that as yet, and it's more about educating
developers on how they can work with large language models in a workflow and step
oriented system.
to get started let's come to the top here. We're going to click on code. And in this
case I'm going to use GitHub CLI.
I've just created a folder called test. And we're going to paste in gh repo clone
OpenAI / Swarm and let it come down.
Now the repository with the examples are on the computer. But what we'll do is we'll
come here and we'll click on the install command.
coming back to the terminal, we'll just paste in that command and make sure it's
installed.
Now I've opened up the repository here in VSCode and we should check out a few things.
if we open up the Swarm directory, you'll see that there's a little bit of code going
on in the system, and we'll check some of that out later if needed. There's examples
and we're definitely going to be working through here. But it's the assets will start
with. So if we go and look at the Swarm diagram you can see what's the weather in
New York.
that's being sent to a triage assistant. And its job is to go, well what is the question
coming in and hand it off to the correct agent. In this case it's the weather assistant
and it says it's 67 degrees in New York. Now, if we come back and look at the examples,
there's already a weather agent system that we can go and look at. If we look at
the Readme file, it says, this example is a weather agent demonstrating function
calling with a single agent. So very similar to what we just saw
Now getting started. When you look at this file, there's the import of the agent
from Swarm. And then there's two functions going on. And we can see that these functions
are being put into an array on the functions property of the agent. And we'll look
a bit later as to how this is actually running. But let's have a look at some of
the documentation related. So I've put together this image that shows that it's initiating
the weather agent. And then it's delegating to the get weather request. And some
input parameters need to come through to that. The location and the time from that.
It should be able to retrieve the weather data. Now this is mock data that comes
through in the system. But this is where you would put call to an API. And then after
that it's returned the weather information. And it can then do other tasks such as
sending an email. And if you provide the correct email details, the goal would be
that it sends an email.
Now further into the documentation. What the main starting point is, is an agent
and it just has a system prompt or an instruction called you are a helpful agent.
And the only other thing it knows about is that it's got two functions that it can
delegate responsibility to the get weather and the send email. So when we look at
those functions, we'll see that the get weather is get the current weather in a given
location. Location must be a city. And that's listed. And there's also a time. And
this by at the moment when we look at the functions will default to. Now the goal
of this is to return some sort of JSON structure that has the information we need.
There's also an additional function going on called Send email. With that it takes
a recipient subject and body and we'll see how well that works.
So let's work out how we're going to run this. So it's pretty simple. It says here
Python three run py. Now what is that. So we're currently looking at code from the
agents py. There's also this run py and it's taking the weather agent that we've
just defined right here and putting it through to something called run demo loop.
So what is that? So if we come down to the Swarm area we have this file called repl.py.
And within that we've got the ability to process and print the streaming responses.
We can do pretty messages, but the main loop that's going on is sitting here. So
the incoming agent in this case weather agent would come in through here and it would
get passed in
to the client, run in the agent variable. And the agent variable is just being loaded
there.
So I've got the code open, but we've come into terminal and what we'll do is we'll
CD into the examples web agent folder. From there we should be able to do the Python
three run.pi and see what we get.
the first thing it's saying is who is the user? And I say I might just say hi, I'm
AppyDave and we'll see what it comes up with. Hello AppyDave, how can I assist you
today? What is the temperature?
You can't spell I think in Sydney and we'll see what it comes up with. So it's calling
a function called Get Weather and it says the current temperature in Sydney is 65°F.
Now when we look at the code we can see that that's hard coded into the system.
So if you want this to return a real value, you would go and change this line so
that it's calling some sort of API to get the current weather for the location and
time. But let's move on to the next one. So this is sending an email to a recipient.
there's three parameters going on. Who is it two subject and body. Let's see how
this works.
Now we're back at the terminal and I'm going to say,
can you send email to David at AppyDave.com and see what it comes up with.
it said could you please provide the subject and body of the email.
subject.
is hot today
it's come back with this message. The email has been sent to david@appydave.com with
the subject what is hot and the body Agent Workflow Builder is hot today.
Agent Workflow Builder is a software application that I'm building in public at the
moment. So I'm demonstrating the code as it goes. And it's basically around designing
agent workflows like the ones we're working with right now.
with the weather agent complete, let's close that down and we'll move on to the triage
agent. Now, if we go and look at the readme file first, we can see this is an example
of a Swarm with a triage agent takes user inputs. It can respond directly, or it
can triage and send to other agents like the sales and refund. It says that we can
run it from the command line using Python three run. If we look at that, we'll see
that it's using that same run demo loop example we saw earlier. If we go into the
code, we'll see that we've got a couple of handoff functions. We've got three different
agents going on some more handoff functions.
let's have a look at that documentation here. We've got this example of the Swarm
containing triage agent will take inputs from the user and decide what to do, including
sending it to the sales and refunds. So we can see the triage agent going on here.
It understands what the request type is, and we'll send it to one of these two agents.
Now from this point, the agents have their own logic that they can do. They can proceed
with doing a sale, they can apply discounts or do refunds. So there's a bunch of
things going on in here. Now, if we look at it from this documentation point of view,
there's the main agent. And the instructions are determine which agent is best suited
to handle the user's request and transfer the conversation. And who can it transfer
to a handoff function called transfer to sales and one called transfer to refunds.
So after that, you can see there's a few functions going on here, and some of them
return messages like this a message indicating success of the refund, and another
one message indicating that the discount was applied, but some of the others will
just send information back to a different agent. So this one just comes back to itself.
Or we can send it off to the sales agent or the refunds agent.
So when we look at the sales agent, it's got a main system instruction called be
super enthusiastic about selling bees. Now, if it can't handle the question coming
in, it's only job is to go back to the triage agent a bit further on. We've got the
refunds agent, and the main instruction for the refund agent is help the user with
a refund. If the reason was too expensive, offer the user a refund code. If they
insist, then process the refund.
we've got two different hand-off functions going on processing and applying discounts
and otherwise. Let's go back to the triage with this one as well.
let's go and have a look at a bit of code. We've got a couple of functions going
on here. We'll come back to them in a moment because the next area is there are three
agents being defined. Now. The first agent with a name and instructions is going
to control the whole process. From that it has a sales agent
we can work with. And one of the things that the refunds agent can do is delegate
responsibility to handoffs. So we've got the process refund and the apply discount.
we can see that information going on here. Now if we come back to the sales agent
and we go be super enthusiastic about selling bees, and I think that might be the
first thing that we can just play around with and change before we run the agent.
what we'll do is change bees to where selling Agent Workflow Builder. This is the
application that I'm building in public around designing these sorts of workflows.
Now the next thing we've got is help the users with a refund. If the reason is that
it's too expensive, offer the user a refund code. Well, why don't we change that
to a discount code
we'll call it AWB Early Access. After that, we've got a couple more hand off functions
that we can call, and they're being linked up to the triage agent right here.
Now, after that, we've got a final set of handoff functions. So if we think of the
first two handoff functions as being used by the refunds agent here, then what these
ones offer is the transfer back to triage is available to both the sales and the
refund agent,
Whereas the triage agent can send things to either the sales or the refunds agent.
So I've just come down to terminal. We're in Swarm
I think I'm just going to paste in Agent Workflow Builder see what it comes up with.
It says it looks like you're interested in building a workflow for agents. That's
exactly true.
I might just say can I get a discount.
That would be great. So it's thinking at the moment it says, could you please let
me know the reason you're looking for a discount? I can offer you a discount code
of AWB Early Access. That sounds good.
I want the AWB early access. Can you apply it?
I've successfully applied the discount using the code AWB Early Access. It's added
to your cart, saving you $100. So let's see if we can buy it.
I would like to buy AWB.
B and it says great choice to purchase of Agent Workflow Builder you can proceed
to the cart with the discount already applied by it. I wonder whether this is actually
going to work.
So it says it looks like you're ready to make a purchase. I'll transfer you back
to our triage agent, so we'll assume it's done. What I'll say is, I have bought.
When will you ship?
it's just come back with four inquiries related to shipping and order delivery. Let
me transfer you to our sales consultant. So I think we'll go and do a bit of a loop
if we keep doing this. But that's the triage. And we've had multiple agents working
together. We've been able to go back to the master agent. We've been able to go back
to the triage agent.
we've been able to go from the refund agent to the sales agent. And this is a pretty
interesting workflow.
So let's go back to the code and see what we just went through. We came in using
the triage agent, and from that I asked for a discount. So that took us over to the
discount agent that I've put here.
we saw both of these function handoffs called. So we've got the process discount
the applied discount. And you can see it said discounting item because and it had
some sort of reason. And then it said applying a discount and said applied $100 to
your cart. Now at that point I also had a couple of issues getting back to the sales
agent. And when I came back and looked at the code, it made complete sense why it
happened.
the reason for that is that the discount agent currently has three areas that can
go to. It can process a discount. It can apply a discount. The only other area it
can do down here is go back to triage. So the next step would have been to go back
to the operator the triage. And from there move on to the sales. So all up this is
an incredible little workflow and really quite simple.
So we've finished the weather bot. That was fairly simple. We've moved on and done
the triage, sales and refund bot. That's a little bit more complex. Let's see what's
next. So if we minimize this file
and we go over to the support bot, we can see that there's a fair bit more going
on. There's a requirements.txt going on. We've got a Docker container. Looks like
we've got a bunch of articles in the form of JSON documents.
Now, what I want to do is see if I can get this up and running. So we've got the
user interface agent and the help center agent, and there's a bunch of things that
we've got to do. I've already run the make install.
So let's just get Docker Composer up. We'll start that it's running.
So we come over to prep data. We've got some imports. We've got an embedding model.
We're querying through articles. That's the JSON documents. And we're running an
embeddings against them. So we're getting the vector data from this and storing it
into a different client. And what else have we got going on here. If the collection
exists delete it. Otherwise create the collection and then upsert the data. Let's
see if this works. So I ran this a couple of times and I got a few errors. But one
of the things I tried was just trying to hit the collections here. I believe the
data is in, so let's just see if I can get this working.
So we'll come over to our documentation and we've got this new concept called the
Support Bot. This is an example of a customer service bot which includes a user interface
agent and a help center agent. So they're represented here. Help center agent can
query documents, submit a ticket, send an email, and transfer to the help center
agent, which is itself, I'm assuming. So there must be other subagents going on here.
And then we've got the support agent also querying, submitting tickets and sending
an email. So the idea of the support agent is to handle interactions with the user,
called for general support. Issues that aren't handled by other agents, can query
the documentation, submit a ticket, and send an email. If we move on down to the
help center agent we've got. This deals with questions about OpenAI agents such as
GPT models, Dall-E, and whisper, so we'll ask questions of that later. So let's give
it a whirl.
So I think we'll use it before looking at the code. This time I'm just going to say
I'm David and see what it comes up with. Could you please provide more context or
specify a query related to David? Well, I would like to know the time in Chiang Mai,
Thailand, which is currently where I'm living. So Chiang Mai, Thailand.
And hopefully that uses a general sort of bot the local time in Chiang Mai, Thailand
is currently
seven hours ahead of Coordinated Universal Time or UTC. Please check your local time
to add time differences. Well that's great.
can I ask questions about ChatGPT or OpenAI
It should have documents related to
how do I write a prompt for Dall-E three.
It says creating a prompt for Dall-E three. The AI model designed to generate images
from text descriptions involves clear and descriptive help. So we've got be specific
clear language include style and medium, etc.. Okay, how do I make an API call to
the completions API for chat?
And we've had a whole lot of information come through.
Set up your environment pip install requests, obtain an API call, write your API
calls. Now what are we working with? We're working with the user interface agent
in this case. So I'm not sure whether a second agent has come into play. I reckon
we should have a look at the code now.
So I've come over to the main.py file here we've got query the vector store. We've
got query docs. And then we've got a couple of handoff functions send emails, submit
ticket and transfer to the help center. Then the user interface agent, which was
where I was at. So that wasn't doing anything to communicate with the database from
what I can tell. And if we look at the help center agent, which is where we need
to be, this is where we can query docs, submit a ticket, or send an email.
maybe let's try and get to the help center agent.
We're back at our chat client, so we'll say transfer me to the help center. I don't
know whether I need the word agent. I probably shouldn't need it. And let's see if
that changes. So now we're on a help center agent. Seems that a transfer function
is not available at the current stage. However, I can assist you with issues directly.
Can I submit a ticket around
errors
with vector store, which was what I was dealing with earlier? So the main thing I'm
trying to do is see whether the submission ticket system works. It says your ticket
regarding errors has been successfully entered. Can I search for articles
on open AI?
we will go with the voice API, see what it says. Searching for knowledge, retrieving
so it looks like it worked. If we just grab this searching knowledge base for query
and we do a search in here, we can see it popping up OpenAI voice API and it's come
up with some information. Let's just go back to main agent, see what happens.
We're still with the help center agent. Let's go back to user interface agent. See
if we can go back that far.
And we can't. That's okay. And exit won't do anything I don't believe.
Have a great day. It gives us a message. So that's pretty cool.
So I did have a couple of configuration issues with the support bot, but did get
it up and running. Things like the personal shopper and customer service I didn't
use. But let's have a look at basic. And we've got these little scripts that you
can run. We'll just move a couple of them into focus so you can see what's going
on. And the last one is called function calling. I believe we can run them all one
at a time.
So looking at these individually, they're just simple scripts. We've got the agent
handoff where we've got English and Spanish. And one of the things going on is there's
a transfer to Spanish being called by the English agent. So if we come down here
and type in agent Handoff and run it, let's see what we get that's coming through.
Hola. I don't know how to say Spanish.
Let's move on to the next one. So we've got bare minimum. So let's go Python and
we'll type in bare minimum. And what have we got here. How can I assist you today.
So that's really all it's saying.
we can see that the function calling is just an agent. That's helpful. And it will
delegate responsibility to a function. And the function will just return some JSON
data.
if we run that
the weather in New York is currently 67°F. Fahrenheit. This is great. Let's just
move into this last one called Context variables.
So we've got this context variables here. And there's two key value pairs. So let's
change one of them. We'll go name is AppyDave and user ID is 555. And what happens
is we've got this instructions coming through. And instructions now is not a string.
Instead it's a function. And it's taking in the context variables. So we can grab
the user which should be AppyDave you are a helpful agent, greet the user by name.
It should be AppyDave. And if I'm understanding this correctly, we're just going
to run two different responses sequentially. So the first one should be a greeting.
The next one should be the account details. So let's hit save on that. We'll come
over to here and we'll run the context variables script.
Hello AppyDave. How can I assist you today? Account details. AppyDave 555.
So that's OpenAI lightweight multi-agent framework called Swarm. It's experimental
at the moment, 4900 stars. Actually, let's just refresh that. It's already gone to
5100 stars since I started recording this about two hours ago. So the next video
I'm going to do is hooking up my Agent Workflow Builder into Swarm so that I can
automate the stuff that I usually do manually. So this is a workflow that I'll use
very soon. To publish this video, we'll work through the script, we'll work through
the thumbnails, stuff like that.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.