This is the fifth video on using Aider I a pair programmer for programmers. And what
we're going to do in this video is host it within a web server so that we can call
it from other tools. So please like and subscribe if you want to see other videos
in the series. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Now I'm just over at the AppyDave repo, and earlier in this series we built the presentation
tool using Aider. We've also gone and documented the game doom by id software using
a bulk file system and Aider. What we're going to do today is look at the Aider web
server, and I haven't done anything right now, so we're just going to grab this,
come down to a terminal and just start off with a clean repository from which to
build this application.
lastly, we'll just type in Aider and get it up and running ready to go. It's looking
to add some environment setup and the chat conversation history. And so now what
I want to do is just put together a prompt that might help us build this particular
application.
So whenever I'm building an application from scratch, I like to build a relatively
detailed requirements document. And the way I would do that here is I'd come down
and select canvas mode, which we've seen here, and I'll paste in information and
have a conversation. And by the end of this conversation we end up with this requirements
document.
Now the requirements document for the Aider web API is that it should interact with
the Aider scripting tool using Python.
we wanna run it as a local web server. I do wanna run it from more than one directory
at the same time. 'cause theoretically I should be able to
write code against two different projects if I like from an external tool.
Now I've designed a little bit of flexibility into the requirements document on how
that should happen. So would we run the application from two different repos, just
with different port numbers? That's one option. The other option is can we change
the directory inside of the application? Now, I'm not sure how effective that'll
be with environments and stuff like that, so I've given myself leeway to go in either
direction. But the primary idea is that we have a code assistant endpoint and it
takes an instruction. Now, if we go and look at the documentation from ada, you can
see that that's generally how this works. You give it a message and you can optionally
give it some file names. So what I've also said is that files are available, and
after that we've got the directory, which will test whether this is going to work
or whether we should be running multiple web servers. And then there's options. Now,
I grabbed the options out of this document and I've just pasted it in. Now they also
give an example of how to use it in Python, but they've been clear to say that it's
not officially supported
Now I've mentioned that we're using flask to build the web server and it's given
a little bit of information around how to deal with the,
directory changing. At the bottom we've got some use cases and it's talking about
a couple of trade offs about whether one or multiple web services is the way to go.
And I've given it a really simple testing plan. So what I think we can do now is
just go and copy this document and we'll put it in data and see what it generates.
So I've come down to the terminal and what I'll do is just paste in all the information.
Now, I haven't pressed enter just yet because what I think we should do is just pop
on over to Visual Studio on this directory and just have a look at what we get to
start off with. So the first thing we've got is just an input history. We've got
the chat history that we've started and that's before I've pressed enter. So this
ability to press enter and see this come through, should come into this area. The
chat history, which is everything going on, should also happen. There's also this
cased database going on.
I think we should just press enter and see what starts to happen. Well, we've just
seen firstly that the Aider chat history has been updated. If we look at the input
history, we see that going
So I accidentally said yes to reading this URL, which is for an application that
hasn't been built yet, so it doesn't make any sense. But then what it's done is come
up with a plan of action for from the requirements document. So it feels like it
needs a web server. It needs an endpoint for the code assistant. We've got the requirements
asking would I like to proceed. So I've just said can you create it.
So we've got the code being created as per the instructions. So we've got the web
server coming in. We've got the endpoint. It'll be code Assistant. After that we've
got an init. We've just comment for now. Then we've got the code assistant under
the API directory. And we've got some instructions. It's changing directories if
that's provided. And then it looks like the code that we used or found in the documentation
online. We might need to confirm that we've got some information here about options.
After that we've got the requirements document for Python installation. So it's looking
at installing it and getting it running on a particular port. And at the end we've
got a list of everything that it's implemented. So this is great. And we've got the
curl requests that we can test it with. So where are we at now. It looks like we
can now try to start creating these files because they haven't been created just
yet.
Now it's got this question. Would you like me to proceed with creating the files?
So I think we'll bring up Visual Studio so we can see this and we'll press. Yes.
And I've done something wrong there. We'll press yes again and yes, yes, yes. So
we've got four files that have been created. We'll execute on this Python install.
And it says it's running now it's running within the Aider environment. We might
want to start this in a separate process.
Now before we start the web server, let's have a look at what we've got here. So
we've got the code, assistant endpoint, it's marshaling any incoming parameters and
delegating responsibility to the code assistant. Now we can see the code assistant
over here. We've got some comments. We've got a directory that we can change to.
We're using the model
probably don't want to say GPT four
turbo by default. So we will check on that.
It's got a list of file names. Now, when I was looking through the documentation,
I noticed that there was both the file names that could be changed and also the file
names that could be marked as read only. So it might be useful to have parameters
for that in the future. But let's head over to the terminal and we'll just kick off
the server for now. And so we've got a server running and if we create another terminal,
we should be able to do a curl request and we'll try the one that just says create
a script and see what comes through on this.
And this is looking good. It's hit the server.
It's not doing anything. So let's say create a script called
Hello World,
say
Hi from AppyDave and we'll press enter on that.
Now this is where we'll probably find some challenges using this particular technique
and it might be the reason why they haven't exposed it this way. So in a previous
test, it asks the question in the server, which meant you had to go from the terminal,
you would do in the curl request, sign over to the terminal and press yes. Now it's
not actually doing it at all. So what I'm going to do is try and get it to do it
through a prompt. So we'll say please add Hello world, do PI or press yes and we've
got something going on here
and that didn't do anything. So we'll try another one and we'll be quite explicit
and we'll go back to the previous instruction that says, create a script called hello_world.py
Say Hi from a Dave and let's see what happens in that particular case. Now it's writing
it and this is where you can see that it's actually
giving the question in the terminal. Now these ability to say yes to files is apparently
a parameter you can use from the Bash command line.
haven't tried it in the library, but we'll see what we can do with that later on.
But let's see if we get something created
and it looks like it's created something. Let's head over to VS. Code and we've got
our script hi from AppyDave. So I had to be quite explicit to get this to work. So
the interactivity that we get from the terminal is not currently available in the
version that we've done using web services, but we are onto a good start. We'll see
what we can do with this over a few more iterations.
So what I'd like to do now is test it against a different repo. So we'll just start
a new terminal and we'll go down to the dev directory and we'll go into the doom
with docs. Now doom with docs is from the previous video where I documented the game
by id software using Aider. Now we'll just have a let's see what's in there and maybe
just open it up in VS code. So you can see all this documentation that was built
against all the C files. They're all listed here. And this was done in a batch operation.
But it might be useful to figure out what
and make it a parameter in our curl request and see if it works here.
Now. I haven't started from a new clean repo. I've used the one on my computer, which
already has chat history, which we can see here and here around what I last did with
Aider. So what we might do is go down to the bottom of each of the files and just
see whether the changes we make will happen here. Now, the other thing I've done
is just modified that prompt that we were looking at, create a script called hello_world.py,
let's say doom from AppyDave. And I've just put in the directory and we've got it
running here. Let's test it out in the terminal.
Now we're ready to go. We've got Aider web server running in the folder where it
actually is, and that would be where it would normally send requests to. But we're
going to give the directory option, so we'll paste it in. We've got the same question
as before. Create a file called Hello world.py. But say doom from AppyDave. And the
only other thing we've done is change the directory. So now it's hitting the web
server and something is happening. It's saying yes or no. We'll say yes. With that
it's applied a file and look at that. It's actually done it in our new system doom
from AppyDave. So this is a second repo that we've communicated from using the same
web server.
So let's go over where we're at and what could be done next. So we've got the Aider
web server up here. We've got the description, and I've just added in the actual
requirements that I used to build this application. Now, luckily for us, this was
pretty much a one shot prompt. I didn't really need to change anything to make it
work the way we've seen it so far. So why don't we just go into a web view of this
and see the code as it currently
So we've got the hello world that we did against the Aider web server. We've got
the actual web server going on here. We've tested it with an instruction. We've also
tested it with a directory. So if we go and have a look at how that code was actually
implemented, we can see that all it's really doing is changing to the directory to
execute the Aider scripts. From that point of view, we have not tested file names
coming in, and we actually haven't tested any of these options. The other thing we
haven't tested as yet is whether it can be run as two separate web servers. Now It
should work okay, but at least one of the use cases of just changing to a different
folder and targeting that is working.
Now, if you want the code, you can obviously go and download the repo here. If, on
the other hand, you want to recreate it from scratch, it's pretty simple because
we did it all as a one shot prompt, and I've given you all the information here.
Something that you might want to change is you might not want to use flask as the
framework, or there might be other options that you want to add into this system
and build it all yourself from scratch.
So that's the fifth video in our Aider series, and there is a link to the playlist
in the description. But in the next video, what I thought I'd do is create a domain
specific language to make it really easy to call this tool just from little text
files in my IDE. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the
next video.