So here we have our robot with the intro and the outro. And if we go to the top,
we've got our clock with the fast moving hands. We've got YouTube variations of it
as well.
Now we just finished the set up for the titles, the thumbnail elements, the text
that goes onto them. The next thing that I have to do when publishing a video is
getting the YouTube description. And one of the things I'm going to need are the
keywords. Now we have a bunch of keywords that we found during the content analysis
phase. We've also got the title that we're using and the abridgement.
Now I've got to
that prompt and we can see here a struggling to create smooth intros and outros in
your YouTube videos. So we have this basic sort of description. Now how does that
fit with a regular YouTube description? If we look at one of the videos I've already
done in the past, you can see there's many areas of the YouTube description, including
keywords, affiliate links, branding, social media. But the section we just generated
would be this area here. It's the basic idea of what the video is meant to be about.
Let's move on and build the rest of this.
So we'll come back to the description, take a copy of it, and we'll move on to the
writing of the description, where we've got a whole lot of extra information that
I just talked about. We'll just paste in the simple YouTube description you can see
above. We've got the chapters and all that and make a copy of what we've got here,
and I'll just paste it into ChatGPT. You can also use anthropic if you want, and
it'll start generating a more detailed YouTube description.
Now I have uploaded this video yet so I can't put it into YouTube. But what you can
see over here on the left is the original text and we got it visualized on the right.
And this first area is something to look at, mainly because this is the stuff that
goes above the fold. And what that means is that when someone's looking at a video
but they haven't opened up the description, everything above the fold should be the
highest
priority. So one of the things that I've done here is had a link to an opt in for
one of my products, or sometimes I'll use the buy me a coffee link.
And then when they expand the description, there might be another high level opt
in that you want to have. Plus, the rest of the information comes down in the appropriate
order.
Now this is an evolving system. So there's other steps here that I'm not currently
using like the pinned comments, but they'll come over time. But let's move into the
last phase. And the last phase is how are you going to share the YouTube video? Are
you going to share it with LinkedIn? Are you going to write a medium article or maybe
a tweet? Now the ones I do generally at the moment are tweets and LinkedIn articles.
So we'll just go straight in and have a look at them.
we're in the social media post phase, and we can see for creating a tweet that I
need the title of the video. We've got some keywords that can be used and basically
a summary which is a bit smaller than the transcript or the abridgement, and we'll
paste in a link. Now I haven't uploaded the video, so this is just one of my other
videos for now, and we'll move through to the LinkedIn post.
information here is exactly the same, though I like to use the abridgement because
it's more detailed than the summary.
we have five tweets that are being created. We've got the information that's related
to the video keywords. And then we've got the link at the bottom. You can pick one
of the ones you want or rewrite them as you see fit. As we scroll down, you'll also
see that there's a LinkedIn post being generated and it'll be way more detailed.
It's not based on the summary, it's based on the abridgment.
it'll have the video at the end.
the way they can look is that we've got different tweets that we've been able to
put out in the past, and if we go over to the LinkedIn posts, you can see a bunch
of LinkedIn posts that I get a lot of engagement from. And this is I find a great
way to send traffic back to the YouTube channel.
So there you have my extensive launch sequence. This is everything I do to get a
video released and up onto YouTube and published. This takes about 30 steps, and
in the past I used to take 3 to 5 weeks to get a video out. I'm now down to about
1 or 2 videos a week, and it's GPT workflows like this that help me.
if you're interested in the Agent Workflow Builder, there's a link in the description.
It's software that I'm building and will make available soon.
I'm AppyDave. I do videos generally on GPT Prompt Engineering and this agent workflow
tool that I'm building. Please like and subscribe or click on the Buy Me a Coffee
link. That's one of the ways that funds this particular channel and the content that
I'm creating. Anyway, I'll see you in the next video.