In this video, I wanna share my 30 step formula to launching a YouTube video. A few
months ago, I passed 1000 subscribers and I did that producing a video once every
three to five weeks. In the last two weeks, I've released five videos, and part of
that is due to this launch formula.
Now, if you like me, you probably thought the hardest part of creating a YouTube
video is recording and doing the editing.
I find that to be the easiest part of the process for me. The hardest part is everything
that goes after I've done my initial recording and post-production. So I've gotta
take a video like the one that we've got here and send it to a video editor. I've
just started getting a video editor involved, but that means I've gotta write up
a brief or record all the information to let that person know what I need to do Along
the way, I've gotta create b-roll, so you'll see a lot of b-roll in the intro, what
you're watching right now of my video, a lot in the outro. Some will be in calls
to action. Next thing I've gotta do is figure out a compelling title, a thumbnail,
the design I want for the thumbnail, the text that I'm going to put on the thumbnail.
After that, I've gotta do a whole lot of post-analysis on the transcript. I need
to work out what keywords, the chapters that need to go into the YouTube description.
Is there any sort of branding or affiliate information I wanna put in? I often like
to share my videos on Twitter or LinkedIn, so how do I write the LinkedIn post? How
do I write the tweet or any other social media post for that matter?
I'm also often trying to do an analysis of the text for things like what was the
topic, what might be the search terms, and if my video editor produces a YouTube
short for me, I've gotta go through the same process again. I've gotta come up with
a title. I've gotta come up with a YouTube description.
As a YouTuber that talks about prompt engineering and AI agents, you can imagine
that I'm using these sort of technologies to automate my own problems. And the software
I have is called Agent Workflow Builder. It's in development at the moment, but you
can find a link in the description if you want to have early access to it. Otherwise,
like and subscribe and let's get into it.
So let's have a look at the video. We're going to launch and we're here in a product
called Gling. It's a pretty good video editing software that allows you to edit videos
using just text.
as we look through it, we've got areas of the screen that I've recorded using E Cam
live, another product that IU,
love to use. But if we go up to the intro, there's no graphics. It's just me in my
living room at the moment.
And this is an area that we are going to need to get some b-roll and put it behind.
you would've noticed that I'm using a green screen for the intro so that I can make
the b-roll look more effective than I've done in the past.
let's have a look at the files that are involved. So we're currently in the Launch
optimizer, which is the video I'm recording right now, but we'll move up to the agent
workflow intro/outro. And this was an ability to improve my intros and improve my
outros based on the previous and the next videos. And when I recorded it, we have
this video here. We have a whole lot of recordings that I'd done and put through
that Gling video editor that we're talking about. There's also the idea of assets,
which we're going to create as part of this particular process. And if we just open
up the video, we can see
that I have this nine minute video. We've got the areas that I'm gonna need to get
the video editor to add B roll. And then when we get into the video, he's going to
have to do a whole lot of transitions and sound
Now the most useful file in this particular workflow is the SRT file. What that is
is the subtext file. It's got all the words that I said, the time that I said them,
and the sequence that they happened in.
that's going to be uploaded into the YouTube as the,
lower thirds. But we are also got a copy of it as just raw text, and we're going
to take a copy of that. 'cause I'm going to run every process of this one transcript.
So here's the workflow we're going to operate. It's the YouTube launch optimizer.
It's based on a bunch of sections. There are currently 31 steps, and this keeps growing.
So we'll work through the video preparation, building the chapters for the video,
any B roll suggestions that we need in the intro, outro or elsewhere. We've got content
analysis, like what's the theme, the keywords, the title and the thumbnail will work
through. And then we're looking at the metadata, which is mostly the information
that goes into the YouTube description. And lastly, we'll create a couple of social
media posts. And what we can do is go straight into configuration, and I'm just going
to go down to where the transcript is and I'm going to paste all that information
in.
Now I've come through and filled in a few other pieces of information. I already
know a bunch of calls to action and information about my brand, but what I'd like
to do is fill in the short title.
So I have a prompt here that'll use the transcript.
if we look at what it's produced, we can see a bunch of short titles I could go with.
And I looked through this. And for me, I think the creating effective intros and
outros is the best way to go. So I'm just going to add it into the workflow.
Next I want to get a summary of the transcript and I often use that for tweets and
other areas. So what I've done is created one. We are just going to copy it, I've
read through it, it's quite accurate, and we can just come back, move on to the next
step and we'll just paste it in.
after that we'll try and create an abridgement, which is a similar sort of document,
but with a little bit more depth to it and not a loss of facts. So the information
that's coming through right now,
we'll run the validation. I don't always do that 'cause I tend to trust what comes
through. I like to observe it because one of the things that does bring up is that
there might not be as much information in the in bridgement as in the transcript,
and I can check it just to make sure there's nothing missing.
So I'm glad I looked through this. Usually I don't have to worry about what's in
here, but of the 10 items that are listed, three of them probably should be added
into the abridgement. They'll make a lot of sense when I do the LinkedIn post, which
usually uses the abridgement to figure out what to write. And it's things like number
six, the reverse engineering of the Vid IQ strategy is probably an important thing
to talk about. But other things like anecdotes and observations, they don't really
make much sense in an in bridgement 'cause I don't really need 'em in the sort of
documents and social content that I create. So we're just going to run this little
prompt here and just make sure these additional pieces of information go into the
abridgement.
So I've just taken a copy of that information and I'm just going to update
My next step is to separate the intro and the outro from the transcript, and I've
got a few different usages for it. The main one is the B-roll, but in the future
I'd like to do an analysis of them to see whether they can be improved. So what I've
got is a copy of this prompt just running through, and we've pulled out the intro
here and we've pulled out the outro.
just gonna
and make sure it's in the outro section,
we're looking at the video in Gling and we're seeing the intro that it's extracted
and we can see that they're the same. Hi, you are creating videos for YouTube. It's
the same as what we got in Gling. And this goes all the way through to what would
happen if I had a script pre-prepared. And we can see that there. And when I read
this intro, this is clearly the same information. The problem I've got is that I
need to get B-roll for everywhere from this section that we're seeing. But I also
need it for this section
linguistically it's not the intro. So chat, GPT got the right information for me,
but personally I'm gonna want this extra information as well. So I've just asked
Chat GPT to add it
we'll come over to the workflow. We'll put in the introduction
what we've done now is we've completed the video preparation area, we've configured,
got the summary abridgement, we've checked the quality of it, separated the intro
and the outro. And the last thing is I like to save an outcome notes so that I've
got all this information recorded.
the next section in my workflow is finding and developing the chapters. And this
is not an area that's working too well for me just yet, but I'm going to show you
what I've got. So firstly, I wanna find the chapters. So if we go over to the GPT
that I've just run, we can see that we've got chapter
examples. These are headings that we could go with and the words that were said at
each point.
I will use this as a baseline and I definitely take a copy of it, but at the moment
I'm still looking through my video trying to find the chapters I've worked through
the idea of using the SRT file as a way of figuring out timings and coming up with
better terminology where it comes up with the times and simple names for chapters,
but it doesn't work too well. I've also used all the tools out there, and so far
I haven't found something that I like to use, but this is a problem that I'll solve
over time, or I'll find a third party tool.
I'm just in my outcomes document. This is the information that chat GPT came up with
for me. And what I did was I watched the video on double time. It's a nine minute
video, and this took me about 15 to 20 minutes to do. So it's a bit of an arduous
task just for chapters, but it's one of the things that I think from a quality point
of view is really important to get right in your YouTube description. So I've broken
it down into intros and outros, the struggle that's mapping to this. And as I was
going through, I was often using the headings for inspiration, but then rewriting
'em based on what I saw. So we'll take a copy of that
I'm just gonna paste it into the chapters
I wanna generate a bunch of B-roll for the intro and outro and other areas.
I'm going to do that in Leonardo ai. And so we're in this section at the moment called
the B-Roll Suggestions. We'll do the intro outro B-roll. We're also going to create
a brief for the video editor so that he knows what to do. And we're also gonna think
about design style and transcript design ideas.
So I've just come over to A GPT, which is in the middle of creating intros and outro
graphics. But let's go to the top of it. We've got concepts. So the first idea is
in the intro, we've got struggling. We've creating intros and outros for YouTube
videos. That's something I talk about in the video. Increased video production quality
after hiring an editor.
this was just a statement that I made, and it might be useful to have that as b-roll
in the background. And it's just developing different ideas that are visually appealing
for all the sentences in the intro and the outro.
After the intro outro concepts that we've got here, we start seeing the prompts and
they're going to match. So number one, which is struggling with creating intros and
outros for YouTube videos are going to fit with one A and one b. I tend to create
two prompts for each area, and we've got a frustrated content creator struggling
with video editing, specifically focusing on intro and outro segments. And then we've
got another one here, illustration of a YouTube creator puzzled by the intros and
outros of videos. And that just repeats for all six concepts in the intro. And in
this case, there were six concepts in the outro. And we can use this over in Midjourney,
or I like to use Leonardo ai.
Now we're over in the personal feed of Leonardo ai and I've generated about 96 images
through here for both the intro and the outro.
So if we look at these images here, we've got a YouTube creator with a mixture of
anxiety. And what I've done is I've come over to my computer and I've downloaded
and renamed every image, and we can see those particular images we were just talking
about
Now, as I was doing this, this took me about 10 or 15 minutes just to rename the
files. So when I got to the outro,
I decided to automate that.
yesterday I took an hour and a half out to create a video.
In the middle of recording this video, I realized just how long it took me to rename
the files, and I thought, I'll show you a little automation. And what I did was I
went straight to chat, GPT, voice mode. It's a new feature that came in chat, GPT.
I just had a conversation with it about how I could automate that and it wrote the
script for me in about 10 minutes. And then when I got all these files here, I didn't
have to come through and manually rename them, and that was taking me 10 to 15 minutes
to do that alone.
the next step I have is letting my video editor know what instructions I want. So
I have these basic general instructions that I want worked on. We've got the intro
and outro ideas, and then I just pass in the special instructions chapters and the
intro outro ideas. And here's an example of what we got. We've got video editing
brief for intros and outros. We got stuff around the intro outro, the chapter breakdown
so they know where to look at
particularly for transitions and maybe some b-roll graphics, extra special instructions,
and CTA,
because one of the things I've found in the past is that I want the calls to action
to look a little bit more impressive than other areas of the system. And it's about
notifying the video editor of that requirement.
Okay,
coming back to the B-roll images, you might have noticed that there's no design consistency
going on. Everything looks pretty good individually, but
as a collective in a video, it's not that great. So can we fix that? And that's what
the next step is about. This is design style list. So with this particular prompt,
we're trying to figure out if there's a look and feel that I want in the video.
So coming over to chat GPT, we've got 10 different styles. They're all based off
the transcript that we just wrote and included. And the one that might look good
could be the workflow mind map.
We come and have a look at the next step, and this is about taking one of those ideas
and any other special instructions and taking the original set of prompts, and let's
make 'em more the same style.
here I've said I want to use workflow, my map style, but every time you do it, I
need the words agent workflow builder, in quotes. Now I'm just saying that because
that's what this software is, it's agent workflow builder.
if you're looking at a way of automating any standard operating procedure in this
particular case, it's a YouTube launch sequence. Then maybe check out the link in
the description below.
Now heading over to GPT, we can see that list of files have come through. The fourth
item in this CSV file is the prompt, and one of the things that you'll notice is
that the word agent workflow builder is built into all of these.
So I've just taken three prompts from that list and let's just look at a couple of
them. So here we've got the word agent workflow builder. Not very legible, but it's
there. In this particular version, we've got more agent workflow builder as part
of a sign, which is interesting. Here. It becomes very clear, and I'm actually loving
these ones, so much so that I might end up downloading them and using in the video
because they're very professional. Now, we still haven't quite got the style right
between them all because I didn't put a lot of effort into that. But let's have a
look at what you could do.
Now to see a good example of this image, consistency in action. You can see a video
I released yesterday on my other channel, AI-TLDR This channel is about AI technology,
but it's done creating by using AI technology to create it, and the clue is to do
less, or clueless is a little coding language that I'm creating to allow me to create
videos really quickly. If you wanna find out more about that, check out the link
in the description, or if you just wanna see a great example of consistent storyboards,
come out and check this video on AI-TLDR.
Now what I wanna do is get content analysis out of the transcript. We've got the
essence, the audience engagement, and the call to action plus competitors.
if we look at the first one, we're going to identify the main topic and theme, and
we've got three other points that we look into.
I repeat that for the audience engagement and the cost action and competitors. And
if we go and have a look at things, we've got a main topic, so it's figured that
out. This is an important piece of information I use to steer different articles
and tweets and that that I create. We've got keywords that could be useful in the
YouTube description. There could be important statistics. You might wanna communicate
this to your video editor so that they highlight it during the video creation. Same
thing with the key takeaway.
I have a section here on the audience engagement. We've got emotional triggers, overall
tone, style, audience insights. So far, I haven't used this a whole lot, and you
can see because I'm very dry in my delivery, there's a lot in here that I could take
into future videos, but if we go down the bottom, we've got all the calls to action
and maybe search terms that you can use around this topic.
We've now moved into the next phase, which is creating the thumbnails, the text that
goes in the thumbnail and the title of the video. So what we'll do is I'm going to
start off with just a short idea for a title that I came up right at the beginning
of this session, and I'm just going to throw in the main topic as described in the
last content analysis phase. Now, in the past, I've used something as simple as this,
and some keywords, I just take it a little bit further. Sometimes I'll also use the
transcript or the transcript summary, but I find just knowing the topic theme
Here we've got some content highlights. We'll just paste them in
and we'll just run the prompt related to that. And we're getting a bunch of YouTube
titles coming through. Now, I can usually work something a little bit manual from
this. I don't always go exactly what's here. Sometimes I'll run it again, but I find
this a pretty effective way of getting my first draft of a YouTube title.
Next, I wanna get the text that goes on our thumbnail. Now if you look at the thumbnails
I currently do, you'll see that there's different areas of text and there's also
a title that they're related to.
I try to do is something
contrary, the words on the thumbnail just need to be a little bit different to the
words on the title. You don't need to say the same thing twice.
we've got a prompt here that we'll take the title that we're going to go with. I've
decided on automate intros and outros for better continuity between videos.
I've also listed all the others because there's probably good wording in here that
we can do a contrary point of view on.
we've also got the theme and the content highlights available.
we've had five engaging thumbnail text ideas based on the provided information,
and I'm just going to increase it by another five. The things that I'm looking for
are the parts, the one, two, and three, where there's usually really good words that
can be taken from here and used on the thumb.
Next, I wanna format this information so I can bring it directly into Canva.
take the table that we've got here and rerun it again this time in a CSV format.
And I'll just use the bulk image upload within Canva to see all these text elements.
come over to Canva and I've got a template that I've pre-designed, and I've just
uploaded the CSV file and we can see 'em all listed here. So then when I generate
10 designs, what we're gonna see is different combinations of text based on different
title ideas and concepts. And I can just click through these and if there's any words
that I want to use, just use it in my
thumbnail template.
At this point, I generate a template just to get started. We've got a few different
designs we can work with, different images of me that I can add to the system, some
examples that I've done in the past. And one of the things that I'll do near the
front is I'll drag any images that we're about to generate
I've trained in some images into the
we can see that the prompt that I used took the title, the content highlights, and
the title ideas. And from there we've generated this extracted information about
the theme, the highlight, the power of automation. But the main thing going on is
that there's an area for different prompts. So we can look at the robotic arm. If
we go further down, we can look at the large clock with the faster moving hand.
So here we have our robot with the intro and the outro, and if we go to the top,
we've got our clock with the fast moving hands, we've got YouTube variations of it
as well.
Now we just finished the setup for the titles, the thumbnail elements, the text that
goes onto 'em. The next thing that I have to do when publishing a video is getting
the YouTube description, and one of the things I'm gonna need are the keywords. Now
we have a bunch of keywords that we found during the content analysis phase. We've
also got the title that we're using and the abridgement.
I've gone and run that prompt and we can see here a struggling to create smooth intros
and outros in your YouTube videos. So we have this basic sort of description. Now,
how does that fit with a regular YouTube description? If we look at one of the videos
I've already done in the past, you can see there's many areas of the YouTube description
including keywords, affiliate links, branding, social media. But the section we just
generated would be this area here. It's the basic idea of what the video is meant
to be about. Let's move on and build the rest of this.
So we'll come back to the description, take a copy of it, and we'll move on to the
writing of the description where we've got a whole lot of extra information that
I just talked about. We'll just paste in the simple YouTube description. You can
see above. We've got the chapters and all that. And make a copy of what we've got
here
and I'll just paste it into chat, GPT. You can also use anthropic if you want, and
it'll start generating a more detailed YouTube description.
Now, I haven't uploaded this video yet, so I can't put it into YouTube, but what
you can see over here on the left is the original text and we got it visualized on
the right. And this first area is something to look at mainly because this is the
stuff that goes above the fold. And what that means is that when someone's looking
at a video, but they haven't opened up the description,
Everything above the fold should be high priority.
one of the things that I've done here is had a link to an opt-in for one of my e
products. Or sometimes I'll use the buy me a coffee link.
And then when they expand the description, there might be another high level opt-in
that you want to have, plus the rest of the information comes down in the appropriate
order.
this is an evolving system, so there's other steps here that I'm not currently using,
like the pinned comments, but they'll come over time. But let's move into the last
phase. And the last phase is how are you going to share the YouTube video? Are you
gonna share it with LinkedIn? Are you going to write a medium article or maybe a
tweet?
the ones I do generally at the moment are tweets and LinkedIn articles. So we'll
just go straight in and have a look at them.
Now we're in the social media post phase, and we can see for creating a tweet that
I need the title of the video. We've got some keywords that can be used, and basically
a summary, which is a bit smaller than the transcript or the abridgement, and we'll
paste in a link. Now, I haven't uploaded the videos, so this is just one of my other
videos for now, and we'll move through to the LinkedIn post. I don't tend to do a
Facebook post anymore, and the information here is exactly the same, though I like
to use the Abridgement because it's more detailed than the summary.
here we have five tweets that have been created. We've got the information that's
related to the video keywords, and then we've got the link at the bottom. You can
pick one of the ones you want or rewrite A as see fit as we scroll down. You'll also
see that there's a LinkedIn post being generated and it'll be way more detailed.
It's not based on the summary, it's based on the abridgement, and it'll have the
video at the end. And the way they can look is that we've got different tweets that
we've been able to put out in the past, and if we go over to the LinkedIn posts,
you can see a bunch of LinkedIn posts that I get a lot of engagement from. And this
I find a great way to send traffic back to the YouTube channel.
So there you have my extensive launch sequence. This is everything I do to get a
video released and up onto YouTube and published. This takes about 30 steps, and
in the past I used to take three to five weeks to get a video out. I'm now down to
about one or two videos a week, and it's GPT workflows like this that help me. So
if you're interested in the agent workflow builder, there's a link in the description.
It's software that I'm building and we'll make available soon.
I'm AppyDave. I do videos generally on GPT, prompt Engineering and this agent workflow
tool that I'm building. Please like and subscribe or click on the buy me a coffee
link. That's one of the ways that funds this particular channel and the content that
I'm creating. Anyway, I'll see in the next video.