Today we're looking at o1 preview. This is a new model by OpenAI, also known as Strawberry,
and it promises advanced reasoning capability.
I will put it to the test and use it to read, analyze, and enhance documentation
for an AI workflow engine. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
When I opened up chat GPT this morning, I had access to the new model, so I went
straight to perplexity and just asked what's going on with this new model? And it's
come up with this recently introduced oh one preview, a new series of models designed
to enhance reasoning capabilities, particularly for complex tasks like coding, science,
and mathematics.
a key feature is enhanced reasoning, and what we've got here is that in tests model
performed comparably to PHD students. It's working on the idea that with the mathematics
Olympiad, the model achieved 83% success rate compared to the 13% of ChatGPT 4o
is available today for ChatGPT plus and team users, but you can only do 30 messages
a week at the moment if you are using it for development point of view through the
API, there's some missing capabilities such as function calling.
since we're limited by the number of messages and missing capabilities, the use case
today is just to send it a whole lot of notes, documentation, requirement, specs
around an agent, workflow builder that I'm building for myself, and let's just see
what it can do.
let's head over to chat GPT and we'll click on the dropdown. And we now have access
to o1-mini and 01-preview, and I've read up that 01-mini is apart from Being Faster,
should be good for coding related jobs. The one we're gonna work with today is 01-preview,
so we'll just click on it here.
Now to get started, we're going to need some documentation and I've just come over
to a Read Me file for an agent workflow Builder, an application designed to work
with GPT Workflows and different large language models. And there's a bunch of information
in here. There's a schema. If we click on the schema, there's a bunch of table information
I wanna grab the content of those files.
we'll just run this little command. It's going to give us access to the files, and
if I run it again without the tree, we'll get all the code as well.
I'll just come over and I'm gonna put in, read and paste it in. So all the information
in the three files that I've got being requirements schema and sample workflows,
is now ready to go into this chat, GPT window.
Now I've just added a little instruction in front of this documentation. Can you
read the requirements schema and sample workflows, infer what the application is
doing?
let me know what type of people could use this style of application.
let's have a look at what might be missing in the form of topics or sections from
the document.
press enter and we'll see what happens.
at the moment, it started thinking,
understanding, provided context, figuring out requirements. There might actually
be a dropdown here that we can look at different stuff accessing the workflow, understanding
the functionality is going on,
and that thought went for 15 seconds.
this initial review is looking really detailed and quite correct.
we've got the agent workflow builder designed to create, manage, and execute structured
workflows.
And what they look like is, this example is a YouTube launch optimizer workflow with
a bunch of,
sections or phases and a bunch of steps.
so we can see here it's got the workflow definition, it's got attribute management,
which would be going on over here somewhere. We've also got the prompt customization,
and then there's the dynamic execution. So tools like CrewAI and Lang Chain, they're
dynamic execution engines for agents.
this is all part of this particular application.
Now when we moved down to the second section, we got the types of people that could
use a product like this. We've got content creators and marketers, we've got developers,
we've got project managers. One of the things it would've said earlier was that it's
dealing with human in the loop interactions is what makes it different to an automation
framework.
what that meant with, say, the Launch Optimizer is there could be a section for developing
titles for a YouTube video. So there's a bunch of parameters that you can pass in
with prompts, and as you go through the different phases, there's human in the loop
all the way.
if we move down to the next section, which is missing topic sections for more complete
requirements documents, and we've got a lot of information here. We've got the user
interface and mocks. Now you've seen some, so that's something I should be able to
provide as an image, except that this version of the model probably doesn't have
image capabilities at the moment. Then we've got things like the access control,
error handling. We've got many different areas of software development that need
to be developed for the requirements document for this particular application.
this is really quite complete.
this is a pretty solid outcome.
What I'd like to do now is integrate some extra code and examples from an agent as
code application, and let's build it into the main requirements.
So we've come over to our chat window and we'll just paste in a starting prompt.
I'm going to introduce agent as code domain specific language for you to read and
understand the languages designed to quickly create agentic workflows for HITL and
automated generative workflow.
it can be either human in the loop or it can be automations.
Now we're gonna need some code examples. So this is the one I use when I'm designing
new agent workflows. I've also got a quite a big one that I use for YouTube launch
optimization.
I'm just gonna run a little command here to gather some agent as code examples. I've
got four that I wanna work with.
I'll modify it just to get all the code that's related and we can come back over
here and just paste it in.
we've got a whole lot of context in the form of four little scripts, really, that
we'll build agent workflows. And we've got our little prompt and we'll just start
it.
So we get the step by step thinking. So the chain of thought is going on right here.
We can minimize that as we go.
it thought for 18 seconds, I think it's still in the middle of writing information.
the output we've got here is great. We've got understanding agents as code, and it's
talking about it being useful for Human in the loop and automated workflows. It's
broken down the key components. There's a workflow area for settings, like which
large language model would you like to use from the beginning areas for prompts,
attributes, and the sections and the steps.
the way workflows operate is there's a primary goal and then there's just phases
that you work through with a bunch of steps and you're just updating data along the
way. Now there's the idea of saving the information so it can be exported to places
like CrewAI or Lang Chain. Then we've got some examples.
I've done videos on each of these examples in use, so you can see more information
on the channel. But we've got the YouTube launch optimizer. It's worked out the information
that's available there. We've got the YouTube outro booster, which is how I write
scripts to go from one video to another. And then it's got the agent workflow architect.
So it's now related this to the application requirements we did earlier. It's worked
out that this is about handling structured GPT workflows in a programmatic way. So
I don't tend to use user interfaces to design agent frameworks. I like to use coding
constructs, and that's what this is all talking about. It then talks about the implications
for users such as using this to automate the different agentic framework design in
CICD pipelines.
think this conclusion here really hits the nail on the head with this particular
part of the application. By encapsulating workflows and tools, it bridges the gap
between development and business users. 'cause it's designed to be usable by business
users to design workflows without actually having to know detailed programming examples.
Now that we've got some general documentation and agent as code documentation, let's
try testing a bunch of different prompts against this information.
So the 01 model has come up with five different ideas. The first one's being a visual
drag and drop workflow editor. Now, one of the things to notice, you can expand this
to see how it came up with the ideas, and it's working through an analysis and adherence.
We've got generating visual design ideas, the workflow creation, and making human
input easier. So if we move down, the next one it's got is an interactive workflow
dashboard, followed by contextual side panels for human interventions. And there's
two more down here. We've got the comprehensive analytics reporting interface and
a reusable templates and components library. Now we're going to work with a couple
of these. We'll probably
work with the fifth one, reusable templates and component libraries, and the visual
drag and drop workflow editor. But I think it might be useful to compare this to
ChatGPT 4o. So what I've done is I've got the same question going on here, and I've
also fed in a lot of the information that we just used,
plus I've fed in the answers that the oh one preview model gave. So at least the
information's the same. So let's just run it and see what this one comes up with.
Now side by side, we're looking at the oh one preview versus the 4o model, and the
first one is implement an intuitive can versus where users can construct workflows
by dragging and dropping components. Here we've got the interactive workflow canvas
with drag and drop functionality, so headings wise, they seem similar. The way this
is come up, there's a design idea. There's also the HITL relevance down the bottom,
and then a bunch of key features
We've just got more detailed sort of components
There's meant to be an example, but it's not showing up. In this particular case,
unless I dove deeper into this and tried to use them, I wouldn't be able to say which
one is a better technique at the moment.
Here we're matching the third item on the oh one model. We've got contextual side
panels for human intervention versus prompt customization panel with real time preview
and similar. Again, we've got an idea with key features and the human in the loop
relevance. This is a good structure the way this is coming up,
whereas the version over here is also pretty good. It's got a little bit more depth
and detail in the items,
But there's no design idea or human in the loop relevance in these lists, and this
just continues on. So at the moment, I don't have an opinion over one system versus
the other
though, where things do improve a little bit with the o1 is when you get to the bottom
and there's additional design considerations going on
Let's test out getting a design brief for either Figma or Sketch from two of these
examples.
So the prompt we're gonna test is can you write a design brief so a human can prototype
these ideas in Figma or Sketch for?
visual drag and drop workflow editor, and we've got the reusable templates and component
libraries. It's starting to think.
we've got a bunch of ideas of what it's doing, the assistance task with crafting
the design brief, and then I'm working on the design brief for the drag and drop
editor. Then I'm building the structure for the high tour agent. So I love that we
get to see the way it's thinking.
we've got our title and introduction and just the areas that it's going to focus
on. And then we've got a really detailed idea of each visualization. We've got the
objective target audience, key features and functionalities. This is around the visual
drag and drop workflow editor.
And then we've got different visual design elements being listed down below.
After that, we've got the user experience guidelines, the technical considerations,
then we've got the deliverables like a high fidelity graphic en figma and the style
guide, swatches,
And then we've got the expected deliverables.
for the second design idea, we've got pretty much the same thing. We've got reusable
templates and component libraries. We've got the objective target audience and the
key features and functionality
followed by the user interface experience guidelines, and a user flow example. There's
still the technical considerations and deliverable after that. It's provided the
general sort of feedback. We've got the branding and visual guidelines, accessibility
and prototype requirements.
There's also a timeline and milestones. So the conclusion here is this design brief
outlines the essential features and design considerations for prototyping the visual
drag and drop workflow editor and the reusable template components library. The prototype
should focus on delivering an intuitive and efficient user experience demonstrating
how users can create and manage complex workflows with ease.
Head over to the 4o model where I've given it the same starting information. I've
just asked it to read it and wait for my next question, and we'll just paste in the
same prompt that we used on the oh one preview and we'll see if we get similar sorts
of information coming through.
the first thing you notice is that we don't know how it's coming up with the ideas.
We don't get to see its thinking process.
At the moment, we're looking at the design brief headline. From the left hand side
is the o1-preview, and the right hand side is the 4o They're different, but there's
also a lot of similarity between them. Minor differences is that we've got design
brief Fortor agent workflow, web application builder, whereas over here it says
the product we're building, plus the two design ideas that are going on. Those two
design ideas are also broken down in this section here.
On the left, we've got an objective and a target audience. Whereas on the right we've
just got a list of design goal.
When we get to the key features and functionality, you can start to see a clear difference.
There's a fair bit more information across multiple components going on. I think
there's about seven of them.
From the key features and functionality, you see a lot more depth. With the new model,
we've got six items going on in here versus the four that are in the older model.
Then we move on to the interactions to prototype drag and drop behaviors, zoom and
panning customization panel,
on first glance is really similar but different. It's, it's not one is stronger than
the other.
but the o1-preview is also going a bit further to talk about the technical considerations
and the deliverables.
The second design for the reusable templates and component libraries has similar
pattern. We've got more detail on the left than we do on the right, but as to which
one's better, I'm not going in deep enough to actually understand that particular
answer.
But when we do get to the conclusion of the 4o document, there's only a little bit
of information being shown versus a much greater deal of detail, and we've got the
conclusion down the bottom.
For the next prompt, I'm going to test them side by side and it's a multi-part prompt.
We're going to use the visual drag and drop workflow edited design from above with
both models.
we're going to select a diagram type to represent data or event flows.
what I wanted to do is explain why it picks a particular diagram type. So I want
it to come up
diagram. And then lastly, I want it to visualize it in an ASCI representation.
we'll kick off the 4o
and we are straight into writing some information with 4o while we're still examining
and working through details.
it's come up with a diagram type of flowchart, node based diagram, why chose it,
clarity and sim simplicity, node based design alignment.
we've got this diagram showing up here on the right
and we can see an explanation of what's going on. Now the other one is firing away
on the left here.
the chain of thought going on is quite extensive. And then we get to the diagram
type selected is a data flow diagram (DFD) and it gives a reason for that. I chose
the DFD to represent the data flows for the agent workflow builder. Because it's
data-centric focus, it can deal with hierarchies and it's easy to represent in asci,
which is the main format that you can do with chat GPT
for 4o. We've also got a bunch of reasons that when I look through 'em, I quite rational
and I dare say, a very nice visualization when I compare it to the source document.
So it's taken the source document being the YouTube launch optimizer and we've got
the configured workflow load, the prompt script, summary script, debridement, and
these sorts of concepts. So going on right here you can see as it goes down to new
areas. So here we've got the analyze content essence. That's this area here listed.
So this is a good diagram
and it's given a good explanation over here on the right.
We got
create tweet, Facebook post, and LinkedIn and that sort of stuff is going on here.
So I've just had a look through this context diagram and the other DFD diagrams.
This is really powerful. Where it's different is that we've just got a visualization
of data based on one of the agent as code workflows that I've designed in the past.
But when we look through here, we've got various levels of data flow diagrams. The
first one being the context diagram, where we've got the user
who works with workflow definitions, does inputs, reviews the information that leads
onto the agent workflow builder, where we're defining workflows, executing 'em, we're
interacting with the large language models, and then we are managing the persistence
and the retrieval of data stores. There's this next area prompts and data exchanges
with the large language models and what ones are we using, are they from open AI
or anthropic, et cetera. This goes into a little bit more detail as we move on. We've
got a detailed data flow where we can look at it individually, so the user defines
the workflow and provides some input.
So we can see here that process one is defining and configuring the workflow and
then storing that definition into a data store. Then we move on to process number
two, which is where we might execute a workflow against a large language model. And
to do that, we'd need to retrieve the inputs that the user has entered in. And from
there we can merge the inputs with a particular prompt. There can be insertion values
along the way, and then those prompts are sent to the large language model
the large language model outputs,
which can be presented to the human for review. The human in the loop interaction
is, does it accept it? Do they wanna modify it so they can review that and either
give feedback, give modifications, they could change the data directly. And from
there, we can execute further into the workflow.
Now, that's exactly how I do workflows in my own systems. I'll have these inputs
and prompts,
and with the input, like some content goes here, it would get merged into the prompt
and we can see that listed down the bottom. And as this is executed against a large
language model, the output is going into an output attributes to be reused in future
steps.
considering that the o1-preview has never seen this user interface, it's never seen
the idea of these workflows in action, all it's looked at is a few requirements,
documents, and an agent-as-code structure, it's
accurately represented the data flow diagram. If we move on further, we've got a
detailed explanation of what's going on
and a detailed conclusion to show us how everything fits together.
for the next test, what I wanna do is visualize one of these workflows. I do not
believe I have access to DALE3 within this version of ChatGPT, but I can at least
create some good prompts. I'm hoping that can be turned into images using Leonardo.
I've written a prompt here called, given the following, two design briefs, can you
create a prompt for diffusion models like DALE-3 Midjourney that could create two
prompts for each design.
I've just copied the design brief from Strawberry. We'll past it in, and we'll get
that one going. And while that's happening, we'll run the other version on ChatGPT
4o
I've got four prompts for chat, GPT-4. Looking at 'em on the surface, it's really
difficult to tell which one's going to be better. One of the interesting things though,
is that we can see the design decisions that came up through the chain of thought
prompting here. So it's mapping out design considerations, mapping the tasks. One
of the areas that it talks about is, is it policy compliant? And it does that in
a couple of areas. So we're not going to have a problem with bad,
images coming through because of policy things. One of the thing that's interesting
though is it's giving all these guidelines on how it came up with the visual designs,
but there's nothing in here to state that it's doing prompts that are geared towards
a diffusion model. 'cause the way you do prompting for images is quite a bit different
to the way you do prompting for ChatGPT as an example.
I would've thought there would've been a step involved there.
I generated 32 images because we have two language models, two designs per language
model, and two prompts per design. And when you generate four images for each of
them, you end up with 32 of them. So if we click on a couple, we can start having
a look at some interesting designs that have come through.
I wonder if we can create a little application to showcase all 32 images.
Now I've just put all the images into a folder on my computer and we can see a couple
of them here. And I've also created a little prompt.
And this prompt is not actually little, it's quite complex. So I say we've got two
LLM
that we're testing. We've got GPT oh one preview and GPT-4. I've created two prompts
for two visuals for each large language model. Listed below is a large language model
followed by the design,
name and two prompts for each design. I've also included a file prefix.
Then after that I've said I want you to create a HTML/JavaScript slideshow. Each
slide represents a unique large language model, design, name and prompt content composite
key. And every slide should have the following. So the large language model should
go into a heading one,
the design name into a heading two, the the content. You should use a paragraph.
And we're going to display four images. Now I do want to go a little bit more detailed
than this, but I already, I feel like there's too much in this prompt, so we'll see
what happens. I've also told at my brand colors, so we've got a dark brown, a light
brown, a yellow, and a white. And I've said that there should be the ability to move
slides left and right using the arrow key.
Then I've said, here is the information about the LLM designs prompts and file prefixes.
then I've just listed everything out. Now it's relatively well structured, but it's
also freeform, so there's not a lot of guidance from semantic, meaning in here. We'll
see whether this works. And lastly, I've just said files in the current folder, and
I've listed all of them. So I think from here, we should just be able to copy.
here we have the conversation that we've been working on all along, and we're just
gonna paste all that information in and hope for the best.
So it started thinking it's crafting a HTML/JavaScript slideshow,
We've got
some CSS for the body. Slideshow, container slides. We've got the colors coming through,
using the colors I've suggested.
We've got highlight going on for the on hover.
got a bunch of HTML
It's given us instructions on how to work with this code just to create a file and
copy the information in. It's given us e explanation of the HTML, the styling and
the navigation. There's also a JavaScript,
show slide and active function going on. Where do we have that? It's right here.
I've just gone into my folder and created a file called Slideshow, HTML. We'll just
copy the code, we'll press save on that
and we should be able to right click on it and say Open in live server.
And that has come up and hey, it looks like it's working. Let's make it full screen.
And here we have the slideshow. It's using the brand colors for the highlight. We've
got the light brown as the background, and we can just skip through each of these.
Let's make one little change to it. I would like some buttons that make this all
get bigger so that we can see a more detailed view of the image.
So I'm just updating the prompt a little bit to say that everything works well. Can
you update the user interface so that there are four buttons down the bottom left?
I don't think I need to tell it. To use the highlight colors. It should work. As
you hover over the buttons, a image should just become expanded and larger and hopefully
take up primary,
view on the screen. I don't want to lose the headings or the prompt. I still wanna
be able to visualize that.
Now, I've gone and copied this and I'll just bring it up and it's failed. It hasn't
worked the way I wanted though. There's some success. You can see that you can hover
over these icons here and see the enlarged
image, which is what I wanted, but the arrows to go left and right don't work, and
the fact that we don't have the original images on the screen is also a bit of a
problem.
Now I tried fixing the problem with the prompt. I said, when you altered the code,
you broke the buttons. I've also said, you have broken the layout of the original
four images, and I expected everything to stay as it was just with four new buttons.
Now you can see here on screen that I've got regeneration errors and I had a bunch
of issues go on. Firstly, it didn't generate the code, then it did generate the code,
and I thought I had a working version. We'll just bring it up. This is it. Here,
we've got four images. They look great. We've got these hover buttons. We can hover
up and see an enlarged version, but what doesn't work
is the left and the right to go between different slides.
when I tried to fix that, nothing seemed to work the way I wanted.
So I've abandoned this for now because I've only got 30 credits for the week.
Well, that's been a first look at open AI's oh one preview. In the next video, I
hope to use some of the credits that I've got remaining to create a documentation
programming language, basically at DSL. So stay tuned for the next video where we'll
be looking at that or comment and like and subscribe. I'm AppyDave See you in the
next video.