Now I've just had a little bit of a look through the documentation. Everything looks
good. So what we should do now is publish it and make it available for a project.
So what I'm going to do is just click on the copy button, and where I want it to
go is into the handlebars project. Now this project is two years old and it hasn't
had a change since about a year ago. It had a minor change. And if we look at the
current usage documentation, it's not available. So this is what we're going to change.
So let's head over to Cursor. And what I've done is I've just changed the path of
the documentation and created a new empty file. And we should be able to paste all
of that in. Let's just do one little check to see that visually it looks okay. Things
seem to be coming through okay.
I'd like to just publish this up to a Ruby gem repository. So what we're doing at
the moment is just merging the changes into the repo. It's going to update the semantic
version number. Hopefully we're going to go from 13.1. I believe it currently is
to version 14. That's also going to bring it into alignment with the other project
that we just did, the cmdlets, which are currently on 14 as well. So once this in
place, we should then be able to use the documentation in the next project that we're
going to be working on.
Now the CI pipeline just finished. Let's check out what it's done. So currently we're
on version 0.13.1. If we refresh this we move up to 0.14.0. For the documentation.
There's the old documentation. Let's update it. And I did get a misspell here. But
essentially all of the documentation has now come into place. Let's have a look at
the Ruby gems. So currently the Ruby gems should show Commandlet on 14 and handlebars
on 13.1. But if we refresh that, that has now moved to 14 zero. So both of these
are in alignment as well.
Now, with our documentation created, let's check out how we could use it in an AI
pair programmer.
I've come over to the Cursor AI IDE, and there's a brand new project that I've started
called k_template. It's an embedded web server that uses handlebars templates to
render information.
what I've just quickly done is come through. We've got some dependencies here. We
should change them to 14 because this is what the gems are going to be. And lastly
we need to go and check the settings within Cursor. So at the moment we're on general,
if you head over to a concept called features, you can scroll down and add documentation
into the system. So we'll click on Add Docs and I'm just going to paste in the information.
I've changed the letters usage. So that should be okay. Now we'll press enter on
that. And it's now starting to add handlebars JS. We'll press confirm on that. And
currently it's indexing. So what I'll do is I'll take us over to cmdlet as well.
And we'll come back to Cursor. We'll add docs. The last one has finished. So we can
now add in cmdlet. It's probably going to ask the same question. We'll press confirm
and now it's starting to index that documentation as well.
Let's just do a quick progress report. In this video, we've rapidly created documentation
using GPT canvas. In the last video, we did the same thing, but we used Cursor AI
to create the documentation. In the next video, we're going to bring together both
pieces of documentation to rapidly create a web application that uses handlebars.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.