In the last video we used Cursor AI to create documentation for this project called
cmdlet. Now at the end of that process, we had an extensive documentation system
that included a whole lot of code examples, which will be really useful for any AI
pair programmer. Now in this video we want to look at Handlebars.js, and in particular,
let's fix up the documentation that's missing from this internal project of mine.
So today I thought we'd use ChatGPT canvas, see if it does as good a job or maybe
even a better job. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and let's get into it.
So I've come over to ChatGPT and what I'm going to do is select the new canvas model.
Now this is designed for writing code, not for writing documentation. So I'm not
even sure how well this is going to work. But what I do know is that in the last
video, when we were creating the documentation for this Commandlet tool, it ran into
a few problems, and the nature of the problems happened to be how ChatGPT and different
systems like this work with code examples. So if you look at this markdown document
where we've got level two headings, we've got some text going on. We've got a little
command showing up inside of ticks. The moment it gets to a triple tick like this,
which is what we use when we want to show different formats of code. This was breaking
the formatting within the chat window within Cursor AI now what I'm hoping I can
do is use GPT canvas and let it think of the document that it's building as just
a markdown document, of which there is a combination of markdown and code in it.
let's start writing a prompt and what we'll start off with is I'm going to give you
a raw markdown document. You will be helping me create a new markdown document for
a different project. What you need to focus on is, number one, good clear documentation
for the new project. And number two, formatting markdown with code blocks correctly.
Note that the code examples
which we will be working with in the new project will either be ruby blocks or handlebars
JS blocks.
So we'll go over to our other project here and we'll click on code and this gives
us a raw format.
what we can do is press the copy button here, come back and we'll paste it in.
let's just see what ChatGPT canvas can do with this.
firstly, this is already a whole lot better than what Cursor AI was doing in that
we don't see these breaks in the code flow from markdown, which is all this stuff
here versus the actual code snippets that are being shown.
Now, if we come over to the left here, we've got a chat that says, it seems like
you want a new document for a different project that still focuses on good documentation.
It wants to do formatting for ruby and handlebars examples, and we can start doing
a chat in the left. I'll say, I want you to give me an outline, and I'm going to
give it a bunch of files, and I want it to just stick to the heading one, heading
two, heading three. So we'll say here is the existing outline. And we're going to
have to go and get that.
let's figure out what files we want. Now the Handlebars.js project has a library
folder, and it also has a unit test folder. And under this we have what are called
helpers. And the helpers are really just handlebars helpers that are hooked up to
the cmdlets that we looked at in the previous project. So there'll be things for
case transformation, like turning text into a constant format, or a title or a dash
notation. So we know where we can find the structure. It should be there. There are
probably other information that might be useful for the documentation in this particular
area. We would call that configuration or setup. And as for examples there should
be examples down in the unit test. So if we go to the unit test and we open up here,
we'll go and have a look at the inflection and maybe look at the pluralization. And
we can see how it could be used in handlebars and the sort of output that should
come from it.
So what I'll do is go into a terminal and I'll run a little tool, and it's called
GPT context. And what it's going to do is capture the files. And we can just see
that if I go straight into a text area and paste it, it's also in my clipboard.
We will go back to the chat window and we'll paste that information in there as well.
Let's just check it's all in place. It is. We'll press go. And from that prompt,
what I'm hoping we'll get is a new markdown document that's really only focusing
on the structure.
information is coming through. It's trying to do some configuration which is a little
odd because I haven't given it any information just yet.
Now when I look through this, it's done some things correctly, but it's missed part
of the prompt that I stated. So the first thing we look at is the helpers. I've got
at least six different helper groups. There's only three listed here. It's also giving
installation and configuration, but we've not given it any information to work with
yet. And while the examples all look like handlebars, again, we haven't given any
examples for it to work from. The only thing that feels quite correct is this file
structure down the bottom.
So let's just write a correction prompt here.
You went and included details which will be incorrect because I haven't given any
information yet. You don't know how it's configured and there's no examples. Then
we say you are only meant to write an outline in headings like level one, two and
three would be good from my point of view.
You also only wrote three helper groups in the table of contents. There are six in
the structure, so I'm just letting it know that the old markdown document was for
style guidelines, not for informational purposes.
we'll press go on that and let's see what it comes up with. So we've got handlebars
and Ruby Helper documentation guide. That title won't be quite correct but that's
okay. We've got a good table of contents. Now we've got a file structure. This is
looking perfect.
let's go and fill out some of the documentation. And I think the area I want to focus
on is just here. So we can start writing a prompt. And the prompt will go with is
I'll give you an example code from the root of the application. And we're just looking
for it to figure out from that code. Introduction configuration and setup.
Coming back to VS code, what we can do is click on the lib folder. We've got the
handlebars and I believe these are the files we probably want. So I'll go into a
terminal and I'll put in this command that I've got called GPT context. And we're
only looking for the files in that particular folder. And there they are listed here.
Now if we just paste that in you can see it's in the clipboard. But we can just change
this command slightly. What we'll do is get the format of tree turned off. And what
it will now do when it finishes is give us all the code. So now what we've got is
the tree structure that is definitely put in each time, plus the file name related
to each system. We've got code and as we move down we've got the next one. So what
that means is if we go back over to the web view, we should be able to just pop in
over here, paste it all in. Now there'll be things in here like the version which
isn't relevant. So hopefully it doesn't fill that particular information in. But
now we've got an introduction. We've got installation handlebars helpers. That's
not actually correct. It should be handlebars JS and I can change that later. It's
now started to fill in information, which it feels like it might have missed the
point a little bit though. This area looks pretty good,
Now it's got a couple of mistakes. I've just started a prompt. Please correct these
mistakes. So the first thing that I can see here is that this is not handlebars helpers,
it's actually handlebars JS the configuration. I'm hesitant to include this because
it didn't get it totally from the information I gave, but I might leave it for now.
But the actual helpers. This is a bit of a problem, so we'll just change this and
we'll say I never gave you any example helpers. I shouldn't see any usage. And the
gem is not called handlebars helpers, it's called handlebars.js. So we'll run that.
And the way
it rewrites everything from the top, and that can be a little bit slow, but it's
still incredibly fast compared to previous versions of ChatGPT, and it's a lot more
accurate than Cursor I, so I do like that, so we'll leave that for what it is. We've
got some helpers, we've got some registration, we've got some troubleshooting, we've
got contributing and we've got the file structure.
What I'd like to do now is fill out the usage instructions. So if we go to the table
of contents, we've got available helpers. We've got all our different categories.
Looks like we've got string helpers twice there. Not sure what's going on there.
And I think if we head over to the message box we'll go with the prompt. Can you
work through the following unit tests and write down the instructions in the markdown
document under available helpers.
we're trying to go into this section right here.
what it should focus on is 1 or 2 usage examples for each helper. I know from the
unit tests that there may be more than one data scenario with each of these, so we'll
see what it comes up with.
Now we'll come back to VS code. We'll go over to the spec folder and let's go have
a look at join. So here we've got the values of one, two and three being joined together.
Now by default if you do join and values it'll be one comma two comma three. If you
provide a separator it'll be one pipe to pipe three. So these are the sort of usage
examples that we want to see. So we'll close that down. We'll go into our terminal
and we'll use our command. And this time we're looking for the files that are in
the spec folder. And they're all listed here. Now if we just change this command
a little bit and we'll get rid of the format, we've now got the code as well.
And from there we should be able to go over to ChatGPT canvas and paste it in.
based on that prompt, that's a lot of information coming through. So maybe there'll
be some mistakes. We've got our installation, we've got our configuration coming
through, and now we've got
available helpers. So the safe one with a value input hello name world output hello
name world.
if we look at our join that we were just looking at we've got values.
Input values are one two, three. Join with a pipe. Should be 123.