Vibe Coding with Opus 4.5 is really awesome. And in this video, which is number three
in a series on building a particular application for managing my recording system,
we're going to integrate whisper AI.
what that will allow us to do is take any recordings and transcribe the text
so that we can then send that information through large language models. I'm AppyDave.
Let's get into it.
In video number one in this series, we essentially built this recording Namer application.
We did it all with vibe coding, and it had the ability to watch for videos from an
ECamm Live stream and put them directly into a project directory.
By the end of that video, any incoming recordings and at the moment we got the one
I'm doing right now, plus four that are here would be ready to be either discarded
or put into the recordings folder. And this is how it would work. I would do a rename
on the one that I like, and I would discard the rest. And what would be left with
is a recording stored somewhere on the computer.
In the second video on the Opus 4.5, I demonstrated that new capabilities were added.
We had projects, we had thumbnails that we could preview and add to the video that
we were recording. We'd have assets that we could then go and manage and assign next
to different videos
and we developed a few more capabilities around the tagging and the statuses of videos.
So as I'd add in a second video here, we could see it available over in the recording.
And by this point, this application was already doubling the productivity that I
was doing with YouTube videos.
So the capability I want to add to the application today is transcription. And the
way I think it's going to work is that whenever a video is recorded and put into
the recordings folder, the next thing that should happen is a background process
should run and it starts transcribing the individual video. And when it's done, we
should be able to click on it and see the actual transcription.
Now, the other capability I want from the transcription system is that when a chapter
is finished and currently this is the intro, I would like to bundle up all the text
and be able to figure out things like what should the chapter link from an SEO perspective
be? So if we go back to the incoming where I've just finished a video and I'm calling
it the scenario and we rename it, what should happen at this point because we are
on a new chapter, is that all of these transcriptions should be bundled up together
so that I can do chapter level assessment with large language models.
So let's just get straight into coding, or at the very least understanding the agents
we're going to work with. So I'm just in the fly video Namer project at the moment,
and I'm going to run Claude in dangerous skip permissions, which means that it won't
ask me if it needs to change any files or run any sort of command. And also just
kick off this little starter prompt just to find out what information is in our Claude
MD. Now, for the last couple of days, the whole conversation for writing requirements
has been down here in the bottom right hand corner.
but it's very unstructured. And the reason for that is that I didn't want to use
any context engineering. I just wanted to find out what the Opus 4.5 model could
do. And it is exceptional. But now that
the application is getting a bit more complex, I would like to have a bit of structure
and maybe a couple of agents.
So I've just brought an old development conversation down here. I don't think I need
it, but I want to keep it for context. And I'm just going to say for this one is
what is your role? What are the basic responsibilities of the product owner? And
we can see the basic ideas. The responsibility is to gather requirements from me.
We've got general documents that we want to work with, a backlog of ideas. Any time
we change something, we need to keep a change log. And we've got some implementation
notes
and user stories or specifications. Now, this is not the BMAD method, which is usually
what I do for complex applications,
but I have instructed it to have at least some form of context engineering going
on
So as the application gets a little bit more complex, it's just not making silly
mistakes because it doesn't have enough context available.
Now, I'll just point out that if you do really want to understand context engineering,
then I've just released a video on BMAD. It's all about context engineering and the
application that we build over three epics and 14 stories is using the SDK agent
from Claude, and you'll have a self editing application at the end of it, built using
Bmad.
So coming back to our product owner, the main usage being the requirements document,
we should also go and have a look at the developer. So what we'll do is we'll just
go slash dev and load that one up. And if we look at them side by side, you can just
see that it's two different terminal windows with two different conversations going
on. We'll also just ask a simple question what are your main skills, capabilities
and responsibilities
from the developer agent? And we can see that it's already been set up with core
capabilities for React and Socket.io in the background.
and we can see that the areas of expertise are front end and back end. It's specifically
TypeScript with react 19 and also an express web server with Socket.io integration.
So I'm coming over to our product owner, and I just wanna check what functional requirements
we have that are pending. There are a lot that have been done,
and so he's reading from the backlog at the moment,
and some of this may need to be cleaned up. I'm not sure whether they're being done
or not. I've just been keeping 'em in the backlog. But the one we're interested in
today is FR 30.
And the first thing that we're going to do is ask it,
can you create a handover document for the developer for FR 30, which is the video
transcription requirements. And what we're doing is we're just letting that go into
the conversation stream.
because this conversation should only be about reading, writing, and validating the
requirements when information needs to go to the developer, we give handover notes.
You can see that one of the main documents that the PO was reading was this video
transcription spec. This was a short conversation I had just before starting this
video.
Now we will go and read the video transcription spec in a moment, but this is essentially
the handover document. And what we can do is just go up to the developer and say,
can you implement
something like that? And we'll just paste in that particular information. Now, what
should happen is the developer should start writing the code for us following the
specification.
So the development has started. There's quite a lot of actions that are going to
take place. Let's just go over and have a look at the documentation over here,
and we got the problem statement listed, which is that we record a video, we rename
it in the app later, we run a transcription manually.
The idea now is that as we're recording individual videos, we should just be able
to create transcriptions directly in a transcripts folder. And I've got a list of
where they're going to be. So currently recordings either go into the recordings
directory or once they're safe, and I think this is good, I'll move them into the
safe directory. And I just want to keep whatever recordings are in either directory.
I want the transcripts to be here.
Now the capability should happen automatically whenever a new recording is added
to the system.
And we've got a little bit of a UI design guide going on here. So currently where
we see the movie files and we can see the size of the video in seconds, we can see
the size of it in megabytes. We should now be able to see no transcript or transcribing
or let's go and view or open it.
now from time to time, we'll just jump over and see where the development's up to.
So it's got through four different areas. It's still working its way through. We'll
come back to our documentation.
And so we are also planning to have a transcriptions live logged view,
We should also be able to see anything that might have failed. Now, I don't have
any retry capability in this feature. If I need it later, we'll add it,
but we can see how the engine's going to work. So I'm not actually trying to integrate
any libraries. I'm just using a little command line tool that I already use for my
transcriptions.
and I've got a recent video on Ito.AI, it's a voice agent system and I've got access
to the open source code base and I would love to integrate this into that. But that's
a future job.
and it's also written all the instructions for the developer. It's basically read
the code base before writing the requirements document. So this has a lot of similarity
to working with BMAD or Spec Kit
and just get back over and look at the code. We've gone through another four items,
So we'll come back to our documentation and see that there's an API design in place
to list the transcriptions, but also to probably update the transcriptions going
through here.
Now I also point out that this wasn't the document I gave the developer. This is
the document that has suspects. The document I gave was the handover notes. And the
handover notes were just written on the spot to say, you can find the information
in the video transcription, and this is the basic ideas that you need to work through.
So we'll just come back to the coding session. There's been plenty of stuff going
on here. Notice I'm not really reading the code
when I'm using BMAD. What I'm usually doing is just context engineering. It's all
software architecture documents and when things go wrong, what I like to do is either
build agents or patterns or anti-patterns or principles or other sorts of documents
that solve the problem.
And that might go against what a lot of developers think they should do. But I believe
that the way agents are going in the world at the moment
within a year from now, so long as you're doing the right documentation, they'll
do the right coding for you.
Now we're just to the end. It's just happened right now and I had noticed that there
were already changes. So we've got this concept called transcripts. Let's see what
happens when we click on that. And we've got a, oh, it looks like it's already doing
a video that I've sent through. Let's see which one it is. This is oh four two. We'll
just go over to our recordings. It'll be down the bottom and it is transcribed. Look
at that. This is just working. I haven't even gone to test this. We got a 208 megabyte
file. This is pretty long recording. I just did, I think it was about four minutes.
I wonder what happens when we look at the transcripts here.
We'll head over to the development and read through what it's implemented.
So the summary is that it's going to use my local whisper AI command line tool. It's
going to wait till a file is renamed into the recordings
at which point it's going to start the transcription,
So we can see the backend changes. There's just a bunch of entries. I'm not bothering
to read the code. We've got the front end entries going on.
we've got the transcriptions page, and we've got some sort of transcriptions. My
dialogue.
I'm just going to go over the, to the webpage. We've also got a little link. This
should actually open up in Finder. So we'll go to Finder for a moment.
And that opened up automatically. We've got a transcript. Look at that. It's just
finished by the way.
and I can see that because if I go over to the transcriptions, we've got it listed.
Let's see what happens if we click view. So the development has started. So there's
everything I said in that particular video. Might be nice if we had some sizes of
the videos. Now one of the other things that happened while I was recording it is
that,
ECA m stopped and we got a new video. So what I'm going to do is run a rename on
this. This will become sequence three in the implementing of the feature. That's
what we're doing right now. It's a smaller video.
one minute and eight seconds long. We'll hit rename. So that should then head over
to transcripts. And there it is. We've got the one that we were doing and now we've
got a new one.
And we can see the actual whisper AI running from the command line. It's whisper_transcribe.py.
I don't think we saw that before. I'm kind of wondering whether the capability was
added while we were looking at the screen.
But what this will allow us to do is see if we can run two at the same time. So the
way we do that is I will stop the video and I'm using a stream deck pedal to do that,
and then I will restart straight away. And what should happen is that the new video
should come in here. So let's stop it.
and now what we're doing is restarting it. And there it is. And we will do a rename.
And now if we go over to our transcripts, hopefully we've got two being processed.
So we got one being queued, which is chapter four sequence four. And we're currently
processing chapter four, sequence three.
we can just line up video after video and they'll just transcribe on the fly as we
go.
So I just want to do one other quick test. What we'll do is we'll come over to incoming
and I will say the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog, and we'll come back to
the website and we'll stop.
and we'll start again. And what happens is we've got the quick brown Fox video. It's
only 13 seconds long. We'll hit rename on that. Head back to our transcripts. We
now have two that are in the queue.
So another one is just finished. We've got the next one in the queue. This is the
one I want to go and test the text on.
and we can see when we're looking at the recordings, which ones have transcripts,
which ones transcribing, which ones queued.
I guess I'm going to have to add some buttons here so that I can transcribe the ones
that don't have transcriptions. I think while we're waiting, we should just kick
off a development environment. For that, we're going to need an updated requirements
document.
Now I've come over to the product owner conversation and made the statement that
FR 30 is complete. We will send some handover documents to let it know that it's
done, but can it just add a couple of capabilities? So the two that I want is can
we get a transcript button?
And that transcript button should happen somewhere
in this column. I think we've already got the transcript label, so I'm assuming that's
the right place to do it. I haven't given it instruction, so it may actually end
up putting it over here.
I've asked if it's can create another button for us for doing chapter transcriptions.
Now we shouldn't need to do an actual transcription. Should be a case of some sort
of button up here that when we click it just concatenates all the transcriptions
that are there.
But I did have to give it one extra instruction and that's to let it know that we
don't know the best name for it. So it's going to have to review the documentation.
So at the moment it's just making some modifications to the FR 30 specification.
it's got some,
ideas on how it should be written and then it's just started writing a whole lot
of documentation for it.
And I think this is going to be as easy as just selecting this text. We'll go over
to our developer conversation
and we'll just paste the text right in and it should go and do the development. While
that's happening, let's go back to our web application and see where we're at.
Look at that. It's finished everything. Now we only had about 13 seconds,
I just wanna do one test and this is what I said. The quick brown thoughts jumped
over the lazy dog.
now. This is incredible. So we've got new coding going on right now and that's going
to give us access to new capabilities.
basically when we go to the recordings, we are going to have a button. It looks like
we've already got that button. I wonder if we should kick it off on something.
We'll do this video 'cause it's relatively small. 16 megabytes. Let's kick that off
and we'll come back up to our transcripts and we can see a new one is running. What
I'm a little concerned about is that we lost the other transcription notes.
Not sure if that's because it restarted the application, but we can see everything
that's been,
transcripted already. We can see the stuff that's now newly being transcribed.
If I go down to the coding agent, we can see that it's about to implement the bottom
for the chapter headings. So that hasn't been done right now.
and then it happens there it is combined.
So here's my chapter test.
The quick brown fox.
Jumped over the lazy dog.
And went straight to the link in the description where he could go to AppyDave Skool
on context engineering.
So what should have happened right then is a whole set of chapter recordings have
come in. They're all queued at the moment.
We can head over to the transcriptions.
Everything's progressing. I noticed there's a little bug. We go to the recordings.
Well, maybe it's a bug, but the idea of the combine is only showing up where we've
got a transcription. I personally don't want to see it unless I've got all the transcriptions.
So what I've done is I've combined it. I did that by mistake. We'll go and do another
one in a moment, but let's click on view and see what we've got.
And this is okay. It probably won't be good in the future. I don't think I wanna
see the actual video names in here, but for testing, this is perfect. So we can see
that I said, so here's my chapter test. The quick brown fox jumped over the lazy
dog and went straight to a link in the description where he could go to AppyDave
school on context engineering.
Let's see what this button does.
going to copy it to the clipboard, and this is going to open it in the folder system.
we can see the file down here. So one last test. We're just going to go to this big
one. We'll do combine, and then we will
do view,
and then we will do clipboard,
and then we will do paste.
there's all the sequences from one chapter all listed.
So there we have it. The third video on testing out Opus 4.5 in a pure vibe coding
sort of scenario. We're not doing a lot of context engineering frameworks, though.
We are doing a little bit of context engineering from the point of view of having
a changelog, a backlog, and a couple of agents that we handcrafted.
But you're noticing that there aren't really any bugs. Things just work.
where anthropic has got to with this model is incredible.
So I think for the next video we'll continue the Opus 4.5. And what we'll do is we'll
come over to the system where the different recordings get combined into one video.
And at that point we use a digital asset management system that were built and will
integrate it into this. And what that's planning to do is take these files that are
basically local to my computer at the moment and make them available in S3 drives,
also Glacier, and also as a network addressable storage system in another country.
So that's the progress we want to start on in the next video.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe. I'll see you in the next video.