In this video, we're going to use cursor AI to bulk update thousands of changes across
hundreds of files within an existing PR.
The way we will do is by generating dozens of prompts ready for use by Cursor AI.
And what those prompts will do is change thousands of lines of code across hundreds
of files, and they'll all be put together using a programming construct called KlueLess
that I'm designing at the moment. And this is one of the first previews of how I
see it working. So stick to the end and we'll streamline the ability to use Cursor
AI
I've been saying a lot of articles and questions lately on bulk code creation using
different tools, so people are using ChatGPT. Other people are using Cursor and Aider.
And the situation I found myself in recently was that I was helping a company move
from Ruby two to Ruby three, and they had 900 odd files that needed changing, but
there was a problem that needed to be dealt with en masse.
So when the PR was being reviewed, there were hundreds of files, and one of the things
that was noticed was that there was a new stylistic change which had to do with an
improvement to the Ruby programming language, whereby you could use the old format,
or you could go to the new format, which would be simpler to read. But it was decided
that this was not a format that we'd needed in the application. The problem is that
it had been done relatively early in the PR, or was going to be very difficult to
undo this particular change.
So I played around with a prompt generation technique, and you can see eight files
that have been changed here. And in one of the files there's a bunch of changes that
have been made, essentially undoing the stylistic change that was done using a linter.
For years, I've been experimenting with domain specific languages designed to generate
code and other sorts of constructs. The ability to become a polyglot programmer,
where you start from a design pattern or first principles and generate any sort of
code, is the goal that I've had now, rather than doing a no code platform, I've always
thought of it as a flow code platform where you're generating a freaking lot of code.
Now, the way I see it working is some sort of domain specific language that you integrate
with the AI programmer that you like to use.
So let's have a look at how this could work. So I've got a little KlueLess construct
called Git diff. And the idea of it is that you should be able to do a comparison
between, say, the master branch and another PR, and from there you should be able
to process the changes. Let's see them in both JSON and maybe flattened out into
a CSV format.
Now we have the construct here ready to save. And we've got two files that it's going
to output to. So if we let that run, what should happen is we'll get a list of JSON
structure where all the diffs and the particular files. So here's a gem file. And
there's a bunch of diffs going on in there. Now over on the right where you see the
CSV file, it's just a flattened version of it.
Now if we make this CSV file easier to see, you can see it's basically a bunch of
files. We've got the number of changes or diffs that are in it. Plus we can see the
diff. So if we look at the gem file here, we can see that there are eight different
changes going on in that particular file. At the moment we don't have any matches,
because what we're trying to do is figure out what sort of changes are going in there,
and then make appropriate changes based on the match type.
So the next step is to categorize all these files. And you can see that there's over
2000 files and changes going on here. And if we go to the very top you'll see that
none of them are being processed and the match type has not been filled in. Now if
we look at what it will look like, the idea is that they have all been processed.
Some of them don't match on anything, others match on gem version, investigate, others
match on hash shorthand syntax.
and it's the hash shorthand syntax that I want to generate new code for.
So let's have a look at how this KlueLess construct could work. So here I've got
an idea called prompt matcher. And what it's going to do is take an input file. In
this case it's going to be the diff
csv. From there we want to find a patterns. So the pattern I'm going to call it issues.
And I've just started writing it. Analyze the following diff and identify the pattern
below. So I've listed what the old and the new code should look like. And then I've
said if it finds it, return hash shorthand syntax. After that. If it's not found,
return no match. And I want to make sure that it doesn't try to return any other
sorts of information. From there, just insert the actual content that you want it
to compare from. The other thing I do is I put some constraints in it as to what
the default value is, if it can't figure anything out, and what the expected values
happen to be. After that, we find the matches and update the diffs.csv.
Now. At the moment it deals with one pattern, but if you want it to deal with a second
pattern, you can expand the prompt and you just change things to suit what you need.
Now, if we look at the differences between these two prompts, we've got a little
bit change in the wording. We've got the example of a second pattern going on, and
we've just got extra information going on in the expected results so that they can
be validated.
So let's work with this version. And what we'll do is we'll also print out a report.
And when we look at that we can see this report has come through. It's got the different
match types including no match. And then it's got a column of how many are for each
type. So if we look at the gem version, investigate it found five in the gem file.
It found seven in the Gem file lock. And then we've got a scattering of hash syntax
shorthand matches throughout all the other files.
Now if we look at how many changes could happen, we've got this column B, which has
the things that we want to change and we look through and there's hundreds of files.
If we get down to the very bottom of this, we can see there are 940 potential files.
Not all of them are selected. This is a lot of changes that are going to go on. So
we now need to wrap this up and bundle it into specific prompts that we can use in
Cursor.
So now what we're going to do is build out the prompts for Cursor to work with. So
we're at the generate prompts and I've put in our diff file as input. It's now been
updated with matches. From there we want to filter the items. Now there's particular
items that we want in the list. So what we'll do is where the pattern match is true.
And we've got a match type equal to the hash shorthand syntax. From there we'll do
a header to the prompt. So all the prompts will start with something like this. This
is just explaining the pattern for ChatGPT to go and update, or in this case Cursor.
From there, we'll iterate over every item, and we'll just include the content from
the particular item we've got. And then lastly, put in a bit of a footer to close
it off. The other thing that's important is that when we're creating the files, we
do batch them up, because I don't want Cursor to make all the changes in one hit.
I want to look at them, say 20 files at a time. So what I've done here is said filtered
items. In this case it's batch size 15. I want them all to go out to a particular
folder and have a text extension.
So we're about to look at the prompts. Before we do, we'll just start back from the
beginning. What we firstly generated was a JSON structure from a diff between two
different branches. From that, we then turned it into a CSV file and we've matched
different things. You can see the report going on there. Then lastly it's created
the prompts and the prompt set. It's created number 65 different prompts that I need
to run. But that's all dealing with about 15 changes per prompt. And if we look at
the first one we can see that we've got the header section. And then we've got the
actual code that needs to be looked at and analyzed. And that just keeps repeating.
And right at the bottom there should be a closure for it as well.
Now let's head over to Cursor. And you can see here we've got the reverse Ruby shorthand
syntax. Let's click on that. And we can see the main part of the prompt. And there's
a lot of changes going in here. Different files. But they're cherry picked to the
specific changes. And then we can see them all come through here.
I went and applied each of these changes.
Now we'll go and have a look at the files that have changed on the PR at the moment.
We'll open up the assets controller. We can see the changes have come through and
they're accurate. Look at the activities controller. We've got similar sorts of things
going on. And all of this has just been cherry picked out of the prompts. And just
run on automation with Cursor.
So let's actually test another one with Cursor. So I've come over to the list of
prompts and I'm just going with the second one at the moment.
And here we are at Cursor. I'll press command L to bring up a chat. And I'm just
going to paste everything in and let's run it and see what happens. So certainly
here's the necessary fixes. We've got the next file company targets controller home
page dashboard location updatable.
And if we go to the bottom it says these changes reverse the shorthand hash syntax.
So from here I'm just going to press apply on this particular change. From there
we'll go with command y. Command y. Again let's just check there's nothing else going
on in here. We can then press apply on this one and look through to where the actual
change happens to be.
And you can see these little blue lines is where you look for the change.
just scroll all the way down to the next one and press Y on that.
So now we've gone from the eight that we originally had to now 15 files and we can
look through and see how the changes were. And we're looking at the email controller
and we can see some changes that around line 370 and more at around line 700.