So I was able to use cursor I to take this PR with 950 file changes. There's 2200
diffs and recreate a new PR with over a thousand changes in it. 412 files. And this
was all with the power of simple automation scripts and cursor AI.
Now, contrary to that last statement, not everything was fun, and I took a bunch
of notes along the way of what happens. So there's this idea of pressing command
Y on the Mac, which will apply the changes automatically for you one at a time. And
it's a great tool. I was using it all the time, but you can't do it until all the
changes have been processed in the file. So if you've got many changes, say 20, you
might be waiting around for 20 or 30s before you can even start.
Now, if you want to do a bulk set up, one of the things I noticed is that as you're
pressing, apply on each of these, you're getting the changes over here. You can press
command Y or command. And if you don't want to accept the change. But once they're
all in place, you can press the accept. Now, you'll see soon that I didn't use this
feature because I kept finding little edge cases where things didn't work, and I
had to manually check every line as I went.
I sometimes found the speed at which I could get stuff done here, being impaired
through the way it was communicating messages. There were inconsistencies with the
colors that would show up on the bar. There were inconsistencies with the messaging,
and I'd be sitting here waiting, going, has it finished yet or not? So sometimes
things just took longer than I think they should have.
That also led into issues with using the mouse and the command y together. If you
press page down and your cursor goes below an area that's changed and then you press
command Y, it would actually do the next area. So there was a little bit of challenges
just getting used to how that interface works. But the big problems happen to be
with code not working the way you would think. So here we had a change, and it actually
changed a variable name from an act to not an act. So this was something that I wasn't
able to accept. Then it was making some legitimate changes, but they weren't in keeping
with the prompt or were still it would just create an actual bug by taking something
out that was meant to be there.
Once I was getting into the groove of working with 15 changes at a time, that's how
the prompts were set up. I decided to increase it to 100, and at that point things
just stopped working, and the way it communicated just didn't really give me an idea
of what was going on. So it might just make one file change. So I had to go back
to smaller prompts, which is fair enough with large language models, but it was something
I learnt. And if we come down to five, six and seven, these are pretty much similar
to the ones before where it's gone and made these odd changes that would only introduce
bugs into the system. So same with number eight.
If you want access to the code that I use to generate the diffs and the prompts,
check out the link in the description. I also put a link to the clueless coding language
ideas that I'm working through at the moment. In the next video, I plan to use v0
to create a video asset management tool to communicate with a video editor, so stay
tuned for that. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe! See you soon!