In this video, what I want to do is just take you through some
examples of what's coming in the form of animated
diagrams, charts, ah, it's great for educational sort of
stuff. Uhm, and I'll,
I'll do it by showing this example. So this example is a video that
Mary did, based on an image I saw.
Over it in Facebook,
so people are often doing the top 10 ways to do whatever.
And they're usually just this grid and they list all the tools.
Now, I said to her, we need,
ah, this is a, it's called a listicle in article writing,
ah, so a list article listicle.
And, um, she put together this video.
The, the, the information is pretty good, but it has a few problems.
Um, so when we hit play on this and it's got the AI
talking about it, VO three is the undisputed champ while open AI is
4.0 is your go-to for now.
I'll just turn off the sound. What's happening is that we've got categories on
the left and we got the, what tool you use so we can see
it. It's kind of this, emerging thing.
Now there's a few problems. So you might've noticed it just shifted
position and that's because at some stage during the presenting,
presenting of the graphics, Mary would have duplicated a page.
Then she would have shifted something by accident and not noticed it.
So this sort of, uh,
floor in the, um, in the aesthetics is,
uh, it's, it's a bit of a pain.
Um, it's not something that we want to do.
You can even see it in a few areas here where you've got these
lines that aren't quite aligned in these two positions.
Now there's also a bunch of other challenges when building these sorts of
screens. So first is, if we wanted to change the style,
it's very problematic because it's about,
20 different slides to do this,
um, visual that you're seeing,
right? So you've got essentially,
uh, 10 different concepts,
but you generally got two slides per concept to deal with the animation.
Now, if you wanted advanced animations,
like highlighting anything, then we don't even bother.
It's just too hard. So this is,
an idea of, um, an autumn,
something that could be automated, but how do you do that?
And that's what I want to talk about in this video. I want to
show one that we just proof of concept from one prompt.
We're going to make a minor change to it as well,
and then potentially see if we can use some prompts that I've pre-created to
see if we can make more automations.
So, I designed this design. Big prompt,
it's, um, quite long and it describes everything we want to do,
like showing the categories, showing the tools,
all that sort of stuff. And it's all in this one little document and
I was able to put it into Claude code.
And if I've got Claude code down below me,
it's just here. I was able to put it into this document.
I think it was, uh, and here.
and And what we did was we generated a little
application and that application is sitting right here.
This is all programming language and it was all created essentially
in one shot and then I did a bit of a modification over the
top of it. And what it produced is this little,
uhm, thing here. We'll just click on it.
You and if we hit play,
what we'll see is the animation come to life.
Now it's just an app. It's just a program where shift something in place,
color it, maybe expand it, whatever.
But this is all done in a new video programming,
uh, language that looks like a regular timeline
editor for videos because it's meant to work that way.
Bye but it runs the program under the hood.
So I'll hit play and we should see this,
uh, same video concepts that we were just looking at,
but now they're animated. They're using whatever colors that we want.
Now I made a minor modification so that the top three of them would
actually change color and we see that right now.
And what I'd like to do now is maybe make one more change.
More modification to that particular,
uh, video. So I think the,
uh, changes I want to do is I want to make this green,
uh, this blue, this yellow,
yellow, the way it is. And I probably want to narrow everything.
So what I'm going to do is I'm just going to come over to,
uh, my Claude system where we kind of talk to these apps.
And I'm just going to make a prompt here.
So the essential prompt I said was,
can you alter the first three items?
So that one is green, two is blue, three is yellow,
and that they come in one at a time. And can we make it
narrow? So it just fits on a mobile phone.
And what this is going to do under the hood is it's going to
read this information and it's stuck going to start writing.
code into here.
So this whole program is going to change one way or another.
So what we can see here is we've got,
ah, first place, second place, third place colours are being defined and they're using
colour codes. And we've also got some timing and size
sort of stuff going on, positioning going on here.
Sorry. A mathematical calculations for how the animation is going
to move. Here we've got information
around the flashing, the intensity of the flash,
the colours, the background colours are being dealt with here.
And then ultimately it just gives us a summary of everything that you
did, uh, right there. So if I hit play on the,
It's got the top 10 AI tools of 2025,
and the first 10 items are coming in as per what they originally did.
By the way, a lot of this can actually be changed.
We can do whatever we like here, but I'm going to leave it as
red as it comes through. And then the last three are going to come
in as per what we requested it to do.
Now if something didn't work, we can see that because I did,
I did want it to be a narrower image,
but I can go in and refat to that and should be able to
solve it on the next run. But instead,
what we'll do is we will pop in over to the documentation.
I'll say, I might just have a look at the pre-prompt I did on
this one. And in fact,
all I've got to do is say, Ken.
Sorry. I'm just going to say, can you create the requirements for 002?
So this was all done a week ago.
I don't even remember what it's all about,
but we can see that this is some sort of GitHub profile animation.
It's building this long requirements.
And this is the sort of stuff you would do as a one-shot prompt
for building a little micro-application.
But a lot of the designs and the ideas, uh,
uh, including animations.
So we're just going to copy that information,
head down to Claude Code,
and what we'll do. So I'm just asking it to integrate the guidelines
that I'm about to paste in. They're being pasted in right now.
And we want it to go into this folder just here.
So what we're doing is taking the information that,
that was in a single requirements document the way it would be for a
micro application. And we're putting it into a folder that's been
pre-designed for a video animation.
So concept like assets and data and overview are ready to go.
And all of this is going to be expanded with new information as it
starts working through this requirements.
So at the moment it's building the shot list,
which is really kind of like the frames in an animation are coming through
right here. Then what it plans to do is start
reading or creating a GitHub profile JSON.
So essentially a JSON document is a machine readable data
format. It's going to go off to,
uh, one of them. My GitHub user names and start extracting information and
loading it into here. And this is going to give really rich data that
can be used in the animation. And so we can see it here.
We've got Clueless I.O. Uh,
David Crewas building beautiful code and digital blah,
blah, blah. So there's a whole lot of information coming through here.
And then lastly, it's going to build the specific application,
which is kind of like the requirements for the video animation that we're doing.
So now we've got an overview,
a shot list. We've got our data files,
specifications, information around how the animation works.
We've even got some color coding coming in.
If we jump in over here, we should now have a complex document.
So I think, All we need to do now. So I've just asked it
to create a remotion animation.
Umm, I said in React.
It says reaction, but hopefully it figures that out.
And the name of the root control should follow React,
uhm, naming component conventions.
But I do want it to actually use this numbering system 002,
because I figure if I'm creating many- Good night. Animations that they should all
just be sequential in the folder. So now it's going to start building a
bunch of React concepts.
We've got the title scene, the profile header, pinned repositories.
Let's actually go have a look at what this could be based on.
So this is just a set of repositories under one of my user
names. There's 88 in here.
Umm, I don't- know what it does from a visualization.
We've got a visualization. Hasn't been a lot of code this year.
But umm, all of this sort of information is what we want to see
coming through in the animation. So we're seeing a whole
lot of data. So this- this is the GitHub profile JSON document.
We've got pinned repositories. positive treatment. 7 8 attributes.
We've got contribution graph,
I guess, is coming through here. We've got contribution levels.
And finally finished with a bunch of useful
information, I hope. So let's just jump on.
So it's just finished. Finished here.
And what have we got? Tweet. Tweet,
type on expanding component.
So the main idea is a tweet card.
Uh, 480 frames, 16 seconds at 30 frames per second.
Comprehensive zod validation.
So all the type safety is in place in the GitHub profile.
We've got the title scene, the profile header.
List of pinned repositories.
So this looks like it's the timing,
so that must be about, uh, four seconds to whatever
that is to attempt. So that must be about four to ten seconds going
on there. Then we've got,
The contribution graph and the call to action I think if we go and
find it, it's just here. Looks like we've got information that we can change.
Here's Clueless.io. We've got a bug already.
So all we do is we take all that information and we come in
over here and we just paste it. We don't even need to state that
it is a bug that should fix it on its own.
So it's figured out what the particular issue is.
It's going to be. And if we just hit play again
over here, let's see what happens. So exploring GitHub profile for Clueless.io.
Uh, then we've got information about the pinned repositories
coming in and see they're all being typed ahead.
Then we've got the contribution graph.
This is, uh, a bit fake. It's not realistic at the moment,
but it built all of the, That, based off,
uh,
these pinned repositories, which are all about five or six years old,
but it's all coming through quite cleanly as an animation.
And one of the things that you can, and one of the things you
can do here is go and click on this little render button,
and we can do a render video,
and this will turn it into an MP4 down on the,
Hard drive, it can then be included into,
uh, however you want to use it in your video production.
So, now we're just going to recreate requirement number
three, which happens to be about animated Twitter post example
this time. So we're just building another documentation system
with the very simple, create a remotion
documentation 003 using the following requirements,
put it into .03 folder,
it's updating all the different things that we had before.
We've got the overview, the shot list, we've got the Twitter post JSON data,
so any of the machine readable data will go into there.
Here's our specifications or overview coming into place at the moment.
So, So I've pre-set up the next thing to create the components.
It's the same prompt as before, just with the numbers being changed.
But while it's still writing this, we might just go and change a little
bit of data here, and we'll just say Appie,
and we'll just say Appie Dave,
like that, and we might just change both of those.
Is it anywhere else? And we'll just call that, Dave as well,
and we'll hit Save. So with that in place,
and a summary of everything happening, let's go and create the controls.
So what should be happening right now is it's reading through this documentation
that it's gone and created, and we're going to get another control here.
Now I was hoping earlier that it would be pre-fixed with a number,
umm. Maybe that's, uh,
and a little bit of a confirmation that,
uh, starting a component with 002 is a no-no,
so that's the reason it didn't happen.
But here it is going through.
But here it is going through and creating the component
tree for this new animation.
Now, it's written everything.
One of the things I noticed, one of the things I noticed,
which was a mistake on my part,
is that I actually pointed folders at the wrong naming
convention, so they're a little bit reversed. So this is the one we've just
created. It's the animated tweet coming through.
Uh, again, maybe a little bit- fast,
you- from a video point of view, you can actually slow it down here.
But, um, what really needs to happen is that this one here should
be the tweet type on expanding card,
while this one up here should be the GitHub profile showcase,
but it's only a title change that's out of,
uh, out of whack there,
so we'll let this run over here, we'll just speed it up- a little
bit so we can see it coming through quickly.
One of the other things I did was I made it a little bit
bigger just by changing this, so it was sitting on fit when we were
looking at it earlier, we'll just bring it back up to a hundred percent,
and we can see the information a lot cleaner.
And the same thing when we do our little tabular table
now. Wha what's happened here, let's just make this a bit fifty percent as
well because we were losing a heading.
And we've just made it fifty percent as well because we were losing the
heading here. And I've just made it fifty percent on this one
so that we can see the little table and the headlines at the top.
And here come in step one,
two and three, and here come in the- winners, one,
two and three. So we go through the process one more time and this
last one we're doing is creating the requirements for number four.
And it had actually picked the wrong requirements when it
just drew what it did above. So I've just told it to work on
number four, which is a YouTube channel outro.
So in the past I've had channel out.
Shows where you see, uh, the different videos I've got,
the like and subscribe button, the comments,
the number of subscribers and suggested videos.
And I think it would be nice to have that style of animation being
automatically created. I don't think it'll get it with the graphics at the moment,
but we'll see what it does produce. So the same steps,
again, we just take our requirements and And we get it merged
into this structure of shot list, data and specification.
It's all going to appear in this folder very soon.
We can close a lot of them as we go.
The overview is coming into place at the moment.
We can see that it's picked up. Happy Dave with,
uh, 2,400 subscribers.
165 videos.
So these are the sorts of metrics that, uh,
we'd like to include in any sort of outro.
One of the things that you can do with remotion is you can make
a lot of these, uh, variables that can be changeable.
You saw that earlier changing the colors, but you can also change these numbers
as you go. Uh, which is great.
We've got our data coming through here.
So, verified. We've got the names Aipowered app development
tutorials. And our standard prompt can kick in next.
It'll be, please implement this remotion animation in React and name the root
control using React component convention,
but using the name 004. So this is actually all wrong because we've
already debunked it that we can start with numbers.
I've still- So, Got the, uh, typo from earlier as well,
reaction. So I've just been pressing the upper arrow button to go back to
previous prompts and changing some things.
I haven't really read it through because I'm just doing this video quickly at
the moment. So now it's going to start creating the controls.
I will just, um, come back over to remotion if we can find
it. It should be over here somewhere. And,
uh- out. One of the things that you can notice, so if we go
to the hello world, what I was talking about earlier with properties is
this sort of stuff. So, hello from Appie Dave can
go in here, and then we can play it around with colours like this
here. So, all these sorts of properties can be configured.
I haven't done it yet. Um, it kind of happens automatically but- you can
change what it does as it goes.
Oh, and this little window over here that's just changing.
This is the actual React application running,
so if I just, uh, kill that,
we'll just clear it, and we'll do a node run dev,
let it run. It starts reloading,
and you'll see here it's about to reload the page for us in this
location.
Okay, we've got everything created.
Let's go and check it out.
And where is it? YouTube channel outro.
So, happy Dave. We've got some sort of graphic going on behind the scenes.
We've got subscribers. Terrible color-coding going on
here. And is that it? Let's, uh,
let's hit play. So,
here it's coming through. We've got different videos available.
Uh,
like and subscribe. Sounds good.
This is using a whole lot of,
um, stop photography,
which isn't necessarily what I want.
Can we get rid of this? We can.
Next up for you. Ah, perfect.
Okay, so it could use a lot of,
um, So, we'll be tweaking. But this is where I can talk about the
next three videos coming up. Please like and subscribe.
Umm, ring the notification bell.
Uh, here's one of the next videos that we're working on.
And here's some timestamps. A little bit of a tweak going on.
Okay. This is cool. I, I can see how I could create these animations
dynamically. And then just talk to whatever.
whatever. I see. So here are the latest videos.
Uh, please like and subscribe.
Uh, it'll help us out immediately.
It'd be, I don't know why it didn't do the comment section.
But here we've got the chapter links going on.
And join the conversation. There's where we can do the commenting sort of concepts.
So there we have it. That's just a quick overview video of me just.
please. Playing around with the technology hasn't been designed,
uh, to be published on YouTube.
This video, buddy,
will be it. This is really a raw sort of, uh, video that I've
put together in bloom. But, uh, that's it. I'm happy Dave. Please like and
subscribe. I'll see you in the next video.