Imagine having a programming language that you constructed that allowed you to create
ebooks with images and stories, maybe create videos using Sora or Runway ML. Or how
about processing thousands of lines of code using a large language model AI pair
programmer like Cursor or Aider.
In this video, we're going to use OpenAI's canvas to see if we can process some programming
languages designed just to solve those problems.
So let's give it a little bit of context before we get started. For a little while
now, I've been writing a coding language called KlueLess. The clue is to do less,
and the idea is a set of programming languages that interact with large language
models. And I've been working on various forms of documentation and examples and
the rules around how this coding language works.
Now imagine you wanted to create a programming language purely to work out the costs
for a cafe in Thailand. Seems like an odd idea, but let's have a look at a programming
language that could do just that. So here we have this concept called Cosy Cafe,
and within it there's costs that are involved that are in local Thai baht. But we
might want to express those costs in US dollars or Australian dollars. And then there's
a bunch of settings. What's coffee shop called? Where's it located? How about the
recurring costs that are related to this particular cafe? The coffee shop probably
needs an owner, and there's a role that the owner might have, and there may be other
people involved in working in the cafe. And as you keep going on, there's investment
and estimates for different products. And then the actual costs involved in setting
up this particular shop.
Now that may seem a little esoteric, so let's drop into a more practical example
and look at a tool that I've got that allows me to gather all the files in tree structures
or in content structures, so that I can use it with AI pair programmer. So in this
particular case it's called context gatherer. It gathers files like the requirements
documentation, any of the database schema files that are needed, a bunch of use cases
and code, but it doesn't include the node modules folder. And if you run this particular
script, the idea is that it would go into the clipboard and it would capture both
the tree and the content.
Now, that little domain specific language that you just saw is actually backed by
a real tool that's designed to gather content trees from different applications,
including their content. It allows you to include the files that you want, exclude
the files that you don't want, and then format the information either as code or
tree structure.
Or imagine you want to combine concepts. So here we have a little coding language
called Build Prompt. It gathers different files that you might have on your system.
And then using those files it puts it through a prompt generation process. So here
we have the header for the prompt. Then each file name that's found from above is
included in the prompt. And then it's closed off with a footer. And all of that information
might be put directly into the clipboard so that you can use it in OpenAI's canvas
or Cursor.
So let's get into it. We're over in ChatGPT and I'm going to select GPT four with
canvas. Now at first it'll look the same as the other models, but as soon as we type
a prompt and press enter things will change.
So here's our starting prompt. Firstly, you're going to help me process a Ruby inspired
DSL structure to JSON. There'll be two parts to what we're doing here. There'll be
part one where we're just going to work with a simple reflection based technique,
and then part two, which we may do, which will be about converting it into an AST
technique. And lastly, to get started, I'm going to give you some example DSLs and
let's see what it can do.
So I said, sounds good and it's waiting for the first Ruby DSL. So what I'm going
to do is paste in the code that we were just looking at earlier, and you can see
things start to change around. We've got code concepts going on on the right. We've
got conversation going on on the left and the code conversations that it's done is
as per the request that I made in the chat window. Can you convert that data structure
into a hash format, which is very similar to a JSON format?
Now I'll just bring up the code that we copied, and you can see it down the bottom
here. And it's looking exactly the same only in this new format. So let's move on
to the other one we've got, which is called the Build prompt.
And I'm just going to come over to the chat and paste that one in and see what happens.
So it's going through the old hash format that was there, and now it's building a
new one so it can understand converting the Ruby DSL structure into a Ruby hash structure.
hopefully when we get to writing code, this will be a pretty simple process.
Now, if you're interested in seeing how I process files using prompts, you might
want to check out the video I did recently on processing a git diff with 1000 files,
about 2000 changes, and I was essentially looking for a particular issue in the code,
and then using a prompt on those found issues to generate new code using Cursor AI
I have this DSL, which I use for GPT agent workflows. And the particular workflow
is how I release my videos. There's all sorts of prompts that I do. There's sections
and steps that I do around the thumbnail, the title, the LinkedIn post, etc. and
all of this information happens to live in a domain specific language.
we'll just copy that information.
And we'll come back to ChatGPT canvas and paste it all in and see what it reads out
of that. Now this is quite a complex file coming through. So it scans through the
original files. And then we're going into this concept called a GPT agent workflow.
We've got the description of it. We've got the different prompts that it's reading.
We've got the sections the name of a section. So this is the video preparation where
I'll configure some data and then I'll write the script the abridgement the I'll
do some QA work. So all of this information is coming together and it's finished.
I think we'll do one more example. Imagine you had a dream sequence video with a
whole lot of prompts that you turned into images using something like Midjourney
or Leonardo. Well, that's exactly what I've done in the past. There's a video up
above, but here it is, story board graphics, and it's called the dream sequence in
this case.
generate image prompts from a video transcript and you would supply the transcript
file from there, give it some sort of design that you want, and then write out a
prompt CSV file and send it to a particular API, maybe flux one or Midjourney. So
what we'll do is we'll copy that information and we'll just paste it in and let the
last bit of information come into the system. Next we're going to start writing a
bit of code.
here's the prompt that I wrote. Now I did it using my voice. So some grammatical
errors. But basically it's just saying here are the files that we're going to work
with. They're based on the files that it's already been looking at. I've said that
it needs to create a little tool that uses reflection based approach to read those
files and convert them into a JSON format. One of the things that I've told it is
that there might be issues with positional parameters, because the idea is that the
method name and the named parameters would make up the attribute names and the node
names within the JSON document, but sometimes you don't actually have a value. I
think I have an example here. So if we look at the YouTube optimizer, you can see
here that there's a node called input, but there's no actual name. We don't know
what parameters coming in on this case.
same with the section and the step title.
we've got to allow it to figure out what to do in that situation. And then I've just
listed the files that we want.
Now we're back over at ChatGPT canvas and we'll just paste in all that information
and let's see what it comes up with. So it says to accomplish part one of the system
writing reflection based tool that reads the DSL file. And look, I'm not even going
to read that a whole lot of stuff is going on. And it's starting to write an application
called DSL parser, and it looks like it's going to store the internal structure within
a hash.
the key point that I think we need to look for is that it has a method missing going
on. So essentially it's going to interpret the Ruby code and
It doesn't know the method, but it'll interpret that and turn it into data.
let's test it out. What I'm going to do is just copy all this information and we'll
head over to Visual Studio. And I'm just going to paste it in there. Now there's
additional parsing down the bottom. But what we'll do is I'll just manually massage
it a little bit. The main thing I want to do is print it out and also write it out
as JSON
Now here is the file I want to parse. First, I've put a little terminal window down
the bottom. So we should see things come through. And I'm just going to hit save
on that. And we've got what looks to be JSON coming down. And if we just click in
over here we can see the same information. Let's just pop that over here and it should
match. So here we've got context gatherer definitely got that. Files include we've
got params lib architecture. So look at that. It didn't quite work.
it didn't get the concept of multiples which makes a whole lot of sense. It doesn't
know how to deal with an array of types, but it got the exclude and it got the actions
and it seems like all the information has come through here.
Now we'll move on to the build prompt example. I'm assuming it's going to have the
same problem here of course. And if we click on that it's created a JSON file. And
if we move it over to the left we can see we've got the context gatherer within the
build prompt. We've got files but we've only got one listed. But everything within
the prompt should come through because they're just single nodes going on.
the way I use this third one is interesting. We've got the storyboard DSL going on,
and I would send this to a tool that I have that reads in the transcript file. It
applies a bit of stylistic design that we might want and generates visualization
prompts. From that they're written out to a CSV file and finally sent to a platform.
And the way that can look is on a video that I've got here, we can see the graphics
are just being transformed using Capcut in this particular case. And we get nice
visualization that allows us to do a story around, in this case, the KlueLess programming
language. The clue is to do less, and that video can be found over on the AI. TLDR
channel that I have. It's just here. I just released it recently and if you want
to find out more, please check it out.
So let's look at the last one. It's got a really interesting use case that I currently
put it through. Now it's got the same problems that we've seen. If we look at the
prompts here there's only going to be one listed. But pretty much all the other data
is starting to come through okay. And what I tend to do is I like to write my agents
as code using DSLs. And as soon as I've written a schema object that allows me to
make sure that it can deal with arrays, different type definitions, and other sorts
of rules, what I can then do is hook that information directly up to a web application
being the agent workflow. And in this, this is just a case of prompts with merge
capabilities for various variables, so that you can generate prompts dynamically
in a workflow sort of system.
the good thing about it is that you can have various phases in the workflow, and
all of it's generated directly from the DSL.
Well, there we have OpenAI's canvas, which I think was an amazing experience. I only
tried it and thought, wow, this is really cool.
if you're interested in what I'm doing with the KlueLess programming language or
the Agent Workflow Builder, there'll be a link in the description. If, on the other
hand, you just want to learn more about prompt engineering or coding with AI, the
next video that I'm going to talk about is creating documentation for AI pair programmers.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.