Last week, an AI autonomous
programmer was announced by cognition.
It's called Devon, and in the week, since
a bunch of open source repositories are
trying to replicate that functionality.
In this video, I'm going to show you open
Devon and how to install it, the backend,
the front end, and the docker container.
And then we'll talk about three
different examples and the actual
cost of using this product.
Let's get straight into installing open
Devon, and the way you can do that is
navigate over to GitHub, open Devon.
Find the repository for open Devon,
and then just click on the code button.
From there, you'll have three
different ways that you can
clone it down onto your computer.
I use the GitHub CLI tool gh
repo clone OpenDevon/OpenDevon.
From there I went into Visual Studio
just to have a look at what we've got.
Run this locally, you're going to
need a couple of runtime environments.
And on my computer, I use ASDF to
manage programming language versions.
I've currently got Node and
Python installed on my computer
with different versions.
And I've also got Docker.
And if you run a Docker PS you'll
see a list of containers that
you've got on your computer.
Now, the one we actually need for.
Open.
Devon is called ghcr.io/opendevon/sandbox.
make sure you do a docker, pull on
that and pull it down to your computer.
I.
Looking at the list of files in your
code editor, what you'll wanna do is copy
the config TOML template to config TOML.
And notice here that it's light gray.
It's also listed in my .gitignore, because
we're going to put secret information
in here like API keys, and we don't
want that to be pushed up to a repo.
We can now configure a large language
model to use with open Devon, and I've
decided I want to use open ai, so I've
headed over to platform.open ai.com
and gone down to the API Keys, created
a new one and just made a copy of it.
From there, what I can do is go
over to the config dot TOML and
just paste the value in there.
You can also export it
to your environment.
With three installation steps.
The first being the backend, what you
need is a Python environment, and from
there we can do a pip install pipenv.
Follow that up with a pip env
install -v and a pip shell.
And what that will do is use the PIP
file that's already in the project
to make sure that the environment
matches what works with open Devon.
If your environment in place,
you can now use uvicorn to
open the backend on Port 3000.
so long as you've gotten through any
troubleshooting sort of issues, if you
come back later on and you try to run
this and you have errors, just remember
that you do need to activate the shell
each time before starting the server.
Let's now look at the front
end chat bot, which we will be
running on port 3001 in this case.
And if you go over to your project,
there will be a folder called Front End.
You can just CD into that
project and run an NPM install.
These installations, we can now start
the application and what you'll see
here are a couple of terminals where
on the left I've got the Python backend
running, and on the right I've got the
node js front end running, and you can
see that it's running on Port 3001.
I.
Now before you write any prompts
to create some code, we do need to
configure and make sure everything
is working with the Docker container.
what you can do is start the application
as normal, run a Docker PS, and
you will see no containers listed.
But the moment you start running
a actual prompt to generate
code, it will reach out.
And from there you should
be able to do a Docker PS.
you'll see the open Devon Sandbox running.
Let's look at the example application
that I wanted to create with Open Devon.
Now, recently I've been playing around
with YouTube automation agents, what
I would call an army of workers, and
I've been doing that using crew ai.
And what I was looking for was if the
agents are running in the background.
How can I communicate with
them from the front end and
what technology would I pick?
And I thought, let's try and create an
Astro JS application using open Devon.
I.
Over to the open Devon
Workspace, we can select a large
language model to work with.
I'm using open ai, so I'll go
with GPT-4 and from there we
just need to write a prompt.
Now, the prompt I had was install a
new Astro JS project named FliVideo.
Use Tailwind CSS and create
a simple homepage for a Sasa
application for YouTube automation.
So started running MPN create Astro
at latest with the parameters that
make sense for the project that
I'm creating, and then starting
to install nodejs dependencies.
one of the things it did do was use
the workspace variable to create
a new workspace folder within
the project that is open Devon.
After that it started running and I
noticed it was running for a little
while and didn't seem to be working.
I wasn't sure what was going on.
I didn't actually investigate the issue
too deeply that it couldn't install
astro js, and what I did was make a
bit of a clumsy mistake of thinking
that this was all running locally on my
computer because I've been using crew
AI where a lot of the Python work is
local and part of your local environment.
So I gave it this.
Prompt saying, I'm using
ASDF, I'm using node 20.
Can you do an installation doing that?
And it tried to do that, and it
failed because what was going
on was, this is all running in a
Docker container and the Docker
container hasn't got ASDF installed.
It should have worked, but I couldn't
figure out what was going on initially.
what this led to.
Was the thought of, is this
costing me any money at the moment?
And what I found out was that five
minutes of playing around with this had
cost me $4 23 in open AI credits, and I
hadn't achieved anything at this point.
So I made a decision just to
abandon this and go to a simplest
solution just using HTML pages.
Moving on to example number two, which
was just to set up a simple HTML page
around this YouTube automation army.
what I did was developed a fairly
complex prompt where I was talking
about this agent framework where
transcripts from YouTube videos could
be processed by different agents.
I needed a couple of fields, the title
of the video, the transcript, a list of
agents that I would like to work with.
And a simple start button.
When the start button runs, the
agents would run and there'd be
events coming back and hopefully a
bunch of results from the agents.
with that all in place, I just
pasted it straight into open
Devon, and let's see what happens.
I.
Devon started running the new task
and it runs an LS command on the
workspace folder, and it figures out
that there's no files there, and you
can see that it's empty here from
here, it then moves on to a planner
and starts writing some code for you.
Open.
Devon is going to show you
the code in a terminal here
and also tell you what it did.
it says, current version of FliVideo
page has a transcripted title.
It's also got a agent selection
list and a start button.
After that, it started going
into a couple of errors.
I wondered.
What this was doing, and
this just kept going on.
If you go and look at the terminal,
you can see that there's big prompts
being sent, and this is step 12
at the moment, and that got me
thinking, is this costing me money?
I went over to the.
The costing and saw that 92 cents
had been consumed at this point.
what did we get for it?
We got this HTML page.
You can see the form here, and it tells
us the information that it's got going on.
Now, normally with a page being created
like this, what you would want to do
is go down to the bottom and type in a
new prompt, but I just stopped at the
server at that stage 'cause something
wasn't working and we were in a repeating
loop that could be quite expensive.
The last example is a continuation.
It's updating the page, but what makes
it a little bit different is that in the
past we had a workspace with no files, so
it knows how to create new applications.
In this case, there are files, so it can
assume that it's just taking the work
that's there and updating it further.
take the prompt that we had before.
I just made a couple of
modifications to the text.
I said, I've already created the
HTML page, and I told it what
sections that had gotten right.
I just added in down below where I'd
already had this information, told it.
This is the next section that I
want you to add into the system.
Now what it's done is said.
Open.
Devon is starting the new task of reading
in the index, HTML in the workspace, and
it's figured out that it needs to create
an event log and a GPT output sections.
What it does is try to work with
a file in a subdirecrtory called
workspace, and that was a bit of an
error, but it self-corrected With
now editing the workspace/index.html,
we've got a bunch of HTML.
The first section being
the event log is table.
The second section, GPT output is a
couple of rows just showing some JSON.
we look at the old form and
the new form is now added,
event log and the GPT output.
if we look at the costing for
this, we can see that cost 36
cents and it was quite successful.
I.
For evaluating whether this
is a good product to use, we
need to look at the costs.
So how much did this cost?
And for me, the first project,
which was a bit of a failure, the
astro js cost me $4 23, and I never
got an output that satisfied me.
The second one was a success, but then
it went into a little bit of an infinite
loop, and I stopped it at 92 cents.
The third one worked.
There was one error during the
process, but it self recovered
and that cost me 36 cents.
So all up this was a $5 and 50
cents using open AI GPT-4 credits.
Open.
Devon is very promising, but it
needs to be guided at the moment.
Otherwise you could incur some big costs.
I look forward to seeing
what they're going to do with
this over the next few weeks.
It could be a worthy contender
and alternative to Devon ai.
I'm AppyDave if you like videos on
ChatGPT coding with GPT or Prompt
Engineering, then like and subscribe
and I'll see you in the next video.