In this video, we're exploring how to get detailed information out of a long conversation
with a large language model. Because the problem that I often find is that I've got
information that it's forgotten about from earlier in the conversation, or when I
try to bring in information from earlier in the conversation. It brings in the information
that we explored but deemed irrelevant at the time, yet it still thinks it's important.
I'm AppyDave. I talk about prompt engineering, so please like and subscribe and let's
get into it.
Today, I'm in the middle of cleaning up a lot of my chats, and the one that I'm looking
at at today is synthesizing a conversation down to the raw information. Now, the
reason this is important for me is that I've got hundreds of chats over here on the
left. I've got a dozen projects going on, and one of those particular projects is
called FliVideo. And then when I go into FliVideo, I've got all these conversations.
A lot of them have the same information and I'm trying to bring this information
together. So what I thought I'd do is look at this particular one, which is called
project Naming Conventions for FliVideo, and see whether I can get all the information
that's in here and ignore some of the stuff that I said wasn't relevant when I was
doing the conversation. So that I've got a final markdown document that I can use
as knowledge for future chats.
I put chapter codes down below. If you want to move forward in the next step, what
we're going to do is look at the complex conversation. And this is important if you
want to understand all the details that are going into bringing this together as
one document. But if you just want to get straight to the prompts technique one is
where we cherry pick a little bit of the information and we use an advanced prompt.
Technique two is where we just use an advanced prompt and a application that I built
to grab conversations. And technique three is where I use a combination of ChatGPT
canvas and notebook.
Now the conversation we're looking at today is of medium size. It's not a large conversation,
but there's enough detail in it to test out some ideas. And when you look at my conversations,
they'll often start with information that I preload it with from previous conversations.
And what it's done in this particular case is figured out a bunch of information.
It's assuming that I'm working with project names for an organization. There's a
concept of a sequence number. The YouTube channel, which was an older channel called
AppyCast We got the name of the project, and we got the fact that it's got a status
of completed and it's worked out this information. Now, I know that this is not the
way I do things today. And further on in this conversation, we change things around,
and it's kind of getting to that end result of what the information really should
be while taking into consideration as my thoughts during the conversation that we're
trying to solve.
Now, the initial analysis in this conversation is that there was a sequence of project
code, a name and a status, and this was for a video project, but that there was also
the concept of multiple episodes within a video series, and that they would have
a sequence like the first, the second, the third, followed by the name of that particular
episode.
Now the conversation has shown some folder structure examples, whether it be for
a single video concept where I'll have individual recordings and particular chapters,
and there could be more than one recording for a chapter. And then it's got another
example for multiple episodes where it's pretty much the same structure, but they're
broken up into more than one episode, and this information is going to be really
important for me to keep
I asked it to write a requirements document and it wrote a whole lot of good and
useful information. I was able to read this and go, this is kind of what I want the
application to do. But then it came to a problem here is that it wrote a bunch of
code for me, which is great, except it's not in the programming language I want.
So I need to make sure that whatever final document we get is in the actual programming
language I need.
Next, I was asking the conversation to rename the project code to a channel code,
and I had codes for AppyDave coding. AppyDave the channel you're using right now.
AI-TLDR. FliVideo and Winning Prompts, which are all faceless YouTube channels, and
I needed to keep this information grouped.
the conversation adapted to understand that there were channel codes going on in
various locations.
so it was giving me an improved requirements document, but it was still keeping to
the Python implementation.
Now, if you've ever done a long conversation in a large language model, you've probably
seen these problems before where you get a diminishing return on the information
you put in because it's forgetting or changing information that you'd already talked
about. So let's try a couple of techniques and bring this back into alignment in
new chat windows.
So let's have a look at technique one and technique one. In this particular scenario
will probably work the best because I've got a fairly clean conversation and I kind
of know where it diverged. So what I've done is I'm just taking the last section
and I'm copying it into the clipboard for now,
and then what I can do is just head over to a new ChatGPT conversation and I'll say,
can you create a Readme document with the following information? And we can just
paste all that information that we've got. Now there's a capability within ChatGPT
of going to canvas mode. And this is a great way for creating documents, in this
case a requirements document. And you can see it just all coming together before
your eyes. Like this. Now one of the things I know should be wrong with this is there
won't be any code, because the section that I grabbed didn't have any code.
So we now have this nice consolidated document. All the information is fairly correct
except for the missing code. And we have a little copy button up in the right hand
corner which would give it to us in markdown. But what we can do now is just have
a little bit more of a conversation and make sure that the code is added to this
document.
Now the next thing I want to do is go back in the conversation to where there was
some code that was useful. Now the code is a fair way up and it doesn't take into
account certain newer concepts that are later in the document,
we'll take a copy of it and come back to our window where we said, can you update
the document with the example code? And we're about to paste that in. And I'll put
it in right here. But the next thing I've also said is it needs to be updated to
understand the concept of tags. 'cause I know that wasn't in the code. So we can
see that the document itself has all information with rules about tags, but the code
doesn't. So if we just press go on this, what should start to happen is we'll get
a rewrite of the requirements document. Nothing should really change. Everything
should be just the way it was originally written. But when we get towards the bottom,
I'm assuming we're going to get the code that I've pasted in modified so that it
understands the concept of flexible and optional tags.
So when we moved to the bottom, we've got an example in Ruby. It'd be important to
see if it's got tags. So we'll just do search. And anything yellow is actually indicating
that we've got tags in the code. And we've even got examples.
So technique number one has worked really well in this particular scenario. What
we can do now is just go over to our project.
This is the one we were using. We've got two options with this. We could either archive
it, but for now I'm just going to rename it and we'll just call it old. And that
just reminds me that I should archive it in the future or delete it.
Now let's look at technique number two. And technique number two is actually really
simple, but it doesn't always work depending on the length of the conversation. So
what we're going to do is we're just going to go to the top of the conversation,
go all the way to the bottom, and we've just shift selected it. And I've pressed
command C to put in my clipboard.
So with this technique, I've gone back to the FliVideo project and I've just put
in a simple prompt, summarize and synthesize the conversation into a coherent document.
Now, one of the things that we've got to do is make sure that it prioritizes the
stuff at the end, but considers the stuff at the beginning. So it needs to retain
key insights early on. And what we can do is just paste all the information, and
it's quite a long document into it and see what it comes up with. Now it's going
straight into canvas mode. I didn't have to tell it what to do, and we're getting
similar information to before.
So I think to test this, we'll just compare it to the other document that we created.
So the one on the right is our new document. The one on the left. Here is the old
document that we've generated with quite a bit of control in the process. And as
we look through it, they look to be very similar. So we've got a sequence channel
code and channel name over here. And we've got sequence channel code and project
name here. Then we've got what happens if the channel code is submitted. And we've
got that example here as well.
Now, as we move down this document, we start getting confirmation that this particular
prompt, which was easier, is actually working fairly well. And that's because we're
seeing the tag one and two. Now they both have the tag one and two. But this was
right at the very end of the conversation. There was a lot of information to read
beforehand, and it's still got it quite correct. It even included the correct tags
that we had in the examples, the CTA and the end cards.
We move further down to where the folder naming conventions are, and there seems
to be no difference between both of those.
So we'll come down to the message prompt, and we're just going to copy and paste
the one that we used in the previous example and see whether it updates it down the
bottom with this new code. So it's just doing the regular rewrite that canvas does
And we're about to hit the end where I'm assuming example code is about to be written,
and it's written it in a totally different fashion.
Just for my own peace of mind. I took all the information that's on the left and
just said, can you update the code with this? And it did it, and it did it in an
interesting way, which I'm happy with, in that it took the individual functions that
we can see all grouped together and put them into the correct spot. So everywhere
we're talking about an idea, there's one example of code that implements
and that keeps getting repeated all the way through to the bottom.
Now before moving on to technique three, let's just recap what we've done. So in
technique number one we cherry picked we firstly picked the end of the conversation
with a lot of information. Said write it in canvas. And then we manually added in
code from an earlier session with technique number two. This was a one shot prompt.
We just said read the entire conversation based on a couple of rules and recreate
it for us. And it did a perfect job as well. We did have to manually add the code
back in, but it did it in a unique and interesting way based on the first technique.
Now we're about to look at technique number three, which is a variation on the one
shot prompt but with different tooling. But I think it's at this point that it would
be good to go and have a look at these requirements documents and understand why
it's so important to create this sort of information.
So we know from the previous example that we could go and select all the information
and put it into the clipboard. But what if I told you I'd written a little application
using a requirements document that did this for me plus more? So what we can do here
is we can go and click on this little button up here and I've got this idea called
GPT conversation
can just press the extract conversation. And now the whole conversation is copied
to the clipboard. And the good thing is it's also labeled with information. So there's
the user with the content that the user said, followed by the agent with the information
that the agent said. But this could do more. We could send it off to another application
if we want. And the great thing is it was done with one prompt in about 10 minutes.
that's the power of these requirements documents. 'cause if you can write one of
these correctly, you don't need to be a programmer to write applications. You can
take information like this, feed it into an AI pair programmer,
And create an application in one, maybe two prompts. So what I've decided to do next
year in 2025 is reactivate a channel that I have called Winning
To solve simple automation problems that I have and other people have, using one
shot prompting and writing code
So if that's of interest to you then please like and subscribe over on Winning Prompts.
Now, let's check out technique three. We're still going to use a one-shot prompt,
but we're gonna use different tooling. So we'll come over and we'll click the Extract
Conversation. You could just copy all the text and put it into the clipboard, and
then head over to Notebook lm. Click on this button and it'll take you to a blank
setup. From here we can create, and what we need to do first is load it up with knowledge.
So we'll click on the paste text and we'll just paste everything in.
things to notice is that because we use the extraction tool, we'll we'll have access
to the user right here.
we've got two different participants in the conversation, the user and the assistant.
And I consider the assistant to be the one that wrote the document, but the user
guided it. So there's a little bit of influence that the user needs to have when
we start working with
And you'll see this pasted text. It's got a description of what's going on. And what
we'll do is we'll paste in the prompt that we used the last time, summarize and synthesize.
We want to make sure it prioritizes recent ideas over earlier stuff,
we'll just add a little bit extra to the prompt, just letting it know that the assistant
wrote the document, but the user's input is considered important. From there, we
can just let it start processing.
Now we have a very different outcome to the last two examples, in that we don't have
a requirements document in markdown format, but what we do now have is a well-analyzed
document. And we can go through and click on numbers here and go to the sources in
the document. You can also come down to here and have a look at specific areas. So
let's say we wanted to look at the project naming. We could click on that and it'll
just do a prompt into the conversation, discuss project naming. And now we've got
all the information related to project naming all in one spot. But the other good
thing is, as we click through on this, we can go and look at the sources around where
the episode name was conversed
So the ability to learn about your document is really easy to do in notebook LM.
Now let's see if we can convert it into a requirements document. So what we'll do
is write a technical requirements doc based on the analyzed content and format using
markdown.
sure you use short code examples related to the section of the requirements. So I
like that second version where we got the code with each bit of writing in the markdown
document, and we'll just let it run.
I've just brought it back to ChatGPT so that I can see it with similar formatting.
the document on the left is the Google LLM. I've just pulled it in and read it and
then converted it to markdown here. The one on the right is the one shot from ChatGPT.
And the main thing that I start to see is that they're very similar, but they do
write a little bit differently. So when we look at the overview, we've got everything
the same in both, except there is a little bit of extra information about talking
about supporting the reverse engineering.
The project naming is the same, slightly different formatting. There is a little
bit of extra information in the ChatGPT around an example, but it's essentially the
same.
Episode naming is similar, but the ChatGPT is a little bit better. It's got example
input ideas. It's also got better formatting, I think, for the output.
ChatGPT did a better job on the recording name. And then when we get down to the
folder structure, it has a folder structure, but we don't really get a folder structure
from the Google notebook LM otherwise a lot of things are similar. When we get to
the very bottom where we've got the non-functional requirements, we have that on
both, but we get a technical specification as well in the Google.
So ultimately the output from ChatGPT is a little bit better than the output from
notebook LM. But the fact that notebook LM has the ability for us to interrogate
information, and of course, the other tools like the podcasting means it's still
a useful tool. Just I wouldn't create the requirements document right now just using
this tool, if that's all I needed.
So an overview of what we've been doing is we've taken a complex conversation, and
we've tried to synthesize it into a new document. And the document in this case is
a requirements document, but it could be any sort of document. Now the first example
we did was cherry picking. So we picked the area towards the end of the document.
And then when we found it didn't have all the information we wanted, we added in
some extra code. Then after that, we went on to the one shot prompt. And in this
particular example, it did just as well. It was actually a really good job. It didn't
include the code, but we were able to add that manually. We then moved on and tried
a different technique, which is notebook LM, and it does nearly as good a job. It
also has the benefit that you can interrogate the document afterwards
but I don't think it proved to be better in the scenarios that we just tried with.
So in this video, we've taken this one complex conversation and converted it into
a single requirements document. But what I'd like to do in the next video is go through
multiple input sources and see if we can bring them in together, and end up with
one document that covers the whole project.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe. I'll see you in the next video.