In this video we're diving into the world of AI art with an epic showdown between
Dali 3 and Mid Journey 5.2. We'll explore 50 advanced prompts, 400 beautiful images and
I'll reveal when to use Dali 3 over Mid Journey.
But that's not all, I will show you how to get started and uncover 4 advantages that
Dali 3 has over Mid Journey. Get ready for a comprehensive journey into the AI art realm.
We can get started by comparing 50 prompts for Dali 3 versus Mid Journey 5.2.
I've set up a little application to test 50 different prompts. The number will show in the
bottom left of the display. Each prompt will start from a reference image which will show
about 4 images that were based off the original prompt. And the prompt that was used for the
reference image will show in the bottom here. So here we've got a cube cut out of an isometric
programmer's bedroom. From there I used my own Mid Journey account to regenerate the image myself
and then applied the same prompt within the new Dali 3 to see what it would look like.
And finally I created 4 different images for both Mid Journey and Dali 3 and as we go through them
I'll hover over these little buttons and we'll just see the different images as they come through.
So stay tuned as I walk through 50 different examples and along the way I will also dive into
some of the advantages that Dali 3 clearly has over Mid Journey but also some of the areas where
Mid Journey reigns supreme. So looking objectively at image prompt number one they're both excellent.
I think the graphics for a cube bedroom is really cool. I think this one is really cool as well.
The difference though is that this is meant to be an isometric programmer's bedroom and I don't see
anything in here to suggest that it is for a programmer. Here we've got a guy he's writing code
he's got two monitors so this is clearly a programmer setup. If we move on to the next
version the same thing again we've got this messy bedroom on the left it looks very technical
so it could be a programmer one but we've got a person sitting in front of a computer on the right.
Here on the third one clear again we've got a messy bedroom on the left we've got a clean and tidy
bedroom with three monitors going on. From a Mid Journey versus Dali perspective for number one
I'm leaning towards the Dali image. Let's move on to the second one four cats up here there is a cat
with a chain around its neck and a fish tattoo on it. Now when we look at Mid Journey this looks
pretty good there's a tattoo over here we look at the cat over here we've got a fish it's not
actually on the cat so maybe that's a little incorrect if we move through here we do have a
tattoo on the cat the fish is off to the side in this case and again the fish is off to the side.
I think what Dali has done is just a different style it looks really good I personally prefer
the Mid Journey one I think it got more accurate with this particular prompt but this is the sort
of things that we're going to discuss as we go through the 50 advanced prompts. Number three is
a virtual window Art Nouveau with colorful nature motives and we've got a big fox in the middle the
reference images look awesome they're great when we look at the Mid Journey I personally think it
looks closer to the reference image and it looks a little bit better the Dali three ones are great
as well they're just a different style all up they're both great personally I like the Mid Journey
number four we've got aliens and we've got an alien with a hand blurry shape focus foreground
when I look at these the hand looks human in this case so that's a bit of a problem going on here it
also looks a bit human here we've got some great images they're both pretty good they're pretty
good the one on the right from Dali looks a little better to me and then we've got this
with the hands kind of looking half alien half human so all pretty good whether it's Mid Journey
or Dali three so we have these two blonde gentlemen in pale gray vested suits club tie
Pomodor haircut staining with ketchup the images over here they they looked very consistent with
the reference as I moved through the different styles images from Dali three though a couple
of things to note is that it got the actual ketchup on the guy's clothes and I think this
looks awesome even though the ketchup hull are coming through on these pictures also look awesome
so they're both great one of the other things to note is that there are only three Dali three
images we got one two three and we moved to the fourth one and there isn't one and this was one
of the things I noticed the Dali three image generation is that you didn't always get four
images now with Mid Journey you you do always get four when you generate a prompt this stage you might
be wondering how can I use Dali three head over to bing.com slash create now that you know how to
set up and use Dali three let's move on as we move into number six we have this great reference
image but the actual prompt is written in Spanish if I move over to google translate we can see what
it stands for need sovereign probably steel avatar and looking back I think the Mid Journey
version that's come through when I did it looks quite accurate though the one from Dali three
kind of looks like the reference image and I'll go into a bit later how I got reference images
but as we move through and we look at others we've got these really interesting but totally
different images coming from Mid Journey and Dali three and I think they're both really good it's
really hard to decide which one I would prefer I guess it's intent would matter the most as we
move on to prompt seven we start looking at text on an image and here it's a sloth on the cover of
vogue the reference image had the word vogue there I don't know whether this was added after the
fat with Photoshop or something but the really interesting thing about Dali three is that it's
clear that we've got the word vogue and as I move through them it consistently got the word vogue
on all of them I believe that this doesn't always work but in this case it did
now the images from Mid Journey also look quite good to me but they're clearly not the intent
that was after which is a sloth on the cover of vogue and so for me that shows us one of the first
advantages that we see out of Dali three is that you can generate text I came across another prompt
that had a text component to it so if we move on to number eight we've got this translucent
glass AR headset designed by brawn at the moment these two images look quite amazing
but there's no text on them if we move to the second one though we can clearly see that brawn
is showing in the Dali image whereas Mid Journey one shows text but you can't read it if we move
over one more we've got it happening again for a second image in the set the third one didn't do
anything at all all of these images are brilliant but the fact that we're seeing text on the Dali
three is that advantage being shown again moving on to number nine we've got this cool reference
image of a female futuristic pop artist when we look at the Mid Journey version that I generated
using the same prompt we see a lot of similarity between the reference image coming out of Mid
Journey the images coming out of Dali three are also excellent they're just a different style
one of the things that I noticed with this one is we didn't get four images from Dali three we only
got three of them but this is again sometimes it doesn't return all four images to me these are both
brilliant examples of this prompt prompt number 10 is a cartoon in the style of tin tin comics
I look at both side by side they're pretty good no matter whether they came from Mid Journey or
whether they came from Dali three here I think they're both winners I mentioned earlier that I
was using reference images and the reference images where I would get the prompt from now let me show
you how I was sourcing this information essentially I was using either lexica or I was using the
showcase capability within Mid Journey and what that means is that if you go over to lexica.art
you'll have all these images that are curated by the community we can even see one here with Vogue
on the front but what I do is come and find something that I might like this image for example
and copy the prompt for every image I've done except for a couple where the reference is blank
I've taken a copy of the original URL and I'll put this in an article if you check in the link below
an article where you can go and find these original images now every image you're seeing up to this
stage have come from lexica but I also used for the rest of the images the showcase from Mid Journey
and Mid Journey showcase is an excellent location to get really good images you can hover over an
image that you like click on the person that created it and you'll see a list of their various
prompts and images and from here you can get the information one of the things I did and this happened
for about 30 of the images that we're seeing is that I copied both the prompt that's here
and any additional settings that were going on and I would try them in both Dali 3 and Mid Journey
now I doubt that these were the same way in Dali 3 but it was interesting that I could just copy
stuff verbatim and get really accurate representations with Dali 3 so if you're looking for some really
good prompts you can check out lexica or the Mid Journey showcase moving on to number 11 we have
an unreal engine scenic render of a rabbit in a Chinese coat when we look at the Mid Journey
image over on the left they look a lot similar to the reference images but everything coming out of
the right on Dali 3 looks pretty awesome in its own right I think these are a tie but to be honest
I'd be curious to hear what you think as I go through different images write a comment down
below of the number of the image and which one you think is the best what's your opinion as we move
on to number 12 we've got another tinting comic example but this time it's an architectural
picture it's a building in Tokyo as we move through all four of them they look excellent no matter
which system you used as we move on to number 13 we've got a very similar image because it's by
the same prompt offer like I said there'll be an articles if you want to go and find these people
I started finding as I went through this that I would follow the same offer over and over for a
few images they was just so brilliant at what they were doing a kudos to those people this is
another tinting comic we've got a lot of black and white coming through on the Dali 3 sometimes
on the mid-journey this was an example where Dali 3 didn't return the fourth image all up
these look great no matter what system you're using we move on to number 14 a symmetrical
burn owl we get images from mid-journey and Dali 3 which are both great they're just different
styles one of the things that you can do is test it out between different systems to get great
quality but different styling as I move on to number 15 we come across an example where the
results in Dali 3 and mid-journey don't actually match the reference image now I tried this a
number of times and we look at these four and we can see that there's nothing about them that look
like the reference image but every now and then mid-journey would give something similar to this
being very specific in language is still important whether it be mid-journey or Dali 3 in number 16
my tests again did not quite match the reference image but they were excellent attempts on both
Dali 3 and mid-journey that we're seeing across the board they're just brilliant it's got this
2d repeating pattern going each time as we move to 17 we see a clear winner in this case it's
mid-journey's ability to do really good images from simple prompts we've got this plain sort of
image over on Dali 3 and that just happened over and over with this particular example
but I will note that Dali 3 did get really good images most of the time this next example is both
really cool and just interesting how people think to go a dinosaur made of wool in a realistic
forest as we look at the mid-journey and the Dali 3 this one looks really cool that one's
pretty good but as we move through there's good quality images coming out of both systems if you
want to create a post star for a horror movie both Dali 3 and mid-journey are doing really good
examples get two different styles but they look pretty good no matter which way you go
I think it might be a good time to look at the next advantage of Dali 3 over mid-journey and
that's that you can use it for free within the Bing chat platform if we go back to our example
that we got here we'll copy the prompt and move into Bing.com and you need to click on the chat
window and what we can do is type in image of just pasting the prompt that we had press enter
and let's have a look at what it does now it's come up with I'm sorry but I'm not able to generate
that image and then it's making a statement your images generate so I wasn't sure what was going
to happen there this actually looks very similar to what we had if we move back it looks very much
like this version that we got on the right here in Dali is what we're seeing coming out of here
if you want to generate images today and you don't want to spend any money you can go straight into
Bing go into the chat functionality and you can create images there example number 20 is a great
example of seeing how mid-journey versus Dali 3 can do two totally different styles when trying to
generate graphics we have a reference image here of a pixelated cat and within mid-journey
it's quite detailed it's very artistic I think when I look at the one in Dali 3 we have more of this
8-bit pixelation the sort of stuff that you might have seen in a computer game in the 80s and as I
scroll through them the various versions the ones on the left look incredible they're very cool
but if I wanted this as an 8-bit representation the one on the right looks better admittedly I could
probably get the 8-bit representation by putting that into the prompt but I just like that you can
test it in both systems and get really different but cool examples advanced prompt comparisons
are great but before we analyze number 26 I think we should talk about another advantage
that Dali 3 clearly has over mid-journey and that's the ability to use it directly from chat gpt plus
now I'm in chat gpt plus I'll hover over the gpt 4 and go to Dali 3 beta now my prompt is
create image of and we'll just paste in the number 26 example which is a mid-journey prompt
and one of the things that we should note is that it's got the word dungeon in here this worked out
great in Dali 3 and mid-journey but there may be issues with certain words within chat gpt at the
moment it's creating the image we've got one coming through at the moment here's the second one in
production now the third and hopefully the fourth will come through it's very slow compared to Dali
3 and the exact issue that I was worried about there's a content policy in the words we've used
I can expect to a simpler pixel art cat we'll see what that does these are great but it shows the
differences between Dali 3 and Dali 3 in chat gpt is that there is a content policy issue that we've
got to deal with prompt number 26 looks great in mid-journey 5 and Dali 3 but we did see the
issue of using it from chat gpt now looking further into this it could be the word dungeon
but it's most likely the man repressed with agony is not getting through the content policy issues
within chat gpt but when we look at the images that are here in Dali 3 they look really good to me
they're just a different style to what we're seeing out of mid-journey but these are excellent
examples this next incredibly impressive reference image looks great within mid-journey and Dali 3
as we hover through similar styles I would say they're looking great but we've got options now
next we have beautiful oil paintings of majestic animals and they're looking good whether it's
here mid-journey whether we've got Dali it's funny that we've got lions on both sides here
we've got horses on both sides here and these images are just being displayed in the order that
they were generated next we have a reference that Dali 3 did not get correct in this case
an 80 year old beautiful Dobie now Dobie is a character from a Harry Potter novel we've got
the picture here and we look through it this one looks great 80 years of age and we move through
and Dali 3 is presenting a dog each time which is interesting so it didn't get the prompt threat
if I tried again maybe it would work okay that's something that happens in mid-journey anyway
it doesn't always get it right the first time now the Dobie example is looking odd in both
mid-journey and Dali 3 in another attempt so we've got a photo of Dobie in Prada outfit and as we
scroll through I'm not sure the reference point of this what it's meant to be but we're not seeing
Dobie the character from Harry Potter but we are seeing Harry from Harry Potter in the Dali 3
another good thing here we can see Prada being written across the shirt so clearly a Prada
outfit going on if we move through we've got Harry Potter again we've got some sort of dog
Harry Potter look tell me in the comments whether you know what this is I didn't understand the
reference of a dog to the term Dobie maybe I'm just missing something here in keeping with the
catwalk star we move back to seeing the sloth again I love these sloths in these generations
as we move through them they're pretty good whether they're Dali 3 or mid-journey generally
these are looking quite amazing before we talk about the next prompt of Vernon Dursley from Star Wars
I think it might be good to have a look at the next advantage that Dali 3 has and that's the
speed and the user experience within the Bing create application now to start off with mid-journey
doesn't actually have an application for which you can generate images in instead it's a system
within a discord server so you have to understand how to use discord if we find our image of Vernon
Dursley we've got him here we've got individual images here now I have about three and a half
thousand images if I want to go back and find certain images it's quite difficult within discord
one thing I can do once I've got an image generated like this and from the web interface I can click
on my username when we get to here you can see all the different images that I've been generating
over time so I really have to use two different systems when I'm working that way the other problem
is if I scroll all the way to the bottom I've generated the pixelated cat again that's a pretty
easy thing to do to generate an image the first time but once you want to play around with settings
you can understand that there's a settings command and there's all these little commands that you
need to memorize or have cheat sheets for whereas if this was an application they could just be
buttons on a screen that you just click so let's contrast this with the Bing create application
we're here in Bing create I'm signed in I've got 92 credits we've got a little search idea of
different images by different creators but what I can do is we'll type in the pixel art cat we'll
do a create on that one of the things I've noticed about Bing create versus mid-journey is that
generally this is a fair bit quicker we've also got access to some images that we've done recently
we've got our pixelated cat coming up we don't have the quick shortcuts that are in mid-journey
of doing a variation on 1 2 3 or 4 directly from this interface but we can click on to an image
and from here we can do something like a customization this has pulled us into another app in the
Microsoft ecosystem called Microsoft Designer there's different stuff that we can do here
but if we go back to the image creator app we might think it's quite minimal at the moment
there's a lot more you can do if you understand the command structure of mid-journey but being
an app this is easily expandable and I'm sure we're going to see features added basically shortcuts
to do common tasks within the Bing creator application I've been pushing the advantages
of Dali a little bit too much let's bring it back to reality I still like mid-journey from an image
creation point of view because generally it does a little bit better than what we're getting out of
Dali 3 if we look at it here we've got the pixelated cat that's within the Bing creator application
we can also see the same sort of image coming out of chat gpt the fact that we can use it in chat
gpt is awesome and I certainly like this fourth image from the chat gpt example but if we go over
to mid-journey what we see here is a far more stylized version of a cat I think for the time being
the advantages of mid-journey is it you've got a little bit more fine control over the creation
process within the prompts I think Dali 3 is really catching up but stay tuned we got more
advanced prompts to look at and we've got one more really big advantage that lives with Dali 3
so we're back on number 32 it's Vernon Dursley as a Star Wars sci-fi robot and when we go through
the different versions we've got an image here where I don't think it looks like Vernon Dursley
out of Dali 3 moving forward they are a little bit closer here so they're all pretty good maybe
mid-journey is better in this scenario number 33 is a snow owl as a Star Wars Ewok this looks great
no matter which system you use so both mid-journey and Dali 3 are doing really good renditions of
this particular prompt if you ever wondered what the anatomy of Voldemort looked like both mid-journey
and Dali 3 have you covered I think the mid-journey versions are a little bit more stylized but we've
got really good pictures in both applications if you ever wondered what the world of a wizard
might look like then this generalized prompt on wizarding looks pretty good in both mid-journey
where we have what looks like a wizard here we've got this fantasy landscape when we look at the
reference image that we moved through mid-journey does it pretty well on the second version it also
does it pretty well on the fourth version in between it's got something totally different
but the images coming out of Dali 3 are also great each time we go through one I think the nature of
this generalized sort of prompt we've got there's nothing too specific in here has led to various
variations that are looking good in both systems this next prompt was a good example where Dali 3
doesn't always render out all the images correctly so we've got reference image here it looks very
close in the mid-journey version it's pretty good in the Dali 3 version but when I move to the next
one we do not have any more images out of Dali 3 maybe you're looking to come up with a design for
a silk scarf now this next example looks great in both mid-journey and Dali 3 as we move through
maybe the mid-journey version has a little bit of the edge but they're good in both systems
this next stunning prompt of a wall carving made out of wood it's a mountain looks great in both
Dali and mid-journey my preference is definitely the mid-journey version I think it looks better
but I'm curious when you look through these do you prefer what's coming out of Dali 3
or do you like what's coming out of mid-journey this next version of robots with flowers looks
excellent in both Dali 3 and mid-journey but we get two fundamentally different styles as we move
through we've got the same robot on the left each time we've got the same robot on the right
but they're very different sort of looks and the same thing happens with this Asian river boats
mountains we've got two great looking images just a little bit different in the stylization
between Dali and mid-journey you can see that repeated on the next version where we've got
these nice mountain river sort of scenes going on here now before we look at a bunch of cats
on a wall I want to talk about the number one advantage that I'm looking for that will be in
Dali and that's the access to the API now this will be a game changer because this means that
those cool images that we've been looking at will be able to integrate into our applications
I think the easiest way to demonstrate what I mean is by looking at a little bit of code I wrote here
it's very simple there's essentially a size of image it'll be a thousand pixels square the next
thing is it'll print out both the prompt and the URL where the generated image will live
and hopefully it will open it up in a chrome browser for us so if we go up to this area called
prompt and we'll put in pixel art cat I think that would be a great way to go and we hit save
a little bit of code will run to generate that image against the open AI endpoints and it's printed
out a couple of URLs and if I head over to my chrome window we will see a version of a pixelated
cat now you might be thinking that doesn't look very good and the reason that doesn't look so good
is because it's using version 2 of Dali now I went and had a look online and three days ago
this question was posed how do we get Dali 3 access to the API and the reality is it's not there yet
but I'll just state that as soon as the Dali 3 API is available the ability to have these cool looking
animals represented within your application by potentially just changing the prompt pressing
go and seeing a new image up here is exactly what we're going to see very soon you've seen so far
that Dali 3 has closed the gap on mid journey in terms of image quality generally the mid
journey images can be a little bit better but when it comes to this API if mid journey don't get
applications that use images so I went and had a look to see whether mid journey have a plan to do
this because this has been the number one feature that developers have wanted from mid journey now
there's a statement here that there may be an API coming out and I assume they have to do it if
Dali and open AI are going to release an API coming back to prompt number 42 I said before
the API section that this was about cats because I was looking at this reference image that looks
like cats but the prompt clearly states dogs and that is what we see here these are really cool
images of dogs so these are just different styles going on as we move through these look a little
bit human cat like this one looks a bit human like here we've got dogs on both sides so pretty
impressed with the images coming out of both systems here if you stayed around to advanced
prompt number 42 you might be looking at this little application that I've got here and wondering
what is it how did I do this and this is an application that I've put together it has concepts
like changing to different images we can click and go to the next image in the list they fade in
we've got a Dali 3 image zooming out we've got a mid journey image zooming out and again we can
just move from image to image and ideally I should be able to just modify the prompt and if we had the
API that we talked about a moment ago should be able to press a button and see the images change
in both systems and you're going well how do I get access to this well if you stay tuned to the
end of the video I'll talk about how I put this together briefly and how you might be able to do
it for yourself
you
50 advanced prompts for mid journey 5.2 versus Dali version 3 now as promised I said I might
talk a little bit about the application I use to demonstrate all this information and it relates
very much to what this channel is about the channel is not about image generation it's about
prompt engineering for use in business and I focus on three areas one is writing code using
prompt engineering two is writing content whether it be marketing content business content and the
third area that I focus on is YouTube automation because what I'm trying to do is build up a
YouTube channel and I'm trying to automate my processes but let's have a look at this application
and how it came about so here we have a little bit of code that I've written it's all through here
and it's producing the page that you're looking at and you may have noticed earlier that my image
my talking head was showing up in this little area here where it's currently brown and I did that by
adding a little bit of code into the system called chrome they're just here which is applying the
green color and this allowed the video to come through as a green screen but if I take it a
little bit further and we'll look at these labels so we've got mid journey 5 to dali 3 and we've got
reference these parts of the application are editable by me so I could change it to something
like api dave and this would be the channel that I use for writing prompts and chat gpt custom
instructions when it comes to coding or I might have winning prompts and I want that to show on
the screen and this is where I do prompt engineering in general and I'm specifically trying to do
youtube automation and that's where I do fly video so as I run four different youtube channels
api cast where I do the behind the scenes fly video where I automate myself winning prompts
where I work through custom gpt instructions and api dave where I do chat gpt coding this
is the sort of tooling that I'm building now I did not write this from scratch what I did was I
wrote gpt custom instructions for areas to do with programming and this whole application was created
on top of astro and tailwind css and the custom instructions allowed me to use documentation
that was live off the internet and if I just scroll through here we see lots of code being
generated this took me a little bit of time to do but what's the interesting is that I didn't need
to put on my programming hat to build an application I could put on my gpt hat now I am a programmer
I've been writing code for about 40 years since I was 11 and professionally since I was 17 so I do
know how to code but these days I like to do all my coding using chat gpt is a very interesting
space to explore I think anyone that's interested in future proofing their jobs
needs to figure out how they currently do what they do using AI thank you for staying till the end
if you're interested in something to do with chat gpt or prompt engineering or how you can
automate yourself in business then have a look at one of these videos up in the corner
you