Devon is a fully autonomous AI software developer by Cognition and in this video we are going
to look at six different use cases, four different risks that you need to be aware of and the
easiest way to get access to it. Cognition Labs just announced Devon, the world's first
autonomous AI programmer. In this video we will look at six different examples. The first
will be the HTML JavaScript one, then we will go on to a couple of Python examples, one
for building AI models, the other for making money on Upwork. After that we will look at
a C++ example with unit testing, moving into Rust where we will look at adding a feature
into an existing repo. Finally look at the React game of life example. Then show you
how to get access to Devon plus a simple tip that might make it easier for you to get it quicker.
After that we will look at four different challenges to do with Devon or AI programmers in
general and that will be around the areas of cybersecurity, creativity, the complexity of
the software development life cycle and the big issue, will it take my job? Let's have a look
at what Devon can do and the first example is about creating secret messages within images
and the developer that used this, Sarah, had asked the question can you read this URL, it's an
article and follow the instructions. Devon had said absolutely I can do that. Do you want me to
generate images and what text would you like it to have? And she's put in Sarah, Devon and Cognition.
Now Devon has come over and opened up the article that was given and from there followed the
instructions from the article. It started writing a bit of code and installing some setup and one
of the things that happened was it ran into an error during setup. You can see down in the
bottom left that it went off to a different website to figure out what the problem was before
writing code. It was able to generate this image with Sarah and it moved on to create one with
Devon and another one with Cognition. The next example is using Devon to train an AI model and
what they've done is they've got this repo here about clora, efficient fine-tuning of
quantised LLMs and they've taken the URL and put it into a prompt within Devon saying can you
fine-tune a 7B Lama model using and then they just provide the link. There should be instructions
in the readme file so there's the assumption that it will go off and read the readme file. Now
from there it's figured out that it needs to clone the repo, set up the environment using PIP and
then it followed the instructions in the readme file. During setup it ran into a problem and it
needed to reinstall the bits and bytes for cuter compatibility. It was able to start running the
training of the model. Training went for about an hour and at the end you can see the progress with
decreasing loss indicating successful model fine-tuning. This next example is really interesting. It's
about adding a feature to an existing open-source repo and the repo is written in the Rust
programming language. It's called Mprots and what it does is monitor services that are running
or processes. You can see here there's this message called down, down, down, down and someone wants
to make this a bit clearer to see exactly what's going on. Now there was already an issue in the
issues register of the repo so they thought can we use this just to build the code that's needed.
A simple question. Write a fix for this issue that's pasted in the URL. Do not commit or push your
changes. It's gone and read the readme file for Mprots. It's installed the dependencies and then
it's decided to use a browser and open up the issue that needs to be implemented. From this it's
been able to write a little bit of Rust code. Now it ran into a few issues and then decided to go
off and read the Rust documentation to figure out how to resolve the issue. From there you can see
the old version of the user interface and then the new version with a little bit more clarity around
what is actually down. After that it was able to create a pull request. Now this next example is
really exciting. It's firstly an Upwork side hustle but the other thing about it is it's using a
Vision AI model. If we look at the job ad what we've got here is make inferences with a computer
vision model. Now the company that posted the ad pays around 23 US dollars an hour for the code being
written. What they've done is they've included this repo to use as a reference so we've got the repo
here. We read through this and we can see that there's Road Crap Detection Challenge 2020 so
it's not even recent and then there's a whole lot of examples including checkpoints. Basically it's
trying to identify where there are cracks in the road pavement. Now rather than reading or
understanding this particular repository all the prompt is I am looking to make inferences with
the models in this repository. Paste in the URL and say please figure it out. Devin goes ahead and
makes a plan of action. We've got these things like clone a repository, read the documentation,
so on and so on. It starts setting up the repo and asks a few questions over on the left. It
ran into an issue. You can see that in the red and it's gone and figured out what the problem was.
The problem was a dependency was out of date so it's gone and fixed that and then downloaded
sample images. It's then started to do an interactive debugging on the code that it wrote.
You can see that it wrote some console logging to solve some problems. It also removed the console
logging before deploying the final code. It was then able to come up with a fix for little issues
that were going on and then ran the image model. From there we get these outputs where we can see
that cracks in the road are being used on new images. This really interesting C++ example
is based on a repo for a competitive programming setup. Someone has come up with an error stating
that in a particular scenario an edge case the code doesn't actually work. The programmer involved
has gone and manually made a change to the code here but now he wants to put in some unit tests
to see if everything is working okay. He's come over to Devin and said I need a test. Basically
read my repo, have a look at the function involved and start thinking about what you need to do.
While he's doing that he's writing the actual requirements for the test so he's listed on
all here. Devin has started writing the code and it ran into a compiler error in what it had to
implemented so it figured out how to resolve that. You can see the fix in here it's an include statement
and basically it was able to get the test running but because this was a function with many sorts of
values that needed to be tested the programmer then went on to say can you do a brute force
testing can you iterate over many different combinations of values let's just see if the
tests work here. One of the examples failed now with that being uncovered Devin was able to go
through put in a bit of console logging to see what is the particular problem going on here
and it found in one particular example there was a negative number it knew it needed to be fixed
it wrote a bit of code to fix that particular edge case and then finally the code ended up running.
Last coding example is about setting up the game of life in a react project we've got this prompt
here in Devin it's gone through and started to create a react application and set up the front
end environment in react and chakra ui it's also added the p5.js library it went straight on to
deploying this code to netlify and we got to see just what would happen when it rendered.
One of the things I was confused of when looking at the example initially was
this is great but why where's the actual code for the game I looked a little deeper into it I can
see that what they were doing was using code from the p5.js I'm assuming Devin went and found all
this particular code and then later on the developer in the example starts showing a little bit of
the code behind the scenes here we've got the game of life code written in javascript and from
there he had a bug that needed to be sorted see on the left 180 there was a bit of a freeze at the
three second mark Devin went in resolved that particular problem but then he asked for it
to make it a little bit more interactive can I click in areas and have the game of life start
here's the game at the beginning we got Devin and then it starts expanding out as it progresses
and then clicking with the mouse we start to see new areas of the game of life being drawn in
different places now if you want to access Devin for yourself what you need to do is go over to
cognition labs and you'll see this little form here where you can join the waitlist now when
you're filling it out it's important that you give them good details because there will be a
selection criteria with this one of the fields just under the company is a prompt that you need
to write for what sort of application you want to build now the one I did is here I basically
wanted content creation application using GPTs but if you want to create your own prompt from
scratch what I suggest is you look at a prompt like this can you write a prompt for an AI programming
bot so this is not a prompt for GPT this is a prompt for Devin in this case the goal is to turn
and whatever your goal happens to be I've then given it a little bit of context about what the
software needs to do we have a couple of examples after that I put in some constraints so in this
case note you don't need to write prompts for the GPTs this is to run locally so I've told
at the architecture or at least the platform that it's running on lastly want Devin to actually
interact with me I don't always want programming bots to go off and do their own thing if you write
a prompt similar to this but fill in your own details it will then go and create a detailed
prompt that you can give as part of the application form let's address the elephant in the room and
that's the risk and fears of working with AI autonomous programmers and the big one is going
to be cyber security there's a big issue at the moment with repos on github being cloned
and then having malicious code added into them how would it be if the bot that you're using
happens to download something that has malicious code in it and it runs locally or it introduces
it into the program you're using the next issue is just the creative limitations of working with AI
programmers they just really don't get a lot of more esoteric issues so what language do I want
to use what architecture what patterns do I want to use have I thought of this particular edge case
these are the sorts of things that the programmer really needs to be involved or other sorts of
designers and testers that then leads into the software development lifecycle and the complexity
especially in an enterprise like how would it be if two different AI bots one's writing it for
one programming language versus another another one's using restful APIs while another one's
using grpc there's all sorts of issues and there can be monetary issues let's say a bot
decides to use open AI endpoints another one uses google endpoints and suddenly the business
units are going how do we pay for this are we paying for this one or are we paying for this one
these are the sorts of problems that need a lot of guidance then when we look at the issue
of job displacement I think what we're going to see is this idea where that you'll have lots of
computer programmers humans whether they be designers testers software developers and all
they're doing is working hand in hand with AI bots I'm happy Dave and if you see AI automation bots
and gpt as a solution which is how I felt for the last 18 months where I put all my energy in here
then come and check out my gpt academy this is where I'm helping people in small groups
either with prompt engineering or prompt engineering for coding