You had trouble researching complex
topics with ChatGPT because you
can't feed it enough information.
In this video, I use custom prompt
instructions to allow research on a
variety of documents while maintaining
short-term memory within the ChatGPT bot.
A couple of weeks ago, a product
called Open Interpreter started
gaining popularity and I realized I
needed to figure out what was going
on with this particular project,
do a little bit of research.
I also wanted to create a video, and I
noticed that there were a lot of people
starting to talk about this product,
and I wanted to listen to the video.
But also put the transcripts through
ChatGPT and a combination of those
transcripts and the documentation
from the project itself was something
that I need to do research on.
There are a few different ways
to research complex documents in
ChatGPT, but the one I'm going to work
with today is custom instructions.
And at the moment I've just started
with this simple little idea to
outline what I'd like to achieve.
What we'll do is start with a
GPT 4 blank slate, and we go down
to our settings where we can.
And put in custom instructions and
I'll just paste the outline that I did.
this is not exactly what I wanna say.
In fact, I don't know the exact prompt at
the beginning of this session because I'm
going to work through it as I develop and
do my research on the particular video.
the main things.
I know I need this custom instruction
to do each time is it needs to
understand the topic that we are
working with and maintain it.
it needs to comprehend new information
coming in and feed it into a simple
information structure that it has a
long-term memory as I do my research.
I don't want it to waste energy trying to
tell me information I don't care about.
I'll ask the questions.
It should just give me simple
replies I will need it to
work with specific commands.
I believe I'll need to add documents.
I might need to break documents appart
and feed 'em in because they're too big.
Sometimes I'll want to get information
of the current state of the second
brain, the second brain being the
information that it's maintaining for me.
I'll move forward and start
writing a custom instruction
and we'll see how it works.
When we look at this first statement, I
realized that the starting point is to let
it know that it's my research assistant.
When we look at you'll need to be
reading and comprehending my documents.
I think the prompt we can put in
here would be something like you will
maintain a document outline and summarize
the information you have collected.
the next step would be to do a
document title, but I really want
to get into commands right now
while they're still in my head.
The thing about maintaining a summary
of information is that ChatGPT doesn't
always maintain the right information,
and I believe I'm going to need some
commands that I can use to tell it
what's really important, what's just
generally important and what is not.
Of use to me right now,
basically a command to ignore
certain pieces of information.
So let's go and think about
the commands we might need.
The first command I've added
here is just called add.
I guess I would like to type ADD: and
then just paste in a transcript and have
that transcript added into the document.
First command we would need would be
to add information to the document
I've put in this ad followed by ad
provided information to the document.
Now, I suspect that when I add
information to the document it might
get things a little bit wrong, and I
think what we could try is a command
called drop, and that will be, if I
give it some extra information, it
just drops that from the main document.
As the document develops, I'm sure there's
going to be like a list or an outline.
So we will add a new command called
T O C for table of Contents, and
essentially I just want to get
the table of contents based on
the document that it's maintained.
This table of contents will help me
understand things, but there'll be
times when I need the detail as well.
We'll add a command called detail
that just shows the entire document.
I suspect that from time to time
I'm going to want it to just give
me its opinion on certain concepts.
When it does that, I don't want the
information added to the document.
I do wanna be able to
evaluate that information.
I also don't want it to write an essay,
so I'm believing something like 50
words might be good, and from time to
time I need to change that as well.
we'll create a command called Q 50 What
it will do is I give it a question.
It'll gimme a 50 word answer.
It won't add it to the document,
and I'll also let it know that
it, can accept other numbers?
I might do Q 30 for 30 words
or Q 100 for a hundred words.
We need to maintain a title we
haven't dealt with that yet.
Maintain and update the
document on research.
We've got that covered.
Provide simple replies.
I'm gonna have to write a prompt for that
soon and respond to specific commands.
We've got most of them in place.
I'll just add one other
we'll put in the title.
Or command this, I would start the
research with, so we have a title.
One of the things that I think will
happen as I research information
is I might want to update the title
based on new information coming in.
this command should be able to create
or update a title on the fly means
we can finally just delete these
pieces of information and let's
figure out how we'll write this.
Prompt deal with how GPT
responds to each of our commands.
There is a section called How would you
like GPT to Respond, which we can fill in.
Essentially, I want to take the
ADD and the DROP command and
make sure it just says, 'YAY'.
I do not need any other information
other than an acknowledgement.
That it's added or removed
it from the document.
When it comes to the table of contents or
the details, it's going to have to give
me the information I want, but I don't
want any other additional information.
lastly, with the question, it can
write whatever it likes so long
as it's 50 words or 30 words.
prompt that I'm going to
put in here looks like this.
Do not give any additional information
for simple commands like add and drop.
Say Yay for table of contents,
write that for details.
Write that and for question, you
will gimme an A answer to the
question in that number of words.
I do know that ChatGPT will
sometimes still give other.
Common phrases around the document
and I may need to come in here and
tell it not to do that, but for now,
this is where we're going to start, I
wanna find out whether it understands
what its role is, what is your role,
press enter, see what it comes up with.
My role is to be your research assistant,
I will maintain a document outline and a
summary of information I have collected.
I will respond to specific commands
such as ADD DROP, TOC DETAIL, Q50
and TITLE as per your instructions.
This is looking good so far.
Let's put in a title.
We'll head on over to the website,
copy the term open interpreter,
and just paste it in, says she.
Perfect.
the documentation around this tool
is that it's a code interpreter
to run locally on your computer.
There's a whole lot of
information in a Read me file.
If I open up that read Me
file in raw format, there'll
be a bunch of information.
It would be nice to strip out the.
H T M L.
But essentially I should just be able
to take a bunch of this raw information,
but not too much because ChatGPT can only
take a certain amount of information.
Head over to ChatGPT.
We'll give our ADD command and we'll
just paste this information in we've got
a response of 'YAY', which is perfect.
I think it might be time
for a table of contents.
we have a partial information.
I haven't read through the documentation,
but this seems to be about right.
Let's head back to the read me file and
we'll grab another chunk of information.
not too much.
We'll get to about here,
I think back to G P T.
We'll put in, add and paste that new
information  type TOC there's definitely
more information coming through.
Just adding a final little bit of
information that I missed at the
bottom, just a little bit of coding.
Information.
At this point, I'd like to see what
detail I can get out of the document.
I don't know that I'd get all the
information from the Readme file
because there's too much information
in the form of tokens, but since
this has been summarizing and keeping
detailed information, we'll just
type in detail, see what we get, and
it's starting to write out a couple
of commands that's going to show us
how to use it, access to the demo.
We've got a.
Quick start, guide, and commands.
This is all looking pretty good and I
could probably use it just as it is as
a question and answer bot to install
and start using this particular project.
But in the next step, what I'd like to do
is watch a couple of the videos by some
of the other people on YouTube and see
how they're working with open interpreter.
My research bot is currently loaded
up with the documentation from code
interpreter, but what I'd like to
do now is take some videos from
YouTube, grab their transcriptions and
load them into my research as well.
the way I've done that is I've used
the ADD command that we already
had access to, and I've added
these transcription summaries we.
Have one here, another one
here, and they just keep going.
I keep adding transcription summaries into
the research, but you might be wondering
how did I get a transcription summary?
And the way I did that was by running
YouTube transcriptions through my
transcription summarizer Bot to
do the transcription summaries.
I actually had to have videos in
which to transcribe, so right here I
have a video called Open Interpreter,
open Source version of ChatGPT.
It's a 13 minute video, and if I move
through the different videos that I
researched, I had all these different
people in the last two weeks who have
been doing detailed videos on open
interpreter, you can grab a transcript
and copy it into a text file, and
I did it for each individual video
that I came across so that I could
use it within the YouTube transcript.
Bot.
from the point of view of the research bot
in which I've added all these different
summarizations, we then need to move over
to one of the YouTube transcription bots.
Here's one on open interpreter.
We've got a summary
here and at the bottom.
I can copy it move it to the original
bot, I just repeat that for each of the
YouTube transcriptions that I want to do.
I grab the information I want, but you
might be wondering where is the YouTube?
Transcription bot.
let's head over to a new ChatGPT
window, and I'm just gonna paste in this
little prompt here called What role and
instructions have I assigned to you?
this is a YouTube transcription bot.
I've preloaded it.
You have assigned me the role of
YouTube transcription assistant.
I can read through transcriptions and
build a detailed document, which is the
goal that I needed for the research,
but it's got similar sorts of commands,
like ADD, DROP, STORIES I can ask.
Questions.
It hasn't listed a particular
command called titles.
I can generate a bunch of YouTube
titles based off the transcript,
this is basically how I make bots
work with one another just using
various custom instructions.
if you want to understand how I built this
particular custom instruction, I'll put a.
Link in the description.
Now we're back at our original research
bot, and I'm just gonna put in a quick
prompt, what is your role and command?
I just want us remember what
I've got available here.
It's to be a research assistant.
We can add, drop, and
get table of contents.
we should do a detail and see what all
the different information that we've
added to the bot has done for us from
this detailed command, we've got a fairly.
Extensive master document
that's been created.
We've got this limitations
for big data, git repository,
cloning, community engagement.
If we move through, there's
additional documents that are
being summarized and added into.
Of the main document open
interpreter, YouTube video analysis.
We've got information here.
If we keep going down,
we've got another one.
One of the things that I notice is a
lot of the commands from the original
instruction guide from GitHub are
missing, but we may still be able
to get them out, let's see if we can
get the setup instructions for open
interpreter, and I could do a Q 50.
I might even just be able to get
away with a regular prompt, but
I'm going to try this one first.
It was one of the commands I set up.
Can you give me a setup
guide to create my own?
Open interpreter.
the great thing about that is it's
just given me the 50 word summary.
Let's do the same prompt
again without the command.
this looks like it's given us a
more detailed list of instructions
that we can run from the terminal.
To set up open interpreter.
I don't tend to do too many more
commands from the research, bot
generally once I've done my research,
I'll take that information over
to other bots, but it doesn't stop
us from doing standard prompts.
What we'll try here is can you
create an engaging YouTube script
based on the detailed document.
, normally I would take that to the YouTube
script and title bot, but let's say.
What it comes up with.
here we have a YouTube script.
Let's look at this intro.
B roll with upbeat music.
Sounds about right.
Hello everyone.
Welcome back to the channel if you
are passionate about AI coding and
game changing technology, and smash
the light button and hit subscribe.
Today we're diving deep into something
that's been buzzing on social media.
Open interpreter, Gary Marcus
himself tweeted about it.
So you know, it's a big deal.
I know that statement did actually come
out of one of the transcriptions that I.
Watched.
is this the way I would write a script?
No.
And that's why I would have a YouTube
script writing set of prompts designed
and feed the information into them
instead so that I can get the style.
But the good thing is this is a pretty
good script, just of its own accord.
This has been a deep dive into
the researcher bot a custom
instruction prompt that you can
use for research and development.
It's also part.
Of a set of advanced prompts that I've
been developing, and they're part of
a podcast that I'm putting together.
You should be able to find information in.