The purpose of this session is to use a combination of MindMeister and your website
to relay requirements through to Gene. Is that correct?
Yeah, basically, yes. Because I was trying to write out what I wanted her to change on my website.
I was handwriting it and you were saying no, you just blame her.
The website.
She's about to come on in. Hi Gene.
Hello Gene.
Hi. Hello everyone. Hi David. Hi Sir Harry.
How are you?
Doing good.
So I got to give you some context of what we're doing today, Gene.
I'm bringing you involved into this because I think it's good for you to understand this process as well, okay?
Okay.
I've had the development over here and what we're going to change this to 26 of Gene requirements.
And what we're going to be doing with this mind map is giving a list of tasks or actions
for you, Gene, to do. So they'll be listed like this. Action number one.
Then there'll be action number two. And if there are sub points, A, B, C, X, Y, Z.
What you've got as capability within MindMeister is the ability to add emojis.
So if we go over to this little emoji button over here on the right.
So you click on the emoji button here and then you click the emoji here.
And I like to use the green, the orange and the black.
What I'm trying to convey here is that this action has not been done or maybe you've got
another rule that you want for black. This action has been done.
This action is partially done. And maybe we can from a sub action go,
this one is done, but this one is not done. Okay.
Why I like this as a technique is that it's like a project management tool.
It's very visual in nature. It's not good for bigger projects,
but it's very good for a task-oriented set of steps that we want to do through the week.
Then the second thing that we want to do is, and we'll pop this over on the left, I think,
is we'll have visual definition of what we want to work through.
So let's just shrink that down a little bit. How do I go into the admin at slash WP admin,
is it? Yep, correct.
That's a WordPress site. Though that was actually incorrect, I'm going to press
escape because we are really only interested in the signed in user view of things.
So if I'm a signed in user, how do I see my profile right?
Okay. If you are a signed in user, you can go to the dashboard.
So I'm clicking on my dashboard.
Yes. And then you can either, yep, that's all the profile that you have.
You can either go to that or customize my account where you can see your name.
Cool. So what we're really trying to do here, though, is that Harry has some requirements
that he wants to communicate to you about things to do. So now it's over to Harry.
If I was on this particular screen, I'm signed in as John Reid. I'll just ask Gene,
is John Reid a major account or a sub account?
It is a master or a major account.
Harry, when you looked at this screen, is there anything wrong with this particular page?
It's not what I would have picked. I haven't really analyzed it. That's what you get.
And I didn't know you could change things.
What would you like to change? It's obviously not this page. So what's something else that you
would like to change? The About Us page was one of the pages I was going to talk to Gene about
later on. I'm going to do another one while we're here because I just see this as being an issue.
Now, let's say the page we want to change and I like to copy the URL. So I've gone up here
to the address bar. I've selected all the text and I might say something like dashboard
because that's where we're at. And we might step back a bit and say we are in as a master account.
So this is giving us context. Are we a master account? Are we a sub account? Are we an administrator
of the system? So we'll say master account and then we'll go dashboard. And then I'll just paste
that link that I copied over here. And what that means is that if Gene or if another user is
looking at these tasks, they can quickly go to the page that you are seeing. So this is Harry's
point of view. This is Gene's point of view. And Harry would like her to work on the dashboard.
So she just comes here and clicks on this link. And suddenly the page that he's talking about
is actually available for her to do a change on. Then what happens is Harry says, I don't
like that the menu has wrapped down onto a second line. Harry might say issue with menu on narrow
display. There can be various ways this problem can be fixed. The normal one with web design
is HTML hamburgers. I'm not expecting you to remember this, but let's just see what they are
for now. And a hamburger menu is when you see those three little slashes. But the thing is
Harry likes had to you need a hamburger when menu is too wide. And you go, okay, that's on the
dashboard. The reality is that this is not just about the dashboard. This would be every page
where the menu happens. So I've just made that minor change. I'm not suggesting you do this.
This is about training for both of you on how we start setting up our sitemap, going to different
pages, documenting them as a node in the mind map. We've just a little bit of brief information
about what we would like to do. We have a hyperlink in the form of that little
attachment icon so that when you're giving the mind map to someone else, they can easily navigate
to the concept inquiry. And a bit later, we'll show how we would record a video for this so that
we deliver the requirement or the action plan for the week in a simple video of this as well.
Coming back to you, Harry, what was the page you wanted me to go to? You wanted me to go to the
about us page. Okay, we're now on the about us page. So the next thing I do from the must
account point of view or from the website point of view, because something like the about us
is not related to an account. So this might be just general. Okay, so general, we have about us.
I like to come up here and grab the URL, paste it in so that the person that you're giving the
information to can easily come over here and just open up that website from the mind map.
You're going to give me just some brief understanding of what is wrong with this page.
Okay, there's a section there about the sellers. Now, I just can't see keep scrolling down a bit.
No, no, it's keep scrolling down a bit there. Just slow down, just slow down there. Oh, yeah,
the reason why sellers prefer here in beauty sellers where it's got the three lines there,
to reposition it says lowest price to list for sale. I want that to be the second line and only
here in beauty sellers listed as the first line. Where you were just there now, that's reasons why
sellers prefer here in beauty sellers. The first slide read lowest price to list for sale. I want
that to be the second line. And the first line will read only here in beauty sellers listed.
Okay, we've never had that there. If we verbally tell someone this, that might be enough.
I changed the copy once I started to read it in detail.
Okay. So what I'm going to do is say, I'm just going to say reasons why sellers just for now,
but I'm not going to do the whole thing. That's not needed. It's just a bit of a guide. This is
something that Jean needs to go and change. We're going to say arrange the lines, add in,
maybe we can just say new text. Tell me exactly what you'd like there, Harry.
The first line was going to read only here in beauty sellers listed.
The second line was going to read lowest price to list for sale.
The third line was going to read quick contact between buyer and seller.
Now, what I'm doing in the mind map here, I personally wouldn't have done it this way.
I don't know whether you've written it onto a paper note or whether you've got it in a Google
doc. But let's say it was a Google doc, I might actually take that text and put it into a Google
doc because it's really easy to share with Jean that way. I think for the example, we'll do that.
So we just go over to dots.google, create a new document. We might call the document the same
as what we've done on the mind map. So we'll say June 26 changes, something like that.
We might go back and just say about us. So that's the page we're going to affect.
Is Google doc the equivalent to Microsoft Word?
It is. But what I like about Google doc is it's so easy to share a document online
and have it really collaborative and it's free. No one needs to pay for it.
I haven't used Word for many years now. So maybe a lot of these features are in there.
And I don't mind if you use Microsoft Word, use whatever you like. So long as it's a document
system that's collaborative and free for the people that you're working with. So about us,
reason why sellers and we can come back here. I'm going to copy these over into that document.
As I said to you before, you probably don't need to write this into the mind map at all.
It's just easier when it's just copied to put it straight into here.
We just take the stuff that mattered. The reason also that I like to deliver it this way rather
than say a screenshot or images or anything like that is that you can check your spelling.
So here's a great example. The spelling is wrong. You can check it, Harry.
You can make sure that the content is what you want it to say. If you don't want it to have
capital all the way through, you can change it. You can do whatever you want.
I live here and beauty sellers listed. Maybe you want a capital L. I don't know.
But the good thing is that the person doing the work or they've got to do is come and copy it
and paste it into the appropriate spot on the website.
Another thing we can then do here is we'll click the share button because we do need to make this
document available. We hit share and we will maybe it's anyone with a link would be fine.
Are they a viewer or are they editing it? In this case, it could be either whatever you like.
We make a copy of that link. We're going to need to give that
to the person getting the requirements. So reasons why sellers we can maybe get rid of that
and say here's the details and paste in the link. So now we've got that link.
Let's make this a video task. Often I would do one video for everything that we're going to do,
but I'm going to keep this very actionable items that can be checked off for now. Let's start up
loom, hit start recording and select the area of the page that we're interested. And so
Hi, Gene. This is the first item I want you to do. It's just a general purpose item
on the about us page. You can see the about us page here. I've put a hyperlink in it for you.
What I need you to do is go down to the reason why sellers and if you scroll down the about us page,
you can see it right there. And I need you to do a bit of line arrangement rearrangement for me,
please. What I need is for this line to be on the second line. Actually, when I look at this text,
I realize that some of this text is not right. So what I've done is I've given you also a link
to a little Word document here or a Google dot. And can you just make sure that these three lines
in this order, say these words. Thank you.
There we've got the first task. Yeah, we get the first task as a one minute video. Now,
once you get good at this, it shouldn't take you more than a few minutes to create each task.
Harry, and they're very actionable now. So let's just hit play. I've got it on two times five
speed. So this is going to go very fast. We'll hit play. Hi, Gene. This is the first item I want you
to do. It's just a general purpose item on the about us page. You can see the about us page.
You see what it is. So now the next thing that we can do is take that link and we can come back
to our mind map. So to do, just paste a link it. There we go. We're done. So let's go and move on
to the next task that we would like to assign for the week. If we back up one point, I love
using the mind map as an organization tool. But it might still be smarter to use a project
management tool with the same hyperlinks. You still do the word document, you still do the loom,
but you put everything as tasks in a project management tool, flick up or whatever you want.
If you're not to the level where you're using a project management tool yet,
the mind map is just a very simple solution. Is there anything else on the about us page
that needs to change Harry? If it was a buyer section where it wouldn't cut reasons why buyers.
Buyers, you got reason why buyers prefer and there were the three lines that are there now.
I wanted to change them. The first one was going to read only here a few sounds come
all in one place. Hold on one sec. I'm going to go back to our document here and say reasons
why buyers only here and busy salons come all in one place.
Yeah, yeah, after salons. Great. Next slide. Direct contact between all parties.
Next slide. A salons available for real Australia. Make that Australia wide.
What I do here now that we've got that we'll go back to our reasons why buyers and to do remember
was a loom. So maybe you say that loom. We can take a copy of the details that we did there
and we can just reuse them again. So that's fine. Or you just say all the details are here.
The good thing about a mind map is that I can delete and move stuff around. If I see I've got
the same information twice, I don't have to repeat it twice. I just move it to a higher level node
and go that's on its own. There's the details. When Jean clicks on it,
she now says the stuff about reasons why buyers and she says the stuff about reasons why sellers
and the stuff for reasons why buyers. They're both there. Now we go and create another to do.
So we go to do or we just say loom. She'll know exactly what we mean when we do this
and we'll record a new loom. Flick up here, press custom size, select it, hit start recording.
Jean the second action that I would like you to work on is reasons for buyers. Now if you go to
the about us page, you can find it down here on the right and we really just need to change this
text here. You can just replace it with the text that I've already written for you. Thank you.
Now we've got a 22 second video that Jean can watch. We just go and make sure we've got a copy
of the hyperlink right there. Go back to this node loom and we paste it in. Now you can just
keep going after that. And so when Jean has finished an action, let's say she's made a change to that.
If this was a project management tool, she would say done and you would receive an email. So that
might be might still be the best way for you to go if you're ready to start using PM software.
But if you're not, she just says to come up here and go, I'm done. Then all you do Jean is in Skype
or whatever till you're using to communicate. So I've done those actions. Harry can go and look at
it. And then he's got the same links. He doesn't need to remember how to get to the about us page.
He doesn't need to remember how to get to the loom video because he can just click on them as well.
Does that seem like a workable communication tool for getting tasks done that you could use,
Harry? Or is it a little bit too complex? There's just a learning curve going on here,
but I think it'd be good because when I'm trying to dictate to Jean what to do,
it's really time consuming. Whereas I can see I can do this and then send it to her and then she
can do it around a leisure without me rabbiting in your bag here. What's happened? I think that
it's worthwhile cursive area with to see if we can make it work. What do you reckon, Jean?
Yeah, I think it tells us a great idea to get this by this way. We can have records of the tasks
that we are doing. For example, in the future, we thought of, oh, did you do this before? I can
just show you some records that we have done it before. I think the way you move things around
so quickly, I can follow where it's going. It'll just be us learning the jargon and that resolves
going through the finish this afternoon. I just wondered how long it was going to take,
because we want to adjust all our listings to Sanadel and make sure they're accurate.
It would be easier for me to just type what I want on that moister and then June can actually
work on the directories pro because you've got a position stuff and put it in the right
field and all those sort of things that take time and you've got to adjust the margins and what have
you. Oh, I'm going to say, you don't even need to go down the complexity of the my master. It's a
good way of ordering your thoughts and thinking about things. So long as you're capturing the
details that you want and a visual of where it is and the leaks, the other technique is you just
go into the Skype window that Jean is using and you just say, I personally would go and change
the title up here to make sure it's clear. Lune comes up with a title, but it's not always clear.
But then you take the URL, you say, there's your first task, Jean.
There's your second task. Okay, you don't need to use a project management tool. You don't need
to use a mind map, but they are obviously good ways for you to have a record and audit log
of what's done, what's not done, and to have comment streams and stuff like that.
One thing I've picked up here straight away that rather than me handwrite this stuff,
I spent some time letting it type a bit more efficiently and then used a Google Doc or a Word
document, then it's easier to transcribe that stuff to Jean's pretty much straight away.
Let me show you a second way of doing it, right? If you're in this document, this is Google Docs,
right? You go to tools, you turn on voice typing, say, hello, Jean, comma, today I would like you
to do all the work really quickly, artificially, blah, blah, blah. Hit stop. Why even type it?
I know she's been doing some sneaky things like that.
Yeah, she's not teaching me. Do we need to talk about anything else or is this good?
Oh, look, it's great, Jean, and I'll just sort it out. I'm looking forward to coming up
there, Jean, more than ever now, because we could just get in the back room somewhere and just
set the brains out. Yeah, yeah, yeah, correct.
Both of you, if you start documenting your best practices this way,
it means that you can expand your team. When you do something, Jean, and you think this is
something that I need to remember to do in the future, you probably do that and you don't document
it. It's so simple to document these things that if you bring on another team member, you can just
say, see this mind map of our best practices, can you go through it? And I've got little videos to
tell you about each best practice. This has a great tool for that. David, that's invaluable.
Well, I've seen it. It's amazing. But I don't know what else to say. It's good stuff. It's just
learning it. No worries. Thank you so much, David.