Now when we come back to our join class, we can see that we've got the file resolver
being delegated to from a method. And we've got this new nested class. And we look
inside of it. It's taking the folder files and sort options. It's doing some processing.
And we've got a bunch of things going on around sorting and resolving the file patterns.
Now the question you might have is is this code actually doing what's intended? Now
we do need to write some unit tests, but we can actually start by going back to ChatGPT
and comparing this particular class to the documentation requirements.
So what I've done is taken all the code from this file, moved over to ChatGPT, and
I've gone into using it with canvas mode 'cause it's designed around coding. And
all I've done is pasted in all the code with a question, does the file resolve a
nested class, satisfy the needs of
the requirements document. And what we then get up is an analysis. And this analysis,
which I've already read through, shows that everything seems to be in place. There's
a couple of edge cases that may need to be expanded on a bit later on.
And then there's a section on
the logging mechanism that I need to put into each of the nested classes and the
primary component. Now this is a little bit outside of the scope of where we're at.
We'll do that probably when we're working on the join class. So I think the next
thing we should do is just using the documentation requirements we've got and the
class as it exists is list a bunch of unit tests that would be appropriate for the
file handler class.
We're in the same chat window and I've just said, can you look through the requirements
document above? After that, I've said, I want it to list any unit tests that it thinks
it needs for the file handler class. I want it to also consider the outer class primary
component being the join component. And lastly, when it starts thinking of the tests
that are needed, I want it to use behavior driven development concepts, BDD testing
and use naming conventions that fit with our spec because as a testing framework,
it actually has certain naming conventions that it likes to use. I've also said keep
the main focus on the file handler class.
So I've just asked it to write the requirement documents for me. I got it to remove
a little bit of information around
logging, and to make sure that the comments are just going to be placeholders. And
by doing it this way, we should be able to just copy these instructions directly
into Cursor AI and create our code.
Now we're back in the original chat dialogue that built this code. And what we're
going to do is we're just going to paste everything in. Now, one of the things I'm
aware of with Cursor is sometimes when it needs to create a new file, it might not
put it in the right location. So what I've done is just come over and created a stub
for join spec. I've also just given it a little bit of knowledge, in the form of
a comment of where it could put some test fixtures, if that's what it thinks it needs
to do. So what we'll do is we'll just come back here and we'll say join spec is now
added
and let's see what it produces from the rules that we've put in place.
Now Cursor has produced some code. What we're going to do is we're just going to
add it. Now, I can already see a couple of issues, but this is saved. It looks like
all the tests are in place. I'm going to need to test this out in a moment. But the
big issue I've got is that it's taking the fixtures idea and tried to create these
files. Now, the idea of having a fixtures folder is that you've pre-set up the files.
If you wanted to use this sort of technique, you would use a temporary folder instead.
So there's a little bit of a mistake in the code, but we can see whether this is
going to work at the very least.
Now I've just brought up guard so we can try these tests out and see whether they
work. I also noticed another issue is that the file resolver is a nested class, and
it should be inside another described block. So there's a couple of other modifications
that I want to make in the future. But what we'll do is we'll just press save and
see what happens when we run it for the first time. Now we've got an error, but if
we scroll up, we've only got one error out of what is quite a lot of tests. So for
just using ChatGPT to build the list of tests that we want, making sure that it works
from the requirements document, we're already off to a really good start with writing
robust code that's self-documenting and self-testing.
So the first problem I want to address is the fixtures versus temp folder issue.
And we've got all this code that's been written based on a fairly simple prompt going
on here. So we'll just say accept and we'll hit save on that. And all our tests should
work except for the one that's still failing. So let's just scroll up. Look. So it
all looks okay.
Now I just had a recording problem and so I've moved ahead a little bit and I'll
just talk through what's happened. So the first thing was there was one error out
of all the tests and I just copied verbatim what I saw in the console log, which
included the particular error. And what it did was it wrote code for me that resolved
that particular issue. The next thing that I looked at was where should the unit
test for the nested class
should it be in a new sub folder?
and I used the GPT canvas that we had before, and it gave me information about how
it thought about it as a best practice and also how it thought about it as an alternative,
which is the one I thought we would go with. So what I've done is I've just taken
this information here
and pasted it directly into Cursor. You can see it here. And what it's gone and done
for me is created the file, resolver spec, and the folder that that happens to be
in is under the join folder. So all the tests have been transferred. Then after that,
it also did the join class. And it's just put in a placeholder or a stub to get us
started.
so if we go over to our unit tests, we can see that the placeholder for the join
class is coming through. Okay. And then all the information that we're trying to
test in the file, resolver is also coming through green.
Next I want to parse the SRT files. So let's just bring one up so we can see what
they look like. And you can see here that they're indexed 12345. They're timestamped
which is the beginning of the sentence or the word in this case and where it finishes.
And then there's the text. So we need to be able to read these sorts of files in.
So what we'll do is we'll come over to the join class. We're in the chat and we're
just going to paste in. Can you create an SRT parser nested class. And can you use
the documentation file to write the code. So we'll just press enter. Oh look at that.
Unable to reach anthropic.
So I'm just testing a new anthropic key. It looks like I ran out of credits with
that. Let's see whether we're back up and running again. And we are. It's generating
code.
So I fixed up the anthropic key, got myself back on track. Now I use a paid version
of Cursor, but I also use the Claude 3.5 model, which you also pay additional money
for. Now, when it ran this particular prompt, can you create an SRT parser? It started,
but you can see that it hasn't really written any code that follows the requirements.
So I've just said you have not followed the requirements spec and it starts writing
the rest of the code for us.
Now I've integrated all the code. We've got the file resolver from the last section,
and now we've got the SRT parser. There's a bunch of code going on inside of this.
If we scroll down to the bottom of the join class, we now have the parse SRT content
being called directly after the resolve files. So we can see that all happening right
here.
Now, as per the last section, I'm not going to do too much checking of the code.
I'm assuming it's okay. What I'll do instead is we'll just come over to GPT canvas
and I said, does the SRT nested parser satisfy the needs of the requirement document?
And what I've done is I've passed in the complete class as we see it at the moment.
And I've done the documentation file.
So when we look at the report generated by ChatGPT, it's similar to the last one.
We've got all the different edge cases and points of view that are being covered
by looking at the code. Compared to the documentation I've read through this, everything
is quite accurate. So with that, I could probably move on to doing the tests because
I think the code will be okay. So what I do is just have another prompt which is
similar to before. Can you list the unit tests that you think are needed in bullet
points? And so we have a bunch of unit tests being listed, and all I do is copy this
information and we take it over to Cursor AI
So I wrote a small prompt. Add a new SRT parser spec to the join folder, follow the
guidelines from the file resolver spec
from before, and update the join spec. And we can see that we've got a SRT parser
spec all in place. We'll see whether that works in a moment. And if we go over to
the join, we can see that there's minor improvements made here.
Now. When I ran the tests, they all worked except for one. There's about ten and
one failed, so all I did, as per before, was just copied the console log and let
it alter the code as it saw fit.
So these SRT examples that you can see here, I want to see it in a separate file
in a fixture file, because I am going to reuse this in a few places. So I've just
asked it can we move these into a fixtures folder. I've given the folder listed.
It's updated the code. So it's now pointing to a couple of files called part one
and part two, and given me file names that it suggests I should put them into. So
if we just click over, we can see the two files in place. And we've got the spec.
So we'll just run the unit test for the primary component, which is called join.
And things seem to be working okay. And we'll go to the SRT parser and run that.
And we've got ten examples that are working. Now this is a point where we should
probably talk about the quality of the code that's come back from ChatGPT or from
anthropic. And think about, does it follow the guidelines that your linter would
use. So what I'm going to do is press enter and we're going to see a whole lot of
warnings come through. And it's saying that 23 offenses detected, 21 of them are
auto correctable. And so these are just simple formatting issues that we can resolve
using just a linting tool. In this case I'm using rubocop.