How successful is your AI pair programming? Maybe you're using Claude Code, or cursor
or root code, and you put in best practices like a requirements document, a PRD,
and a task list, and you're having some success. You're loving the AI pair programming,
but you notice after a while that just some things don't work out the way you want.
And you wonder, could you review all the past work that the AI has done and come
up with a better plan for the future? In this video, we're looking at retrospectives,
and we're going to see if we can implement an AI retrospective. I'm AppyDave. Let's
get into it.
So in traditional software development there is a particular methodology known as
agile. And within that there is a framework known as scrum, in which there's this
ability for people to work for what's called a sprint, a two week period, as an example,
to build a section of the software application as a team. And at the end of the sprint,
there might be something going on called a retrospective, where they look back through
what worked, what didn't work, and see if they can improve things for the next sprint
in the software development cycle.
So if your developers are writing code and you notice inefficiency and you talk about
it in the retrospective, should the same idea be applied to the AI peer programmers
that we're now using? Now, I've just gone and implemented a whole lot of functionality
using Claude Code, and everything ran on autopilot. I was pretty happy with the output,
but I thought there was a little bit of inefficiency that I want to improve the next
time I write a section of code for this application.
So let's have a quick look at the application that I'm talking about. And this is
a minimum viable product, an MVP that I've been putting together in the form of a
wizard. And it's got little capabilities, like a button up here that will preload
with some data so that when I'm testing the application, I don't have to fill it
in. When I press next, we go to a new page and I'll press next again, which is actually
under my picture at the moment. And you'll see that it's starting to load data from
an external source. And the idea of that external source is that it would be an N8N,
workflow, but that's something that I can swap between by being on mock. At the moment
it's fake data. When I click this button, it becomes live data, which would be the
N8N, workflow. And all these capabilities that you're seeing were all done over a
series of individual steps that were well documented, and the AI pair programmer
wrote all the code itself.
So let's step back to the AI retrospective and how I was putting this particular
application together using a concept called the Bmad Method. And what the bmad method
is is based off this video series that I saw called Bmad Code, and there's a GitHub
repo related to it. You can see here, it's an AI powered Agile development framework,
which will take your requirements document and break it up into concepts known as
epics. And when we look at our requirements document here, we can see that I went
through a bunch of epics and each of them will have a list of stories to be executed.
And you just feed these stories one at a time into an AI pair programmer and it starts
writing the code for you. So when we look at the technology stack, which was Epic
one, there were a bunch of stories and that gave this application the ability to
work with,
react Shad, cn, tailwind, CSS, vite,
different technologies like that. When I got to Epic two, we got the application
shell, which is all the stuff that we're seeing with the menus on the left. We've
got little quick search concepts that we can pop up. They're not yet styled. We've
got a little light and dark mode. Again, there's some styling issues going on. But
then I moved on to the main styling, which is what I needed for the main wizard.
And we're seeing that wizard here now as I was developing it, it's essentially a
human in the loop agent wizard backed by N8N workflows.
So when I started this feature, known as an epic, I had seven different stories.
And the first story was this first page that you're seeing right here. And then as
soon as you loaded in data, you could move on to the next page, which would be the
second story. And so since there were six different wizard pages plus a final page,
we had seven stories. But by the time I got to the end of writing all the code, once
I thought of things like the modal dialog, talking to N8N,, talking to mock data,
we ended up with 13 different stories going on, and I had to shift things around
a little bit during the conversational process.
Now, I will point out that the experience of writing code would BMAD and Claude Code,,
and just following through on these stories allowed me to create all these commits,
and each individual commit was done almost in a one shot prompt, in which Claude
would just go through and work through the different items. At the end of it, I'd
put in a little bit of information to say, please create this fancy commit message
that you're seeing, commit it to the repository, push it all the way up, and sometimes
I'd forget. So this one I forgot to do 4.6. So 4.6 and 4.7 went up together. And
this happened a couple of times. But essentially it was writing code. It was writing
documentation like you're seeing right here, and all of it without me actually having
to write any code.
Now before we do the retrospective, if you're actually interested in seeing how I'm
building a human in the loop agent based AI workflow application, and it's all done
using the Bmad method and Claude Code,. Then check out the video down below. But
for now, let's have a look at what this document is that it created. So
at the moment we're looking at epic four, which is a list of all the stories that
it went through as it was developing the software. Now, the stories are not the actual
stories that Claude Code, worked with. What these are are summaries that are expanded
just before it's about to write the code.
So whenever my AI pair programmer Claude Code, in this case was going to work on
a particular story, it would go and create a new story in the stories folder and
it be the same information, just way more expanded. We've got a lot of extra information,
including a section right at the beginning called Definition of Done, and this would
be a checked off list of the things that were done in that story. So now we have
a complete record of what we created, what was done, and we've got that repeated
for every story.
So knowing that, let's have a look through the retrospective analysis prompt. And
we've got this idea that you're conducting a retrospective analysis on epic for the
guided incident capture workflow and that there are objectives. We've got process
improvements, requirements analysis, technical insights, and a look at the Bmad method.
Now it's looking at how it can do that. So it can use data gathering through
the GIT based analysis.
The documentation analysis which is just looking at all those documents we just mentioned,
including the Claude doc. It can also go and look through all the commit messages.
And it can go through the code base analysis by starting from the initial commit
for the epic and going through and looking at the last one. So it's got different
areas that it's going to analyze for us
with the idea of building up a summary, what went well and what we can improve in
the future.
So when we look at the specific insights, there's a lot of them going on. But I think
the best thing is we'll just head down to a terminal and I often run a little alias
called Claude Sonnet to run it with the sonnet model. But for this, we'll go straight
into Claude, which should default to the Opus model. And I'm also gonna press shift
tab, 'cause I want to go into planning mode to do this. And I'm gonna say, can you
run a retrospective?
And with that we'll put in the at sign type in retrospective and it should find the
file we want. It's right there and we'll press enter.
At this point, it's starting to run. We'll just bring up the terminal a little bit
and it should come up with a little plan of action before it starts executing.
it's looking at gathering information using the Git log.
It's wanting to read all the stories, starting with the number four.
So here's the plan of action. It's analyzed 13 different commits. We've got 82 file
changes. We've got 13 stories review, all 13 stories, 4.1 through 4.13. Now, one
of the things that I'm a little confused about is that when we look at this area,
we've got 4.7 all the way through to 4.13, and maybe we don't have enough. So what
I'm going to do is just say no and say the stories you picked start at 4.7 and go
through to 4.13,
but you have not gone through 4.1 to 4.6. So maybe it has done that because part
of the plan mentioned it, but it never mentioned it in the details. So I'd like to
just be a little bit more complete before we move on. So now it's reading that particular
file, and that was what I was noticing as it was reading individual files that these
early stories weren't being read into memory.
And that's interesting. It's going to loop through a bunch of those files. I think
it's combining them all into
one output.
we can see the commits being read right here,
and it's reporting that it has a complete plan with everything from four one to 4, 1 3.
We've got all them listed. We've got the description of what they all do.
So this is the plan of action of what it's going to do. Create an epic four retrospective
document structure, which is great. It's a retrospective, so it's not going to alter
the original epic.
We're going to have an executive summary. What went well, what could have been improved,
key insights and actionable recommendations.
So it's created the document. Let's go have a look at this in VS code.
it out to say the Epic four retrospective guided incident capture workflow. That's
what we were working on. We got an executive summary that states that
Epic four was delivered. It was done using 13 stories and it was done over six days,
and that's about right. So I was spending about 40 minutes to 60 minutes each day
just working on this.
So essentially about two to three stories a day in an hour each. It took six days.
We've got this stories completed, 13, and it says that the original was 11. That's
not actually correct. It was only about seven. So I know there's something going
on here, but the rest of this document, which I've had a bit of a look through, is
pretty useful to me. Now, from your point of view, if you are doing a retrospective,
what you're going to read here is useful, but it will be totally different from your
situation. The main goal that we're trying to achieve here is understand where we
can make improvements to the AI workflows in the future. So let's just have a quick
look at some other areas in here.
So on June 17, 18 and 19, which is when the original part of the wizard was in place,
capturing of data across six pages and showing a final clarification. And what I
hadn't thought of through properly was test data, enhancing it using an API using
a mock so I could go between mop data and also go through the N8N workflow. And then
just doing some UX improvements is all the extra stories that got added on.
Now, where it went well is that in EPIC two, which is where I designed how the wizard
could work without any implementation of pages. And it was able to use that framework
quite successfully to build the seven wizard steps
when it was doing the first clarification. And this was essentially going off to
the server to rework some of the data that was input using a large language model,
was using this ugly little spinner. And I turned it into a clarification step. There
was also a modal dialogue
that refactor proved to be really useful across multiple pages.
I think this statement here is also really useful and shows why the BM a method was
really good. So it would have these acceptance criteria, it would have the definition
of done that would get checked off. And so I never saw it going off and doing stuff
that I never asked it to do.
And this is really powerful, the adaptive development, because there were a bunch
of things that I forgot and I'll show you the screen.
so popping over to the wizard. These forms were all in scope, but this little button
here to provide test data wasn't. So when I press that button, we get new test data.
Now as I move through, we got test data filled in and I'll go one more step where
it's working with mop data and then you'll notice there's no test data here. But
I was able to add a second state to this so that when I click it one more time, it
fill in additional test data. 'cause the idea of this is an MVP, I don't need
to have it work against N8N, I can go from the mock view, which is using a little
JSON structure behind the scenes to actually talking to an N8N server.
And it's those little concepts that this adaptive development are talking about,
adding the API toggle the, this sort of stuff was not thought of and it was easy
to add in. Another thing that was really useful in this, as I was using this Zustand
to store the designs, the shape of the data, and this worked really well,
So I never specified the names of the fields in the API at all. And that ran into
a problem and it's actually identified that by the changes I had to make mid epic.
So worked out some of the things that I hadn't fully worked through with the ux.
It's then mentioned the size of the stories and it's got this idea of combined judo
type coupling. I'm not sure that anything really could have been improved here. So
some of this is informational and not to be acted on,
and now it's starting to point out information in the code base. This is pretty good
actually. The API service layer is mixing concerns. So we've got configurations of
an if statement as to whether it should be mock or live. I assume we've got a little
bit of code that's inside as an IF statement. So this is at least telling us information
in the future that we can improve our code base on.
It's mentioned the missing abstraction, especially this repeated clarification UI
logic. Essentially at one stage in the development it was repeating the code on each
of the wizard pages.
And it's also highlighting something that I haven't done and it wasn't part of the
MVP and that's unit tests.
So this one line here, the API contract importance makes it really useful. If we
are doing another epic and I, I will be moving on to epic five, which is a different
wizard and it will have its own contract. So I now have some guidance from this document
which I could apply to the Epic five document to say is there anything that we learnt
here that could improve the current Epic?
So all of this just keeps going on. I read it, I thought some of it I dismissed,
some of it I thought was accurate. There were the odd hallucinations going on. It
was really good that it worked out a state management pattern using Zustand 'cause
that was not thought of at the beginning of this. I personally am not a JavaScript
developer, so I don't come from the background of knowing exactly what
I need to implement,
I wanted to do a retrospective to point out what I don't currently know in this sort
of code flow.
We've got this new handle next,
enhancement pattern that's going to be useful in the next wizard that we put in place.
And here we can see this if statement around whether it should use the mock data
or should use the real data. Maybe this is an area that I could guide it by using
the inversion of control pattern rather than this if statement. But I think the code's
pretty small and easy to read at the moment.
And so at this point it starts going on to an analysis of the BMAD method. Now the
other thing to note, this is the first time I've used BMAD I was learning myself
and in the meantime they've moved from version three to version four yesterday. So
the next time I do a video I'm gonna go through this method again and I'll understand
it a lot more. But when I look at the weaknesses that are listed here,
I don't see anything in this list that I actually had to worry about. So I'm not
looking at any weaknesses so far the way this has happened
now, I found the planning of these first six stories. It was excellent, it was great.
This idea that I had to be reactive and change things around and sometimes that meant
inserting stories,
ahead of others and having to renumber.
That was a little bit of a challenge.
And then we'd get this estimation accuracy. And this is where things are a little
bit out of whack. These numbers in these two cells are not quite correct because
I don't believe they were there originally Anyway.
Now this next section, which is all about the documentation created by the Bmad method
is actually really useful. So when the epic planning is being done and the improvement
is to have the developer experience stories built in. So what happens with test data
development, tool workflows, debugging utilities, so that could be logging, stuff
like that. And is there any local development setup requirements? So some of the
things that I think I was changing along the way was also ensuring that it was using
a linter correctly.
And this area I really wasn't working on. So I didn't have a flow chart for the user
story. There was no sequence diagram for the API. There was no state management data
flows. So this is useful information that could go into future planning
and understanding the J data contract for both the data going to the end points and
how it comes back is also gonna be really useful.
Now this area around having patterns documented is also something I've been thinking
about from having another repository that I merge into, any code that I'm doing that
has my ideas around single responsibility, principle design patterns, and just basic
patterns of code ready to go with. So it's suggested that we do it within this application
right now though. It's the sort of thing that you probably want to keep doing if
you're doing many applications.
Now, as we look at the process refinements, I want to also point out that if you
are using a tool that can have multiple agents,
what you can do is maybe have something like the architecture review, or you might
have something to generate unit tests being done as a subagent. So not part of the
normal flow, but something that happens asynchronously. So some of this information
that we're seeing is probably too much for me to want to take on board in the next
Epic, but as this continuous improvement happens, I can start thinking of them. Does
it go into the next Epic or does it come in from a different point of view?
such as every time you complete a story, do you run a separate task just around the
unit tests?
or every time you do three stories, such as they say here, do you do
architecture review, check-in?
And this is really interesting. So we could probably run this and get these extractable
reusable patterns put into the code base for us both here
And we could also ask it to go on and build these documents within the architecture
directory. So here we're getting a idea of the lines changed in each of the stories,
but it's this next one that I really love. So before the Epic, this is what it looked
like, A Wizard UI
routes. And after the Epic, this is all the new stuff that's been added.
Now the lessons learned, which is the whole reason for doing a retrospective. Now,
keep in mind that this is done around a framework that I'm using called BMAD, but
you might be using something else. You might be just creating requirements documents.
You might have a PRD product requirements documents. You might have task master and
building out task lists. The reason I'm using BMAD is it kind of rolls all of those
concepts up together, and it's pointed out here that it probably should be adapted
to have developer experience tools. And for me, this was the automatic test or seed
data being populated when I needed it to happen.
There's also the extracting patterns, which is taking that code that's been repeated,
putting it into a patterns directory, and this would be an end of epic capability
that I'd want to do. Every time I'm working through the code base, I.
So that was,
I retrospective, just to check how the progression of a successful code implementation
could be improved and what measures you want to take in the future. Now, if you're
interested in working one on one with me, you can book a call. You come to the website,
click on that button, and book a session. Otherwise, if you're just interested in
learning more about coding with Claude Code, using the Bmad method or building an
application a day, which is my goal, then like and subscribe on the channel I'm AppyDave.
I'll see you in the next video.