555 videos, 55 weeks, 5 channels.
For 10 months I've been testing YouTube strategies, I've actively asked questions,
shared wins and offered tips.
I started with FlyVideo to automate my processes.
Little did I know that the 30 videos I recorded over 10 days would take half a year to release.
It cost a lot, but it was worth it.
I launched my second channel to target prompt engineering.
And early success led to 300 followers in 3 weeks.
When I launched Dappie Dave, I stumbled onto a winning formula, gained 2000 followers in a week
and was monetized in 9 days.
Next came my Carnivore 90 diet and health challenge.
But my happy place is my podcast channel where I record my daily learnings and processes.
The 555 manifesto is a personal challenge to create 555 videos over 55 weeks on 5 channels.