I'm AppyDave, and in this video we're looking at a talk that I gave last night for
Ecamm Live Tech Summit on multi-agent workflows. And specifically, we're looking
at a framework that I've been putting together called Emotional Support Spiders.
In this video, we'll be covering the prompt engineering the AI workflows and agents,
and also talking about how I'm putting together a system for multiple character,
multiple storylines with videography to fit.
So if you're currently a YouTuber or a storyteller online and you're using AI at
the moment, you might be concerned about whether in the future AI is going to get
rid of you from the picture, or is it something that's going to give you superpowers
over time? So in this video, we're looking at different aspects of storytelling and
visualization with AI. For instance, in the next five years, it's predicted that
90% of all content online will be AI generated one way or another. So here I'm talking
about the AI workflows that I use, and what I'm suggesting might be good for creators.
And I do it through what I call the scale framework.
So let's power up, get on our superpowers and have a look at what we can do Today
with video content generation and movies
are forged in the fires of the YouTube battlefield.
Only the strongest, the most persistent, the most clickbait driven warriors
will survive
in the kingdom of contempt, views our power
and the shows. No Mercy AppyDave was once just a creator, but when the prophecy called
for 555 videos in 55 weeks across five channels, he answered, he has climbed the
treacherous mountain of mastery where many have fallen. He has battled burnout,
braved the shadow band swamps, and faced the dreaded demonetization dungeon.
He has studied the sacred texts, viral thumbnails, retention graphs in every cat
video in search of the ultimate truth. Is he a genius, a madman, a man haunted by
the ghosts of unfinished edits? No one knows,
but one thing certain he won't stop
until he finds the answer or loses his mind. Trying. This is the ridiculous legend
of AppyDave and the 5 5 5 Manifesto.
So that was AppyDave, the 5 5 5 Manifesto, which is a Hollywood style blockbuster
video trailer that I put together a couple of months ago for a different tech summit.
And what I wanna do is talk about how I'm putting these together across multiple
channels.
So let's look at one of the fundamental ideas that are needed to succeed on YouTube.
And this comes from MrBeast. When asked the question why after I've done ten videos,
am I not seeing any subscribers or views? And he says that unless you've done 100
videos and looked at how to improve on each and every video, don't bother wasting
his time. And what I did a couple of years ago was to think, can I do that 100 videos?
But can I do it across five different channels?
So for some time now, I've been using this metaphor called the Mountain of Mastery,
which is a spiral learning metaphor that says that as you go around the mountain,
at each stage you can see something different. But as you go around the mountain
a couple of times and you look at a higher level, you have more clarity around what
it is you're seeing. And I find this happens to be the case across concepts like
YouTube titles, how to write descriptions, how to do hooks, how to do outros. As
I go through the mountain of mastery, over time I learn a little bit more.
and what I wanted to do with that knowledge is encapsulate it into AI agents for
YouTube automation. And that's where the 5 5 5 Manifesto started a couple of years
ago in a conversation with ChatGPT, where I said, can I create 555 videos in 55 weeks
across five different channels? And looking to do that using automation systems.
Now to start achieving that, I had to put in place a new system of thinking and automation,
and I call that the scale framework. And the idea of the scale framework is that
we start from the point of view of structured prompt engineering. The ability to
communicate with AI is one of the fundamental skills that we need. The way we're
using large language models today.
Once you understand how to do the prompt engineering, you can move into prompt chains
or crafting different workflows or standard operating procedures that automate certain
parts of your business or your YouTube content creation. After that, I like to package
it all up in agents. Now, these agents might be pure automations, or they might be
automations with human in the loop concepts.
After that we want to hook into low code tools. So let's say you've done a video,
you've generated an article based off the video. You then want to be able to push
that directly into your WordPress site. Or you might want to upload assets to Canva.
And this is where low code automation can kick in. The last thing that we're ultimately
trying to do is become more productive. So how do we empower content creators to
get a whole lot of stuff done, which is involved with this business, with the limited
resources of just some AI agents?
So let's start off with a tutorial on effective prompt engineering. And to do that,
we're going to do it from a storytelling perspective by talking about a woman and
her cat in New York as a storytelling construct. And when I'm doing prompt engineering,
it's all about breaking it down into the component parts, such as, in this case,
a structured sequence of events. We've also got the protagonist, which happens to
be the woman, the environment, or the scene which happens to be New York, and the
fact that she has another character being her cat.
With that information in place, we give the structure of what we want to create,
which is a five scene write up, and we would like something dramatic maybe in the
third scene. And from there we end up getting storytelling that's over five different
scenes. Now, the next thing that we want to do from here is get some sort of visualization.
But before we do the visualization, we need to create what's called a shot list.
Now the shot list is just a simple continuation of the story we just created, just
with a little bit of output formatting. In this case, create a simplified shot list,
and we see that information coming through. And there's a lot of visual componentry
going into what's being written.
Now that we've got the story and the shot list, we can go into generating prompts
that allow us to generate these images in something like Leonardo AI.
Now to create images effectively. The things that are important is that firstly,
we continue the context of the previous part of the conversation with an output format,
which is generate a concise image prompt. After that, we give the aesthetic style
that we want. It's pretty simple here. It's just New York City, a woman 2025. And
then lastly, because there are multiple characters, we want to make sure that each
of the characters are stylistically the same in every scene. Last thing we need is
to see a cat that's brown in one scene and black in the next scene.
So we continue the conversation. And one of the things that you notice is that all
the image prompts that have been generated all have the same fluffy orange tabby
cat in each of the scenes. So hopefully we're going to get visual consistency. So
when we start running this through Leonardo AI, you end up with a bunch of images
that look pretty good. We can notice in the third scene that there is a dramatic
issue going on here. The cat is escaping in the park.
So we have our final story of the woman in her 30s in New York with her cat. But
what if we want to take this same story and restructure it for a different period
in time? And for this, let's go with Elizabethan times or Shakespeare Hamlet sort
of style. From that, we can just take a new prompt, a reframe prompt. We ensure that
the woman and the cat are in each scene, but the scene should be quite different
because it's a different period in time. And we do have a reinforcement part of the
prompt that says that only image prompts are expected. The woman and the cat should
have visual consistency across every scene.
And so now we have our noble woman and her cat in London. It's a similar sort of
concept, but one of the things that you notice when you see them side by side is
that there is a little bit of a flaw. The blonde woman in the first scene is a little
bit different colored blonde, and then she becomes silver and then a darker brunette,
followed by silver at the end. And what we're looking at is what I call instructional
collapse in prompt engineering. So in the next section let's see how we can improve
that with AI workflows.
So in the scale framework we've just looked at Structured Prompt engineering. Now
we're going to look at crafting workflows. And these are simple prompt chains that
you put in place to execute the same sort of instructions over and over again in
a systematic way. And I like to use them in three main areas business optimization,
creative processes like you're seeing in this presentation or in a lot of the YouTube
videos I do, or personal productivity, maybe writing an email or a Facebook message.
Now, if you're doing workflows correctly, you also have extended tools such as fine
tuning, retrieval, augmented generation, memory, human in the loop to interact with
the AI, and maybe different models to solve different problems. So let's have a look
at it from a marketing agency point of view. So let's say you're a digital marketing
company and you've got a lot of workflows that you're doing for many clients. And
it's the same workflows over and over again. And this was one such company I was
working with. And we were looking at the different workflows they've got and just
putting them into structured, prompt chains that they could run over and over again.
Now, one of the things I found interesting about working with this company, that
is that there's a lot of similarity between being a YouTuber, publishing LinkedIn
articles and being an SEO agency, creating various forms of content.
I also worked recently with a branding agency, and what they had put in place already
was competitive analysis, market research tools in the form of prompt packs. And
these prompt packs were done in Canva. They had nice little video walkthroughs of
how to use them, and they were quite simple in nature. Basically a bunch of prompts
that a customer could just copy paste into large language model of choice, maybe
modify a few input variables. So this is a simplistic way of getting your first prompt
chains up and running.
Now as a YouTuber, using prompt chains can be effective in all sorts of areas, like
creation and optimization of your content. You might want to repurpose and redistribute
it as an article or as a carousel, or you might want to deal with analyzing the comments
or building some sort of offer to a sponsorship deal.
So let's look at a tool I use internally called the Agent Workflow Builder to create
videos. And one of the workflows I go through is the YouTube Launch Optimizer. It's
a 30 step workflow that I go through every time I release a video, but one of the
steps involved here is the YouTube titles. So when we were looking at the video at
the beginning of this session called the 5 5 5 Manifesto and the Mountain of Mastery,
I would've run that through a title generator. I would've said the short title is
the 5 5 5 Manifesto. It's main topic is it's about spiral learning, and I would put
in a couple of content highlights. Now, the good thing about this is it would run
a prompt through Chat GPT in this case, and we'd get a bunch of YouTube titles ready
to get started.
Now, personally, I use Vid IQ a lot when I want to use Title Generation, but what
I love about doing it within the age of Workflow Builder is I have full control over
the way titles of being created. So I use it as a first pass, and then I finish off
with Vid iq.
So let's get into a more detailed workflow. Let's look at story building. And in
the video that we saw at the beginning, it starts off with legends are forged in
the fires of the YouTube battlefield. Let's just play that for a second so that you
can see what it sounds like. Again, legends are forged in the fires of the YouTube
battlefield.
Only the strongest, the most persistent.
And so you can see there that we've got nothing more than a transcript, and with
this transcript we can run it through various processes. So the first one I wanna
look at is the shot list that we talked about with the woman in New York, and we're
doing some prompt engineering around coming up with shot lists. And one of the things
that you notice with a scene is that there's more than one concept going here. Firstly,
we've got the scene itself is a mountain in the background, but in the foreground
we've got two different ideas going on. Firstly, we've got the protagonist, the hero
in the story, in the red robes. The second thing we've got is a main artifact or
item. In this case, it happens to be a sword.
Now, the specific details are really important when you're generating graphics and
prompts and stuff like that. So I start off with the primary character generator,
and this is where I work through and solidify what the character is going to look
like. After that, I'll look at the other characters that might be the villains, they
might be the other characters within the story, and how do I get them consistently
looking the same across different scenes? After that, I want to work on the scenes
themselves. Can I come up with a style that's repeatable that I can reuse to get
nice effects? And one of the things that you see in a scene is there's all sorts
of objects, but sometimes there's a major object, and the major object would be something
like the 555 manifesto, where I want to define that and work through consistently
being able to reproduce it in various scenes of the video.
Now as an example, and we'll only talk about the primary character. I've developed
two different styles. So here I've put myself in a black shirt and I've run it through
style one and style two. I decided I liked style two more, but I didn't want to work
with the black shirt, so I just took a different picture of myself
And you can see that the image on the right was used in the Mountain of Mastery YouTube
trailer.
Now we've crafting workflows out of the way. Let's look into the next two sections,
which is AI agents and using low code tools. So an AI agent is an automation generally,
but quite often we'll also do a human in the loop sort of visual interface. So when
it comes to using Vidiq, we can see that a video that I did, I put in a title and
it said your score is only 66. But what it did was suggest better ones. And I went
with the one that was 96. So this is a very simple human in the loop interface, backed
by agent workflows such as the one that I build for myself. But another way of looking
at this, and this is where low code tools can come in, is that you can use a tool
like pickaxe.
Now I've done four videos on this particular tool, but just as a recap, if we look
at these little tools that are AI driven, such as the YouTube title generator, again,
working on similar principles to what we saw in the Agent Workflow Builder,, you
can come along, fill in a little bit of information, and get a list of titles generated
or using a tool that you can market, you can reuse, you can give away to different
people. Another tool that I've done is the video advertisement script writer. And
the idea of this is creating an advert script that converts. So you put in a few
inputs and here we've got the hook that says, "hey, yeah, you scrolling mindlessly,
still thinking of those get rich quick videos will save your ass. Spoiler alert they
won't." And that's a hook.
We've got the pain in the villain, the reveal and then the call to action all at
the end of it.
So with the scale framework out of the way, let's move on to Emotional Support Spiders.
And this is something that I came up with a couple of years ago working with ChatGPT,.
And the idea was looking at the concept of emotional support animals or companion
animals and doing it differently, doing it as a storytelling in a multiverse sort
of event. And so this is called Emotional Support Spiders. It's an idea in which
there are two sentient races. You've got humans and you've got spiders. And what
we're trying to do within it is create buddy stories.
this has been thought of from the very beginning as a multi-agent storytelling system,
where each story can have irony and contrast. We can create trust and connection
between two different characters that are quite different from one another. We can
explore concepts like truth and trauma, hopefully so that we can get inspiration
and hope out of it all.
Now, from the multi-agent point of view, the images that you're seeing, which were
done in Midjourney a couple of years ago, were the idea, could you take individual
images of the spider and the human and create a story narrative back stories? Can
we create forward stories? Join us stories where people come together to form relationships.
And this is where various agents that arrive, a one off character related or storytelling,
are being reused over and over again.
So the way I start storytelling is from a world narrative. This is a set of one-off
agents that define the world that we live in. And the first agent is around philosophical
view of the world. Do I want to have a bit of Buddhism? Do I want some Christianity?
Do I want something else? And the way I like to do this is have a simple human in
the loop interface where I fill in a few values and then behind the scenes use an
agent workflow system such as NA 10 or Zapier to implement and build out all the
information. After that, we can move on to a design and visualization agent. And
when you look at the images in this screenshot at the moment, if we go back one and
we see the spider and the man, and we've got all this stone work, it's a rock mural
sort of system. And this is going to be repeated through the next set of slides.
And to do this, we need to get a design guide going. So we start off by another human
in the loop sort of input form, run it through a bunch of agents to come up with
a consistent style that we want to use.
Now. After that, we need to come up with a detailed fact sheet of what is a human
and what is a spider. And you can think of it the same way as you might a role playing
game, a Dungeons and Dragons, where you've got these attribute sheets that make sense
for humans, and you've got a different attribute sheets that make sense for monsters
as an example.
With our general worldview agents in place, especially this species traits one, we
can now move on to the character development itself. So if we are developing a human
character, one of the things that we wanna do is come up with the attributes, the
sort of stuff that happens when they're born. So with that, do we want to know what
their hair color is? The height that they grow to, what are their general fears and
problems going on in life? What are their desires? We want to do this same concept
with the spiders themselves, and we use a different agent, mainly because the goals,
the behaviors, they're going to be different between the two different species. With
that in place, we can then start to build a timeline of where they are in life, so
they got born, but where are
maybe we've got a human that's 13 years of age. Can we build up a storyline from
the attribute sheet all the way up to that period in time? Now, if we can do that,
we can then start to determine the sort of behaviors and mannerisms that each character
has.
Now, before we build any stories around these characters, a couple of additional
agents that can be useful is that if a scene, a scenario, an action happens, how
does that change their behavior? What's their motivations? Do they lead into a positive
sort of let's move forward in the world, or do they become a bit of a victim now,
no matter what the mapping comes with, the next thing is to read that and put it
back into the character. So if I have a confronting situation and I rise above it,
how do we write that information back into the DNA of who I am as a character?
With all our character development, our timelines in place, we can move on to scenario
writing. And I like to have a different agent for the different types of scenarios
that can happen in the Emotional Support Spiders world. So the first one is that
when you've got two characters that have never met, what brings them together, and
usually that's a dramatic scene, such as a bird attacking the spider and a human
coming in to save the spider. In this particular
Now that dramatic, emotionally charged scene can lead to a bonding. And with the
bonding, we can then go into them sharing their backstory, sharing what they've done,
and finding commonality in hanging out with one another.
Now the Buddy story scenario is a classic in Hollywood. We've seen it in Lethal Weapon,
Dumb and Dumber Bill and Ted's excellent adventure. So what I like to do is now that
we've got this in place, how do these two characters move forward in the future?
And we do that using a new sort of writer that is more on an episode by episode basis
or a day-to-day basis. And so the first one we have is what we saw when we were looking
at the woman and her cat a day in the life story. So we do a scenario based story
based on the idea that we have a world philosophical view. We had the design of the
world. We understand what a human and a spider is from a characteristics point of
view.
We now also have the individual profile or DNA of the spider and the human, their
timeline, their backstory. We also know how they came together in traumatic fashion
to become friends. So now when we just paint a simple scene for a day in the life
story, we've got all this rich information to drive it. After that, we wanna move
into the actual shot list. Again, we did that with the woman and her cat. One of
the things that happens though, when you are doing shot lists, and we can use agents
to do this, is not all scenes will be correct. So let's say we wanted grays and oranges
throughout every scene and we get one that's pink.
In this particular case, we will tell the agent and say, look, you got this one a
little bit incorrect. Can you regenerate the prompt so that we can regenerate the
images?
So that gives you some context of how emotional support spiders are put together
with different agents. The next thing is looking a little bit at the technicality
of it all, and it's really quite simple. What we do is we build little agent workflows.
We can use tools like N 18 or we can code them directly in Python or JavaScript.
From there, we just need to hook 'em up to human in the loop interfaces. So when
we're building in the world philosophy, we'll run in a few pieces of information,
send it to a workflow. After that, we want to figure out what's this world going
to look like? It's just another workflow. When we get onto dealing with the human,
this is on a per human basis or on a per spider basis,
we're defining, how they look, what their motivations are. After that, we run both
workflows through the Backstory generator and we just continue to do this for each
of the different agents that we're trying to build.
So with everything in place, the next thing is to create a story of some form and
the day in the life stories can look like this. Here we have a boy and an emotional
support spider in this particular case, and the boy has been invited to a party but
doesn't know how to associate with people. So from there, we add in a little bit
of a narrative over the top of it,
put in some magic animations sort of stuff that we can do in DZine or Leonardo ai.
I've got links in the description for both of them. And from there we simply animate
the scene. We've got the boy down at the beach and being befriended by a spider in
this particular case. Later on they're at his house where he's teaching them about
computer programming and stuff like that. Later in the day, there's a dramatic scene.
This time the father is angry upstairs, so there's a bit of comfort going
and then we finish the scene with a little bit of hope. They're down at the beach
and they're playing together.
So this was the presentation I gave over at Ecamm Live Leap last night, and it talks
about the scale framework, the structured prompts, creative workflows, the agents,
the low code frameworks, and how we put it together to empower creators. And then
moving on to the emotional support spiders, which is a system that's in developed
by myself so that I can do multi-agent storytelling. Now, if you wanna find out more
about how the actual video structures are being put together, you can come over to
the A-I-T-L-D-R channel where we do a lot of videos that are all AI generated and
there's a lot of storytelling going on. Or if you wanna learn more about the agent
Workflow builder, then just come to the AppyDave website.
I'm AppyDave,. Please book a call if you want to work one on one. Otherwise, like
and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.