In this video, we're taking a first
look at Pickaxe,
which is an AI workflow builder or chat
bot builder.
Now here we are on the home page.
Scroll down. You can have a look
at the different capabilities
that are available right here.
So the first thing is that you can build
your own chat bot or wizards.
You can customize the look and feel.
This is so that you can put it
on your own website.
You can monetize it.
So set up different payment plans for
your customers that are using your tools.
And lastly, you can monitor the analytics
and the capability of the chat bots
that you're building.
So let's dive
a little deeper into this application.
And we can say that it's a no code
platform
that builds human in the loop
AI workflows.
What that means is that your end users
can use simple forms or chat bots
to interact with AI workflows that you've
pre-configured with your own prompts.
Now, if you scroll down,
you'll see that it's a bunch of FAQs.
But if you're interested
in learning any specific capability
within Pickaxe after this
first video, then check out the playlist
that'll be at the end.
But moving forward,
what we're going to do is work with this
first option in creating a Pickaxe,
which is the form.
So we also have conversational bots,
which is a little bit like ChatGPT.
Now the form system is similar to a tool
that I use internally called
the Agent Workflow Builder, and I use this
whenever I'm launching a video.
I go through all these different
workflow steps,
and the one that we're going to look at
today is the title ideas.
So with this particular form
that I've used in the past,
I can take a transcript and I can feed
in a little bit of information
and get a rich YouTube title from it.
We'll see if we can do the same thing
by clicking on here.
And let's get started.
Now when you're in the form builder
you have two areas.
The area on the right
is what we're building.
The area on the left is where
we're doing a lot of the configuration.
Now there is the ability
to add information on the right as well.
So what we're going to do is we'll call
this a YouTube title generator.
Now I've just gone to the next page.
This is started drawing.
So it's taken whatever title you did
and come up with a starter image
that you might want to work with.
If we click on it
we can give it a different prompt.
I'm just gonna go with this
and I might just call it logo for now.
I think that'll be the simplest.
And let's see what we get from this.
And so it's drawn something
which is not very readable.
So I think we'll go back to illustrated.
We'll do a generate
one more time and see what comes through.
And with a little bit of experimentation
we'll go with this one.
Now the next step I want to do
is describe what this tool does.
And I think the easiest way is
if we go and select all the information
from the original prompt, and what we'll
do is we'll head over to checkpoint.
We've got a pasted in
and we just got a little
turn it into a description
sort of capability.
And we'll copy all that information.
And if we head back over here and paste it
in, this 300 character
description should be enough
to give a basic information
to a user about what
the tool is going to do.
Now, at this point,
I want to generate the prompt for this.
So if we click over on the prompt menu
you've got both
the main prompt
for generating the information you want.
But we've also got the role.
And I'm just going to take a copy
of this information.
What we'll do
is we'll head over to ChatGPT
where I'm just giving it that example.
We just copied it.
I've also just asked it
to write a role for me.
So let's see what it comes up with.
And it's going.
You are a seasoned
YouTube title strategist,
SEO, ten compelling, under 70
characters, etc..
Now, I've just mentioned
to my own chat bot
that this information we're currently got,
it's already
going to be in the main prompt.
So we'll just simplify the role right
here, and we'll come back and take a copy
of the prompt that we do want to build
what they're calling the prompt frame.
And we'll paste that in.
And then we'll figure out what we need
to change in here.
So with my prompt in place,
the main change I've done is
I've just added a title between each
input that I want to have.
We've got this “You are a specialist”.
We can get rid of that because this
information is going to be up in the role.
But the rest of the rules
are what we can configure
over time and find improvements from now.
Let's have a look at the model
we can choose from.
So when you click on this you're
going to see that we are on a free plan.
And we can pick the GPT-4.1 nano
or the mini.
And it's come with mini by default.
But nano model’s had be a great one
to work with.
Now I found it a little confusing
what was considered pro and gold.
So we've got this Claude 3 Opus
and GPT 4.1 as pro.
Now when you look at the pricing model,
the Pro is actually the top plan.
And I would have thought that something
like the GPT 3.7 Sonnet
might have been something
that would appear in the pro,
but you get it in the gold.
So if you do an upgrade to $23/month,
again,
there's an affiliate link
in the description.
You'll be able to select that particular
model when you're generating information.
Now at the moment I've got this
three areas where I want to put the
user inputs.
And the way you can do
it is by adding a user input like this.
And you'll see these values.
So what we'll do is would go under shot
title add one.
There we go under video topic same
and we'll go under Content Highlights.
Now if there's something
that you don't want like this one
we can just come over here
and press the delete button.
But with that in place
we should go and copy the different titles
and make sure it's just nice
for the user to read and understand.
We'll find content highlights.
Now, I think the control is covering
is covered
by my head at the moment, but to the right
is this little short answer.
And for the content highlights down here,
I'm going to make it long answer.
So if I just go and do that
and press long answer.
This will get a little bit bigger.
Gives us access
to a thousand characters of input.
What I'd like to do next is test it out
so we can fill in values
down in the bottom right hand corner.
There's a test prompt,
but to get us started,
let's work with one I've done in the past.
This is that same prompt
with some values filled in,
and we'll use it as a reference.
So I'm going to copy the
AI workflows for content creators.
I haven't actually done a video in
about a month for being moving over space,
and I've just arrived in Chiang Mai,
Thailand,
and it's taken me a while to get back up
and running with video content.
But what we'll do
is we'll take all this content highlights
that are done
when whenever I did this video
and we'll paste all the information in
and I'm going to click the test prompt.
We're currently
running the GPT 4o mini.
Let's press that looks like I went 51
characters over the limit of 1000,
but in the original one, this is the
sort of information I had before.
And when we look at it over here,
it looks like a pretty good list of titles
that we can work with.
Now, have we used a credit?
And the answer is, I don't know.
This is the first time
I've used this myself
and what we'll do is we'll
just jump into Nano and we'll just test
the prompt one more time.
And AI responds right here and look,
without actually going deep
and having a look at them side by side.
And this is actually something
I wasn't aware of,
is that I've lost the output
of the previous example.
But from here, these are
pretty good titles to get started with.
Now, before I demonstrate the Pickaxe,
I just want to explain a couple of things,
including a big problem
that I encountered.
So the first is, from a cost
point of view,
the two tests that you've seen me
do have cost to credit.
So we've got 48 to go.
Now, if you go and have a look
at my dashboard at the moment,
one of the things that you'll notice
is that there are no Pickaxes listed.
There is a studio and the reason
this happened is that I was configuring
the Pickaxe that you just saw in the video,
and then I pressed a button
which took me to an information screen
and everything got lost.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to click on the new Pickaxe again.
We're going to go in and click on the form
and I'm going
to show you a recreation
and what not to do.
So here we are
at the new Pickaxe now on a different tab.
I've gone and recreated it again.
And the reason this all happened
is that I lost all the information
is that as you're filling
this out, it's not actually being saved.
And I was just having a look around down
below and I clicked on this
“more options”.
And what it did was
take me to a different page
and I couldn't figure out how to go back.
So I press the back button
and everything was gone.
So what we'll do right now
is press the publish button
and hopefully what's going to happen
is this now site.
So just be aware that at the moment
there's probably a few changes
I need to make to this product
to make it a bit more sound,
but we now have a YouTube
title generator, so we're now on a page
where we've got a URL, which would be
to our YouTube title generator.
We've also got this concept
called website, and that's telling us
your website is a canvas
to hold all your Pickaxes.
So I think what we can do
is just go and open that.
And it's again, it's opening it in page,
not in a new page.
So we've got it all listed here.
It says home
and we're not saying our title generator.
And what I think that is because of
if we go and click on it right here,
there's this website unlisted.
So what we'll do
is we'll say listed right here.
And you can't see it
because my head is covering it I think.
But we'll go and click back on this
and see if that's become available.
Yes. It has now got the YouTube title
generator, which I can click on
and that should take us to
our title generator.
If we just go back one more time,
we should also be able to click on it
by using this button.
So if we use this button right here
that actually opened it
in a new tab, which was more
what I wanted to see happen before.
And we can minimize this area
and start working with it.
Now it's got the information that I left in.
So the next thing I'm going to have to do
is go back and edit this
so that that's actually
this is classed as placeholder text.
So this is really good.
So what we'll do now
is will test it for real.
And what I've got down here is a bunch
of videos that I've done in the past.
One was when I was recently made
redundant, and I did a video
on how I'm planning to create a digital
AI agency.
And so if we move further down
in this conversation,
we should be able to find a short title
that we can work with.
So a copy of that information,
I will just paste it in here.
And then we'll copy that information
and we'll grab that information
and paste it in here.
And we're within the limits
which is good to see.
And these were the titles that were done
at that period of time
when I used it in ChatGPT.
But we'll just press submit.
And there is a “See history”.
So that's something I had an issue
with when testing it.
I wasn't able to see the earlier
title list,
but apparently this has a “see history”,
so maybe we can see more.
We've got information going down here.
What does this do?
And okay, maybe I'm
going to test it with another video.
But let's just see
a comparison side by side.
So what we've got on
the left is what it's come up with.
It's a good set of titles
now where it's a little different to
what I've done in the past
is that when I generated the titles
the first time around, I kind of liked
this particular one for the video.
It's “Lost my job, found my purpose:
Here's what I did”.
But I had access to conversation bot
because I was in ChatGPT
and I was actually able
to improve this particular title.
And where that ultimately got to
was this video
where according to VidIQ,
it had a 91 score.
And one of the things I just noticed
right now is that it's unlisted.
I had it unlisted because there were
people that I was communicating with,
and I didn't want to tell them
that I had lost my job, mainly
because for me, it was
this all happened a month and a half ago.
This is why I'm in Chiang Mai
and ended up with this great opportunity.
But after four years,
it was also a little bit of ego
busting going on because of the job
I was in.
But that said, well, here
we've got on the right the titles
that you can see
and the improvements I can have,
because the conversational capability,
we've got the titles
that are here on the left and earlier on
I was looking to see how I could implement
chat capability into this,
which was the reason
I actually lost all the information
which I talked about earlier in the video.
But what we'll do is we'll come back
to this particular list,
we'll go to videos right here
and we'll find another one to work with.
So let's go with b10.
And in here, if we look for that
title again, we've got another set of data
that we can use,
so synthesizing multi conversational chats.
And is it a case of we can just update it
I think we can. Yep.
All pretty easy.
We'll just press submit on that.
And while that's generating whatever
it's doing we can go and have a look
to what I had originally streamlined
ChatGPT chats
into actionable documents.
And what have we got here?
So there we go.
So the original one we just did
is down here
and we've got the new one going on
right here, which is pretty cool.
Now another thing to notice
is that the history of
we can click on this particular one
if you want to go to them quickly.
Now, if you're actually interested
in that particular video, like I said,
I've just made it public right now.
It got a bunch of views in the first week,
and then I just turned it off.
So let's go back and look at one
more aspect of this system.
So one of the things you notice on
this page
is that you've got this beautiful image.
We've got a title, getting started,
and this is all customizable.
I'm going to do another video
on that in the future.
But I think we just need
to look at the usage.
It's not quite showing you exactly
what's going on.
We've got the total users is two.
One use this today. Two users today.
And we can see the information going on.
But this is from the public facing
aspect of it.
It doesn't include the actual tests
we did.
If we move over to the dashboard
we've got information here.
You click on the username,
you'll be taken over to this page
where you can see the actual pricing
and you can see the actual credits
we used, which is four
have been used. Two in testing, two
as part of the little micro application
that we've published to the internet
for people to use.
So that's Pickaxe.
What we've done is we've created
our YouTube title generator.
It's a little tool
that's been hooked up to a little website.
In the next video,
what I'll do is I'll play around
with a little bit of the designs
and create another workflow just to see
how flexible
this is in other sorts of situations.
But if you want to work with me
one on one, then just head over to AppyDave.com
There's a there's a book
a call button that you can click on
and that will take you to an area where
we can have a discovery call or just work
one on one in a strategy session on prompt
engineering or AI agent workflows.
I'm AppyDave.
Look forward to seeing you in the next video.