Hi, I heard about a library called HTMX from one of the senior developers on my team.
And I was curious, could I learn how to use HTMX without a lot of JavaScript experience?
In this AppiCast, I walked through how I created this product listing website,
using just ChatGPT to learn how to use HTMX.
G'day, I'm Appi Dave and in this AppiCast, we're going to look behind the scenes at this
software called HTMX. Now, I believe it's a JavaScript library that allows you to use
a native HTML sort of setup and the attributes will allow you to do some sort of JavaScript.
I haven't used it, I've just been told about it. So, we'll go into Google search and we've got
HTMX Google search and high-powered tools for HTML and we have this landing page.
Now, what I'm going to do is just copy this basic information here.
Don't need the sponsors, I don't think. So, we'll go into ChatGPT,
do that and let's go with ChatGPT form and say,
you are an expert in writing HTML, JavaScript and CSS comma, but you have come across a library
called HTMX comma and what this library is designed to do is allow you to do JavaScript style of
events using pure HTML. Here is a little bit of information about this software comma. Can you
tell me in 20 words what this software or library will do? So, we have HTMX's small library for
Ajax, CSS, WebSockets, server-side, server-cent events. It uses simple HTML attributes. Okay,
that sounds interesting. Now, we're here, we've got, looks like we've got docs, so let's click on there
and we have, looks like everything here is just a hash anchor. I think all the information is there,
let's just check. It's all there. So, that makes our lives a bit easier. Let's just go into post
slide reader where all the information is now in one simple document. I'm going to copy it and
I've set up a little folder to get started and we'll put the documentation in there.
Now, I'll just get rid of anything that says post slide.
So, that won't make any sense to chat GPT. Looks like we've got the information we need. Now,
there's 900 odd lines of information and I'm assuming some of these lines are pretty long. So,
this information is way too big for chat GPT. What would happen if I paste it in is
it would just say this is too big. So, what we will do is go back up to the top,
select it all and delete it and I think, let's, we're in Java, we're in an environment where
we can do some JavaScript. So, let's create a file called split to files.txt and we'll hit save on
our documentation and what we want to do is take a file called documentation.md as an input and
a size in characters as a second parameter and then split the documentation.md file into
n number of files. Let's make this a comment. Each size
as characters long and write two files called doc01.md doc02.md etc.
And we'll just copy that comment and let's see what chat GPT can do with that.
And we'll say
in JavaScript. Okay, it looks okay. We'll see, see wherever it is.
Hit save. We'll open up a terminal just at this location. I think 1000 is a bit small. I think
we could go for about 8000 and LSA. We've got documentation.md. We'll just type
node and we have a bunch of files here. So, HTMX finishes at LO,
starts at load polling. Okay, so I think we got our documentation that we just got from the HTMX
here. Let's take this first one and throw it in and say,
now one of the things that probably didn't really need to do
was have this script in the same robot or the same bot that we were starting with.
Usually I would set up a new chat window for that, but because it's the only bit of information in
here, we can just go and edit this and the bot will kind of forget that this information existed
unless we change back to it. So what I'm going to do is say, can you read this information
and tell me five interesting things about it and we just paste that in.
We'll press save and submit and it will overwrite the split text code that we had.
The split text code is still there because you can go back through these like this
and you can see it here if you needed it, but I believe that because we're now on path number
three here, the bot as it moves forward won't have any knowledge about the split text,
which is great because we're not actually interested in that concept for testing out this library.
Okay, HTML extends HTML capabilities so allows us to do HTTP requests.
I think, can you give me basic installation instructions comma and a hello world HTML file
to get started. So hello world is the default thing that you do whenever you're starting
a new programming language or library. Obviously, we want it to do something that uses the library,
so it might not quite be what we need, but let's go with that. So it says we can set up our HTML
with this. Let's copy that. Let's create a new folder here. We call it documentation
and we'll move all of this
up here. Now we'll go for a new file and we'll call it sorry.html.
And if we click on this, this will take us over to the library, which is great.
If you prefer, you can download the file. We don't need to do that. And since it is
a hello world sort of thing, let's see what this does. So I'm just going to copy that and replace
the other one. Now we got a div idea message. So I guess this is a get request to an end
point called hello. We're triggered on the click event target message. So whatever comes back,
I'm assuming is going to go into here somehow. Swap the outer HTML. Click me to say hello.
So I do not believe we have enough information to get started, but let's run this. Open in a live
server. Click me to say hello. Okay. Nothing happened there. Once you have a server that responds,
okay. How would would you suggest I set up a server to respond to slash hello?
Okay, let's just run with that. So make server CD server. I don't know that we need the M. Oh,
yes. The HTML weekend, but the life server is for taking static sort of HTML, loading them up.
It's not for actually having a back end server. So we need to create a back end server.
We've called it my server. I wouldn't call it just server, but this is what it said.
Well, NPN install express. And what's this to have a server.js. So let's create that file,
we call it pasted in. And there's an endpoint that returns hello world.
Yeah, we just we run it. We what we might do here server.js. Is that right?
Looks like it is. Local host. Let's open that up. And let's just hit that hello
endpoint. Okay, so that's working. And maybe. Okay, so the first thing to notice is that I've
run the HTML in live server, which means any get requests coming back from the library,
coming back to this same location, which is not the same as our server. So I think what we'll do
is rather than using live server to host this page, let's let our own server do that. So we'll
just ask the question. Can you set up an endpoint called test one that will return
the file test zero one dot HTML?
Do this within the express JS server code that we wrote earlier.
Okay, so let's just follow that path.
That was good. Looks like public create a folder called public.
Put it into my server. Take our file, put it into public. So there.
Go back. I'm just going to copy everything. We know I'm going to copy everything because
we've lost the hello world thing. But let's copy it anyway.
Go to our server, paste it all in. Same. We got a path thing.
Yeah, that's right. We got a join and we still want that, don't we?
So let's rerun this.
Hello world is still working. And now hello world.
Test one is also working. And that says hello world. So we've got the first bit of code working.
We've used chat Jpt to do it all. We haven't read the manual, which is interesting.
What we can now do is take this a little bit further.
We'll tell it first. For each example that I want you to create, could use
make both the HTML page and the express JS route to serve it from now on.
It's doing stuff. So that's great. So we got a great one in this case.
Didn't quite get it the way I wanted.
And the express JS route to serve the HTML page from.
Yeah, that looks right. Second page would be what we're talking about.
That's interesting. Don't even know whether this work. This is like a HTML partial.
So there's our main page. Let's take that section just here.
Go into HTML one. I'm going to call this index, set the name they went with it was
go to our server code, call that index. We'll leave this code. It should still work.
And we'll paste in this additional code here. Just hit refresh on
local host. So now we've got click to say hello. That code should still be working.
It does, which is cool. Hit refresh. Now load second page wouldn't work because we haven't
got a second page, but it's suggested that we have something called second page.
And we'll just copy that pop in over here.
So it's just a partial. It's not the full HTML. And this should just get replaced by.
So what is it? Welcome to the second page.
And we don't need to refresh. We should just click it. There you go. Very cool.
Yeah. Yeah. We have a partial working straight up. Yeah. Okay. Okay. I think we have basic
understanding of how this works. What I want to do now is really just load all the documentation
into chat GPT and just interrogate it as I do each one. So let's start off with a prompt that goes
I'm going to insert all the documentation for HTMX in
and for each piece of content, I want you to tell me three things that might be
interesting within that content. Say yay if you understand.
You paused. Okay. So let's go with this. I'm going to say
paste that in.
Thank you. Understanding HTMX. HTMX stands for HTML extension for Ajax.
By extending HTML, HTMX allows any element to issue a HTTP request.
Any event trigger request, any HTTP verb to be used. Installation. It's straightforward.
You can use CDN or download it. I think we use the CDN. Triggering request request and modifiers
provides granular control over triggering Ajax requests by default elements like input,
text area and form are triggered on the change and submit events while others are triggered
by the click event. However, the HX-trigger attribute. So that's something I guess we can use
just there allows you to customize which event will trigger the request. Additionally,
trigger modifiers such as once changed delay or throttle and from provide additional control.
Great. So we got polling capability provides polling that can be very useful for creating
dynamic and responsive applications using the every syntax with the HX-trigger.
So we got that there. You can set an element to poll a given URL at regular intervals.
So we should think about that. Let's go into chat.
And we'll try and find some URL that we can poll and get something interesting from it on a
timely basis. Ajax and special events. So HTML core is set up with attributes to enable Ajax
requests. What do we got? HX get. So get request, post, port, patch, and delete requests allow
different HTTP methods to be issued. Great. Let's move on to number two. I just took two
letters from the previous one and added it in. I might just say
the four interesting things in 15 to 25 words per item. And then we'll paste it in.
What I'm also going to do is take a copy of that because we're going to use this fairly often.
And we'll just put it there. It's like a prompt that we're going to use.
Move on to number three in a moment, but let's see what it's saying.
Load polling. In scenarios where a process has a definitive endpoint such as progress bars,
load polling is useful. Okay. Request indicators. Users, HTMX indicate a class to provide
user feedback during Ajax requests. This class manages the visibility of the indicator based
on the request status. Okay. I don't think we're going to set this sort of stuff up. We could do.
Target specification. HTMX allows the response to load into a different element than the request
one using the HX target. The support standard and extended CSS syntax for flexibility.
So I guess something we could do here is that if we had, let's say we had a nine by nine square,
let's say we were doing some sort of product listing, we might be able to go get information
that updates all nine listings at the same time, especially if it was the same value for each
listing, or we could update each individual item. So I'm thinking what could we build?
I think we might look at a couple of games if possible. We'll look at Word or maybe we'll look
at Connect 4. But looking at the nature of this library, I think it might be easier to work more
with our web page with dynamic content. So let's say it was like a Shopify product landing page.
And maybe, so let's switch that out. So there's a product landing page with
a grid and maybe even lazy load. Let's move that over there. And maybe there's a product description
page. It'd be interesting if we could use this software and chat gpt and make
that sort of concept pretty easily. See whether this is at all possible.
We come back and we got DOM swapping. HTML offers diverse ways to swap HTML into the DOM.
Supports to additional swapping, morphing. So it looks like it's got dynamic CSS
transitions. We'll see what that means over time. Let's take number three, paste it in,
take a little prompt from earlier, we'll just paste it in there.
Okay, swap and settle model. It uses a model where new content is swapped in with the old
attribute values, then the new attribute values are swapped after settled delay,
allowing CSS transitions to work without additional JavaScript. Okay, out of band swaps.
HTMX can directly swap content from the response into the DOM using an ID attribute
with the HX swap OOB attribute. Okay, file upload. Uploads via setting the HX encoding
attribute to multi-part form data. And then there's a progress event that we can hook into
to see the file uploading. Okay, let's jump over here. Let's stay here. Bursting and progressive
enhancement. HTMX can burst regular HTML anchors and forms into Ajax requests
with the burst attribute supporting progressive enhancement by degrading gracefully
if JavaScript is not enabled. Okay, I think what we'll just do is we'll push on with each question
quickly. Do that one. We'll get another one going form data. And then there's a progress event that
we can hook into to see the file uploading. Okay, let's jump over here.
No, let's stay here. Bursting and progressive enhancement. HTMX can burst regular HTML anchors
by degrading gracefully if JavaScript is not enabled. Okay, I think what we'll just do is we'll
push on with each question quickly. Do that one. We'll get another one going. And one last one.
Let's just read some of this while it's going. Okay, we've read that.
We've read that HTMX promotes progressive enhancement to ensure broader user accessibility
using normal HTML accessibility recommendations like semantic HTML. And clear focus states
supports declarative use of web sockets and service and events, allowing real time interaction
with clients and servers. History support in HTMX enables interaction with the browser history
API so you can go back through different pages by using push URL attribute
allows us to use a back function. HTMX operates with Ajax. And what do we got firing events and
response or connection errors, and also supports cross origin resource sharing. Move on down.
All that's going. We'll start another one here. We have a validate an event
hook allowing developers to add custom validation logic. Check validity. Failed
an event is invoked when validity is false. Haunted. Triggered when a request
isn't issued due to a validation error and non form elements don't validate
by default making before making requests. Okay, scroll down.
The hate checks on allows you to respond to any event provides locality of behavior
enabling scripting logic to be embedded with the relevant HTML elements. Okay. Hyperscript a
front end scripting language created by the team pairs well with HTMX. It's designed easily
for easy embedment in HTML handling custom events and providing a more expressive
scripting language. That's interesting. intercooler.js and hyperscript implementations.
I see remove after so I don't know what this is, which is fine. We'll just jump in there
and we'll just paste it in there as well.
intercooler is a JavaScript library that adds simple and efficient way to add
Ajax functionality to a web application. Click me. Let's keep going.
And we've got caching. Prevents XSS attacks. Let's look at the configuration via meta tags.
Okay. What I'm going to do is build a second brain.
So we have a list of features. And as a secondary item, let's convert it into a blog post.
Could you write me a blog post? And there's a reason for this. I'm trying to create a brain
for a different robot at the moment. Could you write me a blog post that thoroughly
describes the HTMX application
for someone that wanted to use this library?
And most of its features in about 2000 words. Okay.
And what we're going to do was we'll see what this writes. Hopefully it does a good job,
but we're going to use this blog post and the feature list, the 20 feature list that we had
to drive a new bot. Okay. And so we've condensed. Okay. So what I'll do is we'll create a new
document here and we'll call it condensed documentation.md. And we will take all the information
that it's written in this blog post. And we'll just paste it in there like that.
And where it says copy code, let's just fix up a couple of things like that.
We'll copy all the features here and go documentation feature list.md, paste it in there.
And we'll just rename this so that they're grouped together down the bottom. And then we'll start
up a new chatbot. Let me let me introduce you to a new JavaScript library called HTMX.
And what we'll do is we'll take the condensed documentation and the feature list
posted in and say, please read and say yay. Okay. Now you understand the general features
of this JavaScript library comma. Can you give me a list of five different simple
HTML applications that might be suitable for implementation with this language?
So I was thinking whether forecast image gallery, shopping cart. Okay.
Sounds great. One more. Can you see this being used for a shop with a list of products and
a display page for each product comma and some sort of filtering capability for the list of products.
Great. Let's I have set up a simple server.js using expressjs. And
this is its current content. We can change this code as we see fit and add new
controller actions to support the different pages or configuration.
When it comes to a list of products, we will use a JSON document to store that information.
So let's see what it does. Okay. We've got two products started.
Let's just make sure we have that file. We got product one product. Looks good to me.
Copy the code. Go back to our server. Okay. They both get requests.
It's also given us a HTML. We'll dynamically load the products here.
And we'll show one product here. Okay. Let's just take this.
I don't remember exactly how this is.
Am I supposed to have an ID called outer HTML or am I not understanding the use of this
attribute correctly? I know what I'll do. So I'll just paste that in. A list container.
Okay. Maybe I should also just be reading this a little bit. Cool.
The value of outer HTML is one option. Probably replace the whole element or replace inside
the element. Okay. That looks correct. In this updated code, the HX swap inner HTML attribute
is used instead of outer. This will replace the inner HTML content of the post list container.
That feels better to me at least. Let's pop in over here. We'll go to our index page.
Let's just throw them both in. Copy this one.
I'm just going to run it and see where we're at.
Hit save. Unexpected token in the JSON. Okay. Feels like we're good now.
Now, let's test the endpoints. Build my endpoints using this domain port.
There and there. Home page worked. Product list worked. Let's change this to a one.
That one worked. And the second one worked. So our endpoints are okay.
Okay. So if we know that we can get an individual product, we can get a list of products and we
have a HTML page, but we have nothing showing, then what we really need to ask it is,
can you add a div using the HTML that will list the products from the products.json?
But let's stop that because there's an error there.
Okay. This code that you have given me does not actually work because you are not rendering any
HTML for each of the products. Okay. That looks a little bit better.
So that pops in the side. Let's see if that works.
Great. Now, so name description price. So we'll just ask it.
Okay. We're looking at a HTML page. We've got some sort of HTML being shown, not in a loop.
And if we click on it, we get data. So I think I have a misunderstanding of how this product works,
but at this point in the video, I made a couple of assumptions and I went down some rabbit holes.
And the assumptions was that this library was going to work similar to tools like react and
HTML and render it to the screen. And I was thinking that way. I'm like trying to bring back
JSON, which is not the way it works because this particular library uses a different technique
called HTML over the wire. So if I type in HTML over the wire, we search for it,
we have this library out there that's popular with certain type of developers and it's called
hot wire. And what it does is rather than going back, getting JSON, turning it into HTML in the
client, it just goes and hits an endpoint and gets HTML. And whatever HTML comes back, it just puts
it into an ID or whatever on the HTML DOM. So this is, so HTML X, I think, works very similar to
hot wire in that regard. And this is just something I didn't understand at the point when I was
communicating with ChatGPT. Rather than the JSON directly,
won't matter that it's spelled that wrong, you should understand what we're talking about.
So what we'll do is we've got products,
we'll grab that, and we've got our server JS, which has so far been returning
product JSON. And we'll try that out. So we'll come back to our page here, hit refresh.
Let's just click. Okay, let's just look at our products listing here.
Probably need to restart the server. So let's test this endpoint. Now we've got some HTML that
looks better. Let's come back to this page, we'll refresh it and we'll just click here.
Great. So now we have a list of products. I think the next thing is, let's make it clickable.
Can you alter the HTML a little bit so that if I click on the div surrounding the product entry,
comma, it will go and get data from the products slash
point and replace that into the second details div
named. And let's just go find that. We had it over on the index HTML. Looks like that.
Let's make sure you change endpoint to endpoint.
Point. Thank you. So we have a product list. Did we have that before product list?
We didn't. So this looks better to me.
Give a h1 silly machine. You have not followed the documentation.
There is no concept of a hx dash each in the documentation.
You instead need to render out the server side HTML with a clickable link to swap the detail HTML.
Well, it's a bit bogus. That's a bit bogus, but we'll see what it does.
Okay, it's not going to get it right for me.
Let's, I just want to take that, I believe. I also did not read this correctly because it already had
a heading in here. So let's get rid of all of that.
We've got our product list HTML.
For now, I'm just going to wrap this around the div.
So we'll refresh the page. Just click there. Okay, now we've got
a hyperlink like that. It's a little bit odd, but that's okay. We'll click on it.
And it has returned. So whatever code it gave me was not JavaScript interpolation.
Just put that in there.
Hit save, refresh and click on there.
Product list, products.
What we now need is to have a look at our product side decode, which is still returning
JSON. And we need to alter that. So come in here and say,
can you alter the individual product end point, which takes an ID and currently returns JSON?
And instead, can you return a detailed page of HTML? And can you include
an image element with a fake image placeholder?
Can you alter the HTML slightly so that it does not have a HTML or body tag?
Because the HTML that we are using is meant to be a partial, not the full page.
Okay, that's looking good to me. Let's pop that over here.
Okay, we've restarted the server. Let's just check this HTML is coming back. Okay,
rather than JSON, that looks good. And we've got a placeholder image.
Let's try one. Fantastic. I think while we're at it, let's create a couple of fake images.
Imagine a product, say product image of a baseball.
And what we'll do, let that start off, we'll do another one while we're here.
And we'll say product image of a baseball cap.
And do another one, product image of a baseball mitt. So we've got a cap.
We'll let them go. And what we'll do is we'll replace them in overtime. But we come back
to this code here. So I think I want to remove this. That shouldn't be in there.
We now have our list container. We have our details container. And in theory,
this loop over the products will affect our list. And this will affect the detail.
So let's do a refresh. Okay. Now, we have this problem
that it only works when I click on it. I need to work on that in a moment. But let's call that xxx
refresh and click on it. Okay. Something we need to do, we'll load that on page start. Oh,
look at that. That all worked. Product two come up. Now we'll come up as well.
So product two, product one. Nice. While we're here, let's go and have a look at the images that
got created. And that's not a mitt. I got a lot of gloves, don't I? Baseball glove.
Let's come back to here. And which one do you like?
I like the one. Yeah, the one, like Tom right?
Top number two. What do you like?
Bottom right. Bottom right? Yep. Okay. Let's upscale that.
Let's download that image.
Let's download that image. And which one do you like? One, two, three or four?
I don't like any of them. Yeah, no, no, I like, I like top left.
Top left? Well, upscale that. Yep. So what we'll do is we'll jump on down to our
one. So I'm going to update this Jason. I'm going to let the software do it. We'll go with this one.
Can I get you to alter this Jason document so that it has three products, comma, the first
product is a baseball cap. The second product is a baseball comma. The third product is a baseball
glove comma. Can you give me a nice 20 word description for each product, please?
And set an appropriate price. Cool. Let's test, take that. Can you update
this Jason so that it has an image element? Okay, let's copy that. Let's take
each of these and get rid of them. Baseball cap, baseball, baseball glove, great.
Let's come back to our images, save image. We will go over to finder, download images.
Okay, we have our three images here. Let's just create a folder called
images and we'll just drag them in and let's rename them. I think we went with one word for each of
those. Cool. Let's just change these image URLs so that they say we'll worry about the
path in the Jason rather than in the HTML. Keep things simple. Go to our servers, restart it,
press refresh, click on this. Looking good. And we do not have the placeholder cross.
I think what we can do. Can you alter the HTML in the response so that it uses the new image tag
in the product Jason file, comma. Can you also create an endpoint to deliver the image
based on the images folder?
Let's see what that does. I don't think that worked at all.
Product list, product detail. Okay, so what it's done is
serving up the images using the static here. Let's just go to the top, post that in there.
I think it gave it the wrong information. And let's not use GPT. It's probably easy enough
to just go product.image. Sorry. Can you tell it to use that? I can teach it to use it,
but it's not worth it for something that I can do myself much quicker.
What I can do at the end is give it all my code and tell it this is the current state of the
program. So that's a good question, but we don't need to do that. So we click here. So we click here.
And we're looking okay, but it's not finding the image. Okay, I went offline for two minutes just
to resolve the issue. I put the images folder into the public directory. It should have just
been under the server. The other issue I had was that each of the images had an underscore.
That's how they were being downloaded from mid journey and normal convention would be to use a
dash. So I've put a dash in there, made sure that this is just referencing the images slash
file name. Let's do a refresh click on here. Get a product and there's a baseball
hat, a baseball. Let's get rid of that, etc. Let's
go back to chat GPT and say, let's look at what our HTML looks like.
Click that. I have the following HTML and I would like to style the image using CSS so that it looks
like a Polaroid image. So I altered that a little bit to say give CSS for a nicely
framed picture in a blog post. Now we get this HTML. Let's trial that.
Let's create a style tag. Save. So it looks like we need a div.
Class sequels. End of div. Let's run that. It looks good. We'll make it 50% of the page we do.
Let's just go with 50%. I'm not a CSS person, but that should work.
That looks good. That looks good. That looks good. I wonder what would happen if we just go back to
our HTML. Just reverse these around. Chance it to say click for all products.
And I think we can get rid of those now. They're not adding any value.
Chance it to say, I think we can get rid of that too. Refresh. Click for all products. Okay.
Looks good to me. Let's bring this down. I'm not really a HTML person. I'm not a CSS person.
I'm not even a JavaScript person. I'm just a software architect.
But using off the shelf library, I was able to get a product listing and product details working
using just ChatGPT. If I can do it, anyone can do it.