OpenAI released this awesome feature yesterday in ChatGPT, the ability to call
multiple GPTs from the store or your personal ones or within one context
window. Now I did a video on this yesterday, today's video is a cut-down
version just showing you step-by-step how to use it. So we're in a brand new
ChatGPT window and if I type in the at symbol we'll have access to a bunch of
GPTs that you've either used or created, many of these I've created. So if we
look at F Tube teaser, this turns a YouTube video into a Facebook teaser
post, got the same thing for tweets, I can make YouTube intros and recently I
did seven GPTs specifically for YouTube content creators, you can check that out
in the link. Let's talk briefly about why app mention is so important and the
inclusion by OpenAI of custom instructions sometimes called a system
prompt to be really powerful feature. It allowed me to start new chat windows
that had rules that it would follow, maybe it'd be some commands that it would
respond to or maybe it would be the style in which you responded. But the
problem with this system was that whenever you wanted to create a new
chat window you would need to clear out the custom instruction and create a new
one. Next, OpenAI added in GPTs. Now GPTs similar to custom instructions allow
you to create rules and the way ChatGPT would respond but where it's different
is that now you can have multiple GPTs and you can start a new chat window
based off a particular GPT. It's a good enhancement but it still has one big
problem and that's that it can't talk to other GPTs. Yesterday a new capability
was added into ChatGPT and that was the ability to use the app symbol and
mention various GPTs in your regular conversation. Now they didn't speak about
it, there was no fanfare about this and I've come to understand that it's
probably because it's not solidified as to how it's going to work in the future
but at the moment it works really well and what you can do now is from a
regular chat window you can then switch over to any of the GPTs in the store or
any that you've created. Let's dive in and see how this fits together and I'll
show you an example of it being used. What I think I'll do is I'll just use
speech to text and we'll just type a prompt right now. Everything that we've
talked about above is exactly what this feature is about. What I would like you
to do is take the information and run it through my Twitter creation bot and
create a tweet for me. What we'll do is we'll just type at tweet tube. Talking to
cheek tube is what it does and we've just got this prompt and press enter and
we'll see whether it does what I expect it to do. Wow this is it. It's writing
tweets the way my tweet tube bot does so discover the power of customization with
chat GPT plus at feature instantly switch between specialized GPT models for
tailored responses perfect for content strategists educators tech pros writers
and polyglots that's people that work in multiple languages. It's put in a bunch
of hashtags usually this is a one-hit wonder I'm really happy with this. This
is cool already I'm already sold on this feature but maybe I could create an
intro for this particular video that I'm recording. I'm still talking to the
tweet tube so I believe we'll just press this cross take me over to the at YouTube
intro GPT and allow me to configure it so that we can create a YouTube intro for
this particular video. Looks like I might have to type this in so we'll go intro maker
press enter. It's taken me over to my bot YouTube intro maker bot has a
configuration capability now it talks about it here. The niche we're going for
is GPT plus the topic is that there's a feature announcement called at mentions
in chat GPT plus. Now the framework you can use marketing frameworks like AIDA
and Paz Paz is problem agitation solution but I like to keep things fairly
simple so I'll go with none keep it simple and the structure I think we want
is problem solution what's problem here's the solution and the tone excited I
think this is an awesome feature but keep it professional just press enter on
that I think we can just say create is one of the commands I think we'll copy
from here all the way through fact sheet that you would want for a script on this
sort of video we'll move down to the bottom and we'll just say create an
intro based on this concept we have a starter intro script welcome to the
future of AI customization and efficiency today we're unveiling an
extraordinary feature in chat GPT plus the at feature simply a powerful tool
that's changing the game problem highlight have you ever found yourself
wishing for a more specialized efficient and integrated AI experience this is my
issue all the time with chat GPT one that understands your specific needs
without having to switch contacts or explain repeatedly your weight is over
and then the solution with the at feature in chat GPT plus you now have the
ability to quickly access various GPT models tailored for unique tasks and
areas of expertise what we could do is just say this intro is really good I
love the first three paragraphs but it's way too long at the moment everything
goes for about one minute and 30 seconds to two minutes I really need this to be
a 30 second script it's now writing a new script for us with a little bit of
tweaking would be a good introduction to the video let's just switch one more
context can you create an article for me on LinkedIn at link tube and the idea of
the link tube article generator is it's a single shot prompt it'll get it right
most times it's designed specifically around turning YouTube videos into
LinkedIn articles I'm just going to say create and I'm going to paste this in
which is basically the script from earlier usually when I do a create
command for a LinkedIn post I would also give it the title and the YouTube
video but we haven't created the YouTube video yet we can't do that just go
create like that and see what happens now we've got a title which may be the
title that we want to use I would usually use my title GPT to generate
this revolutionizing AI interactions the app feature in chat GPT plus I think
that might be good enough for the video anyway introduction in the ever-
evolving world of artificial intelligence we've got concepts problems
practical use cases and conclusions can you add emojis and hashtags please let
it rewrite the article now with a couple of emojis tube outro writer and
we're in it and we'll just go straight into a config so we'll just configure it
and we'll go with a style here called recap so whatever we've said in the
video we want to recap it but I only want it to go for about 15 seconds and I
want to have a link to a playlist I believe in this case I've done YouTube
automation GPT's there's a bunch of them all in a playlist and that's what we
should mention now the outro that you're seeing on screen right now went into
yesterday's video thank you I'm happy Dave and I've included a link to the
GPT's in the end card