Good day. It's AppyDave.
And today we're talking about using
Claude artifacts and Claude widgets.
And I'm here with Alec from Take One Tech.
Good day, Alec, how are you, mate?
Great to see you all. All good.
Thank you.
And, thank you for coming on
this live stream at the last minute.
I just,
this was just something I decided to do
yesterday, asked if you wanted to come.
You're on board.
And,
this is related to some conversations
that we've been having around, vibe
coding, building applications on the fly
and potentially,
how can you build applications
that we can use in live streams,
like what we're doing now.
And also dealing with how
we can build applications just to solve
different business related problems.
But what's your take on
what's going on in the vibe coding,
the Cloude code, the artifacts?
What what's your knowledge of this
at the moment?
Well,
certainly not as deep as yours.
And that's why
I always value your opinions.
Because you're someone who comes to this
with, you know, extensive programing
experience already, so can,
can actually see, the real time savings
that are involved with it.
And I just,
you know, know that
all those things that we've looked at,
like in, group sessions that we've
had, it's been just amazing
to see how quickly you can now
develop these sorts of things
with, a few simple prompts.
So yeah, excited to see where this goes.
Okay, well, let's get into it.
What I've done is
I've set up a couple documents
which hopefully will lead to success
in the creation of applications today.
And the first one I've set up
is just a little live stream outline.
And I'm just going to take a copy
of this information,
and I'm going to head over to a Chat GPT
window. But the document, that we're going
to be working with, the Cloude Artifacts
live stream was made in Gemini,
and it's about knowing
when to use the right tool
to solve the problem.
So what I've done is
I've got a little project going called
App-a-Day, because my goal is to be able
to build an application every day.
But what we're doing today is looking at
live widgets, live stream.
And I've just started this conversation
and we have access
to the live stream document,
and we've also just grabbed
all the information around the outline.
And what I'm going to do
is I'm just going to read this information
and use it as a starting point.
Now, the information
that I've just dropped in here
is basically a five point
outline of what I want to cover.
So I'm just going to say,
can you just tell me what the first area
that we're talking about
today is going to be about?
And the reason I'm doing it
the way I'm doing it is that I want to
take the information dynamically,
however it comes out of ChatGPT
or Gemini or Claude,
and I want to turn it into stuff.
And in this case, maybe
we turn it into some sort of presentation
in Cloude, that might be a good way
to go, actually.
So like I said, it's
very fly by the seat of your pants.
So the goal of this is the big picture
of widgets introduced to Claude artifacts.
We're going to explain the completion
code system, and we're going
to highlight the deployment,
how it's
how you can deploy this
for free for content creators.
Now, best way to get started
is to build our first application.
So I'm going to head over
to a little thumbnail that I created.
And right next to that we have Claude.
And in here I'm going to give it
a simple little instruction and says,
I would like you to build
little Claude artifacts
for me, little micro applications.
And the first one I want to do
is some sort of present and slide deck
that tells people about what
we're doing in the live stream together.
Here is the first piece of information.
And I'm going to get rid of the word first,
because it's actually
the whole information.
And what I'm hoping is going to happen
here is it's going to create
a split pane window in a moment
in which what we can see is code
being generated on the right,
based on the information
that we entered in on the left.
So essentially I created a pre prompt.
Pre prompt is
this is what I'd like you to do.
I'd like you to create some artifacts.
And then I just took the information
which was taken
from the first part of my outline.
And what Claude will start doing
is creating what's called a HTML document.
We can see that this is starting
to show up as a presentation.
It's got a class
called presentation going here.
So we have our first artifact created.
That is just mind blowing,
what's just happened.
It has just driven me insane.
Like it literally just wrote out
what you're looking at there, is not like,
I mean, it's a presentation,
but it's an HTML presentation.
It's just being created with a, you know,
it's created the look and feel of it.
It's created dynamically
moving background, going on
there as well.
And it was like seconds
it just it just spat it out.
It was amazing. Amazing.
let's test whether this works.
And let's also test
the widget feature.
So this is now a publishable link.
I can go and click on this button
right here.
And if I head back to the starting point.
So everything started from here,
I should actually be able
to just paste that URL in.
What do we got here?
Building with Claude artifacts, creating
micro applications in the life stream.
but I like it.
And look at that,
look at these background animations.
So one of the things, I love
when I watch your live streams,
Alec, is the you've always
got these beautiful backgrounds,
and mine are black, I think. Mine’s
really boring, but look at this.
It's created
this beautiful little rotating background.
We got particles moving.
We got a little bit of information
about what it is.
And we've got these next patterns.
And everything is animating
in really cleanly.
So there's the first application built.
And I didn't know
what we were going to get.
I was 95% confident it was going to work,
but it didn't know
what I was going to get.
And I think that's one of the interesting
aspects of this technology
is that I could ask it to generate
this one more time
and get something, completely different.
I now want to talk about how I actually do
coding.
And I wouldn't usually do coding the way
we just saw.
So I'm just going to kick in here and say,
can you tell me what
topic number two in the live stream is?
And hopefully we're going to get
a little bit of information
about the two persona model.
So the large language model is trained
on a corpus of the entire internet
or whatever it is.
So it's an expert in everything.
And so when it tries
to write out information for us,
it can come from any angle.
So what we're trying to do is tell it
who it is, who it is in life,
what's its behavior, what's its past
way of thinking, by training it and say,
okay, you are a software developer
specializing in a particular
programing language, and it will think
and only access the stuff
from its large language model in relation
to that when it gives it sentences.
So it's just a really good way
of shaping the narrative, towards success.
Right?
But before we do that,
let's just jump back
over to that little application we did.
So we had our little presentation
and we've got you down in the bottom
left hand corner.
We can see your background.
It's blues and it’s pinks and yellows,
and we can see it's just copied that.
Exactly.
So I think the interesting thing is we've
created this presentation a second time.
Not really any different, but we've
got your theme and branding in place.
It is incredible.
Yeah. I'm
glad it picked up on the background
rather than my,
my pasty white, pudgy face.
I would love to have seen
a silhouette of you in the background.
What we'll do is we'll now
start defining who these people are.
Now, one of the things that I've done
in this conversation ahead of time
is I've loaded it up
with all the knowledge of best practices
around Claude artifacts, Claude widgets,
because Claude itself
can write code for anything but Claude
widgets and artifacts
have a limited scope of what they can do.
So we want to ensure
that we don't go out of that.
I would like you to create a requirement.
Right. A product manager sort of role.
I want you to think of it
from the point of view of
if this was a job description
that we went to the internet
and we had to write the job description,
or if we were going to LinkedIn
and we were looking
for a specific consultant,
what would they résumé look like?
What would their skills be?
But what I want you to do as you write
this particular persona is
I want you to ensure that it aligns
with a document that you have access to,
which gives the constraints of the types
of requirements that we can do.
And here’s the document you're looking at.
So all I've done is said,
create me a persona
based on a job seeker résumé
or a LinkedIn consultant.
And I've also said write it
within the guidelines of Claude artifacts.
And this was done using a combination
of open AI, deep research.
And then I took it over to Gemini Pro,
because Gemini Pro can deal
with big documents, and I just refined,
refined it a little bit for the live
stream, saved it into a file
on my computer, and I've just re uploaded
it back to the project.
And so now we actually have the job
description
It's got things like it understands that
Claude doesn't have a big context window.
It's only got about 8000 output tokens.
And what what
this actually means from our point of view
is that when we're creating artifacts,
it can't do big applications yet.
Every time I try to get it to do anything
complex, it fails.
So one of the limitations
that we've baked into
our persona is simple applications.
One of the things
that were baked into it
is that it can't access external APIs.
So one of the things we can't do
with Claude artifacts right now
is taught to say a flight's
API or a Bitcoin stock price API.
None of that's available,
but it does have one concept in there,
and it's the ability
to talk to its completion model,
which means the ability
to do conversational AI.
That's actually built into the artifacts.
And the good thing
is that the person with this job title
knows exactly what they're allowed to do.
So we've done that.
The second persona I need is the developer
who is working with these requirements.
What are the skills and capabilities
of this particular developer?
You can look at what you came up with for
the requirements write up,
but you can also go back to the
original documents found in.
It's great.
And also that you're
trying to solve one problem,
but it's not actually one problem.
It needs to be split down into this
two different components there.
So, you know, splitting the two personas,
I think many would have just tried
to think of what is I'm trying to do and,
and just get someone to do all of that.
I'm going to show you
then how it works in reality.
And what we'll do
is we'll bring up our Claude view,
which we have from earlier,
and we can close that down.
And we've got our conversation
going on here.
Now we'll build our requirements for our
applications over here in the ChatGPT.
And we'll do it
using the actual, requirements rather,
but we'll take the persona
that we've created for the developer.
And that's all here.
I'm just going to go down to the bottom,
and I'm going to press the little
copy button that's right here.
And we're going to come over here and say,
I need you to think
from the point of view of this person.
I will be giving you requirements
later on for you to write software.
But please think from this point of view.
And so we've essentially loaded up
the conversation with a way of thinking,
that's it.
And that said, since this is the
chat conversation where we write software,
not come up with the requirements,
we don't need the requirements writer here.
We only need the software developer here.
So hopefully this is going to lead to
some
good quality software development today.
It means we can come back to this person
and we'll say, we're moving on
to step number three in the live stream.
And I believe it's around
thinking of categories of software
that we can create
using the Cloud Artifact system.
If you looked through this categories,
productivity and organization
tools, visualization dashboards,
games, educational learning aids.
Is there anything here that resonates
for you in the sort of live streams
that you do?
A really obvious one is countdown timer.
I mean, I don't actually use countdowns
on my live stream,
but it is an obvious one.
Maybe a Q&A, although it depends on
how people would interact with that.
Let's look at the widgets
and the countdown timer.
And when we think about countdown timers,
I know we're thinking,
we're generally thinking about it
at the beginning of a live stream.
Count count count, live stream starts.
But, I think another really useful idea
of a countdown timer
is some sort of call to action
in the middle of a live stream.
Person is going to win
a competition in 100 seconds.
And it's just counting down.
And we're seeing it
as some sort of widget in the live stream.
Or we might say in 10s, I'm going to tell you
the five most important Claude
artifact rules.
Okay,
so I think that's what we're going to run
with. So I'm going to come here
and I'm going to say.
I need you to act
as the requirements writer,
and I need you to write a requirements.
We're going to do a widgets
for live streamers
and YouTubers sort of application.
One of the things to be aware of
is that this will be embedded
directly into live streams
that can support chroma keys.
And so we must have a background so that
we can see the rest of the live stream.
And what we're thinking of doing here
is a countdown timer.
But the countdown timer
is going to be towards a call to action
in which people will find out
what the five amazing tips
for using Claude powered applications
or creating Claude powered applications.
How would you write this requirements
document?
We've got the powered countdown teaser
for live streamers. Category, author, purpose.
So OBS, StreamYard.
We're using Ecamm live,
we got a chroma key background.
We've got some sort of countdown
timer, call to action.
Amazing tips.
So that's what's going to happen.
We're going to use tailwind CSS,
which is a styling framework
for web applications
with a little bit of animations going on
apparently.
I like it.
I'm just going to copy it
verbatim and head over to our Claude
powered conversation
and say, I'd like you to create
the following application. The only thing
different to the requirements
is that it's a ten second timer.
As a developer, you need to remember
from now on
that when you're using external libraries
that you should be using CDNJS.
And what happened
is that we've got a working
application here,
but you can see it's not really working.
And I believe that that's
the actual problem we just ran into.
So can you update our code
to fix the styling issues?
Okay.
So it's just rewriting it and it's now
using Cloudflare and there we go.
we've got some confetti. Okay.
Can you make sure that the actual message
“five amazing tips
for Claude” doesn't happen
until the countdown timer happens.
If this works,
I've got a little calculator overlay
kicking into place, and I do.
And this is a widget
overlay in Ecamm, which allows you
to just bring in any HTML, well,
effectively any HTML web page.
But originally it was designed
specifically for HTML widgets.
But now any HTML can be brought in.
What I've come over to our system here
is
I've gone up to this little button
called publish.
And in clicking that you have access
to the public URL that anyone can access.
So I'm just copying the link here
and I'm going to go back over to my scenes
and replace the URL and press save.
And so hopefully, okay that works.
Now we've got one other problem.
And that's the chroma key. Okay.
So obviously
I need a little bit of improvement,
but this was one of the things
that I actually wanted to do.
One of the things I wanted to be able
to do with this sort of technology
was create the presentations on the fly
like we did, just based off raw data,
like create some data, search
for some data with perplexity and go,
now I've got a presentation and have it
just cleanly fit within to the
live stream as you were going.
So that's the goal of that. So,
here we go to our ten second countdown.
Something amazing is going to happen.
A little bit of a line artifact.
We're in the final moment and kaboom!
We got some confetti
and we got messaging coming down.
Another thing to develop
could be, an agenda on screen.
So let's say you've got a live stream
and you want to go through like
a series of agenda items on the screen,
you know,
is that something that could be created
so that, you know, you have
a, almost like the bulleted list
instead of having a full on presentation,
but just something that was, you know,
point one, point two, point three?
I'd be able to sort of move through those
that that could be
another cool thing to try.
That would be, straightforward.
Let's test it.
Let's come to here and say, okay.
You're acting from the point of view
of the requirements writer.
And we've just come up with an idea
of an agenda items in a live stream.
Now, since we're in the middle
of a live stream in which you already
understand
the five items that we want to cover,
we'd like this widget
to have the capability to say,
what point are we on
and maybe a little tab control.
What's a tab control
that I can just click on on screen
and it takes us to the next agenda item.
So before you actually write
the requirements documents,
just give me what are the five agenda
items that we're planning
to talk about in this live stream
and how do you see the user interface
working?
Keep in mind that it's a live stream.
We don't have generally the simple
techniques and powerful techniques
that we have in a web application.
So it's going to be really easy to use,
maybe like hotspots on the screen
that when we press it changes
the context of what the agenda is about.
Big picture, personas, application
categories, live fields,
which we're doing at the moment
and polish round.
Okay.
So five minimalistic buttons at the bottom
or top of the screen.
This sounds good because I've seen
some of your live streams
where you do it in keynote,
I think, and you had this sort of effect,
and I know you're not pressing
anybody in this.
I know it changes automatically,
but this is where
I'd like to be able to have it
be a little bit more dynamic.
Can you write this
for our developer please?
Okay.
We've got our requirements document
being created here,
and we will hand that over
to the developer in a second.
So that's still coming through.
And then what we're going to do
is kick off another little widget.
So I've just press copy here and
I said, can you create this application.
Please
remember the rules about using CDNJS.
The interesting thing about this
you mentioned there about like, you know,
the developer should know
what you're essentially doing though is
although we're doing this all on the fly
for this one particular task,
you're actually building up like your
your virtual team, effectively, of you
would have your developer,
you would have your,
you know, graphic designer and you're
kind of building up a virtual team.
And as you find these, you can sort of
tweak them and update them and add them
as you go it just in the same way that
if you had a real team of real people,
you would,
you know, along the way, be instructing
and educating on I'll do it this way
going forward and so on.
Yeah. In fact we might even, if we get time,
we might even jump down to Cloude code.
Yeah, we should
we should just we should do that
rather than doing it here
for the next idea.
So that's in the middle of writing code.
Let's just come back to here and say,
I need a new application, this time
I need a flip card style of application
and what the flip card
style of application is going to do
is teach me how to speak Thai.
Now I'm also going to have a Thai partner
communicate with me
and that person needs to learn
how to speak English.
So any phrase that we use should present
three concepts.
It should present the phrase in English.
It should present the phrase in Thai.
It should present the phrase
in Thai phonetics because that's actually
what I'm going to read
to try and sound out the Thai words.
And because Thai words are out of order
with English words,
I also need some sort of panel,
table of contents,
if you will, that shows a matching
of the English word to the Thai word.
So left and right.
I need this to be stylish.
I need it to be beautiful.
Let's go with a light blue motif.
It's a flip card sort of thing. So what
we see early on in
the piece is just the phrase
that we need to see
in these different things.
If we click on it,
it should roll over with an animation,
and we should see the detailed fact
sheet of all the other language stuff.
It should support ten
different conversation phrases,
and we should be able to go
to the next one
and to the previous one and test it out.
Please write a requirement.
So we'll let that write it's requirement.
While that's happening,
we can see that this little application
that we've got built before
and we won’t to test it here.
What we'll do is we'll click
the publish button and go to copy
and we'll head back over to I think
this window is where we're testing things.
So current topic is the kick off and looks
like I go to press a little button here.
And I can now interact with it.
Oh that's nice.
I like how it's got
the subtle animation as well on the button
that's active.
There's just a little bit of
a little animation going on there as well.
That is really cool.
Yeah.
With this, obviously, you could position
that wherever you wanted it on screen.
But you just said it right.
Let's come back here
and say, we love it.
But what be really nice
is that there's a panel over on the right
that shows details about the topic.
At the moment
you've got that panel down the bottom,
but it'd be nice
if it was over on the right.
I don't think this did a good job
right here, but we'll come back to it.
But I'm going to kick off
a new application for us.
Can you create a new application for me
and we need ten Thai phrases in it.
Can one of those phrases be,
“where have you been today?”
From a male point of view?
While it's writing that code,
we'll just go back
to our live stream agenda agent and
we go publish.
We will just kick off this application again.
And I'm just going to update and see what...
and it worked.
Okay. That worked.
It did.
So this time
what I'll do is I'll just, I'm going
to click the publish button again.
I'm not going to go through the pain
of setting up widgets.
Instead,
what I'm going to do is just go over
to our GPT view
and just paste it into a browser.
So in the browser
we've got our little application.
Looks like I've picked the wrong one,
we’ll copy the correct URL
and see whether that works.
We got it.
So here we got our Thai English Trainer
application and it's in light blue.
Hello, how are you?
I'm just wondering.
Click to flip. What does that do?
Okay, so partly this application
doesn't work, which is great,
because it shows us
how we can fix things.
So if we come here
and we say, the application
that you just created for the Thai
English language trainer does not work
correctly. At the moment,
it shows the complete card
face up and the click to flip
does not work at all.
And partly it's because there's some sort
of console error message going on.
I'm going to give you access
to the console error message.
And the other thing I notice
is that there's no table
showing the English word
matching to the Thai word.
So we take
this will go down to this console.
I'm not sure what we're seeing here.
We've got some errors going on.
We'll just paste this information in
and we'll just see
what it can render for us.
We've got flip card that
allow us to go backwards and forwards.
This is okay.
Publish that.
I've done this before.
They worked really well.
But in the live stream
they're not going to work really well.
And I'm not going to do it that it's done.
It's always the way.
But, wherever you been...
Actually I should, because you probably know,
is this correct?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
I'm using this sort of technique
to learn Thai at the moment.
And the great thing is I can just come up
with new phrases, add aminos, flip cards,
and deal with the fact that even
when I've read a statement like,
we'll get back.
I go, well, what word means “understand”?
I, like, I don't know, I can't look at that
and know which one it is.
I can guess that it's “understand”
in this context, but quite often
they're around in a different order.
And this is why I like to have a
the table of contents.
It also maps the words.
Yeah.
Just not working here today.
It's just mind blowing, like how quickly
all of this can be created.
And these are just simple demonstrations.
With, in a relatively short space of time,
taking basically the first pass,
but with just a few little tweaks here
and there,
you know, you could create an entire
set of fully branded, cohesive,
you know,
whether they're widgets, overlays
that you want to use in your live stream,
whether it's a suite of tools that you're
going to use as part of your business
or content creation or whatever it is.
Yeah.
It's just kind of,
kind of mind blowing, really.
Yeah.
And, I'm only just getting into
using these myself and
that was a new capability
I was just reading about it today.
The Claude complete stuff.
It didn't work for us,
which is a little bit unfortunate.
What I've found, though, is that
for a first pass, this is just perfect.
I think it's been a great,
a great demo of
just how
you can build these things out on the fly
and just a little glimpse
of what's possible,
but really, it's just whatever, whatever
people can imagine is now, certainly
within grasp in, you know, a
relatively short space of time.
It's just a phenomenal.
Yeah.
And what we're seeing today would have
been difficult three months ago.
So the coding AI pair program
has been going from strength to strength
over the last two years.
But to say what we did
today would have been very difficult
to do three months ago.
And even though we’re seeing problems,
I think in six months
time we're not going to have
any of those problems. In six months time
any application that you want to build
that's small in nature will be possible.
You won't need, you know, coding,
and you won't have to worry
too much about the errors.
They'll just all resolve themselves.
And maybe a year or two from now,
big enterprise applications
will totally be within reach
for the average person as well.
Exciting, exciting stuff.
Well, we'll leave it at that.
My name's AppyDave. David.
And, go and check out Alec and,
the work he's doing. Otherwise
like, and subscribe,
and I'll see you in the next video.