An hour ago, this awesome
feature got added to chat GPT.
Now I hadn't seen it.
I hadn't heard about it, but here it is.
It's called the at mention.
And what it's done is allowed me to
create the video you're watching right
now in about one hour using four or
five GPTs, all working in orchestration.
It's just magical.
So we're in a brand new chat GPT
window, and if I type in the at symbol,
we'll have access to a bunch of GPTs
that you've either used or created.
Many of these I've created, so if we
look at F YouTube teaser, this turns a
YouTube video into a Facebook teaser post.
Got the same thing for tweets.
I can make YouTube intros,
and recently I did seven.
GPT is specifically for
YouTube content creators.
You can check that out in the link, I
think we'll play around with tweet tube.
I learned about this feature about
10 minutes ago when I was just in
chat, GPT and a little dialogue
came up talking about at mention
now I hadn't heard about it.
I dunno what it is just yet.
So we're going to use chat GPT to a learn
about it and if it does, what I think
it does, we'll get it to create a tweet
based on the video I'm doing right now
using one of the GPTs I've already done.
what's really interesting is that
even though this feature exists, I'm
not finding any references anywhere
about it my first support of call
has been to ask the question within
ChatGPT and get it to use Bing,
unfortunately, the specific details
about app mentioned feature or not.
Well known.
okay, well where do I go next?
And the best place would
be to go to Google.
So I've headed over to Google and what
is the app mentioned feature in ChatGPT
Plus, there's nothing showing up.
This is from May, 2023.
I.
Currently it's the 27th of January, 2024.
One of the next steps I would
go to is just look in the news.
'cause news is the same as the main
page of Google, but it's very timely.
if we click here and use the
same feature, we've got some
information from a week ago.
We've got some information
from November 15th.
this feature.
Is in chat GPT.
I've seen it, but it's not been talked
about just yet, so I think we'll
move on to the next step and let's
figure out how to use it together.
I've just started writing a prompt
here called Imagine You ChatGPT
Plus had a feature built in whereby
you used the at symbol to make GPTs
that I've created or used available
for use when I'm writing prompts.
Now, this is a.
A hallucination.
Now you've heard about hallucinations
in GPT, where it goes off and
does stuff that's not real.
Well, this is a human hallucination
because I have no idea what this
feature does, just that I've seen it.
what I'm gonna do is kind of
guess what I think it'll do.
Put in this particular statement, I
might just build it up and say, how
do you think I would use this feature?
What problems does it solve and
what are five use cases and let's
just see what chat GPT might come
up for this particular scenario.
ChatGPT has taken my hallucination of
what this feature might be and written
what I consider a pretty compelling use
case and feature if this is how it works.
So if ChatGPT Plus had a feature
that allowed you to use an
at symbol to access and use.
Different GPT models that you've used
or created, it would be a powerful
tool for various applications here's
how you might use this feature.
You could quickly switch between
different GPT models tailored
for specific tasks or expertise.
So recently I did seven or eight.
Videos on GPTs that I created
around content creation.
I wanted to deal with writing a
YouTube intro based off everything
I said in the video or a YouTube
outro based off not only what I said
in the video, but other videos in
the series that I want to link to.
I've also got GPTs that allow me to
share my videos as tweets, LinkedIn
posts, Facebook teasers, and even
write the YouTube description.
What is painful about using these
GPTs at the moment is that I've gotta
create a brand new chat window and
load it up with context each time.
Now, if we could do something
like this switch from GPT to GPT,
from the same conversation, that
would be an incredible feature.
Now it goes on with the problems that
it solves to talk about some of the
things I just mentioned, specialization.
Each of those bots that I like
to create are really specialized,
GPT agents, It's this one.
Context management reduces
the need to repeatedly explain
the context or reorient ai.
That would be an interesting capability.
what's I find interesting around the five
here is that the first four of 'em are
based on GPTs that I've been creating.
So content strategy and development.
I specialize in GPTs for YouTube content
creation, and especially with SEO.
Educational purposes.
I'm in the middle of doing a series
called "The Tudors", and it's basically
a bunch of tutor bots for learning
complex software applications.
I also have a programming language that
I'm developing called KlueLess, a GPT
meta language, and I'm doing this sort
of stuff all the time, though I don't
have any GPT specifically in this area,
I haven't done much here, if this works
the way it's describing here, I'm gonna
be really happy with this new feature.
What I think I'll do is I'll
just use speech to text and we'll
just type a prompt right now.
Everything that we've talked about above
is exactly what this feature is about.
What I would like you to do is take the
information and run it through my Twitter
creation bot and create a tweet for me,
what we'll do is we'll just type at.
Tweet tube.
Talking to Tweet tube is what it does,
and we've just got this prompt and
we'll press it, enter, and we'll see
whether it does what I expect it to do.
wow.
This is it it's writing tweets
the way my tweet tube bot does.
So discover the power of customization
with ChatGPT Plus @mention feature,
instantly switch between specialized GPT
models for tailored responses, perfect
for content strategists, educators,
tech pros, writers, and polyglots.
That's people that work in
multiple languages, it's
put in a bunch of hashtags.
One of the problems I tend to have with
my tweet bot is sometimes it's a couple
of letters over the 144 character length,
sometimes I've gotta modify it a bit.
But usually this is a one hit
wonder I'm really happy with this.
this is cool already.
I'm already sold on this feature, but
maybe I could create an intro for this
particular video that I'm recording
I think what I'll do is I'll create
the YouTube intro for this video, but
I'm a little confused at the moment.
It says I'm still talking to the
tweet tube, so I believe we'll just
press this cross looks good type in.
Can you take me over to
the at YouTube intro, GPT?
And allow me to configure it
so that we can create a YouTube
intro for this particular video.
Looks like I might have to type this in,
so we'll go, @, intro maker, press enter.
it's taken me over to my bot, and my
bot has basic configuration in it.
the YouTube Intro Maker Bot
has a configuration capability.
Now it talks about it here.
the niche we're going for is GPT plus.
The topic is that there's a
feature announcement called
at mentions in chat, GPT plus.
Now the framework.
You can use marketing
frameworks like AIDA and PAS.
PAS is problem agitation solution,
but I like to keep things fairly
simple, so I'll go with none.
Keep it simple.
And the structure I think we want.
Is problem solution, what's the problem?
Here's the solution and the tone excited.
I think this is an awesome
feature, but keep it professional.
we'll just press enter on that.
I think we can just say create is
one of the commands I think we'll
copy from here all the way through.
fact sheet that you would want for
a script on this sort of video.
we'll move down to the bottom
and we'll just say, create an
intro based on this concept.
We have a starter intro script
welcome to the future of AI
customization and efficiency.
Today we're unveiling an extraordinary
feature in ChatGPT Plus, the
AT feature simple yet powerful
tool that's changing the game.
problem highlight.
Have you ever found yourself wishing
for a more specialized, efficient,
and integrated AI experience?
This is my issue all the time with ChatGPT
one that understands your specific needs
without having to switch contacts or
explain repeatedly your weight is over.
And then the solution with the
@ feature in ChatGPT Plus, you now
have the ability to quickly access
various GPT models tailored for
unique tasks and areas of expertise.
Now it goes on, it's got use cases.
I wouldn't work with this because
Personally want to use use
cases that I've created myself.
What we could do is just state
this intro is really good.
I love the first three paragraphs,
but it's way too long at the moment.
Everything goes for about one minute
and 30 seconds to two minutes.
I really need this to
be a 30 second script.
it's now writing a new script for
us, welcome to a revolutionary
feature in ChatGPT plus the @ tool,
transforming AI interactions into
tailored experience ever needed a more
specialized AI response instantly.
The @ feature is your solution, just type
@ followed by your desired GPT model's.
Name and seamlessly switch between
tasks and conversations All within
a single chat interface from at SEO
model for marketing insights to at
Python helper for coding support.
Embrace the new era of specialized AI
with ChatGPT Plus experience efficiency
and customization like never before.
with a little bit of tweaking would
be a good introduction to the video.
I think while we're at it, let's
just switch one more context.
can you create an article
for me on LinkedIn?
at Link Tube and the idea of
the Link Tube article generator
is it's a single shot prompt.
It'll get it right most times.
it's designed specifically around turning
YouTube videos into LinkedIn articles.
Now, this was a little unexpected.
I know what the issue is.
certainly I can use, the feature.
I need a bit more information, like
target audience, key message I use
commands to drive my GPTs, and I didn't
use a command this time, so it's.
Gone into the automatic configuration
options, don't really need that.
I'm just gonna say create, and
I'm gonna paste this in, which is
basically the script from earlier.
Usually when I do a create command
for a LinkedIn post, I would also
give it the title and the YouTube
video, but we haven't created the
YouTube video yet, we can't do that.
just go create like that
and see what happens now.
We've got a title, which may be
the title that we want to use.
I would usually use my TitleGPT to
generate this revolutionizing AI
interactions, the @ feature in ChatGPT
Plus, I think that might be good enough
for the video anyway, introduction.
In the ever evolving world of
artificial intelligence, we've
got concepts, problems, practical
use, cases, and conclusions.
Can you add emojis and hashtags please?
let it rewrite the article now
with a couple of emojis so that
when I paste it into my LinkedIn
page, it just looks, nicer.
We've got our LinkedIn article written.
There's a couple of hashtags
going on down the end.
Let's finish off the video and we might
as well use the OutroGPT to do that.
tube outro writer, and we're in it, and
we'll just go straight into a config
So we'll just configure it and we'll
go with a style here called recap.
So whatever we've said in the video,
we wanna recap it, but I only want
it to go for about 15 seconds and
I wanna have a link to a playlist.
I believe in this case I've done
YouTube automation, GPTs, there's
a bunch of 'em all in a playlist,
and that's what we should mention.
Let's just type create should be enough.
That's a wrap on the Revolutionary App
feature in ChatGPT Plus, tailor your AI
interactions with ease, switch between
specialized models and unlock new
levels of efficiency and customization.
The future of AI is here
and its personalized.
Explore more on AI advantages.
In our YouTube automation GPTs
playlist link displayed on the side,
stay ahead with the latest AI trends.
Usually when I do my outros for videos,
I use a teleprompter and I'll read the
script that we were just looking at.
Now, I'm going to do that, but I'm going
to look at the script that I just created.
I'm not going to pre-prepare it.
I'm not gonna do any editing.
We'll just use it the way it
is, so it goes, that's a wrap.
On the Revolutionary App featuring
ChatGPT Plus tailor your AI interactions
with ease, switch between specialized
models and unlock new levels of
efficiency and customization.
The future of AI is here
and its personalized.
Explore more on AI advancements.
In our YouTube automation GPTs playlist,
stay ahead with the latest in AI tech.
I'm AppyDave and I hope you enjoyed this
news release on the @ mentioned feature.