In this video, we're setting up rails eight with the new basic authentication system
also include tailwind CSS, Postgres guard for automated test watching, R-spec and
Rubocop.
Now let's get started by being on the latest version of Ruby and Rails. So with Ruby,
I'm currently on 3.3.6. Now to install rails, I'll just run gem install rails
That's finished. And we've installed rails 8.00.0.
Now there's a setup guide that you can follow through, but what we've done so far
is check the version of Ruby and install the latest version of rails. What we'll
do now is just set up a repository that you can find this code in.
Now I'm just over at GitHub on AppyDave. We'll create a new repository inside of
this. We'll call it rails8-basicauth. Now we're going to make it public.
we'll set the license to the Mozilla Public License two.
And a basic description. Let's just create this repository.
So the command we're going to start off with is rails new rails eight basic auth.
We're not going to include any test frameworks because we're going to use RSpec.
We will include tailwind CSS and Postgres as the database.
Heading over to the terminal, we'll paste in that command and let it do the standard
rails creation process.
Now the new application is finishing creating. What we're going to need to do is
change into the directory. And because we're using Postgres we'll need to create
the database. So let's just CD into the correct folder. We'll clear the screen here
and we'll do a rails DB create. And that should just create the databases rails eight
basic auth development and test.
Now let's just test whether the server is running. We've got Chrome open, we're starting
up the web server and we'll run it. And we're running rails eight with rack 3.1.8
and Ruby 3.3.6.
Now let's connect this repo up to the repo we've already created on GitHub. So we'll
just put this information in right now. And then let's just run the add dot, commit
the initial request and push it all up. So we'll let that go. And that's all moving.
And we'll come over to the repo and just refresh. And we've got the initial commit.
So as we go along I'll be doing commit along the way. And you can go to any section
that you like.
Now for a little bit of basic setup. We're just going to make sure that everything
that we do is done in a template, that you can just run from the command line. So
we'll just go and create this file. We've created it, we've touched it. And lastly
we'll also put in the setup documentation that we're reading through at the moment.
So this will all be in the repository.
Now we have a standard rails application created with tailwind, CSS and Postgres.
Now what I've added is a rails generator that you can use, and it's just a standard
rails generator with a bunch of steps that we're running through. And as we go through
them, they'll just be called by different numbers so that you can cherry pick what
you want to do with the generation of this application.
I'll just take you through a couple of aliases I've set up, the main one being the
R8. Next is how we'll go through each capability of the rails eight application.
there's also a run command, which will run the rails server with a precompile in
front of it. So what we'll do is just paste all of this and it's now available. Now
we can test that out by typing run. And it should just do a standard rails server
with Precompile.
Now let's just quickly look at this template command that we've set up. There's a
file. We'll look at it in a moment. Some of the information came from prior documentation
that I read a month ago on the pre-releases of rails eight. But if we go to the top,
we're using rails generators as a base class, and then a bunch of classes for each
So what we're going to work through is creating common gems. A home page will do
the layout. We'll get some alert messages
and also adding an email authentication mailer to the system.
run our little command line tool. Right? Next we'll get a menu and we're going to
work with number one. What that'll do is add the various gems and start doing a bundle
install. There's also a bundle outdated going on and it actually finishes off with
a Rubocop dash A. So any issues in the code base will be cleaned up.
Now let's have a quick look at what's changed. Firstly, if we go to the Gemfile,
we can have a look at the original files that have been added. We've got rails eight,
we've got a Postgres gem. These are the new concepts that I'm going to talk about
in a future video around solid cache, queue and cable.
additionally it's also added in the information I want for the custom gems. If we
look at the spec file, it's set up with a require spec helper, and I like to use
the documentation format. If we go into spec, there's a rails helper and a spec helper
already preset up and a guard file. And what the guard
is watching our rails application. If we run it, nothing's happening at the moment.
Now just label this commit. And what that means is that when you come up to the repo,
you should be able to just look through and find the areas that have been changed
labeled in the repo.
Now that I've got the basic gems set up, I'd like to get a home page going. Now you
can see that I'm running a rails server. It's on port 3001 and if we run rate next,
it will be looking for the template file in the public directory called rails template.
So we'll just run number two.
what that's going to do is create the controller and the home page to get started.
So we'll just restart the server with the run command and refresh. And we have rails
eight basic auth. And we can see that there's some tailwind CSS
Giving it a little bit of styling.
Now, a quick look at what we've generated is a standard controller called home with
index. We're skipping routes because we want to use the route for this, and we can
see just a slight modification to the routes. And here's the HTML that's going on.
So we've got this in place here a standard view has been created and we've got a
couple of specs. So we've got this home helper. We've got a request spec and we've
got this view spec. Now I'm going to get rid of the view specs.
but request specs we will look at, especially when we're doing the authentication.
Now I'll just bring the terminal into focus. I'm running guard and we'll run the
tests. And we've got one that's just been skipped, and we've got one that's in error.
the one that's being skipped, which is a helper I'm also going to remove. And let's
have a look at the request spec.
you can see here that it's home slash index. Now I've gone and changed the route
so that the home index will point to the route. So let's just make sure we change
it here and we'll hit save.
And now we have a working request spec for the root.
Let's now play around with the layout. We'll get a menu in place for the authentication
system. We'll also look at alert messages. So we have all this code going on for
the different menus that we want to do. We've got a little bit of changes to the
layout, especially adding in the menu.
in the next step we'll work with the flash messages where they'll just use tailwind
CSS to style them.
We'll head over to the web,
firstly run the layout and we'll just see how things change with that.
this time for the flash messages, which is number four.
if we come and do a refresh, we can see the layout in place. The flash messages will
show up a bit later.
one of the things I was encountering is that the asset precompilation doesn't happen
automatically, and there should be a little bit of styling here.
rerun the web server. It's also going to do the asset precompile.
if we do a refresh we get a new look and feel.
Next I want to generate a few controller pages, but before I do that, I'm going to
modify a few of the settings going on here, and then we'll add in the pages and the
controllers here.
I want to generate three top level pages for the authentication system. But before
we do that, I would like to play around with the configuration of the generator.
So we'll make these changes followed by the generation of the pages.
we can firstly do the application settings,
we'll restart the generator and we'll do the top level pages. Number six.
now we've got our pages controller. There's three actions ready to go. If we look
in the views, we've got some pages being pre-created for us.
We've also got the shared information from the flash messages and the menus that
we just created earlier. If we look down at the unit tests,
You'll see that it's now only generating the request spec. So if we click on that,
there should be three in place ready to go.
Let's just head over to the terminal and put in a guard, and we'll see if these three
request specs are running okay. They are,
come over to the web view and we refresh and we can see there's now three pages available.
you see any styling issues, just restart the server. I know that this should be a
darker color.
if we click on them, we should be able to go to the three different pages that we
want to test with the security system.
the next step is to generate the new authentication system that comes with rails
eight. Now we could run step number seven which would do the rails generate authentication
and update the database. But let's have a look at this manually. So firstly I'm just
going to run rails generate authentication.
we can see the new files come in. Now notice there's also an update database. If
we go and have a look at what that's really doing. It's just a rails DB migrate and
a rails DB test prepare. So let's run them manually as well. So just running the
rails db migrate to update the database. The test prepare will make sure that the
test database is in sync as well.
heading over to the application, let's have a look at what's changed. So if we go
into the database migrations we can see there's a new table being added called users.
It's got an email address and a password digest. After that we've got the sessions
for each time a user signs in with just their IP address and user agent.
heading over to the app folder. There's a lot of changes going on here.
we'll look at the views. We've got the passwords, email and new. There's also a mailer.
So when we send out an email for resets that'll be there.
we've also got the new sessions view going on here.
everything's been done using tailwind CSS.
A simple little mailer has been created for resetting the password, and then we start
looking at the data going on with the models. So the first one would be the user
it's got has secure password and has many sessions. It's also down casing the email
address. Then after that we've got the session which is belonging to a user. And
if you want to access the current user in session, we've got this current attribute
set up with the session and a delegation through to the user. Let's now go have a
look at the controller, where a lot of extra work is happening in the passwords controller
and the session controller.
Now you can see on the passwords controller. This allowed unauthenticated access
and if we go to sessions, it's also got the same thing set up for the new and the
create action here. And to find that we can go to the application controller where
it's including a concept called authentication. And this is a new concern being built
here.
so the bulk of the code going on for the authentication system can be found in this
concern.
Now let's go and see how this is affecting the web application. So we've got the
authentication concern. It's now included automatically on the application controller.
And both the home controller and the pages controller have been left the way they
are now if we head over to the website and this is what we saw before, if I do a
refresh, we now get taken to a sign in page.
should be happening for everything.
So let's start by just putting in a username and password. We haven't registered
it yet and we'll see what happens.
Now we get to see a valid error message coming up here. But the other good thing
is the alert message that we styled with tailwind CSS earlier is now coming through.
I want to relax some of the security, the home and the about page don't need to be
locked down. The account page does, and the authentication page should show information
about whether the user is signed in or not.
So I'm pressing number eight for relax.
we can see there's a change to the home controller and the pages controller. If we
do a refresh and the home page now allows us through, let's go have a look at what's
going on in the pages controller. So the home controller has allow unauthenticated
access, which is why we were able to get to that page with the pages controller.
We've got this concept of allow unauthenticated access only for two of the particular
pages. So let's just save that and we'll see what happens if we click on the about
and the authentication there. Good. And we're still locked down for the account.
Now the next step is to create a bunch of authentication enhancements, especially
registration, the view and links. So what we'll do is we'll find number nine
So let's come and have a look at the changes. If we go into configuration, we can
see there's a change to the routes, and we didn't look at some of the routes from
earlier as well. So we've got the resource registration session and passwords in
place. We've also got
three pages that we added earlier. If we come up to application and look within models,
there's a modification to the user. So we've now got validation going on on the email
address.
A new registrations page has been created,
and a new registration link has been added to the session.
So now we'll be able to register a new user.
we have the registrations controller. There's a new and a create method here. And
if we have a brief look on the application controller, we can see now there's a current
user that we can access
let's test the register. We'll click on here and we'll put in appydave@appydave.com.
click Register.
it has registered successfully. I don't know that we'll be able to sign in yet. Let's
just try that. So we appear to be signed in, but we got no information about the
user.
I would like to put that on the authentication page.
Now to visualize the user we'll press number ten which is authentication information.
We've got a new page. If we do a refresh we now have the idea of what the user is.
But there's something missing here because you would have noticed that we did register.
So to give a little bit of clarity around this authentication model, what we have
done is allow unauthenticated access. So it's basically skipping the require action.
And we can see that going on here. It said for authentication page we don't need
to be authenticated. But that doesn't mean you've got access to the authentication
information. And the authentication information we're interested in is here in the
current session which is looking in the session store. So we need to call this resume
session. So what we can do is come back here and just say before action resume session
for that particular page. Now we'll hit save on that. Come back to the authentication
details and we'll refresh.
now that user that we registered appydave@appydave.com is visible.
a recompile of the assets is giving us the sign out button. Let's see if that's working.
We'll click on it.
Let's try and sign back in appydave@appydave.com we'll click sign in. We'll click
on the authentication page. And there we have it.
Let's now see if we can add email validation to the sign up process. So we'll go
to the register user.
to try with appydave2. Now before we run that we're going to
authentication email.
what we've done is add a new table to the database.
So the main changes are that the confirmation token and confirmed that have been
added to the users. And then after that we've got some extra methods, plus the ability
to send an email and regenerate a token.
Additionally, we've got the registrations. Controller now has a confirm button on
it. We've got a user mailer with the ability to take the email. If we go into routes,
we've got letter opener because that's been added via the gem.
an important thing to think about is with the configuration, the default URL options
change it to the same port as whatever your web server is running on. So let's go
test it out.
Now we're back at the registration where we've got AP Dave two. We'll click Register
and it looks like it's come up with an email system. Let's click on this. Confirm
the account.
we are now confirmed. So we should be able to sign in with that. There's now also
a check email. If we click on that that'll take us over to letter opener. Now we
don't need to do that because we've already done it using the default viewer. But
if we go and click on the authentication page, it won't say that we're signed in
just yet. So let's just click on the sign in and we'll put in appydave2 And we'll
do that one more time.
now we can get to the account page which wasn't available before. If we look at the
authentication page we can see that we're signed in correctly.
I'm AppyDave Please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.