In this video, I'm going to use ChatGPT to create a class to anonymize people's names.
It's a scenario, you have content that you're trying to create and you're using real names
and questions from the internet.
And what you want to do is take the names like DotStreet, Andy and Crystal and change
them to another name that's still realistic but doesn't identify the original person.
I'm just going to take you over to a visual studio and you'll see that I have a data
file here with people's names and we've got Michael, Dot and Andy and from them there
are also more detailed data files with other people's names and these are people's names
that would have replied to a question.
What I want to do is take every name and run it through an anonymization routine but the
names that are coming out of it and if there's a name that I don't like I want to be able
to refresh it on a regular basis.
The way I want to go about that today is to just use ChatGPT to create this class for
me.
Head over to ChatGPT and look at a prompt that I've written and it starts off with I need
a class, I need you to anonymize people's names.
The way I want to use it is that there will be a dictionary of some sort with the original
name followed by the anonymized name and one of the things is a flag called refresh and
the idea of the refresh flag is that if I set it to true I should be able to get a new
name generated.
If it gets set to false it'll stay fixed.
If the refresh flag is true it means that I'm not happy with the new name and it can
be recreated.
If you receive an original name so this is a name that you've already seen before you
will add it to the dictionary and set the refresh flag to true.
You only add names that you have not seen before.
I will need some sort of lookup function on the original name so that I can get the anonymized
name and I want the information stored in a JSON document.
I don't really care how it names it.
One of the reasons I do that is because I find it's pretty good at coming up with the
right names and since naming is an incredibly important aspect of programming let's take
it out of our hands and let the computer do it for us.
Before you write code I would like you to describe the structure of the class meaning
what methods and properties.
The reason that's important to me is that I don't necessarily like every bit of code
that GPT writes so I want to have a look at what it thinks is a good way of going about
it and then I might tweak that a little bit before I get it to generate code.
I want this in Ruby.
That's programming language I'm using for this particular problem.
ChatGPT has come up with this idea of a class called name anonymizer and I'm pretty happy
with that as the name and it believes it will need a dictionary to store the information.
I guess the person's original name will go into this location and the mapped name or
the anonymized name will go into this location.
I assume it's going to work on the idea that if refresh is true it would regenerate the
name before persisting it back into the JSON document.
It has a concept of a file name and it defaults to name mapping.json.
I'll be happy with that.
It has a constructor and initializer.
There's nothing mentioned here about it taking the file name as a parameter
so maybe you have to instantiate it then set the file name if you want a custom one
and then work with the functions but we'll see what it actually generates.
It has the concept of anonymizing a name.
Let's say we give my name David Kruis and it comes back with Bob Smith.
The thing is that it will check for my name in the dictionary.
If present, yes it does then set the refresh flag to false.
It returns the anonymized name.
That might be the right flow.
If not present or if the refresh flag is true it generates a new anonymized name.
If it comes back with Bob Smith and I don't like that then I can set the flag to true
and just call my name again to get a different name back.
Now then there's a method here called refresh anonymized name.
I guess this is the method that's going to do the work was to say.
Set the refresh flag to true for a given name so that a new anonymized name can be generated
next time.
It's really just setting the flag in this case.
I think this name is not necessarily the best name because I got the impression it was going
to do an action but it's actually only going to change a state.
But if I wanted to give a bit extra instruction to JCPT that might be the area that I
do it but quite frankly it's probably going to be easier just to change it in code after
the fact but we'll just see what else it's got here.
The next one is look up with an original name.
This is the main method that would get called each time.
Returns an anonymous name based on an original name.
Then there's a save to file and a load from file.
Additional considerations.
The anonymized name generation process.
You could use simple naming patterns or integrate a more sophisticated name generator.
What I think I'm going to do is suggest to it that it uses a Ruby gem called Faker.
Instadiate the class which loads the existing directory or creates a new one.
Not necessarily what I want to do.
I probably want to have a little bit of control there but we'll see.
Call look up to get the anonymized name for an original name.
And optionally call refresh anonymized name if you want to refresh flag for the name.
Maybe this status name is okay.
We'll see once this generates.
Does this structure align with your requirements?
Is close enough?
I've decided to do a couple of customizations.
The first one is if I look at the refresh anonymized name.
It's actually a pretty good calling technique to work this way.
But it wasn't the way I was planning to use it.
My plan was that if the JSON document on the server changed.
Then the next time that this method is called the getting of a new anonymous name.
It would just go and refresh at the time.
What I'm going to do is rather than even coming up for a name for this method.
It's really interesting when you struggle to find the right name.
That chat GP team may actually be able to solve this problem.
So we'll just write this little prompt and I've already pre-written it.
I think the name refresh anonymized name does not match the intent.
This name suggests that the anonymous name will be refreshed.
But really it's just setting a state flag.
Which will only ever need to be processed the next time the name is requested.
Give me five names that might be better.
Let's see what it does.
It's come up with five different names.
They're all pretty good.
Mark for update, set refresh flag and schedule name refresh.
This is probably the most obvious one.
I know it does not conform to Rubikop.
Which is a linter in the Ruby language.
They do not like using setters and getters like that.
And that gets me thinking that I might just get it to go with mark for update.
It's the class that it's generated.
It's called an anonymous name generator.
I don't believe that's what it came up with before.
It said name anonymize.
I'm going to copy that because I prefer this name for what it's wants.
It's got requirements for JSON and file utilities.
I believe the project I'll use this in already have that.
So it could be removed.
It's seen got an attribute accessor for the underlying mappings.
How about we go through it quickly then come back and look in detail.
An initializer which calls a method called load or initialize mappings.
There's a method for getting anonymous name and one for mark for update.
That looks good.
There's the ability to save a mapping.
And there's the ability to generate anonymized names.
This is not actually what I wanted to do.
I guess I forgot to use the Faker gem as part of the requirements.
I think we'll end up regenerating this but let's look a bit further.
And then we've got a private method called makedir for file.
What that's doing is taking the file name looking at any path that might be related to it.
And then making a directory if it does not exist.
If we use it here and this is how we would use it.
Generator equals anonymous name generator with the name of the file.
Then you can get an anonymous name or you can mark it for update.
As I look through this a couple of things stand out.
This should be private.
This is not a public method.
It's making the directory returning an empty hash if the file does not exist.
Otherwise it's loading it and passing it from JSON into a hash.
And it's been called in the initializer but really that's a private method.
I might tell it to do that.
When I look at this section of code.
I wouldn't necessarily write it this way.
We've got this name mapping to the original name.
So let's say the name is David Kruis for me.
It would be at name mapping David Kruis.
That's been called three times here and then returned here.
Maybe a variable might have been a better technique.
If it does find it that's what gets returned.
Otherwise it generates a new one.
What we've got here is checking for the mark for update is false.
If it was true and keep moving down and get the anonymized name.
And then we build up the structure that we want to store against the original name.
Save the mapping return this anonymized name.
I think all this code would work.
The only thing I want to change is the name of the class
and let it know to use the Faker gem.
I've just created a prompt that I'm going to use to generate this class.
And one of the things I did was I did read through all of this again
and picked out a couple of little tweaks that I want to do to the instructions.
One of them being that I want it to use mark for update.
And what I'll do is we'll paste it in here.
Because I know some of the names can have three words in them
or two words or one word.
I don't really care what the source name is.
But I do want to make sure that the generated name is always the first and the last.
I've made that statement.
I want to take any relative path qualified file name.
So my belief is that I would use this.
And the JSON file might be in a sub folder from where it's being called.
I want to make sure that it can handle concepts like configure my names.json
or my custom name.json or if nothing is provided.
And that's important to say if nothing is provided
so that it realizes the initializer needs an optional parameter
and to use name mapping.json.
The folder name might not exist.
Can it pre-create it if it's there?
I haven't actually stated pre-create the file.
I think it's going to get it.
Use the mark for update flag.
Write this code in Ruby.
We'll hit go and we'll see what it starts writing for us.
Now I've just gone and created a prompt just to make a couple of minute edits.
To be fair, you probably just change its code yourself.
But the good thing about chat GPT is that you can get it to do all your work if you like.
And learning the skill is really important as we move forward
and it gets better and better at doing this sort of stuff.
Can you rename the class to name anonymize?
That's what I liked.
Can you make a particular method private?
There's these constant lookups against the dictionary
which could either be used in a variable.
I think it was only in that one method
or there could be a memwised helper.
Let's just press enter and see what it comes up with.
The initialized code is not in this position anymore.
We've got these two public methods
and then the load is now private.
And we've got a memwised helper
and it's given us a description that it's reducing repetitive dictionary lookups.
So I'm pretty happy with that.
Let's see how that got used up here.
Here's where it gets called.
It's say mapping entry based off the original name
putting it into an entry variable
and then it just works with that entry variable
wherever it needs to except when it's creating the new one.
I just had a look at this method
and this is not a memwised pattern
where you go off and do a long-winded process
and then you store it in a variable
and then the next time you go to get it
you just use that variable again.
Here it's just doing the process every time.
So it didn't really understand that.
I'm not even going to try again with chat.jpt
I'll just write the code myself.
These are the little things that you do need to watch out for.
It probably doesn't matter at all.
This is just a dictionary lookup on a small file.
So performance never is going to be a big concern
with this particular class.
If you have the opportunity to do it right the first time
you can do it right the first time.
What we can do is go through this code
make a couple of tweaks if needed
and we'll test it out.
The first thing I'll look at is this
generate anonymized names
and what I can do is just take this code
and replace it basically with the faker gem.
I'm going to get rid of all the comments.
I don't really need comments or things that are obvious.
I'd like to use single responsibility methods
and the method names really match the intent.
As I said this is not a memwised helper
but one thing I did notice when I looked back over the code
I'll show you that this is probably still the right way to go.
What I noticed is that the calling through to this method
both here and where's the other one there
is just being stored into a variable anyway.
Now if I'd done it the way I was suggesting to chat.jpt
then I would have had to call this method
with the original name over and over again
in this position and this position.
This is still a better technique.
I'll hit save on this file.
I'll get a copy of the class name
and head over to a unit test harness.
It would be useful if we bring up a terminal
with unit test runner already to go.
Basically I've just used here more as an integration test
to call this method.
The method is here
and I've set up a couple of names.
The goal will be that this file will update.
The first thing we look at is that we have an anonymiser.
We will loop through all the names which are here
call the anonymiser.anonymised name
with that name and get a new value back.
While I'm not using this as an actual unit test
there is an expectation that the anonymised name
will not be the same as the regular name
so that should work and that it matches the concept
of having two words with capital and lower letters in it.
And lastly I just want to print out a key value pair
to the console.
I want to take the original name and the anonymous name.
If I hit save we get
David Kruse being mapped to Nina
and Appy Dave mapped to Chet Flatley.
That looks good and we've also got
our values here in the mapped file
and they're not marked for updates.
If I call it again and the best way to do that right here
is just hit save it'll run it again
and we get the same values as before
for both David Kruse and Appy Dave.
What I'd like to do is test this update who
and we'll work with David Kruse.
So what we can do is put my name into this particular parameter
if the parameter exists
then call mark for update with that particular value.
What should happen is that value would become true
when this is called and then when it goes and loops
through all the people here
when it gets this anonymous name
it would update this value
and then set this from true back to false.
I think it might be useful if we see that timing delay
so directly after I set that to true
we'll put in a one second pause
before calling the new anonymous name.
There it is there and I'll just hit save.
If we've got our terminal running
it should just work correctly.
This is true the name changed it's back to false.
If we keep doing that it becomes true for a little while
the name will change and then back to false.
If I want to do it for Appy Dave
I can just go and select that value
and now to be the second one is going to change here.
Chet flatly becomes Jonathan Schoen.
I think one last thing to test
is that if you wanted other names in there
I might just put in at Winning prompts,
Appycast and Carnivore 90.
Now this code I'm going to be using
for presentation capabilities within this YouTube channel
but these are various YouTube channels that I use
but here I'm just going to use the values
to change them to people's names.
I'll hit save and hopefully we end up with
four new entries in the system.
Now every time I refer to fly video for instance
I will always get Mosh Moshi.
If I hit save that value does not change
but if I want fly video to change in this case
it was just say at fly video hit save
and now it's been updated to Deidre.
Now that's an example of how you can create a class
from scratch using just chat GPT
and if you're interested in various automations
that I create using prompt engineering and the GPT APIs
then maybe click one of the links in the description.
you