If you asked most people to write a
script or a story using ChatGPT, they
would write a prompt similar to this one.
In this video, I wanna show you
some advanced prompt engineering
techniques that are both
simple and easy to implement.
prompt engineering is something that I
use all the time as a software developer
and a researcher, but as a YouTuber,
I use it for my content creation,
script writing and image generation.
So let's get into it.
You'll learn how to do storytelling
with ChatGPT, but we'll
also look at the multiverse.
How could this look in
the past or the future?
Let's head over to ChatGPT, and
we'll write a simple prompt,
write an illustrated story
about a woman with her cat.
I need to develop characters,
beliefs, origin, story, and finally
write a day in the life story.
So this is what I want to do.
Now there's a problem if you start writing
a prompt like this and press enter,
what'll happen is ChatGPT will go off
and write a whole lot of information.
Because you haven't given
it enough instructions yet.
So what I like to do when I start
a context is I like to say Yay.
And the idea of the Say Yay instruction
is that ChatGPT just responds with, yay.
It doesn't do anything else.
if you have any problems with this, you
can also go into what are called your
custom instructions and give a little bit
of information about the yay statement.
Here you can see if you see Yay or read.
Just record the information, and these are
two instructions that I use quite a lot.
With our yay instruction in place,
let's head over and write a prompt.
we've got this prompt and one
of the things to notice is that
there is a structure to it.
So it starts off with a task.
Give me a physical description for, so
this is the task that we're looking to do.
From there, we've got a context,
a blonde brunette, and a Raven
Head woman in her thirties.
After that, we just limited in this case.
To 20 words per person.
we paste it into ChatGPT.
We get the information we want,
and we can see here that we've got
the blonde, the brunette, and the
Raven Head woman in their thirties,
which is a good starting point.
With three physical descriptions about
women, let's now come up with three
types of women, and we'll do three
types of women in their thirties.
Include a job, a hobby, and a personality.
And we'll just keep it to 20 words.
And what ChatGPT t will do is come up
with these simple little descriptions.
We've got a pediatricians software
developer and a marketing executive,
and the pediatrician knits in free
time is compassionate, patient, and
always smiling, loves interacting
with children and parents.
Now, later on, we'll randomly mix
physical descriptions with types of women.
But for now, let's go and
look at another character.
Now the story that I wanna build
is around a woman and her cats.
So the next prompt will be,
give me three types of cats.
And what chat GPT came up with was a
Siamese, a Maine Coon, and a Bengal.
And if we look at the main coon, we've
got one of the largest domesticated cat
breeds known for their bushy tails, tuft
ears, and friendly doglike personalities.
Now that we have some basic
description and type information
about the cats and the women, let's
go into how they might be thinking.
Basically, we're looking
at their belief systems.
Now, whether you're a human or an
animal, you do have some sort of a
belief system, and we can get ChatGPT
to build this for us so that the story
is in alignment with the motivations.
We'll do a little bit of research
around belief systems found in women.
give me six.
So that's the number of
philosophical views that we're
going to get from American women.
But what I also wanna do is break
it up into two distinct groups.
So we've got the traditional perspectives
and we've got the polarizing.
Points of view.
And from that we get these six
different philosophical belief systems.
We've got pragmatism, existentialism,
and humanism as traditionals.
And in the radical we've got
postmodern feminism, eCamm,
feminism, and transhumanism.
Next we'll develop a
belief system for cats.
And you might be wondering
how can you do that?
the way I look at it is we can have a
life experience that the cat experiences.
So gimme three mild
traumas affecting cats.
But we can also have a positive
or a negative experience
based on different scenarios.
So here I've said, list the positive
reaction that they might have.
If the owner was around and the negative
reaction that they might have with another
human being or a particular scenario, so
we end up getting these three different
traumas plus two different reactions based
on whether they're around the owner or
around the thing that causes the trauma.
Now that we have descriptions,
types, and belief systems for our
characters, let's develop a personal
identity for each of the characters.
So what we can do is just
ask questions of chat GPT.
Now, it already has a lot of context
in the background, so we'll just say,
give me three female names, ages, And
something they might be passionate about.
Now, keep in mind, we've already
developed the concept that these
are women in their thirties, so
the age should be around that area.
We know they're American women, so the
names probably will be American in nature.
When we go for the cats and we ask for
the name and the age, we don't expect
an age to be 50 years of age for a
cat because they don't live that long.
So let's see what happens
with this basic prompt.
we end up with three female characters
and three feline characters.
So we've got Emily, Claire, and Nora.
They're all in their thirties
except for Emily, who's 29.
And we've got three different
felines, whiskers, Luna and
Oliver, three, five, and two years.
And with the sort of names that might
actually apply to a cat, 'cause no human
would generally be called Whiskers.
Now let's develop our backstory or
the origin story for our characters.
Now, up until now, everything has
been done with pretty simple prompts.
We've got a lot of information
that's being created.
We don't know what information
we want to select yet.
So to build up the origin story is about
drawing all that information together.
So let's get started with the prompt.
And the first thing we're
going to do is write context.
I already selected Emily and Whiskers,
and all we have about them is their name
and their age, and we're saying create
a character backstory about these two.
It's going to be 500 words.
Now, from that, I've said.
Specifically that I want to brunette.
Now, we did have a blonde and a Raven
head lady as well, and I've said I
want the main coon out of the three
different types of cats that we had.
But from ChatGPT, I'm going to
let it select the type of woman
there were three to choose from,
and the philosophical perspective.
There were six to choose from,
and from the traumas we'll.
Just randomly select one of them.
Now, the next thing you wanna do
is develop a guideline for the
instructions, so ensure all the
categories are covered and expanded.
most of the categories were only
about 20 words long, so this expanded
capability says well take it a
little bit further, make it bigger,
but use that as the starting point.
The other thing is don't hallucinate.
What we wanna do is make sure it
doesn't say anything that wasn't
in the original information.
So I said, when building the backstory,
include details about their relationship,
And keep consistent to the selected
characteristics of Emily and Whiskers.
the last bit in this
is template expansion.
So we said three to choose
from, six to choose from.
And I've just given it a brief instruction
that says when you see choose from,
look up the details from earlier in
the conversation and expand on it.
let's see what chat GPT comes up with.
And firstly, we've got Emily, who we
did select, and we know that Emily
was a 29-year-old now, the career
marketing and the philosophy, humanist
was selected randomly by chat GPT,
but the hair color was selected by me.
for the cat, we've got Whiskers, a
3-year-old main coon, and what we can
see is that we've got this 500 word
backstory about these two different
characters, and hopefully it includes
all the traumas, the interactions, and
just their philosophical points of view.
What's really interesting about
developing a bat story this way is that
you have all this information about
their philosophical point of view,
maybe how they come together, different
background stories, which makes it really
easy to develop day in the life sort
of stories or other forms of stories.
I.
Now before I go into the actual prompts
talking about Day In the Life, let's
look at how this could be automated.
So one of the things that you can do
with Chat GPT is you can create GPTs
or you can use the APIs, what I'm
about to show you as prompts could be
automated so that every day for the
next 365 days, you could create a Daily
Chronicle about Emily and Whiskers
and have a different story each day.
So let's create the first day in
our Daily Chronicles, and here I've
said, create a day in the life of
Emily and Whiskers in six scenes.
I've given it a guideline.
I've said, ensure that Emily
and Whiskers are in each scene.
Ensure consistency with the
backstory and the Daily Chronicle.
Now, if you had more
than one Daily Chronicle.
Day one, day two, day three.
Then you wanna put in a little
bit of information to make sure
it checks the previous days so
that you have continuity of story.
But for this one, what we're going to do.
Is make sure that there are four
scenes that are based on our backstory.
So we've got a scene where we see the type
of woman that she is, a challenge based
on Emily's philosophical perspective.
One that shows the effect
of whiskers under trauma.
the last one is the positive reaction
that Whiskers has with Emily.
Now when we run the prompt, we end
up getting six scenes created for
our day in the life and the first
scene, Is with Emily and Whiskers
doing their morning routine.
we move on to a walk in the park,
and based on the guidelines we put
into the prompt, we can see that the
scene illustrates Emily's advocacy
for sustainability and her natural
charisma in engaging the public.
So as I was going through this, I'm also
trying to make images along the way that.
Tend to fit the style.
So most of the images will have
Emily with a blue shirt, brown hair.
We've got a main coon in each one Scene
number three is just trying to demonstrate
the fear or the anxiety that Whiskers
is going on because of mild rain.
We take that a step further in scene
number four, where Whiskers is really
affected by a trauma of a kid running
around the cafe that they're in.
But at the end of the
day, they're now together.
They're calm.
We've got settled in a quiet
corner of the coffee shop.
Emily works on her laptop, and
to finish off the day, we've got
the evening relaxation going on.
I.
Now, as I said before, we can
automate that and have every
day created automatically.
But another thing that you can do,
and we see this in Marvel movies,
is the concept of a multiverse.
So how can we totally change the
style and structure of the story
without changing the backstories?
I wanna base the story off the one
we just created in America, 2024.
So we have a prompt that
says, using Emily and Whiskers
Daily, Chronicle America 2024.
Adapt it so that Emily and Whiskers
are real life characters from Hamlet.
it can take the story that we just had.
Rewrite it in a totally different style,
and from here we can see that we've
got morning revelations, we've got the
courtyard musings, a play within a play.
we've got terminology we've got graphics
that are very Shakespeare in style.
Then we get into the ghostly encounter
and the confrontation that would map to
the child running around in the cafe.
We got the confrontation going on and
then the end of the day, dark solace.
taking this a step further, we can let
ChatGPT come up with our multiverse.
So we'll do a new prompt, gimme a
useful ideas for scenarios, keep it to
20 words per item, Emily and Whiskers
in some sort of dystopian future and
a random theme, example, steam punk.
what ChatGPT has come up
with obviously is cyberpunk.
Cityscape.
We've got steampunk metropolis,
we've got a climate dystopia.
Let's do a daily Chronicle with six
scenes based on steam punk metropolis.
ChatGPT just responds with a similar
structure in this dystopian future.
So from here we've got our morning
ingenuity and twilight triumph.
They're top and tailing the story.
And then in the middle we've got the
market maneuvers, airship encounters,
chased by the cog guard, which would
be similar to the boy in the cafe
and the underground revelations.