So our agent SDK application is built and this is what it can do for us. So we're
going into the chat bot where
we're going to enter in some products. We should be able
to view those products and see that they're being stored in the back end. At any
time we should be able to create an HTML page. Notice that there's a live activity.
There's also live pages. If we click on the
pages, we should be able to go and see the products listing at any time. Then
we should be able to add a new product or update it, and it should come through instantaneously.
If we need a home page, we should be able to add a link and create a home page at
the same time. When we go to that home page, we should be able to navigate back to
the products.
And at the end of the video there's a complex multi page workflow demonstration.