Have you ever wanted to write video ad scripts that actually convert? If you've ever
needed to write a script for YouTube or other sorts of content, you know that a video
ad is at a whole different level.
In the last video, we built a script writing automation using PickAxe. Here's a snippet
from that particular creation.
In this video, we're going to take things up a notch by adding in curated knowledge
based on exceptional ad scripts, and we're going to drop it into the PickAxe automation
using the knowledge capability. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Okay, so our goal is to take the script writing bot that we used in the last video
and level up its capabilities. And what we're going to do is start from the original
hook based script, and we're going to go into PickAxe. And from here we can edit
this particular PickAxe
and we can see that it's simply a set of fields that we can fill in and a fairly
detailed prompt with insertion points for each of those fields. And that's what created
the script that you just saw. What we'd like to do next is start making use of the
knowledge base. And with the knowledge base, what we can do is get a curated list
of best practices for script writing, for say TikTok ads, or YouTube or Facebook
ads. Load 'em all up in here. And we may also come back and change a little bit of
the prompt to support the fact that we have a knowledge base. And let's say if
we can do a much better video advertising script.
So the first thing we're going to do is we'll come to the knowledge base and we're
going to connect a file. Now we haven't created a file yet. So let's see how we can
do that. Now I've got in here a bunch of scripts from five different videos that
are all quite similar to each other, which I thought were good examples of YouTube
video ads, and I'll just read one of them from the top. You open ChatGPT like it's
a vending machine for viral content. But what came out? Beige emotionless buzzword
salad. So this was the style of video I wanted to be able to reproduce for myself.
So I've taken all five transcripts and I've just taken them over to ChatGPT where
I've said read. And by doing that, I've put it into the knowledge base of a conversation.
Once it's absorbed, I can then start doing some additional simple, prompt engineering
to turn this into something really rich.
So rather than reading this bit of the prompt here, all it was was four different
questions that I was trying to gather information around the five scripts that I
provided. So let's have a look at the answers to them.
So when it read through all five scripts, it worked out that four of them were actually
all pretty similar in nature. They were this hard, impacting a lot of swear words
aimed at a male Gen Z sort of audience, sort of aggressive humor. So I knew about
that. There was also a fifth one in there that I hadn't been fully aware of the format,
but it was basically the coaching unlock formula where you might have a statement
like, here's how you actually do prompt engineering.
Now that led into my second question, which was what sort of advert were we seeing
here? And the reason this is important is that to reverse engineer and build your
own high performing adverts, you can't just clone someone else. You have to understand
the nature of how it's put together and we can see this. What style of advert? So
the shock and roast marketing is Gary Vee meets South Park sort of thing.
got pattern interrupt plus tribal rallying. So we've got pushes away the normies,
attracts the rebels. So this particular style of advert is going to be really useful
for a type of customer, a type of avatar if you like. But I did want to have other
types of avatars that I could create video adverts for that would resonate with them
more so than this particular style.
Now, my third question was other types of avatars. How would storytelling in video
adverts relate to them? And it's come up with three tonal pivots to soften the structure.
We've got the empathetic coach, curious teacher, and the story first mentor,
what I think we can do with the advertising script generation bot is have one seed
story and produce 3 or 4 totally different types of adverts for different audiences.
The last question that I wanted clarity from was this separation of story from the
actual structure of the adverts. So it's come up with the idea that you should be
able to have a very simple and bland story that you work from, and from that it can
identify the psychological triggers, like what's going on that we can hone in on
for any sort of advertising structure. Once that's in place, we can wrap all of that
into an advertising transcript using the various structures. And we're looking at
one here that has the hook, the punch, the insight and the call to action.
Now we're about to do some research, but I had one more question to ask, and it was
related to this statement that the three tonal pivots that we're seeing right here
would soften the delivery. And the last thing I needed was for the adverts to lose
their energy, to not do what adverts are meant to do, which is to create calls to
action to have click through rates.
So I asked this question about will it affect the actual advertisements, and it's
come up with some useful information stating that these styles can be really effective
advertising
But you've got to make sure that things are punchy and that you don't slow down.
Now, the inside it's given on the new styles is that you don't need to be rude, which
is what the first advert style was to create anxiety or tension within the adverts,
which helps to create click through rates. And the TLDR the "too long, didn't read"
is that for the empathetic coach, it would require fast emotional resonance. Immediate
problem identification. We've got the curious teacher here high concept hook or a
surprising truth in the next two seconds. And the story first mentor just needs to
tease the conflict fast and character connection.
now while we're talking about TLDR, I want to take you over to AI. TLDR which is
the whole reason that this video advert script system is being created.
Now AI-TLDR has been one of my experiment channels and in this it's currently got
150 videos, 850 odd subscribers, and most of the videos here are all on various forms
of AI style content creation, whether it be using notebook LLM or using design, which
is an incredible animation tool. We use a lot of Leonardo. We've created a whole
video trailers with this and avatars. And it occurred to me that as I'm building
out this particular channel, that all the lessons that are learned in this are really
easy to transfer to people that want to create their own YouTube channels. The problem
I had was that I didn't know how to send people to the actual course. It's not a
skill that I've got, so I thought the first thing I've got to do is create video
advert trailers,
and that's what we're enhancing in this PickAxe today.
So if you want to learn the multiple techniques that we're using on this particular
channel to build AI generated content, then come over to AI. TLDR and there'll be
a link in the description on how to access the upcoming course.
Now we're just about ready to create the document that will be in our knowledge base.
So I've taken a screenshot of PickAxe all this information, including all the input
variables, and I've asked it a question, basically stating that it should build up
a detailed research question. And that's what it's gone and done. It's come up with
information about understanding that there are five different advert styles that
we want to work with, that it's about getting the structure, understanding how story
integration works. And also really important is can it come up with examples from
the real world that fit these sort of advert structures?
and then it's just going to structure the report for us. So let's see what it came
up with.
So I ran the research prompt through ChatGPT Deep research. We've got a detailed
activity log here. It asked a couple of questions up front about whether I wanted
English or non-English. It also asked if I wanted to target a particular sort of
product like coaching or e-commerce. And I said, no, this is only for digital courses.
So everything that it's come up with, we've got the short form video scripts that
you might see on the major social networks. We've got the different types of scripts
worked out. Plus, how are the variables that we've already identified going to map
into all of this?
So we have a detailed walkthrough of each of the five. We've got the roast to call
out with the emotional effectiveness, the structure that goes on, and the type of
audience that it would resonate with.
It also talks about turning negative concepts into positive returns for the audience.
And we get a detailed analysis for the other four types. So with the Tactical Coach,
what we're doing here is delivering quick wins and actionable value upfront.
The empathetic coach is about deep emotional resonance and trust building.
The Cur teacher is providing intrigue and intellectual stimulation. And what I think
is interesting about all five types that we're looking at
is that we should be able to take any story, repurpose it, and put it out as a collection
of adverts of which some will resonate with people, some won't.
so if you like to receive information in the story first mentor style, which is captivating
through narrative and authenticity, then you'll resonate with that advert style.
whereas other people resonate with the story through a shock and awe sort of approach.
Now it's also come up with a good variable mapping concept, and this is useful when
we think of the way people can input into the tool. And they might not necessarily
know what to fill in. Like do I type in shock? What does that actually mean? Do I
do emotional failure?
What does that mean behind the scenes. And this has all been mapped. So when we look
at the hook type and we say this is what it can look like in a roast callout, but
we've got one for each of the five different styles going on here.
Now it's given me three new variables. If I want to get really detailed in the configuration,
I'm not sure if I'm going to do that with this particular version of the add bot,
the one thing that's really powerful here is the real world examples by each of the
different styles. So if we look at the roast call out examples.
Through to the empathetic coach. We're feeling burnt out. Juggling your business
or family, I get it, I've been there, and it doesn't have to be that way. So all
the way through here, we've got two different examples for each of the different
styles that are based on real world adverts that actually convert and get business.
And the final set of instructions is how can we take simple stories and turn them
into each of the different advert types step by step? So there's a real detailed
analysis. With all this in place, the only thing to do is to download it and to upload
it into PickAxe. And the good thing about deep research in ChatGPT is that you can
go and click this button here, and what it does is make it available to you as a
PDF. So we'll just click on that button and next we'll go and upload it into PickAxe.
Now, with our complete knowledge base downloaded, we can come over to PickAxe, click
on the knowledge tab here and we can just connect the file. But you might be thinking
so far that's actually been very detailed. And if you were to do it yourself, could
you do it now? It's relatively easy to follow the the process, but if you want to
work one on one with me, then just come over to AppyDave Comm. You can click on the
Book a Call button, and from there we can either do a discovery session or just a
one hour consult just to see what it is that you're trying to achieve. But for now,
let's just click on the connect files. From there we can go add. With that I'm going
to upload a file in this particular case. And I've put the file into the same place
as this recording. And we'll just let it load in.
Now. Once it's finished uploading, we just click on the documents we want to connect
and just press the connect button.
So with our document uploaded, we could turn it off. That's not the point of this.
So we want to leave it on. And you can also have a look at it. Now the document is
actually 34 pages long, with the final set of information just being some citations
to other resources that it can look at. So a heck of a lot of great information that
will help us generate our scripts effectively. One other thing that I've made a minor
change to is just when should it pick it? Now it should pick it every time, I believe.
But I've just said refer to the high performance, short form ad doc examples, structures
and emotional hooks across the five different advert types.
Now I'm just going to make a small modification to the role. One of the big things
is that the tailored platform trends and digital education products have been added
in. Next thing is to have a look at the instruction set which had these original
variables. We are going to need some new ones.
So I've taken the instruction, the prompt as such. It's got some modifications. One
of the main ones being is that there are new variables being added. We've also got
the add styles. This I'm going to do as a drop down. So let's just migrate it all
over.
Now I've taken the prompt from the original chat bot, and I've just updated it with
anywhere there's a new field. So we've got the four that are going in right here.
There's also a new ad style which has been reproduced as a radio button list. That
way we can only select one particular value. I've also put in a little bit more description
with each of the labels. So then when we look at it over from the public facing point
of view, we've still got the same heading, the same description, but now we can select
a particular ad style that we want to do and then go and fill the values. So let's
give it a test.
So we're testing this out for the very first time. And I've started pre filling in
some values. I'm going to go with the curious teacher approach. Now before I go into
details of this I will also point out that I created a fake story. So the story is
I've been thinking about starting a YouTube channel for a while. I've tried a couple
of times, recorded a few videos, tested some formats. So talks about different tools
that I might have used 11 labs for voice capture, for video editing, Canva for presentation,
sort of setup. And what I really want is a bunch of tutorials for the different styles
of AI videos.
And the reason I've picked this particular storyline is that's exactly what we've
done over on AI TLDR. We've gone through the process in the past of figuring out
how do you do different sorts of videos, what sort of tools do you use? And this
is actually the course that we want to market as a result of this script building
exercise. So if we come back to the actual setup screen, we've got the curiosity
teacher as the starting point,
and we'll leave the hook tight at curiosity. Similar to the actual ad style we've
got, I failed. This is too hard. This is some of the reasons why you give up on the
different techniques. It's aimed at the person who would actually like to solve the
problem for themselves.
the value that we wanna reveal is an actual course or a mini framework per type of
video that you want to do.
and then it's going to direct people to a community and a course.
Now, I think in keeping with the curious teacher, I'm going to go with the tone as
uplifting, the character archetype as coach and what's the belief that we're trying
to shift? It's you need to hustle to, you just need a simple step-by-step guidance.
So I'll just come back over here, copy. The fake story that we created, it was really
just a generation, and I'm just going to paste it down into the story seed. Let's
see what happens.
So we'll press submit
So here's our first output. We've got the hook. Have you ever thought of starting
a YouTube channel. But it's just impossible. You're not alone I get it. And through
to a call to action, which is join our community today to transform your content
creation journey. What I'll do next is I'm going to test this from a more vulgar,
rude, shock point of view, and I'm going to do it within the testing capability.
And then we'll produce a little video around it.
Now I've come over here to test a more Hollywood action style. So we're going to
go with the roast call out. Now we're gonna go with shock. Bad technique is the reason.
It's the idea of gurus selling you false hope. We are going to reveal a framework
via a direct offer and we will go with sarcastic and rude. The person talking will
be a drill sergeant and we're going to go with a belief shift. You need to hustle
to, you need to get a life and ultimately you're going to gain something. And we'll
go with the Gary v Alex, her Mozy style, mentioning that it's okay to swear. Now
for a story. I've also changed the story right up a bit and I've said the content
protocol
and we got this idea of I woke up in a hotel room with no memory, a half rendered
cap cut timeline playing on a loop, and a whispering in voice in my ear that says
the algorithm has been compromised. So this has much more of a story appeal. So we'll
just copy all of that, come back and paste it in and press test prompt and see what
happens.
So it's starting to write out a story and it goes with hey, yeah, you looking, scrolling
mindlessly, still thinking of those get rich quick videos will save your life.
So rather than me reading this out, what I'll do is I'll turn it into a quick eye
video and let's see how it sounds.
So I wanna give you a conclusion and also just talk about one other aspect of this.
So in conclusion, this creation of a script is not a lot better than the previous
example. It's, it's okay, but the use of rag hasn't worked exactly the way I want.
But let's have a look into why that could be. So if you go down to this little magnifying
glass here and click on it,
get to see the full prompt explored,
which would be an improvement if we could, but what we can do is explore what information
came out of the knowledge base. So at
file name and we can see all the information that was returned and made available
to the prompt. Now I increased the size of the information being returned and the
relevancy score. So all the relevancy scores here on the right are fairly high.
They're all above an initial value of 75. So if we go all the way down to the bottom,
we don't see anything under 75. I also have a cutoff of a roundabout
and it's that 3000 character limit, which is why this little green line is here.
So what I think I want to do in future examples of using the rag and the knowledge
base is to maybe split the file up into both the structure and the examples
and maybe even a file of just turning stories into scripts
so that I get much better modeling of input values to expected output values.
Anyway, I'm AppyDave. If you want to work one on one with me, then book a call. Otherwise
please like and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.