You know, you can build landing pages
for websites like this one
and a variation on it
just here using three simple prompts
in most of the various AI pair programmers,
and with a little bit of a custom
instruction,
you can even change it up a little bit
by giving it a bit of a Christmas theme.
So stay tuned as we explore three prompts
that build these landing pages.
AI is all the rage. And you've decided that you want to create a little business
around something to do with AI and thought, I need a website, I need a landing page.
And now you're researching. Should I use Wix? Should I use WordPress? How do I create
this? In this video, what I'd like to do is see if we can use three simple little
prompts, a little bit of prompt engineering and vibe coding, and create our own landing
page for a brand new business. I'm AppyDave,. Let's get into it.
Vibe coding is getting really powerful in the last couple of months. We're seeing
an influx of people doing videos around this topic here at couple. I've done on building
application shells recently. You can check out these videos over on my YouTube channel,
but I've also been using it to work through React and Tailwind Componentry. This
was a little application I put together yesterday and in the last week I've been
working on this application that uses ai. We can press little buttons here to preload
it with data, and as it works through, it can go off to external systems like N8N
this application will go off and use AI to get questions relating to an incident
in a medical situation.
Now. The client for that project came to me yesterday, gave me a few pieces of information,
such as a logo and a couple of supporting documents and said, can you turn this into
a website landing page?
And so today that's what we're going to try and do using just three prompts.
So I think for today I am just going to go into ChatGTP and just get a starter conversation
going on with the main ideas. So if I was building a landing page for a new business
in HTML and Tailwind CSS, this is all the technology that I've said is available
at the moment
We need an agent or a person who is skilled in the art of making landing pages for
websites, they understand marketing, that sort of stuff.
the next thing we would need is the business or marketing collateral. So the information
about the company or the business that we're trying to
promote on the website. And the last thing we need to know is what would be the requirements
document for the landing page? What would be the structure of the site? So I'm just
going to put this information in and press enter for now.
And what that's done is given us a breakdown of those three areas in just better
writing than I could have done through the inputs. So we've got this role or agent
definition, which is a marketing landing page designer. We've got the skills required
for that particular entity.
Now we've got the sort of information we should collect. I don't know that I'm gonna
have it all, but we've got brand identity, like the logo. We do have colors and fonts.
I don't have that at the moment. Don't currently have a mission and vision. I think.
I haven't actually read all the documents and I don't think that matters too much.
What you really wanna do is the better the information you have available, you just
feed it all in. But this is the sort of information you're trying to come up with.
And then the last one is, what would a requirements document or a product requirements
document look like and the structure? So we've got all this information here. We're
not going to implement it all. We're going to let AI do a lot of the work and we're
just gonna vibe code something that we're happy with.
So because this is a video and we're doing things visually, I just turned that information
firstly into a PowerPoint presentation so I can describe it better to you. We need
an agent role definition. We need business marketing collateral. And we're going
to need a requirements document.
And I'm showing you this because when you're coding keep in mind that all the marketing
imagery you want is as simple as taking the information and just shaping it into
a picture of a particular style. This particular image I just said create image 1609
aspect ratio. Use the Golden Age of Comics as the style that represents. And I said
the three part section above as if it was a PowerPoint presentation.
Now, the first prompt that I want to create is going to be a persona. So the way
we'll do that is we will just select the information it has right here. And I've
just started. Can you take the following information and turn it into a persona.
We'll paste it in and we'll just press enter on that.
So starting to write out information that we'll use in a variety of vibe coding environments.
Now we have a persona document has been created. What I like to do here is just go
into canvas mode. This information, we could use it from any number of vibe coding
tools, but we just copy the information. We can close that down. Head over to VS
code in this case. And I've just set up three blank documents. So the one we're starting
off with is going to be the persona.
we can see all the information that's there. We could edit it over here if we wanted
to.
So the next thing we want to do is go and have a look at these documents. We've got
two PDFs and a word document, and I'll just take us back to our GPT window. And essentially
I want to build this area using that information. So I've just started a prompt that
says can you develop a detailed overview of the company information using the attached
documents? I'm also going to just paste in this regular information.
Now if we bring up the folder view that we had earlier, we can see these three documents.
And hopefully we can just drag them in here. They're now attached and they're loading
into memory. What I'd like it to do is read through all of these and apply the information,
and just see if we can get a detailed brief related to this particular organisation.
So that's just finished creating the information. We've got the company, it's called
Supporting Signal. We've got a mission and a vision. We've got brand identity pillars,
taglines, visual identity. So it looks like we don't have colors.
edit this document dynamically here to adding some colors that make sense for this
sort of organization. We've got a target audience personas, we've got social proof,
differentiation, and we've got a little bit of existing information.
I think for the colors, we should just be able to go back to the logo, which already
has some colors in it. Well, we'll just add that in there and say, can you extract
branding colors
from logo?
And we might also say,
I've also added a little bit. You can add more branding colors
if you think it makes sense.
So we've got new colors being created. Now let's go and turn everything into a document.
So I've just said, can you create brand details document using the recommended color
palette from the AI's point of view? Plus I'm just gonna paste in the rest of the
information that we had above. And this should turn it into a Canvas document. Start
writing everything. There's a little button at the top of this where I can press
copy and we'll just move it directly over to the file system.
So here's our document. We'll go and press copy, go back to Visual Studio in this
case, and we'll click on the brand details document and just paste everything in
and save it.
So the last piece in the puzzle is to create a requirements document that we can
use. Now, we do need to be careful that whatever we create right now doesn't get
too influenced by the other two documents we've done. The role and the marketing
collateral, mainly because we have detailed information there, it's in this conversation,
but when we use it in another tool, I'll be using Claude Code, but it could be replit,
it could be cursor. They are already provided as tangible finished documents.
so what I've done is started a prompt that says, can you create a requirements document
for me? The project is pure HTML and Tailwind CSS landing page. No JavaScript frameworks
or backend logic. Keep the tech minimal and focused. Now, I've also said this prompt
is being used in a separate chat bot and already has access to the two supporting
documents, which is the brand details and the persona document that we've just talked
about. You can let these documents inspire the structure, but don't integrate it.
So in this case, it's a little bit fuzzy. I would write this prompt a little bit
differently if I was going to do the actual vibe coding inside ChatGTP, but in this
case, I'm just preparing documents.
I might also just take the original information that was right here and throw it
down the bottom. You can use this and we'll paste it in
and let's see what sort of a requirements document it produces for us.
So we've got a detailed document with the project scope. The technology is listed.
It looks like the page is going to have a hero, which is the main image at the top
of the website. We've got some features who, it's for compliance and intelligence
section.
this is for government sponsored programs. So this is important. We've got testimonials,
frequently asked questions, and a call to action and footer. We've got all the layout,
SEO media and assets. I think we've even got the location of the file. So a simple
HTML file with simple CSS and an assets folder.
So we'll just copy the information and we'll go down to our requirements document
and we'll paste everything in.
Now I plan to do a few versions of the landing page, and I'll do it from a few different
techniques. So we'll start off in regular Claude at the moment and put in a prompt
that says, can you become. Now what do we want to become? We want to become the persona
that we set up earlier. So if we go over and drag the persona into here and press
go,
it's loading in, the idea of what a marketing landing page designer really encompasses.
Next we'll put in a simple prompt will go. Can you absorb branding design guidelines?
We're waiting for further instructions. We'll go back down to our files. This time.
We'll put in the brand details
and we'll just let that come in. So now we've loaded up this clean conversation with
two useful pieces of information. One is an employee of sorts,
a web designer, in this case. And we've loaded in all of the details around the brand.
And the last prompt is, can you create a website using brand details that we've already
inputted and the following requirements. And we can just drag that information in
and press go. And what it should start to do is create an artifact for us and start
generating the code over on the right. One of the things that we can see here is
that we've got tailwind CSS. This actually might be a little bit problematic, because
I find this particular CDN implementation not to be the best. So we may need to change
that. But at the moment it's just writing all the HTML. We need to do some sort of
visual landing page. And this will change every time you do it. So the good thing
about this technique is that you can run it multiple times, and I'll show you a better
way of doing that soon so that you can test different iterations.
So it failed to create. And it's happened because of an uncaught reference error
to tailwind. I see this fairly regularly, and when I went to go into fix mode, it
just randomly did 6 or 7 tests. That all failed, and I had to give it a little bit
of instructions. And on the ninth one it did work. And so we've got this landing
page that's been created correctly. It's following the branding guidelines that it
assumed would be the right way to go.
I think we could play around with colors a fair bit, but let's test a couple more
ways of generating this same landing page with other tools.
So to test out the next technique, we'll just go to a clean ChatGTP window and I'll
say, I'll give you three documents. I want you to become the persona. I want you
to read and understand the brand details for the client. And lastly, I want you to
create a simple HTML page using the requirements I've also just said for reinforcement,
in other words, as persona rebrand details and create HTML following the requirements.
And if we pop on down to our file system before where we had these files, we should
be able to just drag them in. Once they've loaded, we can just press go and hopefully
it'll start writing html and we'll be able to visualize it in ChatGTP.
So it started writing index html. Maybe it's something that we've gotta bring down
to Visual Studio to edit and run from. One of the things I noticed high up is that
we've got Tailwind CSS, but we don't actually have a link to it to A CDN. So this
wouldn't run the way it is right now. We also don't even have these icons, so things
will be a little bit different when running it this way. And quite frankly, it's
a very small HTML file. So let's just see
what would happen if we just go into the edit mode. So from edit mode, we can actually
preview it. There's a little button up in the top right hand corner, and so we can
see that none of the CSS has come through for us.
So I'm just gonna test whether I can bring this
alignment and working directly from ChatGTP, I've just said, can you make this complete?
In other words, can you replace the asset icons that we had, which were images with
just scalable vetor graphics?
And can we make sure that the CSS is calling A CDN?
And we'll just run that. It'll rewrite the code for us.
We can see the scalable veto graphics being drawn here and here. I don't know what
shape they are, they're just a bunch of mathematical numbers from my point of view
at the moment.
Now, like in Claude, we had similar issues with the tailwind CSS showing up, so I
just gave it a screenshot and said what are the suggestions? Came up with a few.
I said, can you just use the recommended change and rewrote it for us? And what that
means is that if we hit play on this particular one, we now do have a working version
on the screen. It's a little bit different to the other.
But now let's go to the last technique, which I prefer to use over these two.
which is to use Claude Code. So I've come down to Visual Studio. We've got our three
files that we're interested in here, and I'm just going to open up a terminal.
with the terminal open, I can start typing Claude and this will open up, we can initialize
it, we can do options, but I'm just going to use it the way it is right now and start
writing a prompt.
So I've just said, can you become, I'll put in the at symbol and I'll start writing
persona and that becomes available.
Then I say using the brand details again. I put in the at sign, I start typing brand.
I've said create a HTML file called, we can put in anything we want. We can even
use the at symbol, even though it won't make a lot of sense 'cause it doesn't exist
right now. I'll do index one point HTML in this case. And the reason I'm doing the
one is we should be able to create two, three, and four and see different look and
feel. And the last thing we should write here
is follow the requirements. So at that point we can just start typing requirements.
There's the document and we press enter. And press go.
So now it's reading all three files and coming up with a plan of action for what
it wants to do. It says I'll create a marketing landing page for support signal using
the brand details and the requirements provided.
And now it has a list of steps that it's going to work through. We've got creating
the HTML structure.
So it's created the code. It's asking if I want to write it into the system. So we've
got this new file called index one html going on,
and it says it's finished everything.
It's told us everything it's done. If we right click on the file and I've got live
server available, so I can click on that button there and here we have it.
One of the things I find about Claude Code over the last two techniques that we used,
which was ChatGTP plus, and the Claude conversation window as well, is that this
tends to work every time and the quality of the output tends to be a lot better.
This is using the Opus model. In this particular case, we're on index number one.
even things work. So I clicked on a button and we saw start your free trial.
Now for the next example, we'll create index two and we'll start typing in Claude
again. But this time I'm going to put in a model and I'm going to use the sonnet
model. So if we pop this up like this and kick it off, where still in Claude, we're
just doing it from a different location. And I'm gonna paste in a prompt that says,
can you become persona, the same brand details, the same requirements only? We're
going to put it into index number two, so it's gonna go through the same thing all
over again.
Now as that happens, we'll have our visual studio coming up. We can see everything
running down in the bottom right hand corner. And hopefully a new file called index
two will get generated here.
When we look at it in the terminal, it's got all similar stuff to before, but it
will change things around. We could have even used a little bit of a custom instruction
to do something fancy, and we might do that with the third example.
So it's got all the information. It started writing a new file,
So I'll right click on the index two and we can open it up. And here we have it.
Now it looks very similar. If we go down the bottom, let's look at them side by side
here with the other version that we had
slightly different
and we come back.
So we'll right click and open up index two. And here it is. If we look at it compared
to index one
it the same way. It's called from reactive reporting to reformative intelligence.
If we look down at FAQ in number two and we move down, we've got FAQ. Again, it's
slightly different and we've got a different way of doing the email sign up down
the bottom.
So for our final test, we'll just do something a little bit different. I've got exactly
the same prompt in the same conversation. This time I've called it index three, which
makes sense, but I want to give it more of a Christmas feel. So I'll just say it's
Christmas. And we have decided that the landing page needs a Christmas feel. So let's
see what it does the third time.
So it's got our to-dos. It's a little bit different because we're going to structure
it with festive elements.
We're also going to have brand colors plus the Christmas color accents.
Now if you're wondering how long this should take, I'm finding that it's taking somewhere
between two to three minutes to generate these pages. But it is a one shot, it gets
it right each time
So that's finished. We'll go over to Visual Studio. We've got a third file. When
we look through, we've got some colors and look at that. We're starting to see concepts
like animations. We've got Christmas reds. What happens if we go to the web on this?
And it's still our brand colors, but we've now got
Christmas trees, we've got presents, we've got snowflakes, we've got some sort of
border going around. Let's see, and the color of all the panels have all changed
quite a bit. Now this was created from scratch, so normally you wouldn't do it this
way. Normally you might say modify the existing structure to have the Christmas feel.
But this has worked pretty well. I love this.
So to recap, we essentially used three prompts. We had the agent definition role.
So who was going to be building the website for us. We then had our marketing collateral,
our branding information, our second brain. And that could be any information that
you want to see going into the website. And lastly, we did the requirements. We tested
it on Claude OpenAI, ChatGPT plus and Claude Code,. And with the Claude Code,, we
were able to do three different variations, including a Christmas version.
Now if you're interested in working one on one with me with Vibe coding, you can
come and book a call through that. We can arrange some time to work together, but
otherwise, if you just want to learn more about vibe coding and using Prompt Engineering
to write software, then follow the channel AppyDave,. Please like and subscribe.
I'll see you in the next video.