G'day, I'm Dave, and in this ApiCast, I want to go behind the scenes and have a look at
the studio setup that I've got in my living room, how I'm using it to run five face channels.
I have ApiCast, which is long form content, a lot of behind the scenes sort of work, Api
Dave, where I build software using ChatGPT, Winning Prompts, where I do prompt engineering
and look for better ways of writing ChatGPT prompts, Fly Video, where I do YouTube automation,
that's the glue that's making me, allowing me to have multiple channels run at once,
and a personal project called the Carnivore 90 Challenge, which is myself just getting
healthy through a diet that I'm testing out. On top of that, I have two faceless channels
in development at the moment, using pure YouTube automation sort of technologies. Anyway,
to make this all happen, I needed to put together a studio. This is what it looks like.
I walk through my studio setup really needs to start off with this gimbal. It's an Osmo
4, it's one of those older models. I have a video channel called Carnivore 90, where
on 90 Day Challenge, and having used of this gimbal has been awesome. Sitting on top is
a Boya wireless microphone, so I got a little lapel mic going on here. I bought the system
that has two, two of the microphones, one receiver, though I've never used the second
one. In the background, we've got a light going on up here, which would normally be
off, but I've just turned it on to highlight the room a little bit more. And we can move
through to where I've got a few smart lights. There's four of them. What I find useful about
having the four, two on the left, two on the right, is that I can change the whole effect
of an area by changing the colors of just one of them. So I might make the two blue lights
red, and the red and the green mix together give us an effect. Now behind, I've got an old laptop
that I used to use all the time. I've put a little backdrop on there. I'm not finding it
that effective at the moment, it's okay. I took a picture down off the wall, there's a little
hook there. I may end up putting some sort of print up here, or I may also put a projector
just painting a picture onto the wall could be useful. Now over here, we've got sound baffles
on the wall. I currently now use AI software to get rid of all the noise from outside. I happen
to be on a major road and it's very noisy, police go by all sorts of stuff. But what these sound
baffles more do for me is just stop the light going in because that curtain doesn't go far enough
across, not a practical use of sound baffles, but it works. You can see these are the smart lights
that I'm using, I think they're called a TAPO. We pop out to look at the screen, maybe we'll look
at the screen decks. So the first one was stream decks. I'm using a stream deck XL, it's El Gato.
I'm using foot pedals, which are incredible. I find this to be an amazing tool to start
recording, stop recording, pause recording and resume recording. Currently, I've got the main
webcam is a Logitech. It works really well for me. The autofocus is sometimes an issue in my videos.
I have this other one, which I have not started using yet. I'm working on the idea of having
multiple angles. And behind me, I got different speaker arrangements, whether it be my headphones,
which I sometimes use or my JBL. Sitting down here, we've got a little bit of cabling coming down.
I love having these red cables. I just got them on Amazon. By being red, I can see them really
easily. They all hang down to this little three point stand. That's where I might put stuff like
the gimbal that I'm holding right now might just sit here and charge overnight. My phone might go
here. For my microphone, I'm keeping it fairly simple. It's just another Boyer M1 in this case.
I do have one of these, I don't know what you call them, but you can put various microphones into it
if we pop in down here. I do have an arm for a microphone and microphones around somewhere.
I've also got, but not using this streamer pack. It has a lot of the stuff we just talked about.
Then there's a key light. The key light I'm using, I think it was just a cheap knockoff that I got
somewhere. It had a really bright light. One of the challenges is that I personally have red skin
and the bright light was just too harsh. So I've gone for a darker light. Nothing really
professional about this, but it does work. I do get my lighting pretty good at the moment,
especially by stopping the light from coming in from outside because of those baffles.
I would turn this off normally as well. To get the back lighting glow effect,
I'm finding these colored lights to be pretty awesome. I think that's everything. I've made
sure I've had good power supply cable management going on here. I made this little box. I didn't
made the box. I bought the box for $10. Then I did things like cutouts so that it could go over
the legs of the table. I've also shaved the insides of this so that the stream deck fits.
It's stuck down. It's quite solid in there. So that's the full extent of my studio setup.
Other than the monitor, which I will talk briefly about it. It's about two years old now. It's a
Samsung 5K curved monitor. So it's the size of two 27-inch monitors. I find it to be a bit of a
pain in the ass as a YouTube content creator. As a software developer, it's pretty good. But
I was living overseas recently where I had a 32-inch 4K monitor. It was just a lot more
practical for recording content on that video, on that monitor than it was on this monitor.
That said, it's still nice to have a big monitor. I guess lastly, what sort of computer am I using?
It's just a Mac mini. Works pretty well. I've been running out of memory a little bit recently. I've
live and then other stuff as well, all running at the same time. So that's a little bit of a challenge.
That's pretty much my setup. Some of the capabilities that I now have with this setup is that I can
change scenes without my hands. I'm just using foot pedals to control what scene I'm on. Or I can go
to specific ones using my other stream deck. So a web view or a web view with ChatGPT. We can
drill in directly on mid-journey. Look at some graphics that I've been playing around with.
We've got stuff like mixing up mid-journey with folders. Come back to front camera reviews.
Later on, I'll be hooking up the multiple webcam approach so I can hit different angles.
There's also issues that I can solve. I'll just hit pause with my toilet,
whereby I control the lights behind me. I'm just going to go to the medium light at say
blue at the moment, but I can change it to red because there's also a green light up in the top
corner, which I've got soft at the moment. I can change the gradient effect of lights as they come
through. Change the brightness of the lights. Now the studio setup that you see here, I've put it
together over about a month and a half. I've come back from overseas where I was living abroad just
doing a bit of work remotely, and I started my YouTube journey while over there loads a lot in
the last five or six months on the journey. Founded an incredibly challenging process to get videos
out to get them edited. I'm a one man show, though I do have a video editor now working
for me for 10 hours a week. I tend to produce a lot more content than is getting uploaded
to YouTube at the moment. I'm trying to balance that so that the amount of content I'm creating
is leading straight to videos out on YouTube. The combination of the great software that I've
been using, especially I think of late it's Eken Live, having this studio setup, having concepts
like background lights. I also have friends that help me in the form of the apicast. They tend to
act as a muse for me. I get to communicate with them, bounce ideas. I still drive the show, but
they add some valuable insight as I'm building out the different channels. When I hear different
influencers who absolutely know what they're doing when it comes to YouTube, they talk about the idea
of maybe getting to 100 videos before you even worry about what you're doing. That's exactly
what I'm doing. I'm not doing it though across one channel. I'm doing it across five channels plus
two to come. I love doing it this way. It's probably a very dumb way to do it. I don't think any
educator of YouTube influence would teach you to do it this way. But by having three tech channels
that do niches, followed by a long form content channel, followed by a personal project channel,
followed by two faceless channels, I get to see all sorts of angles of the YouTube development
process. I'm trying to automate as I go. I get lots of examples on how you should automate and what
doesn't work. I tell you, one of the big things I have is failure. So much failure in my YouTube
process is driving maturity with what I'm now creating on YouTube. Anyway, thank you for this.
Coming into the behind the scenes, my studio at ApiCast, Api Dave, winning prompts, fly video,
carnival 90, and I won't name the other two channels just yet.