In this video I'm going to use ChatGPT as a personal to-do list create some
commands to manage and maintain more than one list and I'm going to be able
to add remove and mark items as complete. This video won't just show you how to do
a to-do list in ChatGPT but also show you how you can create commands to have
much more control over what you do with ChatGPT. Earlier this year when I was
learning about prompt engineering I was exploring different ideas of controlling
ChatGPT and one of the ideas that I was looking into was could I control it like
I might control an application and at the time I wrote this little prompt around
to-do list and I had concepts like a list create and I would give the name of the
list that I would like to have to-do zone and then I'd have something like a
list add and the be the name of the list that the item would go on to and then
whatever the item would be and there be a list remove and could we see the
various to-do items within different lists. Now I thought I'd re-explore this
idea now that we have access to custom instructions which give us a fair bit more
control over the ideas of what happens every time prompt comes in and what
happens every time a response goes out from ChatGPT. While this video is
specifically about a to-do list what you will find is that you'll be able to
reuse these concepts to make ChatGPT more consistent and easier to use through
commands that you can create yourself. To get started head over to ChatGPT I'm
in the GPT form model at the moment click on the three little dots here and we
can put in some information to handle a request and to handle how ChatGPT will
respond. As we build out the to-do list manager which will be a custom GPT
instruction we're going to work through this infographic here and develop the
AI role the overview and the guidelines on how it should work what commands it
should work with and when a command comes in how should it respond. You can put
any text you like into a custom GPT instruction request or response there is
a limit of 1500 characters for each field but apart from that put in whatever
you like but what we're going to do is look at a little programming language
that I've developed here which will allow us to think in terms of sections what's
important and just to show you how it works I'll just add in some text I'll
say hello world and I'll hit save on this and what we should see is that the AI
role is now updated with hello world if I wanted a command I might do a line
break followed by a command called help and that command if you used it would
show help. Now all this information will be made available later on to both the
request and the response buttons down here and that will just copy the text
into my clipboard so I can use it within chat GPT. A common concept when writing
prompts is defining the role that chat GPT is meant to take and in this case what
we'll do is we'll just say that you are a to-do app. What I'd like to do now is
give an overview of what this bot is meant to do and I think we can start off with
you will maintain my to-do list you will keep different lists so more than one
list is going to be maintained and I want to be able to add a view and markers
complete various to-do items now we'll just hit save we should see that update
now I'd like to test this out but before we do let's add one more concept
and that's the idea of a command and we'll just keep it very simple so I'll
type in command and we'll call it help so essentially I would like to be able to
type the word help and understand what this bot is going to do
so if we fill it in and I'll just paste in this message show the role list of
the commands and an overview of how you work now I don't get my grammar
exactly right I just get the bare minimum of information in because I've only
got 1500 characters in which to write this information
now I would like to test this custom instruction but before I do I'm going to
head over to chat GPT and we'll just see what happens if
we give it a command it's such as help now my expectation is that we'll get
some sort of a generic message from chat GPT we do of course please provide
more information so we'll head back over to our
instruction that we've created we're going to call it to do
app we've got a list of concepts that we want it
in the overview and we've got one command called help
so when I type in help next time we should get
better information we've also said show a list of
commands show the role give an overview of how you're planning to work for us
and we can just go down and click on this request button
and now when we head over to chat GPT I can just
paste and we've got this information here
one of the things to notice is that some of the labels especially the one for
the AI role are not in this list of information
and this will become relevant in a moment now what I won't do
is do it as a regular prompt now you can do you do not need to use custom
instructions you can take this and just use it as a regular prompt
the problem with doing it this way is that if this conversation goes for a long
period of time it will forget all your commands
so instead what we do is we head over to this area click on the three little
dots go to custom instructions and we paste it in here
and this is where I said it was relevant to the amount of information you put
into the text is that we've only got 1500
characters that we can put in here the same with how it should respond
only 1500 characters so some of the things you'll notice
like with the command overview of how you work
grammatically you might write that a little bit more
with more information but it's not needed for
the custom instruction so I keep it as simple as possible
and now when we hit save and we do a new chat
we can just type in help again and hopefully we're going to get a detailed
look at what this can do it's already said that it's
designed to maintain our to-do list its role I'll maintain different lists for
you I will add view mark items now we only
defined one command and it looks like it's listed a bunch of commands
what we'll do over time is we will define our own commands and we may even use
information that's on this list but the problem
with this is that because we haven't defined it again if
any conversation gets long it might just start doing random stuff on us
we really want to be quite specific in the commands we give
and we may also want to name them differently we might want to support an
alias do you really want to type complete when maybe c
colon might be enough information let's test it out though because since it
has come up with commands it might actually work
so I'm just going to type add and I reckon we can go with groceries
and I think I want an apple we'll see what happens with this
says I've added an apple to your groceries list
I think in these examples I'll go between food
and dance I do dancing I do salsa bachata stuff like that
so I think we'll create another list and we'll call it dance
and we'll just say I need to do some salsa tonight
hopefully now we have two to-do items hopefully we've also got two lists so
I'm not sure whether this is going to work the way it's done
we will try the show list command next so if we type in show list
colon press enter and we've got we definitely got two lists so this is a
good thing I decided to explore the command structure the way chat gpt has
come up with it and I'll just go over a couple of things that show up
so as we move down I decided to add orange
now you might notice beforehand it said would you like to manage these lists
further now I don't really want it asking me questions along the way I just
want it executing tasks based on commands so I said add orange I would
hope that it would go on to the groceries list now it has picked up
that it should go on to the grocery list but it's asking
would you like it to be added and the same thing happened when I added
bachata to the dance list it asked a similar sort of question
what that meant is that when I did the show list it only came up with the first
two items it didn't add the new items to the new list so what I think we can do
is improve the instructions improve the commands ourselves
so that it does exactly what we need it to do
we're back over at our to-do list manager instruction and I would like to add
three commands one to set the current list that we're working with
one to add items to a list and one to mark items as being done
so for the set we'll work with an idea that there's a command called set
that it would take a name so the name of the list that you would like to
put the focus on and then it just says set the current list
create a new list if it doesn't exist so you should be able to use this when
there aren't any to-do lists of that name
now if we move on we've got add it takes the list name as the first parameter
notice there's a little question mark there I'll talk about that in a moment
and then the item you would like to add to the list
and we'll add one other command called done so it's got the idea that you can
set a current list you can add an item to an existing list
and you can mark an item on a list as already done
so we'll just hit save on that it should update the visualization
we've got that there the way I'm visualizing it
now this doesn't come through to the GPT instruction this is just for me to
understand the communication of what I'm trying to do
but the things that are light brown the name the item the day
they're parameters so you should be able to change them to whatever value you
like we should be able to add salsa on
Thursday something like that you might notice that with the add and the done
command that I've got this little question mark in here
what I want to chat GPT to know is that
this is an optional parameter I may provide it I may not
but it won't just guess this auto auto magically we need to tell it
so what we'll do is we'll add in a section that says
any parameter with a question mark is optional so
just like an instruction to a human you can give these instructions to the bot
and hopefully it will understand it let's quickly add four new commands
I basically want to be able to see what to do lists are available so we'll have
something like show lists I want to be able to see what items
need to be done on a to-do list we'll call that command to do
and any items that are on the list they should get added to the bottom of the
list but we might want to move them up or down on the list
so the commands will add is we'll have list which
will have show all to-do lists now notice here I've also got this concept
called shortcut and ideally I don't necessarily want to
type list colon and then whatever we're doing
maybe l colon would be good enough it might be really nice to have shortcuts
or aliases or commands now I haven't got that implemented here yet
but this is an idea that you can move forward and I'll show you how you can
implement that in a moment the next one is to-do this will
give us a list of items that we need to do on a particular list
then we've got the up command and the down command
and the idea is that it will take a list item either up
or down and that ideally you should be able to give the
item by name or if it's a long name you don't want to type that in
hopefully they're numbered and you can just say move item three
up now at the moment none of these items are numbered we haven't put that in so
we will need to deal with that and that's something that'll come up when we get
down to the guidelines this is just a little bit of extra
context that we want to give to chat gpt when it's
processing a command or anything else within the system
now the last command that would make sense in a to-do list
concept is the idea of having a clear we should be able to clear the items on a
to-do list now there's also a more generic sort of
command that i like to add into all my custom gpt instructions
and that i'm going to call status and the idea of status is more to give
a short synopsis of what's going on in this case we just want to know what
the current list name is because that was the focus list
we also want to show the command names now i don't want it to be a detailed
list of commands i just want a little prompt to remember
add or list or to do so i have this command called status
it will give us information about these commands but we are going to give it a
little bit of extra information either in the guidelines or in the
response so that it's not too verbose now we've completed our list of commands
but i think the last bit just to give a little bit of extra help
is to let chat gpt know how these commands will be called
so we'll just put in a little bit of text before the mall called
command access is by slash command or
command colon i usually use the command colon
we'll hit save on that it should update the visualization
i think it's time to see how all this information gets
built and we can paste it directly into chat gpt i think also
if we look at the add command and the done command
they might be useful to have shortcuts as well that's something you'll do all the
time i'd like to say a colon and then whatever i want to add
or d colon and have that item marked as done
so what i'm going to do is i'm going to add in these two shortcuts
one called a one called d and i'll show you what happens
with the way this gets written in a moment so let's hit save
we'll pop over to this area called request and click on it to get a copy
and move over to chat gpt where we can go to
our custom instructions and that's the old one that we had
all the way up to the help command and we'll just remove that information and
paste in the new information and a couple things to notice
is that when i give it a command help or set or whatever it is
it renders it as text in uppercase now chat gpt doesn't really need this but
it does help me to see where the commands are
one of the other things that you can see in here is when i had the shortcuts
it's just put a little pipe symbol with the letter a pipe symbol with the letter
d now we may need to give a little bit extra guidelines on what that means
hopefully it'll understand that d means done
but i think we do need to give it additional instructions
but as a short test let's just hit save on this
and we better create a new chat it won't
affect the current chat so we do need a new one
and we'll just type help and see what happens now i can do it with the colon
actually because we did mention slash help let's try that one
instead i'm here to maintain to do this we've got help
set add done list to do up and down it's also put the slash t
so i think we might just try and set it and we'll just go add and we'll say food
and we will put in apples and we'll see what happens try a on its own this time
and we'll say food and we'll say orange while sat's happening we'll type a and
the next one i do i won't do the word food instead i'll just say apple pie
and we'll see whether we get three items all on a food list
now it's added it to the current list so we've got a command up here called
list which will show out to do list we have one called to do which will show
out to do items so we'll just try list and see what
happens that's great to do should in this case
do the same thing the list command didn't work the way i wanted
and this is going to make sense once we start looking at the
response area of chat gpt in that i want to format
the list of to-do lists different to the list of to-do items could test out more
of the commands but i do want to finish this off and then we'll just run
everything through it when we were doing the request and the request is
processing of incoming prompts i have four different sections i have the role
it said to do app i have an overview you will maintain my lists
i have a bunch of commands that are all listed here
and lastly i have guidelines this could be in any order generally but it reads
like any document and most documents have a structure
from the top to the bottom and i want the guidelines to happen
after it understands what the overview of the command is
and the list of the commands that's got available
then any extra context that i want to add in
i'll put into the guidelines all of this is for the request
then we'll look at the response but let's look at what we could do
for some guidelines coming back to our custom instruction language here we'll
move over and have a look at the guidelines and the first guideline we'll add
is that it assigns numbers to each list item as we go by
because really i want to be able to once i've got oranges added
and then apples if i want apples to be above oranges
i just want to say up to i don't want to have to type in apples
so we've just tiled chat gpt to assign each item a number
and to be able to refer to that and that also fits in well with these
little command variables that we're putting here called number
earlier we gave this little question mark here for a parameter to be optional
but what we haven't said is that when the name
is optional what does that mean like where does it focus
so we can add another guideline and what we'll do is we'll go with
name question mark is optional so we're just reinforcing that statement
if i don't give you a name you should use the current list
the next thing that i would like to be able to support is the idea of day we
said earlier that there was this day variable but what does that mean
if you see day monday tuesday wednesday put it
into a day of week column now one of the things that we haven't
talked about is what columns are going to be on this to-do list
at the moment we've given it a bit of an instruction that says
there might be a day column but we don't need to do that every time
either now i'll just save this and we should have our guidelines up to date
now let's take all this information that we've
got for our request and we'll click on this button here
what we can do is head over to chat gpt and come back to the custom instruction
we'll clear everything out that was here and paste in our new section
which is going to have the guidelines and it might be time now to talk about
what a response is if you've written any prompts
you know that it takes your information your request
and it converts it into some sort of document that it returns
now if you gave it say an email or an article
you could say can you summarize it but more importantly you could say
can you put it into bullet points and i don't want any bullet point to be more
than say 10 characters long or you could give it a
list of bullet points and say can you give me a paragraph
30 words long per bullet point and it knows how to do this
and this is the idea of the respond field
we've moved into this response area of the instruction
and there'll be similarities to the commands
plus the normal guidelines so what we'll do is we'll add in
a responder called list and we're basically saying
display to-do list names and number of tasks in a table format
now let's look at what we would do for the to-do items
that would be display to-do list items in table format
with numbers and checkboxes now something that you
do can either be done or not done and this is where the checkbox could be
important and i have a couple more statements
here the done if we mark something is done i may
only give the first one or two letters from the word
so if we've got something like salsa and bachata salsa starts with an
essay bachata starts with a ba there's no ambiguity between them
so we should be able to just say done ba and hopefully the bachata gets removed
also with the status the idea of a status for me is really just tell me the
current context that we're in such as what is the
current to-do list also when i'm looking at help
i either want detailed help and i'll use the help command for that
but the status is more here are just a list of command names that you can
access i'll add a last bit of freeform text
to the response so that every time any command happens
whether it be the add or the to-do we get a status command
now you could call the status command directly but since it's a simple command
that lists the name of the commands that are
available and the current focus list in bold
i would like that to run every time i run any command
so what we'll do is we'll say show status after each command
except for help we don't need to do it for help because help is already a
detailed help list with the current focus
list being shown so it's only for all other commands
and before we finish this off i might also make
an additional change to the guidelines here
what i haven't really talked about is the shape of the data
and in programming or databases this is often called a schema
so what we'll do is add this section to the guidelines
called schema now the word schema means a lot to database people
programmers stuff like that and it will mean something to chat gpt
so i don't really need to describe what it means
but i do need to follow it up with the schema and i'm basically saying that
for the list item i want to show the list name
and the task count so how many tasks are in that list
and for the to-do list i want to show the task name
the day of week because we did have support for days
and a completed task and i think i need one more statement here in the guideline
i need to handle right at the very beginning
when i haven't set a current focus list but i'm adding one
that it goes okay if you're adding one and you don't currently have any list
maybe we should set that so we'll just paste this in
if list name is not provided for add done to do up or down
then act against the current focus list you can set the current focus list if it
is not set with the add command so we'll hit save on this
and now we have a little bit more complete set of guidelines for incoming prompts
and we have how we would like to respond either for individual commands
or for commands in general what we'll do now is we'll come down to this response
we'll click on this we'll head over to chat gpt we're in the custom instructions
now i've made sure that this has been updated with the schema
and we'll head over to the response we'll add in all this information we can hit save
and start a brand new chat again we'll reduce this
and i think we can do a rapid fire run at this so
let's type in help with a slash at the beginning could be done with a colon as
well and we'll see what happens now this is looking pretty good the
role is i'm your to-do app responsible for maintaining to do this
we've got a list of commands that are all set up
talks about how it works and that currently there is no current focus
this set let's just see what happens if we add an item
so i'm going to add in dance and we'll try bachata and press enter
it's about to add the next item now it's said default list so it hasn't
worked on the idea that it's bachata i'd like to see what this does so we'll do
dance and we'll say salsa and currently it still thinks we have a default list
so i'm just going to try the list command and see what we get here default
and it's called to now one of the things we haven't done
is given a rename list command but that shouldn't matter this should work so
i'm just going to say rename list default to dance
and we'll see whether this works we'll try an l colon and now we have a list
called dance and it has two items in it now to go to our grocery or our third
list i think we'll use the set command this time so we'll say set food if we do
an l colon we probably get two list items one with zero entries which is what we
got so i think we'll add some food and we'll say add
food we'll say apple like that and we'll start writing the next one food
we'll say orange now we shouldn't need to add in food each time so let's try add
and we'll say steak and we'll do a list we can use the alias we in the past but
we'll use the full command name now we'll say list and we have three food items
and we have two dance items now currently the focus list is food
if we do the to do command it should give us the three items
out of the third list so let's just type to do
three items are coming down none of them are completed
so maybe we can do that so we'll say done to
remember that we had support for numbers we do not have to
say the whole word we'll say to do
and it's done it's not on the list anymore now we haven't built in any
commands to show stuff that are done we could do that
it may also just work if we wrote the right sort of prompt
but so far this is working the way that i've instructed it
in the custom instruction now one of the things i noticed is it's not giving us
a list of the command names involved so there could be a little bit of tweaking
that i need to do to the custom instruction we might just try the status
command and see whether that gives us extra information
it's not telling us the list of commands available we could do that via help of
course so this is where we can see the commands available
it states here that show command names
in the current and the current list name so it should have happened
when i've tested this in the past it does but this just means that the custom
instruction needs a little bit more tweaking let's try another thing
we're currently on the third list i'm going to do the dance list again
and tonight it's a sunday afternoon and i'm about to go and do
so what we'll do is we'll say add to dance
we'll say zooc and it's a sunday so we'll just say on sun and we'll see what
happens it said add zooc to dance list for sunday
and it's also changed the list so now when we do it to do
it's gonna try a command that i haven't written so we'll say
change list we'll call it dance and then we'll type in
to do and it's got it right so sometimes
like all chat gpt stuff it doesn't do exactly what you've
asked it to do but a little bit of tweaking we gave it a
change focus of list it worked when it returned the information it added it to
the day of week since this item is actually meant to be done
now might just use the up command and in the past we used a number let's see
what happens if i do zo it says it's moved it up the list
generally this is working the way we need we've used custom instructions in chat
gpt to manage how to do this using a command structure
and i think the important takeaway is that you can recreate these
command structures for any sort of actor or agent
that you're trying to create within chat gpt if you want to see more videos on
custom instructions in gpt check out one of the videos over here
my name's david and this has been an apicast