Now we're nearly at the end and about to demonstrate this system all working. So
the 3.4 planning document ended up getting a fair few changes. This became a little
bit of a conversation to deal with different issues. So the first thing we did was
we added in the light mode, dark mode, and that's working. We've got an activity
slide out panel that's actually working really well. Clicks happen everywhere. It's
all using socket io.
It had nice status checks, some when files are added, deleted, updated.
When I went to use the system, there were a number of issues just with the system
prompt. So I kept feeding the conversations back in and asking it to update the system.
Prompt. It now works really well.
And so now I've set it up for four different demonstrations. Now there's only two
in the video.
The first one is the little example at the beginning of the video is essentially
based off these prompts here.
And the full session that we're about to demonstrate
is the creation of the bookstore. And we can see all the prompts that we're about
to run.
Now we have our chat application created using the Bmad method. It's got the clawed
SDK as a backend. Some of the capabilities is that at the moment we're seeing no
pages, but as we add pages, they'll appear automatically.
There's also an activity log showing every file coming through. So if we just start
off with our first creation, we're going to create five bookstore products. We've
set the prices. One of them is out of stock,
Now it's created a file and automatically created products.json, we can see five
products created here.
Next, we'll create a products HTML file. Now as that comes through, it should automatically
update this to show one product, at which point we'll be able to click on it and
see a menu.
So we'll go and add a few more products and if we pop up the website, hopefully we're
going to see it dynamically low because of the socket connection, which means that
any updates on the server will automatically come through to the client. We're seeing
that right there.
If we don't like the style, we can ask for it to create a product CSS file. This
is going to go with a professional blue and gold color scheme. Now this probably
won't update the HTML because we're only asking for it to create the CSS at the moment
and nothing has updated. So we'll just say update the products. HTML sell. It uses
the CSS. While we're doing that, we'll have a look at what it's created. So we've
got a bunch of CSS created right here and it's just started writing the file. And
a refresh is showing the blue and gold coming through on the website.
Now there's a little homepage. If we click on that, we are going to get a file not
found.
So what we'll do is we'll come back to our chat client and put in create a HTML file.
This is the index. We also wanna feature a few products on the front page.
So let's bring up our page and we'll click on the home, see what we get, and we've
got a shop now and a chat with us, and it looks like we've got some featured products
on the beginning. Let's go back to shop now, and we're taken back to the products.
At this point, it might be useful to create some blog posts. So we'll start with
a little bit of data
and we can see that it's creating it with a title, offer, date, content,
and tag.
So it's very much related to the bookstore. If we click on the blog posts, we can
see the information coming through here and here.
So we'll create a HTML page. We're making sure we're using the sockets. We bring
up the page
that started writing the page.
Now I think it's created the blog page, but when we look, there's no link on
the products. There's no link on the homepage. So what we'll do is we'll just jot
down and put in a,
Can you add a link on the home and at the products page? If we click through,
we can read our blog articles here. This looks good. We will click on home, we'll
come back to the products, and we've got the blog here as well.
So the three articles, we've got Golden Age of Reading, building your Personal Library,
and we've got philosophy in pages. Let's go and add another blog post to the blog.json.
It's in the middle of writing.
And we have creating your home library.
So at that point, it might be good to think about, it's coming up to Christmas. Can
we have a design that makes sense? So we'll apply a Christmas styling to the product
CSS with snow for animation,
and festive red green colors.
it's started to come through.
There's styling bugs, and we can't currently click on the blog post.
if we go over to the blog, we can see the tinsel coming through here. One thing you
might notice though, is that there were a number of attempts to get this working.
So we started with apply Christmas styling to the product CSS
and had to follow it up with five different prompts to get it working across all
the different pages.
It had a recommendation to go with scalable veto graphics. So that was the recommendation
we went through.
I.
Now since it's Christmas, I think we should take the sold out item and do an article
about promoting some of it. So we'll write a blog post announcing that there's a
special that the product has gone from $32 to $22, but there's only 10 left.
Now the article has been written, but we better go and update the products so that
it's in stock and we have a price for it. We'll click on products,
and this is the product that we're looking to see change.
And there it is. It's changed through. It might be useful to change the color as
well. We're
just asking for it to be highlighted at the moment.
And there's our holiday special, slightly misaligned, but we'll leave that for now.
And
Let's make sure the homepage has a product for the
holiday special exclusive, and we should be able to view it in the catalog.
So that brings us to the end. And what we've been able to do is build this complete
application just with natural language prompts. And we did that using context engineering.
That's with the BMAD method. And the back end system that we've built is using the
Claude Agent SDK. So this is giving us all the power of claude code within our own
web applications. So the demonstrations we did was that we were able to create HTML
pages, JSON documents, CSS files, make sure all the links go from page to page.
Now all the code is available.
you can check it out in the repository. And if you want to join the community, we
have more of a discussion and teachings each day on prompt engineering.
Now, if you're loving the power of BMAD in the next video, we're going to use BMAD
Again. But this time we're going to recreate an orchestration framework, just like
BMAD. We're going to call it POEM, which is the prompt orchestration and engineering
method. And the whole idea of it is so that we can create and test prompts in a technique
very similar toBMAD. I'm AppyDave, I'll see you in the next video.