Imagine building a self editing application. What that means is that you could talk
to it and it generates all the data in the back end, or you could ask it to visualize
it on HTML pages suddenly materialized. In this video we're going to use the Agent
SDK from Claude Code to do that. And we're going to build this application using
the BMAD method. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Now this video is a step by step tutorial, so if you want to move ahead or go backwards
and forwards, check out the chapter links in the description.
Now, what we're building today is this self editing application. We're going to use
the Claude Agent SDK and the BMAD method.
Now, if this all works, what we'll be demonstrating is the idea of creating a bunch
of products, building out a product listing, maybe even a details page for it, adding
a home page, making some of those products featured, and then adding more products
along the way.
Now. The magic of a self editing application is firstly this human experience. So
we'll be able to talk to the computer, have it generate features, have it generate
data and we'll be doing that using vibe coding sort of techniques.
But the technical reality of this is that we're going to use context engineering
using the BMAD method, and tools like the Agent SDK to make this application a reality.
Now let's just talk a little bit about the planning ahead of time. So I've already
got a planning folder in place for what we're going to do. I've got some preliminary
tech stack stuff, but I wanna run all of this through the BMAD method. Now, which
version
of the BMAD method should we use?
Should we use version four, which is the current, or should we use the version six
alpha nine. Now I tried a video yesterday on alpha eight and I don't
particularly believe it's ready for use just yet for this sort of project. So we
are going to work with version four,
and that means what we're going to do is use this command here, NPX BMAD Method in
install. If you do want to use the version six, it's all available
now the problems I ran into with version six, I've already communicated with Brian
from BMAD and he's aware of it and he's talking through the changes that are coming
in place related to those issues. But for today, we'll keep it simple and work with
version four.
Now in the repo that we're building all this, which is 007 BMAD Claude SDK, you can
go to the bottom and find the links. So here's the link to the version for Bmad.
And if you scroll down a little bit we'll go and select our starting command. With
that selected we can go over to
our terminal. And I've already got some pages here.
the readme that you were just seeing is in here at that location. And I've got a
planning phase in my documents directory already,
so we've cleared the screen and putting in the npx bmad-method install. And that's
going to walk us through a wizard.
So let's work through step by step. And the first thing is the folder. Now it's opened
it up to an empty directory. So what I'm going to do is put in the directory where
we're building this application today. After that it's talking about different frameworks
of BMAD that we can install. This all changes a fair bit in version six. We've got
better game set up in that particular version. For now, we'll just go with the agile
core in version four. When it comes to the PRD product requirements document and
the architecture document, you can shard the files, meaning that they can be split
up into individual files after generation. This changes a little bit in version six,
but for today we'll say yes.
And then you can decide on what agent coding system you're going to use. I'm using
Claude Code. So we'll just select that.
And in this example we're not going to use Gemini or Codex. So I'm going to say no
to those models.
Now it started off with this idea of reading the user guide. So we'll take a copy
of that and head over to Visual Studio. Now let's have a look at what I already had
in place. So I already have a docs folder with just this planning directory. So there's
a fair bit of spikes and examples of how this application could work. We'll draw
on that when we are building our product brief. We've got a Claude file in place.
We've
got our Claude sub folder, and you'll notice that there's a area called Command.
So all the BMAD methods have been set up within this area.
And then the rest of BMAD is in the BMAD core, where we've got different workflows,
teams, templates for working through checklists. We've got our agents and we've got
this little user guide that it told us to read. So let's pop that up.
We've gotta use the guide for the Greenfield project. So this is a brand new project.
Brownfield is for if you've already got an existing code base. And we can start with
a project idea.
we've got an optional analyst research. Now we don't need that because I've already
done all the planning, but we might just work through it temporarily to see what
it does. Then we've gotta build the brief. So with the brief, we're doing the product
requirements document. We'll do a bit of UX design, we'll do a little bit of architecture
design, and then at the end we'll make it all cohesive
And with the cohesion in place, that's when we'll start using a scrub master to design
stories and a developer to actually create the code for those stories.
So let's start with our terminal and we're going to use Claude Code. And I'm going
to run it with the dangerously skipped permissions.
Now it's fresh context. And we've just added a lot of context from Claude. So I'm
just going to run an init on this. I'm going to give it a little bit of extra information.
We've got this planning folder, but I don't want it to take too much over with the
Claude file. I want it to be referenced. I want it to maybe use it as a guideline
for what the project will be about.
But the main focus of Claude should be on the BMAD method and whatever it decides
to create.
So with those two statements, what we can see is that we're improving the Claude
MD to prioritize the BMAD workflow. So what is Claude md? That's essentially the
system prompt. So it's available every time we do a prompt that anything in this
file will be used and we want it to be hyper-focused on what it does.
So anything in red has been removed, and that's a lot of the stuff that I did in
pre-planning before this video.
We can see that my folder hierarchy that does exist has been removed from the system
prompt, but the important stuff that it's a self editing application is in place
that the core of the server should only be about 200 lines of code.
It's got a very clean understanding of what the BMAD workflow is. So we've got the
workflow primary path. We've got step one, which is installation. Now we've already
done that. We've got step two, which will be the analyst agent doing a workflow-init
and it just keeps going, doing this hyper-focused system prompt.
So we'll start off by having a fresh version of Claude and we'll put in a slash command.
And the one we're going to go with is analyst and Analyst will load up Mary. Now
there's a lot of things that Mary can do for this session. Mostly we're going to
focus on creating a project brief,
but she's one of these agents that you can spend a long time in just doing all sorts
of planning and research.
So we just go back to Claude Code and we'll have create a project brief by reading
an existing document. And if we put in the @ sign, we can start putting in Project
Reference and we'll select it and we'll see what she can do with that particular
document.
So the Create Project Brief is going to read from our project reference.
And what it does is it uses commands like the Create Doc, which is based on a template
already in the BMAD call.
And for this we're going to work in the interactive mode. So we'll just press one.
YOLO would be the fast way to do it and with my project documentation it could just
work out perfectly, but I wanna be pretty sure with this.
So notice that the output file is going to be dots brief and we can see that it's
working through many to do's
Currently it's written the executive summary for it
and I've read it through, it's all pretty perfect. I think the target market says
it all. It's developers learning ai, agent integration and self-modifying systems.
It's for technical educators. That's what I do where I want to generate systems that
are a bit flexible and dynamic pretty quickly.
that's also rapid prototyping. That's what we're doing today. And then we've got
the BMAD method practitioners. Now one thing is to know that I, I'll be testing this
with version six BMAD
And if there is anything you want me to test it with, let me know in the comments
below.
But for now we'll just proceed to the next section.
and the good thing is it started writing the briefs. So we'll just bring up Visual
Studio and click on this file here. And so as it goes, we can keep track of what's
going on the left hand side,
But let's have a look at this problem statement that it's come up with.
So reading through the problem statement, everything's pretty good. One of the things
I notice is the database. This is where this application will be a little different
to a lot of applications. It won't have
a database. Instead it's just going to have JSON documents, JSON. They're gonna be
stored in the server and for saving them,
it's just going to be committed to a repository. Now this is not a normal application
that you would run in the cloud I guess,
But for me it allows me to rapidly create tools that I use locally on my computer
through a web interface. So I think we can just move on to the next section. And
what it'll start doing is writing an updated brief. We should see it pop in below,
it's updating so we can see a whole new green section. And here it is listed in the
markdown document.
Now if there was anything out of whack with it, rather than using Claude to change
it, you might just manually come in and alter the document here to have
to rectify any flaws that you notice.
It's important also that you do rectify flaws because these propagate through. If
you fix it now you have less issues in the future.
So the next area we're going to work on is the proposed
solution section.
So it's written the proposed solution. If we go over and have a look, we can see
that it's going to use an express JavaScript server.
embedded into it will be a clawed agent, SDK backend.
Some of the tools that we'll have is the ability to read and write JSON files and
also to write HTML files.
The main front end technology is that we'll use React. We have socket io so that
we can stream information live and we are going to use BMAD method version four
there's also a little note here about using Shad CN for the user interface. We might
also use the vercel AI elements
Now the backend is meant to be simple, just about 200 lines of code. And one of the
key requirements is that I can just use it with my max account from Claude. I don't
need to go and pay any API costs with this particular tool.
Now while that's been happening in the background, it's been setting up the target
users. We'll get it to start writing that brief for us. Once it's done, the target
users section, it should move on automatically to the goals and success metrics.
All I've had to do each time is basically say the next number for it to save the
file.
So the target users have been updated, it should go directly into the next area.
But if we have a look at the target users, we can see that it's a learning system
for developers.
but I would argue that it's for anyone that wants to learn Context engineering, which
is partly about building applications, but it's about building any system in a business
or in your personal workflows.
This is also an area that you could
pull out,
because I think anyone should be able to learn this. One of the things about what
we're doing is that we're not writing any code ourselves. Everything is just understanding
a little bit of architecture following a plan and using natural language processes
the entire way.
So now it's about to create the goals and success metrics. We've already written
all the target user information, it reads the brief each time does what it needs
to do, and then writes the brief again. And you might be wondering, well what does
it need to do? How does it know to do that? And this is just one of the internal
mechanisms of the BMAD method.
So now the KPIs or the key performance indicators have been updated. We can go look
at it while we move on to the next section. One of the things I would suggest is
in this case, they're not that useful for me. I don't really care about these numbers
here. Thousand developers, clonal Fork, the repository not important to me.
content amplification if people use it, I'd be really happy about that.
I guess if anything was important is that people are using a sound content engineering
system, which is BMAD method
but quite frankly, this section is a bit of fluff today for us. But the next area
is really important and this is the minimum viable product.
And so as a must have, it's working on the idea of it having three epics. Now, this
is not normal by the way. This is not the normal area to put in epics. Usually we
do that after we've done the architecture and the PRD and it comes later. But I put
this specifically into my planning documents 'cause I'm thinking of this as a simple
application with three different areas that we need to do. We need a foundation that's
the server, the client, it just needs to be set up after that. The backend is the
main area that we wanna work on.
for the Claude agent SDK implementation, I've already done what's called a core loop
or the event loop,
uh,
documentation.
And essentially this is just a human readable list.
It should work no matter what target language this system is built for. Now we are
going for JavaScript and so hopefully that'll translate pretty readily. And then
the third area is that we're going to have a beautiful user interface. So this is
basically using the Versal and Shad CN and Tailwind CSS and just getting it to talk
to the backend with streams.
And as that information hits the SDK perform, any data creation or webpage designs
as we go.
And the next section of the MVP is what not to do. So we don't need a database. We
don't need multi-tenancy multi-user. We don't need authentication or authorization.
We don't need model context protocol. Good thing about using BMAD is that I've used
it for enterprise applications really effectively. So it can do all of these, but
we're keeping it out of the example.
So after that, we are going to build the
post MVP or the post minimum viable product vision. And we can see that it's already
come up with most of that. It's got different tools that we might want to add later
on.
And additional areas like multi-agent workflows,
production release. Now, quite frankly, I could maybe delete all of the s and b happy
because I'm not planning to go further with this particular project. It's going to
be the foundation for other tools that you'll see me creating using the BMAD method.
So it's gone off and now thought about the technical considerations. They've all
been set up. It feels that we need to use React version 19.
And if we look at it in the markdown, it's typescript , Vite and ShadCN,
tailwind, CSS,
And this is all for the front end. If we look a bit further, we've got the back end,
which is an express server. We've got an installation of the agent SDK planned. We
are going to communicate between the two systems with socket io and we're running
it on node for our database. It's just going to be some Jason documents in the data
directory future. We could use the database if we like. And the hosting is, it's
just planned to run on local host.
So with that, we can go and look at the next section. It's currently working on the
constraints and assumptions. So this was a big thing for me. Is it going to cost
me anything? No, I want it to hook into
my max account, and that should be how it works. Develop a time, 40 to 60 hours for
the MVP.
let's go and look at the risk and open question.
And this is really useful. I've never done the agent SDK, so it is a dependency with
high risk for me when I'm doing this video.
the constraint, I think
that the statement here could be true, but I, I don't think it matters.
it's not that I have to do it in 200 lines of code, it's just that I don't want it
to be complex. That's kind of why I'm doing the constraint.
I will talk about this section briefly.
I took out a section called the BMAD,
quality Gates. What I wanted to have happen is that rather than pure vibe coding
where the user says, I would like a new homepage, I wanted it to actually create
a BMAD story on the backend. Now I think for this demonstration, it's maybe a reach
goal. Maybe we'll do it. But this would be a really powerful idea that users could
just sit on the front end and say, I want a new capability. And BMAD at the other
end. Here's that and says, well, let me create a story for you and then the developer
can go off and create it. But for today, I've taken it out.
So that's the docs brief finish. You notice it's now saying to go on to the next
agent. It's got everything written. What we are going to do is exit out. 'cause what
I'd like to do is have a clean context the next time we start. But while we're looking
at that, let's just see what that last section was. So we've got the next step. Immediate
action is we're going to create the product requirements document. We're gonna do
that by loading the project manager agent and running the create PRD command.
Let's also look at what we've got in our system. So everything that you see on the
left in planning is stuff I've done ahead of time. So the only one document we have
in the system specifically created by BMAD is the brief.
Now I'll just take a moment out to suggest that if you want a little bit more handholding
or just seeing day-to-day operations on using the BMAD method context engineering
to produce applications or other sorts of business systems, then you might wanna
check the link in the description where you can go to my SKOOL community where I'll
be talking about this on a day by day basis.
But next, let's go and look at creating this PRD. Now, to do that, we're going
to have a new agent. And the agent we want is the project manager. So we load the
project manager in with the slash pm command,
and John comes into existence with a whole lot of capabilities. Now the one we want
is the star create PRD. So we just paste that in and let's see what comes up. And
you notice that the way BMAD works is it works with context documents. So we've got
the Create Doc md. There was also a template going on,
which we can see here, and a bit of configuration YAML now in version six. A lot
of this stuff still happens similarly, but they've made it a lot more flexible.
Now, you may notice when you start with a clean Claude Code is that the context is
empty and so certain things it doesn't know about. So this idea of do you have a
project brief which we just worked on is something it doesn't currently know about.
So I'm just going to put in one. That's what we want to do. And I'll put in the @
sign and start typing brief and we'll just press enter. So it'll use that as loaded
context.
So it's read in the brief. I've read it. Everything seems okay to me. So I'm just
going to press one and continue on that.
Notice as it goes, it creates a change log. So we've got version one, which is the
initial PRD created from the project brief.
And now we get into the hearts of what a product requirements document is. We're
coming up with the functional requirements as we go. So FR one would be the first
functional requirement.
So it's listing all the basic capabilities that this application is going to do.
And then after that it does the non-functional requirements,
which is all abstractions or ideas that the system's going to work on, such as the
line limit on the server. The fact that we're going to use CLAUDE Auth to log into
the system.
Now, like with the interactive mode with product brief, we could just move on to
the next section, but it's got a couple of areas needing validation. Is 200 lines
realistic and should we have prebuilt examples? So I'm just going to make a simple
adjustment here that says the 200 is a suggestion. What I'm trying to do is have
the actual event loop of the agent be fairly small and contained. There's not a lot
that you need to do there, but this is a guideline. It's not a limit at all. What
I wanted to ensure that it does is not create complex structures as it builds out
this system. 'cause there's nothing complex about the Claude Code event loop.
the other thing I wanted to talk about is this area of, should we have a prebuilt
example application? No, we shouldn't. This is all vibe coding
that we're going to ask people to do, but we may actually create some examples later
on. So we'll just press a enter on that.
And so the functional requirements have been updated. We've removed a concept and
we've done slight updates. And so this is a lot more important than in the brief
to get this right. So we'll move on to the next step. But the idea is that this is
what's actually going to get built.
Now the user interface design guides have come through. I've read through all of
this and most of it was good except there was one area and probably the core area,
which is the screens. And this is not working the way I'm thinking. So the first
thing it says is chat interface, primary screen, full height, chat with message,
history, input field streaming indicator and example starters. Love
that. That is the only thing that I saw this initial application having. It's then
got concept of a status panel shows active story, recent file operations, quality
gate
status. Now that's more complexity than I need.
My thoughts were that as soon as you started typing stuff in here,
You could generate HTML in the back end. And now that doesn't necessarily mean the
menus would work, but the actual pages should work.
I had a plan for this particular application that BMAD stories would get generated.
That's what the quality gates were. But then I've taken it out, made it a future
thing. So if we go to the very bottom, I said, this section here doesn't make sense
anymore.
and then I've said the next two steps, which are these ones down here, which I've
copied from above are too complex and I've given it a little bit more clarity on
what to do. So we'll just run with that again. It's so important in this area that
you actually get it stating exactly what you think you wanna see.
So it's come through red is what it's changing. Green is what it's changing it to.
you can see it's continuing with simplified user interface, but we can also go over
to Visual Studio and have a look at the document like before here in a simple markdown
viewer. So BMAD, Claude self editing application. We've got our functional requirements
kicking into place here, and we can see some of the modifications, like the slash
chat and the slash products as examples. So we go back to our conversation, and this
makes a whole lot more sense. We've got the application presents as a minimal chat
interface.
We know it can generate concepts like products and blogs, even though there may not
be a navigation menu in place.
The one little bit of styling we'll have is that it can do dart mode and light mode.
And so we can move on to the next step. There is one big issue in here, and this
is the issue of anyone using vibe coding, is that this application, when we build
it, will allow us to change our backend server. Now that's both a security issue.
You wouldn't do this on a public website. This is an internal tool, but it means
how do we manage those changes? And I'm assuming in my setup that I'm going to use
Git commit, so I should be able to roll back. But that's not necessarily the most
technically easy thing for people to use. But for this example, that's how I'm planning
to do it.
now here, what it's done is come up with the technical assumptions. They're all based
off the project brief, which is great. I've read through all of them and they're
all very accurate. This is exactly the way I see it happening. But I thought I'd
point out one area. So where did this all come from? It came from something called
the Storyline app.
Now, I think it's important that we look at the storyline application because the
catalyst for building this project was could we generate stories dynamically on the
fly? So if we head over to a web view and we are looking at what is a client and
server sort of system. So currently we are connected to the server and it's using
the same technology we're about to build. And if we go and have a look at our project
files, we've got something called the Boy and the baker. Now the boy and the baker
is a five minute video that we've created. And when you look at it, you can see that
it's the story. And the story starts off with an elderly baker walks into his shop
to see a boy being beaten and bullied by some younger children. So we can see pictures
of this baker along the way. Now if we go and toggle the image display, we can see
that we got an establishing shot. We've also got other versions of the shot available.
So as we move through this story and it goes for five minutes, all of these images
are character consistent, they're theme and style consistent.
And so we build our movie by using the image prompts with tools like DALE-3 and SORA
2. And we use the animation prompts along the way for doing
the animations in Hailou or VOE 3.
the interesting thing is that everything that you're seeing is based off this one
narrative. So we've got a little narrative. It creates setting the ambiance, the
characters, the description. We've got the image prompt and we've got the animation
prompt. And I've been going through and refactoring this so that this is a lot more
deeper. But really I just want to type this into a text box and have all of this
extra information generated for me automatically.
and that's what this application is meant to do. We should just be able to save something
into a text box and have complex data structures form around that information.
So let me give you a glimpse of what the application we're currently building can
be used for. And it's this storyline application that generated this movie. We've
got character consistency, scene consistency, and everything was generated using
Claude Code in the background to generate the data structures. So as we start asking
questions like, can you create three products that will generate complex JSON documents
behind the scene? Well, that's what's happened with the storyline application. But
instead, there's a simple narrative that converts into image and style guides.
Now, if you're interested in seeing the five minute video around The Boy and the
Baker by Voz, then check out the link in the description below.
But for now, let's get back to John, our product manager.
So I just press one to move forward and we've got our epic list and it looks like
there's going to be three epics, which is what I'd suggested it to do anyway, so
we've got the mono repo set up with basic client and server,
NPM workspaces. We're can express server, minimal HTML client.
so that looks good. After that, we're really working on the backend, which is the
agent SDK integration. It's going to have the three tools that it talked about
And then we're gonna polish up the communication with the front end chat interface
here.
So then we've got our sequencing logic. I think the good bit is the story count.
It's listing three to four stories per epic. There isn't a lot of work in each section,
and then it's listed, it's rationale and decisions. I read through that. This all
seems to make sense for me.
So at this point, we've got many stories already set up for different epics.
The first one is Monorepo set up with a client and server. So the basic application
structure for the front end talking to the back end.
Next we have epic number two, which is essentially setting up the Claude Agent SDK
so that it can communicate from server through to the client.
And when you look at the goal, there's also tools included such as talking to JSON
and HTML files.
And the final epic, epic number three is all about building a react front end
and using libraries like Shadchan and Tailwind CSS.
Now if we go back to the top of the epic, we'll see that every story follows a common
formula that's designed for agile development. So firstly, we've got a story number.
So in this case it's 1.1. Then we've got a simple title for what the story is going
to be about. This is initializing, the workspace and the mono repo.
So the idea of a user story is this three part formula that says, as a particular
person using the capability, what do they want to achieve? That's the I want. And
if they did achieve it, what would they get?
then there's an acceptance criteria. So this story is considered complete when all
of these items are checked off.
and this concept's going to repeat through every story in the epic.
So what I'll do now is I'll read through every story headline, and then we'll see
pretty quickly that there may be some flaws in the way that it's come up with. So
the first thing it wants to do in the epic is initialize the npm workspaces and monorepo.
That sounds really good. Then it's going to create an express TypeScript server.
After that, it's going to get a very basic HTML client up and running. And finally
we're just going to have a little bit of an end to end test. And mainly that'll be
worked out by starting both servers and checking the browser logs. Checking the console
logs. So so far epic number one looks pretty good. We'll see if it needs any changes
when we look at the next epic.
So now we're moving on to epic two, which is all about setting up the Anthropic Cloud
SDK. And it talks about let's get it installed. Seems like a good first step. After
that, it's trying to implement one of the tools which is the read JSON. Then it's
going to do the right JSON and the right file. And then after all of that
we're going to integrate socket streaming. And we're going to do it both for the
server. But we're also going to have the chat messages working with this. And then
after that we're going to implement the full event loop. Now it's this particular
epic that I'm having a few challenges with,
and I'll go over what they are soon and how I can change them pretty quickly. But
let's look at the third epic.
Now the third Epic is all about setting up a React application as the front end.
So when we look at 3.1, it's initializing react with VI application. Then 3.2 is
setting up Shad cn, configuring it with Tailwind CSS. After that, we build the chat
interface using the Vercel AI elements.
And lastly, we're just giving it a simple light mode, dark mode. Now we've got all
sorts of rationale being listed. We could move on from there.
But like I said, I think there's a problem in Epic two. And the main issue is, I
can see is that after installing the SDK, it starts going into setting up tools.
But we haven't defined yet where they fit into the event loop. We don't even know
whether the event loop is going to work and communicate correctly with the client.
and so as we work through all the stories in Epic two, we're gonna be pretty blind
to whether they're working until the very end of the epic where it all comes together
in a big avalanche.
So to resolve this problem, I could have a conversation here, but what I find easier
is to just start selecting the context we need.
And what I've done is copied all the way up to when the epic first started. At this
point, I just select that, put in the clipboard.
After that, I just like to open a new conversation, which I've got down below and
I've started it with the statement. I want you to read and absorb the following information
and then wait for me for guidance.
And that complete epic list has been pasted in.
So that new conversation knows what we've got. We've got it highlighted in blue and
I just tell it that you are going to help me build up an instruction that we can
put back into the previous conversation.
So the goal of this conversation is purely to build a prompt to paste into this conversation.
But before we get started, I ask it to do a bitof a Q&A session with me to get clarity
around the problems as I see it.
I tell it that I'm pretty happy with Epic one. I think it's good, but I think there's
stuff that's we're going to talk about in Epic two that will impact it. So I just
prepare it to know that it can change Epic one even though at the moment it's pretty
good.
After that I went through Epic two and each of the stories and I just gave it this
long diatribe. Now I was just dictating directly into the microphone. It was writing
out everything as we go. And so the good thing about this is it can make it more
readable for me. So the first thing it does is start to unpack the issues that I
had addressed.
figured out that stories
2.2, 2.3 and 2.4 can't be properly
verified until we've done the event loop.
It also worked out that the event loop is not a single story. There's both a beginning
and an incremental development of it before it finishes. It identified from my conversation
that what was called story 2.4 was actually two different concepts. One was the streaming
client area, the other was the same streaming client, but specifically for the agent
SDK.
And this also led it to understanding that 1.4 might need some modifications.
Now, because I asked it to do a q and A system, it actually came up with four pretty
solid questions. But one of the things I noticed while reading them was it, it kind
of suggested the answers as it went. So it's a question of is it asking me questions
or does it already have good recommendations and I just need to sign 'em off.
So I just told it that the questions it's asking, I already thought it had the answer,
could you just give me the recommendation? It just saves me a lot more time than
actually engaging in the Q&A.
And so it wrote these recommendations. So the minimum viable event loop after 2.1
becomes this idea of create a basic event loop. And there's no tooling, no streaming,
there's just the fact that it can receive messages fromthe SDK
at the moment, at the end of Epic one, we're just doing HTTP requests, but it thinks
that it might be useful to put in some socket functionality at that point.
It now feels that the event loop that we're building is a bunch of capabilities that
can be done as multiple stories,
And we can move the tools that we want to do into 2.4 to 2.6. And when I look at
that, I realize that even before we move on to Epic three, if I wanna build in other
capabilities like Claude skills, this Epic will be the right way to go.
because it's designed in such a way that each cross-cutting concern or aspect can
be added one at a time later on if needed.
So it's already figured out a much better plan. But remember that the initial part
of this conversation was can you create the instruction for me?
So I just tell it down the bottom here and I'll press enter that. This is perfect.
I love the way it's thinking. What it needs to do is now create those instructions
that we want to put back into the top conversation. And just so you know, that top
conversation is this one that's here. We're going to take whatever's comes out of
this conversation and drop it straight into here to modify it.
So here's our detailed instruction set. We can just go all the way to the bottom
with this. We'll make a copy of it, come up here and paste it in 203 lines of information
just by asking a couple of questions.
So it was already started working on things. One of the interesting things is it's
also playing around with the product requirements document right here.
So the changes we asked for have been implemented. We've got a change to story 1.4
and we've got a whole new re reordering and breaking up of Epic two. And what the
number of stories really tell us is how many development sessions are going to go
on because
We'll get the scrum master and the developer to work on each of the stories sequentially,
starting from one and going through to number 14.
So quickly looking at the PRD, we've got the new Epic list. It's the monorepo set
up, the agents or the server in the backend and the front end client. And then we've
got all the details coming through one story at a time. These are just simple stories.
They'll be converted into full blown stories with the scrum master.
and then add streaming and logging as we go. And then after that we can do the tools
And then finally connect it all up to the React front end.
So with the very complete epic list in place, we'll come back to our conversation
and just move on to the next step, which is the checklist.
So what the checklist has done is just read the PRD. Now this is from a product owner
or a product manager's point of view. So this is all the business cases have been
covered. We haven't yet gone to the tech stack or the software architect's point
of view. That's the next area. But when we look at it, it says it's 92% complete.
There's,
problems with it, but it's mentioned that
the user research area isn't really that relevant for a demonstration like this.
So I won't worry about it. And so everything else has passed except for this area
in the MVP.
So any blockers to moving forward? Well, there's none identified. Are there any high
level issues that we should be aware of? I think this is one we might address, but
we'll do it
asking a recommendation rather than actually taking the time to define it, because
the AI will probably do a better job than me at coming up with an answer anyway.
These medium level issues don't really matter to me. Like the target user doesn't
matter. And the success metrics don't matter in this particular project.
Now my background has been software engineering, software architecture, and even
for a time a scrum master. So these numbers that you're seeing here, the,
23 days to get this application written are legitimate numbers. This is about how
long it would take to do a project like this if you were doing it in an enterprise
system. But at the end of the video, I'll tell you how long it's taken to do the
documentation and to do the coding. So we'll see what numbers really come back. So
I've just dictated a little statement about the outer scope area, like what does
it suggest we put in there? And I've also said that for the logging, I don't want
to use a logging framework, but I wouldn't mind simplistic patterns predefined before
we get started.
And this is perfect. This is just what I didn't want to actually type in myself.
So we're not going to use database and persistent authentication. Authorization isn't
needed. It's not for production testing. Infrastructure is not important in this
process.
advanced features like quality gate hooks, all this sort of stuff was all outta scope
for me.
it doesn't need to be a polished ui though. I hope it'll be pretty good with shad
CN and Tailwind CSS
logging and monitoring is also really good. It's come up with just a simple JavaScript
logger platform. It's not trying to use libraries or anything like that.
So I'm just asking it to update the PRD with all the changes. The only little change
I mentioned is that the hot module reloading, which is a developer experience,
changes like modifying a bit of code and seeing it updated directly in the client
is a really nice capability to have in the application
So we're all complete with our PRD.
at this point it's suggesting that we hand off to the architect. We could do it in
this conversation, but what we'll do is we'll just exit out a Claude and
and start a new Claude session because we wanna have a clean context to get up and
running with the architecture.
Now I just wanna point out some basic maintenance that I like to do with working
with Claude. So I've just put in this little prompt here
And the reason is that we've created a brief, we've created a PRD, but my initial
system prompt, or the Claude prompt is pointing to the planning phase of the system.
But now that BMAD method has done these great documents, I want to ensure that my
Claude file knows about them.
And so it's taken some old ideas, like the planning documents and the BMAD execution
guide, which are, now, this one's not relevant anymore, and this one's just lower
priority. So it said, we've got the brief, we've got the PRD, and then we've got
the planning guide.
Now a lot of changes being made, but if we go down the bottom and have a look at
the summary, we can see
that our system prompt has a very clear understanding of everything we've done right
now.
one of the other things I noticed is that it knows that the next step is going to
be the architecture. So if we come down and we will clear out again and start with
a new Claude context,
we'll go straight into the architecture agent, let it load,
and we can move into creating things. So we don't need the backend architecture and
front end individually. We just need the full stack architecture.
So we'll just pace that in and kick it off.
So the architect is going to generate our architecture at this location.
in the dots folder, it's read the project brief, it's read the PRD.
We have a basic introduction and it's worked out for
starter templates that while it's based on a different idea, there is no starter
template.
So for us, it's just going to put in a change log and
we can move on to the next section, which is the main architecture.
So it's written out a lot of information.
I've read through it all. It's pretty much just restating a lot of the stuff we've
already got. We've got a technical summary, we've got the platform and infrastructure.
One of the things that it notices is
that for an MVP,
we don't need any complexities like a platform or infrastructure service approach.
We've got some sort of interesting graph that's going to show up in our markdown
document
and a list of the architecture patterns and the rationale. At that point, we can
just move on to the next section, which is building the tech stack.
So it currently has a written the mark down documents. A lot of this is a little
unreadable, but we've got the full tech stack table going on
and again, we've got rationale summary, including the key technology choices. We've
got the trade offs of not having concepts like caching and the database we are going
to use,
version P pinning. So it should be recording what version it's on, like react 19.
And these ideas could be important if we're using an MCP to go and get documentation
around react or express. It needs to know what version to work with. Now if you are
actually coming from a point of view where you don't fully understand all the terminology
going on, remember there are other ways that you can deal with this documentation.
So you can use chain of thought, all sorts of q and a sort of stuff. I understand
generally the technology going on, so I'm just pressing one to move forward.
So now it gets into the data models, and this is just a transport or usage of data
in the system. So the first idea of the chat interface and the fact that it might
have a ID such as the user or the AI bot.
content and status. This is all great. The only thing I'm a little concerned about
is does it match with the Vercel AI elements?
got a section, the tool calling, so the reading of the Jason, writing of the Jason,
and then just messaging between client and server.
So it's only identified three different objects that we need, the chat message tool
call and the socket event. So with that, I'm just gonna move forward.
So we can now just move on to the API specification. The only thing I was looking
at here, which I thought interesting, is that we are using this bio directional communication
pattern. Now, I don't know how much I'm going to be changing specifically on the
server that I need to send back to the client
because I know this was based off a different application, the storyline app that
I talked about, where a lot of that would happen. But I think this will work pretty
cleanly.
So now it's just working out all the different components where it thinks the files
are going to be as it builds out the application. One of the interesting things about
doing it this way is that when we go back and look at the PRD,
we may find out that the order of doing things, which the PRD will list might be
in conflict with some of the architecture decisions.
Now in version six of the BMAD method, they deal with that with a section called
solutioning. I don't think it existed in version four. So we'll deal with that ourselves
when we get to it.
We can also see here that there's a big component diagram being created that we can
go and look at a bit later.
so it's pretty good. It's come up with the idea that there's a data directory and
that's where it's going to put JSON documents based on the ideas I've already told
it about.
It's got the concept of products,
it's got the concept of blog posts, maybe it needs some configuration. So if we needed
to do a homepage and it had a logo or a theme, that's where that sort of information
could go.
It's given a sample file structure talking about the idea that files should be in
kebab case and that it's essentially just an array of JSON objects.
Though we can see with that one that that's more just a general object.
Now there's no schema validation. So this system could be brittle or fragile in the
real world, but I think for the use cases we're doing, it'll work pretty well.
And if we did want a more strict
rules system, we could introduce something like Zod or some sort of schema to make
sure that any data being written or read from always follows a certain format.
So we'll just move on to the next area. One of the things we can see here from our
trade-offs is that this is not designed for big systems.
is really just a little internal tool that I want to use it for at the moment.
So it's come up with a plan for our front end components. We've got the chat interface,
we've got some generic UI controls. We've got the idea of the sockets.
It'll just be a single page application, no router involved,
and a bunch of static HTML pages. I think the big issue we might have there is keeping
style consistency when we generate things and we haven't catered for that, but we'll
see how it goes when we start running the application.
So plenty more examples coming through.
So we're nearly done with the architecture. We've just put in the system backend.
We've got the agents, how they're all going to work. We've got the tools that we
need to work with a couple of utilities, plenty of example code coming through,
more diagrams being added to the system.
so we can see here it's going to have a native NPM workspace.
we're going to have three packages. So we've got the server client and the shared
types going on.
Now the full workflow from the command line has been listed.
got node NPM, we've got the Claude Auth.
This will allow us to hook up our agent SDK to our local Cluade account.
It plans to have a single line to get it all up and running, just NPM Run Dev. We'll
start both the server and the client. And now we're onto the remaining sections.
So we've got the deployment strategy coming through.
We've got a continuous integration, continuous development pipeline, but it's very
empty. There's nothing really going on just yet.
Conversations about environment, we've got security coming through, we've got performance
metrics, we've got
all the testing approaches just documented as future. They're not in place just yet,
but we do have sample code of what it could look like in the future.
and then we've got the error handling strategy. We've got a diagram and we've got
sample codes to work with that.
Now we've got a two and a half thousand line document created. It's quite extensive.
If we jump over to VS code and look at it, we can see it's got concepts like the
high level architecture. We've got diagrams being generated.
We can see that the plan is for the user to interact with the browser and for that
to talk
to the agent event loop.
The agent event loop should then be doing any tool calling that it needs to do and
returning information. Back to the Chat GPT stream. We've got the ability to write
different files as we go.
Whole lot of architectural patterns. We've got the defined tech stack. Very extensive
data models are defined
and clearly written out using TypeScript.
We've got the custom tool utilities, which are integrated into the SDK right here.
Then we move into components related to the front end and how it communicates with
the back end
because the shape of data on both the front end, the back end can be the same. We've
got a shared types to transport that data
and then we get a visualization of the components on both the front end and how they
communicate through to the back end. And we can see a little bit of where the shared
components meet.
Now we've got a sequence diagram that's showing us the way data flows through the
system, and this is based on the happy path, meaning what happens when nothing goes
wrong. We've then got examples of the tool invocation. This is the writing of Jason.
Then the error handling workflow. So this is the unhappy workflow.
Now the thing with web sockets is that they can stop working. So we've got a reconnection
workflow coming through
and examples of if I had the product catalog working, what it would all look like,
the writing of the product JSON as an example. Then it talks about database schema.
Well, we don't really have one, but we do have a storage architecture. It's just
going to be files and samples of what in this case, products could look like
blog posts and the configuration for the system and just how the files are going
to be laid out. Then it's documenting what we're not going to have. So we don't have
schema validation. We don't have in-depth and performance,
sorted out. We're not using caching. We'll just,
the data that we store will just be version controlled in GitHub. Then we've got
a full list of what the front end architecture's going to look,
followed by component templates. So when it needs to write a component, it can use
the component template. To start there, we've got the state management architecture
up on the client. So this is the examples of how the client can talk to the backend.
And this has all been listed through here. We've got the routing organization. Now
remember, we don't have a router. This is just a single page application, but we
do have concepts like dealing with static HTML,
and
Then we move on to the backend architecture. We've got the files that are planned
to be created. We've got an example template for what a controller could look like
storing of data. We'll use the repository pattern,
but it'll be file-based persistent. And then we've got authentication and authorization
flows, which is really just the CLUADE authentication for the SDK
kicking in
simple little middleware guard. But generally we don't have any authentication going
on. And then we've got the full unified project coming through right here.
So with all this information done, the next thing to do is just to confirm that our
PRD that we've created is actually going to match with the architecture that we've
got now in version six of BMAD method. They have a section called solutioning, which
takes care of that, but we'll do it manually today.
Now I'm just going to go into the PM and we're just going to ensure that we've still
got alignment between the PRD and the architecture because the PRD was created before
the architecture. So I've just told John the PM to check that the architecture document
and the PRD are in alignment. Main thing I want to ensure is that the PRD is still
in the right order based on the architecture. I also wanna see if any of the stories
or the epics or anything needs to change based on what we did with the architecture.
if you are using version six of the BMAD method, this is called solutioning. It's
just something I tend to do manually
because I found it effective in the past.
So it's finished the alignment with the architecture document. It's listed a bunch
of areas I've read through them all and they're very minor. So I think the main thing
that we can do
is just apply number one, which is the recommendations to the PRD can be applied
right now.
So those minor alignment issues are now being fixed between the PRD and the architecture.
What we're going to do now is change over to the po,
the product owner. And this is because we wanna shard the documents. Now, if I just
jump down to this view here, sharding is the idea of splitting up a big document
into little documents. And a few of the agents can do sharding, but the one that's
designed to do for both architecture and PRDs is the po. And that's why we've jumped
over to there.
And we can see the command here, it's called shard-doc, followed by the document
we wanna work with and the destination that we wanna put it in. So we'll start by
typing in shard-doc and I'll put in the at sign and type in the PRD. And after that
we'll put it into a file that doesn't currently exist, which is why I haven't used
the at sign. It's docs, PRD.
Now, while that's doing that, we'll head over to VS code to see what's going on.
So it's this big document that we've got going on here and we're moving it into this
folder and you can see everything being split up
and there should be a little index that points to where all the different parts of
that file exist. So with that done, we go back and we run the shard-dock again. This
time we're going to click on architecture,
and if we head over, we should get an architecture folder being generated. And we've
got all the indexes pointing to each individual file as well.
Now we're about to get into development, but we should have a look at what our docs
look like. So we have the brief that was generated. We've split the PRD out into
individual files. We've done the same thing for the architecture, but I haven't gotten
rid of those files. So I've moved them into an archive directory, and I've left the
planning document because that's got a lot of detailed files that we can lean on
if we need to at the time of generating the stories.
So now we are ready to start developing our application. So to get started, we need
the scrub master and the scrub master will read through the Epic and create the first
story for us. And that can be done by using this command here called Draft. So what
we'll do is we'll type in draft
and we could say something like Draft first story in this case.
So I've got draft first story from first Epic, and if we go over and have a look
at the Epics list,
The first one is the mono repo set up with the basic server and client.
So we can see it starting to gather architecture context. Here. We've got all the
different documents that we've created
in the architecture folder being read as needed.
It's the ensuring for the first time that we've made the stories directory. Now I've
already done that manually.
Now keep in mind that from the epic point of view, it's only got this basic information
to start with. So it's drawing from that, followed by all the architecture documents.
and we now have our first story in draft mode.
And we can see that it's grabbed from the Epic, the story card and the acceptance
criteria. And from that, it's just developed a bunch of tasks and sub-task to work
with.
It's aware that there's no story to start off with. This is the first one. It accesses
the tech stack. We've got the project structure that it's meant to be creating. We
understand the work space that we're in,
and it's gone and prepared some shared types. So it's grabbing a lot of this information
from the architecture document,
setting up the naming conventions and the coding standards. And it also understands
how to set up the types script configuration. It's filled in an area for testing,
which at the moment we don't have any testing. And so at this point, we could start
doing development. Now the normal flow in an application would be to read through
this and check everything is okay. For now, I'm just going to change this from draft
to ready and hit save. And then we can go back to Claude
where we can start doing our development. Now it needed to be in that ready mode,
so we've done that. So we'll just switch over to the development agent
and we can just type develop story. Now I'm going to put in the 1.1 because it'll
make it easier for it to find the correct document without having to look through
documents.
And now it has a plan of of what it's going to work through. So it's going to set
up our package, Jason, create the workspace directory structure for us, move on to
configuring type script, create the workspace package.json, and
create the shared types. We'll do the .gitignore. And then finally it'll verify that
the mono repo has been set up correctly.
So it's finished developing all the code, it makes a statement that everything is
in place. It's a little bit hard to test because we don't actually have any source
code just yet. But when
the story has been updated with a lot of check boxes of the work that's been done.
When I personally run the
build, I got a couple of errors, but they're actually listed here. So that's okay.
All the files have actually been created. So at that point we can close off this
story.
Now you might notice at the end of the story there's an area for the QA agent. So
what we can do is go back over type in
/qa for the quality assurance agent.
Now, this is not an agent I would normally use in my own projects. What I have a
custom agents more for story acceptance testing and that's about generating a document
for the human to work through and test different things that would be visual in nature.
But for this video, we would use the QA agent and we'll just do a review on 1.1.
I mentioned that I'd normally do a story acceptance test plan. Now that doesn't preclude
doing normal tests as well. So usually when you are developing an application, you
wanna have unit tests.
you might want to have end-to-end tests, but definitely you need some sort of a test
plan at the end of the story that says these are the things that you have to go and
look at.
And in a more complex application. I like it to actually walk me through and say,
first click on this menu, fill in this piece of information. And all of this information
can be derived from a story.
And if it was something I was doing with this project, the way it would look is that
it would create a new file right next to the story. So we've got 1.1 dot story, but
I would have a 1.1.story-SAT.
And in that would be all the guidance and instructions for me to go and visually
check that everything's working.
Now, currently we can see that the QA agent has come in and started to update the
document.
So we now have our overall quality assessment in place. Everything seems to be okay
and one of the interesting statements is this one right here. So it's just talking
about future considerations that'll be important with new stories. Now if we go back
to our VS code, we can see that the story has been updated with all this extra quality
assurance checks.
So with our first story down, we'll do a commit
and we can see that there's all the new configuration and set up for the mono repo.
Plus there's all the architecture PRD and the initial story has been added as well.
We'll set up a new Claude code and the first thing we need to do is make sure we're
on the scrum master
and we'll type in draft story 1.2 and let it go and build that new document for us.
now light before it goes through a template loads in information from the Epic that
we're on story 1.2 loads in all the technical architecture documents
also reads from the previous story so it knows what's already been done.
So story 1.2 has been drafted,
I just had a quick look through the document. So I've set the status to ready, but
we've got our acceptance criteria, we've got all of our subtask in place,
so now it's time to develop. We just go back, I've already set up the development
agent and we'll just type in develop story 1.2 and let it run.
now while that's running, I'll just talk about the idea of working with multiple
projects at once. One of the things I love about BMAD is that if you are generating
two different applications, you've got a fair bit of time while the development is
going on. So you saw what I did, I set up the story, then I switched over to the
developer agent and I kicked it off.
At that point I'll go to another terminal where I've already got BMAD running on
a different project and goes through the same process. Now, personally, I can't do
three projects at a time because usually the first project has finished
and I've gotta go back and manually review it. But the good thing is that you can
be working on two different applications at the same time.
So we'll just come back and have a look at what it's doing and we can see that as
it goes, it's signing off on tasks that it's done and it just keeps working through
them.
So it's finished.
the development, the definition of done has been filled in.
We got some new files. What we'll do is we'll jump over to the quality assurance
agent. So again, we are going through a number of code quality metrics
and we can see a list of the changes that wherever it says this story. And we can
go and have a look at the code over here.
Now, if you're a developer, this is an area that you probably spend a lot of time
looking. I work more as a software architect and so
while it would be smart for me to check all the code, I usually don't check the code.
And that's an interesting thing about this. I've built complete enterprise applications
and I spend more time working on the documentation to check the code quality. Then
I do in actually looking at the code.
Now, the agents I use for that, I'll talk about in future videos. At the moment,
we're just trying to build a simple application.
So all the completion notes have been filled in.
we know the files that have been changed and now the QA has come in. So if we go
and open up QA and look at the Quality Gate number 1.2, we can see a YA L file. On
the changes though, it's a lot easier to see it back in the Claude context window.
Now at this point we could be moving on to 1.3, but I suspect there might be something
in this code that we could test that we can see if it's working. But the problem
is that we don't have a list
that we can check. So I've gone and set myself up a new window. This is a conversation
I have with a second brain.
and the second brain has knowledge about things like BMAD version four and version
six.
And I've had it just construct for me instructions for creating a story acceptance
testing agent.
Now, I'll just point out behind the scenes what's really going on is that if we do
a tree, you can see all the different documents that I've got available on Claude.
So we've got the SDK here, we've got Claude code, we've got skills. And you can also
see stuff on BMAD method. We've got mostly V four, but we've also got information
on V six as well.
and it's through having access to that information plus the project we're working
on that we've been able to build these instructions. So what I'm going to do is just
take all the information down to the bottom
and we'll just go into our current conversation and say, can you create a new agent
for me within the BMAD system? I'm going to paste the information in
so that's coming through, and we'll paste all that information and let it go. Now
if this was version six of BMAD,
you would have access to a system called BMB, which is the BMAD module builder. And
if we go back to our second brain, you can see where I've got that information. There
is this BMB folder that allows you to create agents for different workflow modules.
But because we're in V four, we don't have access to that module. And so I've just
let it come through.
So what I'm going to do is select the command we've got, I've copied it into the
clipboard, and it says that if we run it, we should see some blue timestamp ISO 8 6 0 1
format. So what we'll do is we'll jump over to a terminal, we'll paste it in and
see what happens when we run it. And yet certainly does, we've got some line console
items here.
So the good thing is we can see what the application is meant to do based on what
the story says it should do. Now this is a little bit different to a user acceptance
to test because this will change from story to story. Something that would've been
a UAT in say 1.1 might now be defunct and not useful in 1.3. So it's not quite the
same as A UAT, which is generally for the life of the application. This is only for
the life of the story.
So now we'll come down to AC four. This is about checking the health of the server.
Apparently if we hit the a i Health endpoint, we should get a status. Okay, so I'm
just coming up to a terminal and we'll run it. And yes,
it's saying status. Okay,
so that's just a quick demonstration on how you can create your own agents. So at
any time it's easy to just say, model it after something, give it a little bit of
instructions on what to do. One of the things I find with that particular agent that
I did is that some of those commands like was the terminal blue is not something
I need to visually check, but I could get the AI to do it. So I tend to split it
up into two groups. Those that I have to go and check out myself, like entering in
a form, did I see an error message
versus the ones that could just be tested by Claude Code itself.
But hang on, you might be saying, what about playwright or end-to-end tests? Could
you set them up? And the answer is yes, you can. You probably should. But I find
that they're quite hard to get going. They're very fragile. So they're always breaking
and you spend more time wasted around in debugging them. Where then all you really
want in this particular case is do the forms work the way the story said they were
going to be implemented? And I need to test it visually anyway. I can't purely rely
on E two E testing. And this is where the SAT agent is really good.
So at that point, I've just come back to Claude code and what we are going to do
is just do a commit and push this up.
So what I've done is started a new claude code. We've gone over to the scrum master,
we started drafting story 1.3.
So it's finished creating the story.
let's head over to Visual Studio. I've already set it to ready. I think after it
gets through the task. The main thing that we're going to want to look at is the
fact that there's now a HTML page. So we should be able to see something. Apparently
there's going to be a little bit of JavaScript going on, so let's go back and start
developing.
So I'm just letting it,
load up the developer and once that's done, we can just develop story 1.3.
So now the development is finished. It looks like we're going to have an index file
that we can go and look at. We will do the SAT soon, but let's just go over to the
QA bot for a moment
and we'll run our review on 1.3.
While that's running, we'll just do a quick check of the document. It says all the
tasks done, there should be a public directory. We've got the HTML index. We've got
script tags coming through.
In a moment we should see an update to the QA results.
So the QA results are in. We've got a new gate file. We can see the story. We will
check an SAT soon.
There's updates to the packages.
the client application now has an index HTML page going on.
so let's go and test our story acceptance spot. We should be able to type in SAT
and we've got sat.
So currently Taylor is loading into memory. We've got a create SAT command available.
We've also got an update, SAT command.
Now we'll kick off the create and this command, this one here that we haven't used
yet is just in case. I don't like the instructions that the current bot has. We've
got the ability to update the bot.
So this is reading our SAT is reading the story. That's going to be the source of
truth. It's also looking at some of the code that's been created, like the client
index, HTML.
And at the end of this, we should have a new file just sitting next to 1.3 story.
So it's just created it. Let's pop it open. So the story itself was about creating
a basic HTML page. And the human test that we can do
requires us to run the server,
which I've just done. And then it wants
to go
to the chat window and
We should see a blue header called Client Server Communication test. Let's just bring
it up.
that looks like it. And it's also got a text input box saying, enter a message optional.
Yep,
That's in place.
and a blue button labeled test health endpoint.
I was also saying gray response area with test response will go here. I wonder if
it works.
Now we'll come back to having a look at our form. We've got some things around styling.
I'm not that concerned about that. What's this form? Submission without a page reload
should just say server response status is okay. And apparently there's no page reload.
So we will bring up our website and we'll click on test endpoint.
And there wasn't a refresh, but we did see the server response update.
Apparently there's a bonus visual test. We can stop the server,
which I've just done. And if we click on test health endpoint, we get failed to fetch,
make sure the server is running.
So that's really cool. I wasn't planning to create the SAT agent as part of this
video, but this is the idea of it is that you don't have to think about what the
code did. It tells you what has happened and tells you how to reproduce it,
which just saves you a heap of time when you are using the BMAD method to develop
an application.
We'll come back to our terminal where I was running that server and we'll just clean
up after ourselves. So we'll do a bit of a commit right now
and we've got a great commit message. Everything's listed.
So for story 1.4, I've just run everything at once. I haven't done any testing yet.
We started off with Bob, the Scrum Master. He created the story.
I went a little bit premature into Taylor for the story acceptance test, because
that can be derived from the story, but it should also be done after the development.
So I needed to do a bit of an update later. I also ran James to develop all the code,
and then did Quinn to do the quality assurance.
So the new documentation files are that we have a story, we have an SAT and we have
a Q&A document. And from a code point of view, we've got new files plus a little
bit of an update to the Readme.
So we can see the endpoints that we want to test, but if we go and look at the SAT
plan, we've got
a little bit of console logging that we should see in chat, and we should see some
server responses. If we type anything into the chat window, apparently it can also
handle a disconnection. So let's go test them out.
So here's our web application will hit refresh, and it's saying that we're currently
connected.
let's just say AppyDave here, press enter and we're getting a response received.
I've just asked it to kill the server over in Claude code because I think it's running
in the background over here. I didn't actually start it and look at that. It's starting
to say that it's disconnected.
What I'll do is restart it from the terminal myself, and if we come back to our web
application, hopefully it just automatically reconnects.
So at this point, we're right at the very end of the epic. So number one is done.
We've done stories one, two, three and four from the epic. Now at this point we might
want to do a retrospective. This is something that you would do in agile development
I recently talked about that in a video. So this video here how to make your AI Coding
Partner Smarter was an AI retrospective that I did a few months ago on Bmad. This
has now been implemented into Bmad, so you'll see that in the version six once that's
available. Otherwise you can watch this video to see how it works.
But for now, we will just move straight on to epic number two.
So at this point we have finished our first feature, our first epic in the system.
We have this client and server application. It uses Socket.io and has bidirectional
communication, meaning that we can type something in the text box and it immediately
hits the server. Or if the server was to want to communicate with the client, it
could do that as well.
Now all the code and prompt sequences are available up on the GitHub repo. If you
want to access that, there's a link to my community down below.
Now next up we're going to work on epic two, which is the Claude Agent SDK. And what
that's going to allow us to do is put the equivalent of Claude Code into our server.
So all the sorts of stuff you've seen me doing with Bmad, which is creating code,
writing documents, doing research. Hopefully we can do that from our own application
so that we can build HTML pages and we can generate product and blog posts content.
So we'll head back to Claude Code and we've got our scrum master set up and we're
going to draft story 2.1.
And so we have our story created. It's as a developer, I want a Claude agent, SDK
installed and authenticated,
so that I can integrate the agent driven conversational capabilities into the application.
Now we'll do one extra step this time and we're going to go over to the product owner
agent. And with this we are going to run this validate story, draft 2.1, and what
that'll do
is run a validation on the story that we've already done. And what it's really attempting
to do here, and this is an optional task, is just ensure that there were no hallucinations
or mistakes made in generating the story.
Now, I don't normally do the validation system because it slows down my general workflow,
but sometimes what you notice is that code goes off the rails and if you'd have done
the validation, you would've saved yourself a lot of headaches. So let's have a look
at what the validation system is trying to do. So firstly, it's an anti hallucination
protection is going on,
what it does is a QA
against just inventing stuff.
Then what it does is make sure that all the documentation it needs is in
internally stored within that story.
And then finally a whole lot of checks and balances on the template and the sequence
of the story.
so use the product owner agents validate story with discretion, like when you think
something's complex,
because this will save a lot of future headache if things go off the rails during
the development cycle. Now so far we've gone through a full epic without any issues,
so I didn't really need to do it, but I thought I'd just throw it in so you can see
what it does.
So after that, we go into developing the 2.1 task and everything was going really
well, created all the code that we needed, ran the definition of done checklist,
and this is when a bunch of warnings popped up.
So you can see here that there's an external dependency that we need, which is to
authenticate into Claude. So we'll just open up a new terminal window and we'll paste
that in and see what happens.
So I ran into a couple of problems doing authentication and apparently I was on the
wrong version of Claude. So what I've done is an update and I'm going to take you
through the workflow. As it stands, I've just logged into 2.0 0.42 and I'm just going
to do a logout. So this ensures that we are now out of Claude.
And down below I've created a little test, SDK script.
and
we're seeing an SDK test fail because we're not logged in. So what we'll do is we'll
come back up here
and we'll run the login function and we'll say yes and yes,
we're using our browser subscription. So we can just come up and click on the authorized
button
and we'll come back to the terminal. It says we're signed in, so let's clear this
and try it again.
And it's just going to say hello in exactly five words and hopefully it gets something
back. And so now we can see that our SDK is actually working.
So at the moment the 2.1 story is finished. If we go and look at the main story acceptance
tests that we need to look for, it's just that we've got colored timestamp with the
Agent SDK running successfully. If we go down to our terminal, we can see that entry
just here. So from a terminal point of view, the server seems to be working.
All of our acceptance tests have worked.
And the little test tool that was created is also returning valid data that the authentication
is working.
Now for story 2.2, the basic Agent event loop. I've run this ahead of time and so
we'll go straight into testing it. So here we can put in a message. I'm going to
say can you help me with the cloud SDK. We'll press send to agent and you'll see
a message coming through here. And currently it's saying processing.
And we've got this great formatted HTML response. I'd be happy to help you with the
SDK. However I need to clarify that I'm an HTML application building bot,
And the messaging that's here happens to be because of a system prompt that was created
in the last story.
So let's go and check out the flow that we did in conversation. And you can see that
we started off with the scrum master
and we just asked Bob to draft story 2.2.
And with the story created, we can see that it's about doing the minimal event loop
for communicating with the SDK.
And we can already see from the success criteria that we were able to send a message,
see it logged,
and then
see it displayed in HTML.
Now the main file created will be the agent event loop.
And we've got this solid readiness score and we've also got a list of things that
the development could do. But we'll notice at the bottom that it does suggest that
we could use a validation. We don't really have to with this sort of story, but I've
run one. So we look at Sarah, the technical product owner,
we can then validate the next story.
Now it's just comparing the story to other documents in the system, previous documents
goals, making sure that everything's in alignment. Everything's great. There's one
little yellow flag here, so we'll go have a look at it.
There's a slight little question here,
but we won't worry about it in the story or rectifying it because the development
agent, we'll figure this out pretty easily.
And so next we just install the dev agent, which is James,
and then we can just run the develop story command.
As James gets all the work done, it's all being marked off on the task list.
The story document is being filled in along the way
and we're seeing a little bit of a state change in the document, just making sure
that it's now ready for review.
We see confirmation of what was either created or modified.
And so with the code complete, I just now need a plan of action written up for me.
So the story acceptance test is what will kick off. This is that new agent we created.
We've loaded it up, Taylor is in place,
And we just run the create story acceptance test for 2.2. So a new document is created
and that helps us understanding things like what are the new files or the modifications
going on if we want to go and have a look at the code,
a writeup of what the code is, plus a little bit of key implementation details just
to help,
just so that you can understand it a little bit easier.
So we'll go and have a look at that document. We've got the acceptance test guide
with the prerequisites, how to set it up. And then we go straight into the human
test.
And we started all of this off by running this particular test where we saw the information
coming through, we saw the log messages coming through.
Now you got to see the happy path.
if we put in, hello, can you help me?
We'd get some sort of clean response coming back from the agent SDK.
So what I did for the acceptance Test eight happy path is I pasted in the console
log,
with a little bit of a message saying that I don't see anything suggesting that this
actually got all the way through.
It said that I probably need to do a hard reset on the HTML. So I did that
and I started getting a response. This was very good, except what I was seeing was
object, object all the way through the response.
So I just asked it, was it expecting that that was all we were going to get? 'cause
I didn't go in thorough enough reading the story to know whether
I was going to get clean data. It said, no, it's not right. So went and made some
modifications to the code.
It first started by suggesting what those modifications were, and then it made the
changes automatically.
And that brings us to where we are at the moment
where we can now put in a message, we'll say, what do you think would be a good application
to build with the Claude SDK?
And we've got a conversation, a stream that makes a whole lot of sense.
and remember that this agent is paired with a system prompt, which is about building
web applications.
So we clean up the end of the story by just using the QA agent, which is Quinn, and
we ran the review story to build this quality Gate document.
So we have this audit trail of things that have happened, including that the initial
implementation did have a failure in it.
Now I've just implemented 2.3, which is real time streaming. And one of the interesting
things is I was also able to create a BMAD workflow to do all the work for me in
one sequential flow. We'll look at that in a moment, but for now, let's just test
it out.
So I've created a bunch of testing prompts that we can work with. The idea is that
I want to see chunks come through the system. So we'll go and select this particular
one and come back to our web form. Now I've made a minor change to the system prompt
so that it has a command called test. What I want it to do is ignore the idea that
it's a web application building agent. And we'll just paste this information in.
And it's starting to write some information. And you can see here it's saying processing
at the moment.
And all of this has been done in one chunk. So
the interesting thing about the Claude Agent SDK is that you can't stream word by
word. It is done in chunks. So it's a little bit slow between updates,
But you can see that the streaming is working between where my initial message came
through, and then the agent got involved.
We'll try a different version where we're testing of reading the package.json. We've
got I'll help you read the package.json. So we see chunk zero coming through right
here.
and now it'll do an analysis MD.
And we can see the three chunks coming through over in the console log.
So the last test is what would happen if we bombarded it with ideas. So I'm going
to put in number 10 and we'll press enter. Then we'll paste and we'll put 20 and
we'll paste and we'll put 100 and then we'll paste and we'll do 10 again.
And we can see that counting to 10, this is what it's come up with. Count to 20,
it's done that for us, count to 20 and notice things are starting to get a little
bit out of order. So it's basically, as the information comes in is when it's written
to the stream.
And what I notice about this, that is that it works very much similar to how Claude
Code would work, which is different to chat GPT, where you actually have to wait
for each response to come through.
Now I don't personally know whether the way we've Claude code, if I was to rapid
fire prompts like this, I kind of get aggregated
you can put in an idea and then follow it up with a change of idea and it takes it
into account. I don't think that's happening here, but we've got the rudimentary
ideas of what you can already do with Claude code or working.
Now let's get back to the workflow because I created a custom workflow to build all
this out so that it could just run without too much input from me. And it's called
the affidavit workflow. What it does is it starts off by asking a question, what
story do you want to have? So we did 2.3 At that point it started creating the story
and it did that by starting up the scrum master and running the draft story command.
And as per normal, we got a detailed story written, it's in draft format at the moment,
and it's, as a developer, I want to stream responses
so that the end users can see information progressively. Now we've seen that working,
so we know it's all going on.
It wrote the initial plan of what the code should look like in the story
and then it gave me this status update so we can see that it's in draft
acceptance criteria is there and it's got a couple of questions. Do I want to continue?
Do I wanna skip or exit?
so we got a final summary of the creation of the story. We can see that it's in draft
mode at the moment and it's asked me do I want to continue on to validation or skip.
Now I said that the validation is optional, but I decided to just press continue
and we can see that it's now going into to the product owner and validating the information
in the story against other documents.
Now we're onto story 2.4, which is all about reading the JSON document. And you can
see that I've done a basic test here. We can see the conversation, finding information
on the computer. It's got three sample products in place.
And if we jump down to the conversation, it started as usual with the new AppyDave
of workflow. We've got 2.4 being the story that we want to run.
It created that story and then I just typed in continue
this, moved on to validating the file that gave a 9.5 out of 10. And the little issues
that were there were all dealt with pretty cleanly during the development phase.
So we didn't need to do anything.
Once I then set the status to develop, we were able to come in and click on the developed
story.
It also set up some sample data automatically. So we had some test products in place.
we also have broken data, which we haven't done a test case on just yet.
Next, it built the story acceptance test based off the story and the code that we've
developed. It also ran for me all the automated tests that it could do anything that
was to do with the terminal or something that could be run from a command.
Now during the SAT
generation, it also generated a couple of files that were very unexpected. There
was this human test, there was also a quick test
So what I had to do was let it know that the SAT agent that we had created earlier
in this project probably has some flaws and if it could go through and rectify them
at the same time as cleaning up these files and putting them in the correct location.
And this is the sort of bespoke issue that you can get from time to time.
as soon as you see something out of the ordinary. With BMAD method, it's important
that you probably fix it in the moment
and let the system know either through learning documents or your claude.md or in
this case an agent's file that it's not quite right, can it go and update itself?
So we can see right here that the create SAT task has been updated with new instructions
and the cleanup of unnecessary files has happened right here.
now when I went to read the JSON using the AI agent, there were a couple of problems
that needed to use the development agent to fix. The first one was a little permission
issue. It rectified that really quickly based off documentation. Then there was the
wrong folder. It got that fixed up as soon as I gave it an example of where I was
trying to read and where the files actually were. And then lastly, which was the
hardest one, was that we were implementing this concept of Read Jason, but it didn't
have any ability to figure out what JSON documents were available or to discover
the one you actually wanted.
So it suggested and then quickly built two extra tools. The list would show any files
that were available
and the preview would let the agent interrogate the files to figure out which one
you actually wanted.
So let's go and test the Raid system. We've got a little products document and we've
also got a broken document. And we'll just head over to our site and we'll say, can
you get me a list of products? We'll send that to the agent. It's processing at the
moment.
I'll help you get a list of products first. Let's discover them. I've found some
products. Let me read them. And it's got the file. And look at that. It's got the
AppyDave on school. So it's got that file that we just updated.
And we'll see if this test against the broken JSON document will work, we'll say.
Can you get a list of items from broken? And it's doing some processing at the moment.
It's found that we have a broken JSON document. Let's read it.
And this is perfect. It's giving a nice message that the data is malformed and the
system is not falling over.
just finished story 2.5, which is the ability to write information to the different
data files. I've done a few use cases,
but let's go through the individual changes that have happened. So from the appydave
workflow point of view, there's a little bit of an improvement
because on load it has a look through to see what the last story was that was done
and suggests the next story to go and write. So I've just put in 2.5 here.
So it's created the story really quickly. But the challenge I had with the last story,
was that we added a couple of new tools. That was the list,
and the preview JSON.
And so what I did at the time of validation, which is the next thing
I then gave it some extra context
by talking about the list and preview
from the previous story and also giving it a little bit of a use case.
So I was able to talk through the capabilities it could already see with adding Jason,
but then it went on to document a bunch of critical gaps, which is exactly what we
want. We want it to pick up old ideas, bring 'em into the new story and make it available
for the development.
So it gave me a bunch of options. I went with number one, that's just fix or update
the story.
So we're seeing new information being added to the story
and that allowed us to go into developing with the new capabilities thought of along
the way. And then when it wrote the SAT plan, one of the things that did automatically
this time, this because I'm gradually improving agents and workflows as we go, is
that it did the automated tests of the terminal commands.
But I did ask it to run up more one more time and just give me a summary of what's
going on. So we can see the eight tests that are from the terminal are all working.
And then it started listing eight different tests that I as the human could go and
test and the steps to work on 'em. Now, the first one actually failed
and the failure was simply that it wrote the Jason document out in quote mark, so
as a string. So I let it know that there was an issue there,
quickly found and rectified that particular problem.
Then I ran into a new problem, which didn't end up being a bug, but just a gap in
the requirements. And you can see the basic idea here is that I had a conversation
that said Add sugar for 50 cents. Now, I said that statement after a prior statement
of looking in the products table. So I assume contextually it would just work.
And the issue is that it had no conversational memory
each time it went back to the SDK,
So it suggested we could either fix it or create a new story. So what I've done is
added a new story to this epic called 2.7
just based directly off the information right here.
so the ability to have conversational memory is something we'll do in two stories
time.
So let's test the idea of adding and updating files in the data folder. We've gotta
test products. We can see the information that's here. We've got one broken file
as well.
And we'll come over and say, can you add a product? We want sugar and we want it
to be 50 cents.
After that, we'll just go down to our use cases and we've got this create an electronics
js document under the catalog folder. So it'll be a nested file
and it's saying it will do it with a laptop and a phone.
Now we'll head down to our Jason document. We can see that this is expanded to have
sugar at 50 cents. Looks like we've got our new file. Let's just drag that in. We've
got an electronics catalog and we've got multiple items coming in here and they're
quite detailed.
Now let's try out a couple of discovery commands. So we'll go what Jason exists
in the data directory. Let's see what comes through.
We can see the broken and the test products. We don't have the catalog so it hasn't
looked deeply,
but what we'll do is we'll add a category field to the test products table.
So click that center agent.
It's telling us it'll add a category, now it's done it,
and if we head over to VS code, we can now see that on products. We've got these
categories. So we've got groceries over here.
And there was a couple of other interesting use cases that all worked, which I didn't
even think of. It just created these and the ability to create a file outside of
the data directory was blocked.
Creating a file with circular references.
And the last useful example is to just add five items, an array to a new table.
So here we have five sites added.
So what we're seeing now is this really powerful mechanism where we can read, we
can write, we can update,
we can work with sub directories of files back on our server. Now these are data
files. Next we'll be looking at how we can do HTML files. But the whole idea of this
is more for an internal tool. I wouldn't, it's not the sort of tool that we would
use up on a public website where it can write to your server. But if you're trying
to build a little application for yourself and you want the ability to dynamically
update data just by talking into the microphone, then this is a perfect technique
that we can be using.
Now is star 2.6. Our conversational bot is now starting to get really powerful. So
what we'll do is we'll start off with a simple question. And that's what HTML files
exist in the public directory.
And you can see here it's saying that there are currently no HTML files in the public
directory. And if we head down to VS code we can confirm that. So we've got our data
directory from the last session available. But in the server when we click on public
there's nothing there right now.
So the full conversation for this workflow was that we started with the AppyDave
workflow. It figured out that it had done 2.5 and that it could move on to 2.6,
and so it was able to start up the scrum master and create the story for us. Now,
because we'd made a lot of extensions within the 2.4 and the 2.5 story, I decided
to let it know that it was modeling these two stories, except rather than for data
it was going to be for HTML.
And so while there were major differences, like the type of file and the location
that they were going to be, the actual tooling was pretty much the same.
And so I suggested that it have a look at the 2.4 and the 2.5
before updating this story with new capability.
From that, it was able to notice all the critical gaps that were in place
and come up with four separate tools to implement. Before that, it had only had one
tool, which was writing the HTML.
Now to show that this was an extensive change, we can see as we scroll through that
there's a lot of green and reds, a lot of stuff being taken out, a lot of new stuff
being added,
and the public directory is the 2.6 story. So then we changed over to the development
agent. Everything pretty much went off without a hitch
There were two different problems that I did need to address and you can see them
here. The first one was that it wasn't actually serving from the public directory.
I was able to test all the HTML, but not from the application. So that was a bit
of a problem.
the other problem was that when I was trying to display data that we created in the
previous story, it, it also wasn't showing through.
so it did a little bit of prompt engineering just to get the code working. It was
really easy to do
because Claude Code gave me option A, B, and C, and I just said, let's go with A
and C, and it just wrote all the code that we needed,
So with our chat agent set up to story 2.6, we'll just put in a simple prompt that
says, can you createa HTML page for AppyDave?
And along with that question, I'll just paste in a little bit of information I just
copied from my website and we'll press enter and see what it does with that.
Now you'll notice as it's building it that we've got this concept down the bottom
of pages. So I've also added a little menu to the bottom of the chat box to show
any public pages that are being created.
So it's just come back with, I'll create
page. Let me check. I'll create it. And it looks like a bunch of stuff's being created
and we can see this little index. Let's click on that and see what we get. We've
got AppyDave, and this is actually a whole lot of information from my main website.
We'll just pop over and have a look at that. And we can see Master AI and prompt
engineering different projects and down the bottom different channels. So if we come
through and look at it here, it looks like it's all the same information.
all it's done is created this little HTML file for us, and it's put all the colors
in there.
Let's see if we can do something a little bit more complex. And we'll do a prompt
that says, can you create a HTML page called Cat dash Dog and do it talking about
a pet store that is about cats and dogs. And let's go with the colors of brown, yellow,
and green.
So we'll just let this prompt come through as soon as it's typed in.
So we'll send that through to the agent.
And we can see all our product data down here. We can see our cat dog and our HTML
file.
So what I think I wanna do now is create a new HTML file. We'll go with a CSS file
as well
So the prompt will go,
can you create a HTML file called a AI-TLDR
And can we create a cs s file to go with that?
can the colors of that CSS be light blue, dark blue and white? And can we make sure
that we're displaying a whole lot of products? Can the products come from our test
products
document?
So I'll just let that prompt come through. There it is. And we'll press enter. So
there's a couple of typos in there,
but it looks like we're going to create A HTML file matching CSS file.
Perfect. Now let me check what pages exist
and while that's happening, what AI TLDR is is one of my other channels. This is
a faceless YouTube channel where most of the focus is on
YouTube storytelling.
so we've got something coming through. They're not necessarily the colors we normally
use, but let's go and click on this and see what we get. A-I-T-L-D-R product catalog.
And this is really interesting from a few points of view. So the actual widgets that
are in the product listing, aby school sugar, this has all come through, but we've
even got the HTML links so we can get to the homepage. Can we get to
the cat and dog?
We can get to the cat and dog. What about products that's taking us to where we are
And if we go back to the chat interface,
So at this point, we've almost achieved everything I wanted with this project. It
was the ability to create any sort of data we want. Let's go and test the idea of
updating data.
Can you go and add three different products about nail polish? Let that come through
and send that to the agent. And what I'm hoping it'll do is it'll come up with three
interesting products. It should be able to add it to the only file we've got, which
is the test
products.
probably should go and rename that. Well, let's just go back to this.
It can see the file. It's now apparently added things. Oh, look at that. It's showing
them as well. So we'll go and click on the AI TLDR page and see what that's showing.
Okay, we've got five products.
Now our page hasn't updated, but if I go down to Visual Studio, we can see that three
actual products have been added. So my assumption is it's not reading from the JavaScript
and it's not, it's actually been hard coded. So maybe we can modify that.
So we're going to work with the idea of can we update the HTML of AI-TLDR so that
the products are actually just reading from that URL. So we'll send that through.
While that's doing its theme, we can have a look at the URL. This is the data that's
available to us.
It says that the page is working. Let's go and click on it and look at that. We've
got eight products, we've got three new products added. So yeah, we're using our
chat interface to both,
create data, update data, delete it, or we dunno whether it can delete and to actually
modify the HTML. So let's see if we can do one more compound idea.
So we'll go with the idea of can it delete widgets from the test products
table, the JSON document, can we also go to the AI-TLDR CSS and we'll start changing
the colors to be a light pink, blue and yellow. We'll send that through to the agent.
We should see it coming down the bottom here. So currently it's doing a search broadly
for the CSS files. It's found them. It's now going to read the full content from
them.
It's found widget A, B and C which it's going to remove from the JSON. Then it's
going to go and update the CSS. And it looks like it's done that.
And what we'll do is click on AI-TLDR and look at that.
we got pinks blues and yellows. And we've removed the three widgets.
Moving on to story 2.7, which is a new story that came about 'cause we encountered
a bug where if you typed in a couple of messages it didn't understand the previous
messages. So we've put it in place and what I thought we'd do is test it by maybe
changing the title of this particular website and at the same time also change the
price of just cats. And we'll do that in two separate messages.
So here's our first prompt.
Can you change the title of the cat dog website so that rather than saying cat and
Dog Pet store, it just says Pet store.
So we'll kick that off and then we'll start the next prompt.
Can you go to the Cat Dog website and change every product
that is related to a cat so that it is $100 more?
And we'll just press enter on that one. Now, if we look at the current website, it
says Cat and Dog Pet Store. Now I've done a refresh on it and we can see that the
pet store has been updated.
we wanna see ifthe 24.99 becomes 124.99.
And they have changed. So there's the new value and we've got the old value as 24 99
and Cat and Dog Pet store.
So from a conversational point of view, it was pretty much the standard workflow.
We started off with the appydave-workflow. We created the 2.7 story, we validated
it.
The minor change here was that I asked it to go and read the documentation around
the SDK.
And we have a second brain of information around that particular tool.
the basic findings from that were all listed and updated the story.
We then just did our standard development phase. We did an SAT. There was nothing
in there other than to run the two commands that I did.
And so we just finish off with a review from the QA agent
So that brings us to the end of Epic two, and what we can now do is we can add products
or any sort of data that we like. We can update it. We can also play around with
HTML, CSS or JavaScript
and we could call this a complete application, but if we look at what Epic Number
three is going to be about,
we'll be able to give the chat interface a much needed upgrade
and we'll do that by going to React where we'll use VI Shad cn, tailwind CSS, and
we'll use the Vercel AI elements to give a really clean chat interface.
Now it's a fairly simple epic, we're going to initialize the React application, then
we're going to install the Shad CN and configure Tailwind CSS. Then we'll build the
chat interface again using Vercel AI elements. And lastly, we'll implement a simple
dark mode, light mode toggle.
So one of the things that we have to do before we actually start the first story
for Epic number three is we just need to do a little bit of a retrospective. So I've
got a basic question just asking it to think about what it would need to do a retrospective,
and it's come up with a long list of tasks that it should perform to build up that
particular document.
I've specifically told it to think deeply, and I've also given it as much time as
it needs to do a detailed job. And so it goes through and it writes this long document
and we don't have to read the document, but
It will have information from here that it can pull on when generating the stories
for Epic three.
So story 3.1 is finished. There's not actually a lot to see. There's a little bit
of console logging. We can see now that it's using React and Vite. And from a front
end point of view, all we've got is hello world, be mad Claude SDK and the fact that
it says vite connected.
and we'll just check that the hot module reloading is working. That's working. Okay.
So we have a foundation now for the react version of the chat client.
Let's move on to story 3.2.
Now we are on story 3.2 and there's not a lot to be seen just yet. We've got an installation
of Shadchan and UI, and if we pop it up, what we'll see is this user interface with
the basic typing area in place. We've got to click me and we've got some buttons.
And the styling is very ordinary at the moment.
And according to the component verification, that's exactly what we want to see at
the moment.
We've just completed story 3.3, and we're really close to the end of building the
application. And what you can see now is that it started to come together quite nicely.
We'll demonstrate where it's at in a moment, but I'll point out that this is the
14th story that we've done, and every story we've done up until this one just came
across without a hitch. It was able to be created. It was validated.
It was written by the software developer. We were able to do
the story acceptance testing, and we were able to do the QA afterwards. And everything
was really quite quick. This is the one story where everything changed. So I'll do
a little bit of a postmortem analysis of it as well, after I've demonstrated where
we're at.
So let's test out our new chat bot. And what we'll do is we'll search for products
first. So can you tell me what products are available? And we'll let this prompt
come through. We'll press enter. And so we can see this little bubble coming up here.
That's what the user has said. This is what the agent SDK is responding with at the
moment. And there are our products. We've got some groceries, we've got some beauty
products, nail art sort of stuff. So let's create a little website.
Can you create a little HTML website called Beauty and Joy? Can this be a nail art
sort of store? Can we get both a HTML page and a CSS file?
And we'll let that kick off. And in a moment it'll come up with a plan of action.
And here it's starting to happen. And what we can also do is just head over to VS
code where we can see what we currently have. We have a couple of websites here,
cat Dog Index and AI-AITLDR. And if we come back and we look at these little pages
here, this is where we can see this and look at that. It just created beauty and
joy. So maybe that's already started. Let's go back and see whether it's created
here. Yes, we can see it. We've got a CSS file and a HTML file, and that's why that
came about. So let's go and click on that and see what we get. Okay, we've got a
interesting looking
nail art shop. I think we can do better styling than that. So what I'll do is I'll
bring it back here and say, can you update the CSS styling for the Beauty and Joy
website? And can you use this basic guidelines? So what we'll do is we'll just go
down and paste some extra work and hopefully this will show up plainly. Here we go.
We've got soft, modern, feminine. We got some primary colors coming through
and it should be updating the CSS very soon.
And it looks like it's finished. It's actually created a different HTML. So if we
go up, we now have two. We have beauty and joy. And we have beauty. Let's look at
the old one. Here's the old one. And the new one is looking a fair bit more elegant.
Now, ideally, I would've liked that to actually update the original website, but
for a first pass at a chat bot that can create data, read data, and also use it for
websites.
This is working really well.
Now I said that this story wasn't actually as successful in the coding as any other
story that we've done, but let's have a look at what it was originally. It's build
a chat interface with Sal AI as a developer, a chat interface using the AI element
patterns so that users can send messages and have streaming agent responses. Now
that's working and so pretty happy with that.
but let's have a look at the post mortem. And this is where a number of issues happened.
Now, part of the issues happened because I think when I was doing it, I was really
tired, so I wasn't paying attention,
to different things going on. But the main issue, which I seem to run into every
time I do tailwind and totally forgot about it in this particular case,
is that it got configured with V3 syntax, but it was a V4 Tailwind.
and you might've noticed in the last story that there was styling that looked pretty
average. And I said, well, that's actually how it's meant to be. Well, that's not
the case. And the reason is that the tailwind styling was misconfigured and it took
a little while to find it out. Another issue that was happening under the hood for
me is that one of the servers there, there are two in this,
was meant to be running on 5173, but Claude was actually running a separate one on
5174. And so I was trying to see updates and nothing was coming through, and I kept
saying to Claude, this is not working. And he kept saying, I've fixed it, but I wasn't
seeing anything visually. Now, again, a lot of that was me tied at the time,
but this is one of the realities of having AI agents that can run the servers for
you is that if they've got a conflict with your current server, then it's just going
to spawn a new one on a different port.
Then it had a bunch of issues with the bubbles and the dropdown menu that we saw
go showing up underneath the bubbles.
Now, the reason I actually wrote this document wasn't just so that I could show you
the sort of challenges that you can run into, but because once you write a document
like this, you can make it a part of your documentation system. So if any other issues
happen in the future and you notice it, you can say, can you go and read other documentation
or lessons learnt that,
we've done in the past?
and this can be a perfect way of training the AI model to you to write code the right
way if you see a certain problem showing up again and again.