So that brings us to the end. And what we've been able to do is build this complete
application just with natural language prompts. And we did that using context engineering.
That's with the BMAD method. And the back end system that we've built is using the
Claude Agent SDK. So this is giving us all the power of claude code within our own
web applications. So the demonstrations we did was that we were able to create HTML
pages, JSON documents, CSS files, make sure all the links go from page to page.
Now all the code is available.
you can check it out in the repository. And if you want to join the community, we
have more of a discussion and teachings each day on prompt engineering.
Now, if you're loving the power of BMAD in the next video, we're going to use BMAD
Again. But this time we're going to recreate an orchestration framework, just like
BMAD. We're going to call it POEM, which is the prompt orchestration and engineering
method. And the whole idea of it is so that we can create and test prompts in a technique
very similar toBMAD. I'm AppyDave, I'll see you in the next video.