Aider is a pair programmer that you can run from the command line. And yesterday
I did a video on how to set it up now. Today I would like to create a presentation
software to display scalable vector graphics.
reason I want to do this is that I was in the middle of doing a video and realized
I needed this capability, did not want to use Canva or Google Slides, and I thought,
why don't we just use Aider to recreate this software? I'm AppyDave. Let's get into
it.
And here's our presentation using Reveal.js and napkin I for image generation. And
all of this was with a one shot prompt using Aider AI
Now in this video, I'm going to use GPT four canvas just to do a little bit of Q
and A and write a requirements document. And then I'm going to feed that requirements
document into Aider to produce the application.
Now let's have a look at the problem that I'm trying to solve. So here I am on an
application called napkin. And what it allows you to do is just take some lists of
information and press a little button here and convert it into these graphics.
we just go down to this particular list here and we click on the button, it'll go
into this generation mode. And from there we can select different graphics. Now once
we select a graphic, what we can do is head over to it
click on this little button here for export. And we can export a PNG or a scalable
vector graphic. Now it's a scalable vector graphic I would like to show in a presentation.
And the good thing is you can download it. Or in my case I just want to copy it to
the clipboard.
So I've come over to GPT canvas, where we're going to start the Q&A session. And
where we'll start is I would like a simple presentation software using JavaScript
library. I don't know which one to use. So let's go and find one needs to be able
to display scalable vector graphics. And I really only need about 20 word description
for each type. I just want to get an idea. So let's come up with Reveal.js and impress.j
reveal-md, bespoke.js and deck.js. Now I don't know the last three, but I do know
the first two and the one I want to work with today I think will be Reveal.js.
So I've started writing the prompt that says I plan to use Reveal.js.
I want to create a slide presentation with one or more slides, and that they're going
to be showing some headings and maybe a scalable vector graphic. Now from here, I
just want it to think about the steps that I'm going to need to do to implement this.
Think about the layouts, basic capabilities, brand guidelines. So I'm probably going
to want some colors.
how are we going to store these and reference the Scalable Vector graphics. Lastly,
I would like 1 or 2 simple edge cases
And let's make sure that it's not going to write any code. I only want information
at the
So it's come up with a whole lot of guidelines, and it's working on steps to consider
when creating a reveal.js presentation. Now we're looking at single SVG and a heading
versus multiple. We've got brand guidelines. And what that's making me think is that
we're probably going to need to ask a question about colors and fonts,
Then we've got where we're going to put the SVG files. We've got the slide navigation.
It's assumed that that's something that can be done by Reveal.js, but there are different
effects that we can load in. So this to me seems like another configuration option.
And then after that we've got what to do with missing Scalable Vector graphics and
content overflow. So that's interesting. So I think from here we should just start
writing a prompt to make this available for another developer. Now in this case the
developer is going to be Aider.
Now let's build the basic prompt. So we'll start off with can you turn this into
a simple requirements document. We want to let it know that the programmer knows
how to code in Reveal.js, and that we don't want any code. I'm going to let Aider
come up with the ideas and the plans rather than GPT canvas. Just give it clear guidelines.
After that, let's make sure it says text in a code block. That way I can just copy
it and paste it directly in.
we need to have configuration settings. The ones that I've worked through is that
we need a slide type and the brand considerations.
So to configure this we'll go over to Canva where I've got my brand guidelines. And
what we'll do is we'll just start pasting some stuff in. So we'll need a foreground
color, a background color and a highlight color. I like to use yellow for that.
And for the font we'll go with Bebas new and that's a Google font. So we'll just
paste that in and let's see what it generates for us
as a requirements document.
as you can see because I'm using GPT canvas, it's now changed context because it's
actually writing the document.
So we've got our requirements document. If we read through it, we can see that number
one is general slide layout requirements. So it's talking about the single scalable
vetor graphic or the multiple layouts. We've got the brand guidelines and it's talking
about how to name the
where the assets should be. After that, we've got additional configuration around
the transition. Now, if we move down into five, six, and seven, these are areas that
I think I wanna change. And this is the reason why with number five, responsive design
requirements. This is a given. This is reveal js. It knows how to do this. So we
don't actually need to confuse the AI pair programmer with information it doesn't
need to know about.
number six, which is a template based slide creation. If this was a more featured
product than what I actually need, this might be a good thing to do, but I really
wanna replace this with a new idea. And if we look at number seven, the edge cases,
I'm also not concerned about them. So what I think I'll do is say remove steps five,
six, and seven, and let's see what it does. Now, the way GPT Canvas works is it just
starts
rewriting the file and we should see it just disappear. We're down to four. We've
got the configuration summary and the notes for implementation. Let's add in one
more capability.
Now I wanted to find one more capability, and that's the ability to configure this
on a multiple presentation front. Now, I only need to use this once, but I think
it might make sense to configure it with a little bit of extra information. So what
we'll do is say I want a basic structure for adjacent document and I want it to have
multiple slides with different attributes.
probably just want to copy the scalable vetor graphic asset, which is a whole lot
of XML. Put it straight into the field as an embedded concept, but I may also want
to store it as a file.
take both an image and a scalable veto graphic as embedding, and there'll be a layout.
I don't currently have any ideas for layout, so I'll just call it default.
I wanna put in a H1, H2 and maybe some bullet points.
lastly, I just wanna give it some extra ruling around that scalable vetor graphic
and name.
from my point of view. The embedded SVG should take precedence over the actual name
field. So if we press enter on that, let's see what it generates.
So it's just started writing some code down here. We've got slide structures in J
format. Define the structure. We've got image name. Look, this all seems to be good.
We've got some attributes and we've got some notes.
It's updated the requirements document with a new section at the bottom called Slide
Structure in JSON format, and it goes from here all the way through to here. We've
got an example of how the JSON document would look plus information about the attributes.
Now I've come down to a terminal window and we're going to test Aider. Now, I need
to let you know I haven't done this, so this way of writing the requirements document
could fall flat on my face. But what we'll do is we'll make a test directory, we'll
CD into it, and from that point we can just type in Aider.
that'll do is it'll connect to the default model, which in my case will be claude.
I think it's asking me to create a repo.
we using? Clawed 3.5 sonet.
And at this point, we can just start typing prompts.
I don't know yet whether I should break it down into individual prompts or do it
all as one
But we should be able to go back over to our document. There's a copy button, and
if we just paste it all the way in, that's a lot of information. Let's test how good
this Aider system is. So at the moment, it looks like it's creating a reveal JS presentation.
Main HTML file. We've got JavaScript file for configuration. We've got a sample JS
concept. So here's the HTML. It's come up with a custom CSS, and hopefully they're
the colors that we put in from our brand information.
After that, we've got a configuration js, again with various configurations going
on. Then the presentation,
and I don't actually know how to create these yet. We've got a slides, Jason, and
what have we got? Welcome to the presentation. We've got a H two. We've got a graphic
that's been filled in as a circle with some bullet points. This looks good and it's
then telling us to make some directories.
Lastly, it wants us to run it as a server.
Now I'm about to follow the instructions to create this, and I'm going to leave this
HTML page that we're currently seeing. ChatGPT up and running because if it creates
a new page and executes it, it should just pop up automatically. So we'll press yes.
We're creating HTML, CSS, JavaScript presentation. So everything that we saw in there
is available. They've all been applied. It's about to make a directory. We'll do
that. And lastly we're going to run a web server. And this is where hopefully it
might even just pop it up for us.
And it didn't. But I typed it in and it looks like it's working. Now if I remember
right we can do right arrow to go to the next slide and we can go backwards and forwards.
So that was a one shot prompt. That whole requirements document turned into what
we're seeing. This is my theme colors. So the light brown on the dark brown with
a bit of a highlight. We've got a scalable vector graphic. Let's see if we can modify
it.
Now we've got the presentation here. I'll click on the right button. We go to the
next
there's a problem with the image. We'll have to check what that is. But let's go
and grab an image that we can start with. So we've come over to Napkin.AI It turns
these text areas into infographics.
just click on this link here. We'll go export. Now we could work with a PNG. That'd
be fine. But I want to work with a scalable vector graphics. So I'll click on that
and I'll press copy.
we'll drop over to the code and we can see things that we can change. Let's get rid
of these bullet points and we'll hit save. And looks like we'll have to refresh manually.
Let's change this to AppyDave. Channels will do
and I'll just refresh and see what we get. It says AppyDave channels. We've still
got the image problem and it says it's looking for an image file called sample. And
I'm assuming it's going to go into this folder. So we'll just type in sample dot
SVG and paste in the information we copied from napkin.
And we come over to the website. We'll refresh.
there it is. That's looking good. Maybe we can make one more change to this one.
Now we'll come back over to Napkin AI
So let's just pick one at random I'm going to click on this text. And I'm going to
do a regenerate. And it's regenerating right here. And we should be able to scroll
through and find something that we like. This looks good to me. We'll just click
on that and we can come up and click on the export, go to Scalable Vector Graphic
and put it in the clipboard. Now if you want this product there'll be a link in the
description below. This is just excellent for making graphics.
we'll head back to VS code.
we've got this scalable veto graphic that's embedded. This was the other way I wanted
to use it, so I'm just gonna paste everything that we copied. Now it looks like an
issue and it's because there's a couple of carriage returns. We'll just remove them
So we'll paste that in and hit save
and we'll come back to our webpage and just refresh. And that worked as well. So
that's great. It was a little bit fiddly to get the embedded scalable vetor graphic
into the string. But otherwise I can now put this information in IRA's files or directly
into the Jason document.
And now we have our presentation. We can go backwards and forwards between the two
slides, and the only other changes I might want to do in the future is play around
with the layout.
So a quick recap. What we did was we worked with Aider. Now if you want a basic installation
guide, there is a video related that I did yesterday. Then I went into ChatGPT canvas.
I did a Q&A just to get the lay of the land of how I wanted to do the requirements
document, and then I wrote the requirements document. Now, if you want to see a video
on using a documents first approach to using pair programmers, I've also got a video
on that topic. After that, we just ran it and it created the whole application from
one requirements documentation. And then we played around with it and got it working.
In the next video, I want to use the Aider image to code generation technique and
see if I can take this Canva presentation that I've put together and turn it into
slides for reveal.js. Anyway, I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see
you in the next video.