Many people are wondering whether OpenAI, Codex or Claude Code is the way to go.
In this video, I'm going to explore how you could be using them both together and
how I'm also doing that to manage some of the costs I'm AppyDave let's get into it.
Yesterday, I found myself doing a fair bit of coding on some internal tools that
I use and doing a lot of refactoring, and I realized I wanted to make sure that the
tools were updated on Ruby Gems, which is like node packages or Python packages.
And with that, I also wanted to do an extensive refactor where I used Claude Code
as the main creator and OpenAI Codex to just check on the quality of the code being
created.
Now I have a second goal for using Codex with Claude Code, and that's all about managing
token usage. So if we go over to Claude Code and we look at the usage down here,
we can see all the current models. I've used 33% of my usage. I've got about 3 or
4 days to go before it runs out. Now I should be fine, but on a daily basis I'm working
on 2 or 3 projects at the same time. I keep shifting between tabs. To do that, and
I'll be coding for 6 to 12 hours. And when you're doing that all the time, you can
really run through your tokens. So I thought, could I start another session? And
this is the one we're seeing down here, specifically using Codex to not do my coding,
but to check that my coding is actually any good.
So while I was coding with Claude Code, I had this little conversation going on.
Essentially, it was just watching the repo. From time to time. I'd constantly be
tweaking the conversation. It had read individual files, understand the structure
as it was going on. It was creating its own documentation
called Codex Documentation. After a while, I would ask it to look at new commits
that were coming through. I'd ask it to keep focusing on the idea that it was about
patterns and best, best practices, and that it would have to delegate or hand off
the document to Claude Code. So it would be important that it included the line numbers
as well as the descriptions of what was going on.
So with simple tweaks along the way, it would just keep itself up to date.
And so at the end of it, I had a well reasoned document of recommendations. They
had a priority map, it had line numbers, it had descriptions. So I thought, let's
aim this at Claude Code and see what it thinks.
So if we go back to our terminals, we've got our Codex here. We've got the actual
help file from some of the tools that are being used here. And if I pop up to a different
terminal, I've got the start of the analysis of the Codex recommendations by Claude
Code. And because this particular conversation has a lot of historical context
about the work it's been executing, but also its own lessons and learnings.
it has a really good perspective on if someone else tells it, what is the right way
to go of saying yes, that is. Or no, it's not because I've actually solved this problem
a different way.
Claude Code is reading the comprehensive analysis, and it's making its own assessment,
and it's doing it in the conversation where it's already got a lot of knowledge.
And the first thing it realises is that the information about linting or cops in
this particular case is out of date, because it's already done a whole lot of work
there. The next thing is it's looking at the configuration adapters at Codex is putting
in place. So this is a level of abstraction meant to improve the system. But we've
already got really good usage of the singleton pattern for the configuration. We've
also got dependency injection for individual tools, configuration and test data,
which is useful during the unit test phase. So a lot of the stuff that's here is
good to know about, but not something we need to implement.
Scenario number three was really interesting. Codex wants us to get rid of a lot
of the logging, and what Claude Code has pointed out is that this is not a library.
This is a CLI tool where the logging is actually useful as you user feedback. And
it's come up with a counter proposal, which is interesting, but I don't plan to use
this as a library. So I'm going to say no to this particular recommendation.
And so now we're at the fifth proposal and it's talking about the method missing
and wanting to harden this code. Make it more explicit. But this is actually a flexible
configuration system that can dynamically,
change to suit new circumstances.
So this is not a correct pattern for us to implement. So this one I'm going to decline.
So you can see here in Claude code, it's asked what do we wanna do? It's come up
with the same idea that Proposal-3 is the only thing we should work with. It has
other options, but I've just ridden my own ideas here and said that Proposal-0 or
Proposal-1, we won't do Proposal-2 is a good idea, but it doesn't make sense because
we're in a purely
UX environment. It's all interactive.
Proposal-4 is going to be declined. But Proposal-3 is what we do want to implement.
I've also said that it needs to clean up this document. It needs to make sure when
it cleans it up, that it does it in a way that Codex knows what's happened. It's
also going to give its reasons, it's rationales. So with that, we can just press
enter and let Claude code do the changes we want, which is make some new coding improvements
and update this document so that Codex is informed of summaries and verdicts.
Now Claude Code has claimed that it's finished the work it needed to do. It's successful,
it's given the recommendations back to,
Codex.
one of the things that's said is that it's a little bit dogmatic, so it's given new
information pretty much the same as what it did just rewritten. And as it says, Codex
will understand what's implemented, what was rejected, and why the decisions were
made. Now, if we go and look at the code changes from a unit testing point of view,
we can see that everything is working, but there are some problems. So it might be
useful to go and solve them as we go. So we'll just come back to Claude code,
and I've just put in this little statement, can you resolve the linting issues so
as it changes code, the information on the right here should start to refresh and
update.
One of the great things about this is that you'll see the errors coming through,
and then you'll see it all get resolved pretty quickly.
so we've got our tests being updated automatically,
so we can see in the left hand side that the linting issues have been resolved. And
in the right hand side we've got proof or evidence that it's happened.
So that's one of the ways I'm using Claude Code and Codex from OpenAI together, just
to use the strengths that they've got. It's also an example of how to be more cost
effective. So I can use OpenAI Codex at times when I might want to use Claude opus
model, and it can just run in the background. It's running off my $25 team plan,
whereas Claude Code is running off my $100 max plan.
So this is allowing me to use different models for different reasons, but also keep
my costs under control. Now I have a community, so if you're interested in learning
more about how I do the prompt engineering, especially using context engineering
frameworks like BMAD method, then click on the link in the description. Otherwise,
I'll see you in the next video. I'm AppyDave. See you soon!