In this video, we're developing a simple role and design prompt concept that will
allow us to build one shot prompts that design front end applications like what we're
seeing right now from a user experience point of view.
In the last video, we went into detail of setting up both a role and a design brief
for what was classed as a multi app framework. So the idea that you might have various
extensions or plugins, you could have global settings for all of them. You could
collapse that down and from here have individual menu items for each of the applications
and even go from light to dark mode.
Now, to keep things simple, we're building out our new structure. We're going to
take information from the last video, and we're just going to do a slight adaption
on it. So the last video was about a multi app structure within a shell desktop.
In this situation we only want a single application. So what we'll do is have a look
at the structure of how this will come together.
Now, I usually start a conversation with a line similar to this. In this conversation
we will explore and I give it a headline. After that, I give it an instruction to
say yay! And please wait, because I don't actually want it to do anything with this
information because I haven't told it what to do.
Now, I don't usually go straight into getting it to use a detailed design prompt
to build an application. Instead, I want it to become a certain sort of person. In
this case, it's going to be a single app UX/UI, mockup designer, or an architect
or something like that. So I'll have a simple prompt that says read and wait for
guidance. I'll press enter, and then I'll paste in a really detailed description
of the sort of person that would be perfect for writing this sort of application.
Now the last prompt I'll do is code implementation prompt. So see instructions of
what I'm trying to build. And it'll usually be fairly detailed, but it's simply here
is the design brief. Please implement. And then I paste it in. Now you might be wondering
do you need the first two prompts at all?
And the answer is not really the first one. Definitely you don't need, but I like
to start it. Then afterwards, if
the second prompt doesn't do exactly what I want, or
the third prompt doesn't do exactly what I want, I can go back and edit them, knowing
that I still understand where the start of the conversation is. As for the role prompt,
if you don't include that, you'll still probably get a good outcome if your requirements
document is detailed,
But what the role will do is give you a higher probability of success, because it
won't just be reading the instruction from the point of view of a general large language
model, it will impersonate and think like the person that would normally implement
this, and they think of things a little bit differently to a generalist person.
Now, rather than starting from scratch on this one, I'm going to build on top of
a successful implementation because we'd already built this multi application, which
means we've got multiple applications on the left. When you click on one of them,
the idea is that the menu on the right here or in the middle becomes dynamic based
on that particular application,
we essentially want the same application minus this panel and a couple of other global
settings.
So what I've done is just gone down a little bit further after that was created and
given a new prompt, basically saying that earlier in the conversation you gave me
a definition for a role, and I actually pasted the role in again, but I'm asking
for it to just adapt what's going on here so that it's for a single app setup. And
this is because I'm trying to do templates around building micro apps every day,
and I want a consistent user interface each time. And so we develop this role for
someone that can draw that interface for me.
But before it does the work. I also said it might be useful if you give me 2 or 3
questions that I can answer. So what it's done is given me a bunch of Q and A's that
I can work through, and I've essentially taken a couple of headings from its questions
that it gave and gave my own opinion of what I want to see happen, and from there
we ended up with a role basically for a single app UX designer. So it's very similar,
but it's got differences that will be important when we go to generate this new structure.
So with the role created, we can go and select all the information that's in there,
put in the clipboard. And basically after we do our conversation starter and we've
put read and wait for guidance, press enter. We would just paste that particular
information directly into the conversation window.
Now I did that in Claude, but let's look at the code implementation prompt, which
in my case I did in ChatGPT. But what we'd want to do is here is the design brief,
please implement and we'll paste it in. And we can see a design brief has been put
in place, and I'll just go over quickly how I adapted the design brief to make this
one.
Now, the desktop single app design document is fairly extensive. It goes through
and every time I run it, it tends to give an accurate result each time. But to create
it was fairly simple, because what we did was we built on top of the design we did
in the last video, which was the Multi Application framework, and we just pasted
it all in and asked it a simple question.
Now, the follow up statement to that design document was essentially to update the
current Multi-app shell so that it looks more like a single app shell. And when you're
doing that, should we drop anything, simplify or reframe any of the statements that
were there?
Now the drop, simplify, reframe process worked out concepts about what it thought
we should drop one of them I didn't really want to let go of. I wanted the command
K for searching, but I didn't need it for application switching, so a minor change
there. It then talked about different areas that were common and reframed them so
they made more sense in a single application structure. It also gave a couple of
minimal ideas to think about, and I took some of these into account. For instance,
I didn't want to have a footer status bar.
So from there I just gave it a few instructions, such as what I wanted with the command
K, a couple of other changes. It started building a single app spec. Now I read this
in detail. It's really important that you get it right. A couple of things that I
noticed is it was going into the technical side of things, such as using a convex
database, and this is a pure UX experience. I don't want to get into the underlying
technologies when building out this prompt, so I let it know. It made a couple of
modifications, and we kept going until we had a final application design that I could
run on a consistent basis. And this did work the first time.
So now that you got a copy of the design brief, we can work through the three prompts
that are listed here. Now, if we head over to Claude, this is what I did the first
time. In this conversation we'll explore single app UX design, say yay and wait.
So it started waiting, ready to move forward. And I said read and wait for guidance.
And I gave it the role. It became a personality. So it says, got it. I understand
my role and it's got a little bit of conversation about what goes on. Waiting for
your guidance on the single app design we're creating. I said, here is the design
brief, please implement. And I press paste and I pressed enter to see what it would
create. So we end up with a whole lot of code. You'll notice that there's various
versions going on here. So I'm just going to bring up version one, which is the first
one that it created. And you can see that it had a little bit of a challenge here.
So I naturally had a look behind the scenes just to see what was going on. I did
notice the way it was scripting out to tailwind CSS was in the times that it failed.
It looked like this. I gave it a basic prompt that said, why does it look like this?
Is there an issue with CSS or links? And it said, yes, I think it's a CDN issue.
And so then when we move on to version two of this, everything started to come together
looking well. And we can see that it's popping out to Cloudflare to a tailwind module.
So my experience with using this prompt was that it would give really great output.
But when used in the Claude application it would sometimes work, sometimes not unrelated
to the actual code, but more to the order of how things were being called within
the code base. So I'm going to show you a quick way.
Now, I just mentioned that if you want one on one help or guidance on vibe coding
or using AI pair programmers, then go look for AppDave online. Once you get there,
you'll come up to the main website where you can book a call with me and we can do
one on one sessions in the area of AI pair programming and coding.
So getting back to this session, what I found was generating it within the Claude
application was hit or miss. So if we move on to version three, we start seeing similar
sorts of errors over and over again. And it's not until we get to version five that
we get another working version, though not quite as good. So what I thought was I'll
break out to an IDE, or in this case we'll be using Claude Code just to generate
bulk versions of this.
So I've just opened up Visual Studio, and you can see here that I've got three examples,
which we'll look at soon. But the first thing we should look at is the role. And
so the role is in markdown format. We can see that it's a single app,
UX UI design specialist. We've got all the expertise, all the guidance for what that
role should entail. After that, we've got the design brief going on here, and this
is a full spec of what we would like to generate. It's a single app framework shell.
we've got the layout, a menu. On the left. We've got the different pages that we
want to see an example of. We've got a content panel in the center. We're gonna have
command K as a key that can make things happen, like search. And there's an optional
top bar. We'll see what it does there.
And we've got this important idea of theming is that it supports light and dark mode.
So from there, all we can do is go into a terminal and I'm just going to use Claude
in this case. So we'll go Claude. I'm specifically going to use the Sonnet model.
I don't wanna waste my credits on Opus. It's not really needed for the problem we're
trying to deal with here.
So the simple prompt will be something similar to this. Become
the role and we'll just put in the At sign and we'll go and select role down the
bottom there. And this is this file that we can see over on the left being used.
Now I'll just come over to the design brief. Can you implement.
And we'll just say design brief. We'll select that and right into
index example four. So it's just going to impersonate the role. Try to implement
the design brief and then write it out to a file that doesn't currently exist.
So it's now going through a chain of thought. It's going to create a HTML structure,
implement the different concepts as we go. At the end we're going to see a green
file here called index example four
HTML.
So that took about two or three minutes.
So let's figure out how this all works. So we'll come over. We've got a dashboard.
It's looking pretty good. We can go to a wizard. There should only be one step implemented.
That's all I asked for in the prompt. Then we've got a form and it's a pretty complex
form. This is great. We've got analytics. Now we've got to figure out where the theme
changes are.
We can't see them yet. Let's check this command K first. So if I type in dashboard
yep. Great. And Wizard this is working good. If I go down to settings
here are our themes. So we've got light and we've got dark. This is looking pretty
good. So that's our dashboard and wizard.
So moving on to the first example, which I did earlier, and we've got the dashboard,
a wizard. We've got a form. It's similar, but it is different
analytics. The command K on this one works. I know that. So we can type information
in when we look at how the settings were done, it's same concept, just a different
way of implementing the control. This is working. Great. Moving on to example two.
Much better look and feel. This was what I loved about this, was the idea that you
could use the same role and prompt multiple times and get totally different outputs
while still keeping true to the goal. So we've got a wizard, we've got a data form
and we've got analytics.
we've got our little theme button here, but if we click on it, the dark theme is
not quite the colors we want. We'd need to play around with this a little bit. And
can I go back? I can command K seems to work. This is good.
And what do preferences do?
we can do our themes here as well. Interesting. And if I move on to the last example,
which is example three for me, we've got dashboard, wizard, form, and analytics.
We've got command K, so if we put in dashboard looking great and settings, it does
it as a little button, which is pretty cool.
So just as a quick recap, in the last video I did, we created a role and we created
a brief on multi app desktop design briefs. In this video, what we've done is taken
those original prompts and we've used an adaption technique. We've modified the role
to a single app person. We've modified the design brief
to a single app design brief. After that, what we did was we just worked through
the simple, prompt structure, start the conversation, inject the role, finally inject
the design brief. We basically the word implement and let it go and do what it needs
to do.
now, it worked really well in Claude code. It was a little bit hit and miss in the
Claude Web application, but that had nothing to do so much with the code, but just
the way it was trying to load JavaScript in that particular environment.
Anyway, I'm AppDave. In the next video, we'll be continuing this journey of of developing
micro apps using Claude Code. So if you want to see more about this then please like
and subscribe and I'll see you in the next video.