I have a script that I can say in 60 seconds and it took me about 3 or 4 hours to write.
I did it for a competition and I've just found out that I need to say it in about 30 seconds.
So what I want to do is see if I can create a prompt that will maintain the value of this
script but cut it in half.
Here's the idea.
Can you take an awesome script, cut it in half, keep it awesome.
I've already created a video and here's the transcript from it.
Now the main things that are in here that are making it go a bit longer is that I'm talking
about this 555 manifesto both at the end and at the beginning.
I also talk about the journey of five different YouTube channels that I've worked on and the
problem is I probably go into a little bit too much depth on each of them.
The idea is could we get ChatGPT to rewrite this script for me in about 30 seconds.
Currently it takes 60 seconds.
To get started let's paste in a little prompt that I've just prepared.
I need to take this 60 second script, get five variations.
I want to test them all by listening to them using AI voices but I want each of them to be 25
seconds or less and this part of the prompt is essentially setting up the goal of what
we're trying to achieve but there's one thing that's missing because if I run this prompt on its own
it won't take into account what I think is the important and I've already stated that
the 555 manifesto is not actually important so I'm going to write another prompt and we'd say
before you proceed can you make sure to ask questions about what is important.
We might even add to that.
Just added this section here.
Keep asking me questions about what is important until I say write script.
So I need it to interrogate me, have a look at the script and then come back with a set of
questions. I'll answer them and when I'm ready then I'll ask it to write the script.
Now we can just check it all.
Looks all good.
Let's hit go and see what we come up with.
Now I like what it's come up here.
It's talked about having five different questions that it needs to ask me.
What are the key milestones?
Are there any specific channels to highlight which is not the case?
I don't have any.
They're all important.
How essential is it to include details about followers, speed of monetization?
It's important but I can get rid of it if that makes sense.
Do you have a preference for mentioning certain achievements?
Not really.
It is the essence of 555 manifesto.
Important not at all because that I can do in a different video.
There is one thing that I also need to add to this is that it's done for a competition
by Video Ranking Academy.
It's a course that I'm part of and I'm trying to create this 32nd video to submit to that course.
I better try and include something like that.
Let's see what we can add as answer to these questions.
Now looking at the questions, what I've done is written five different answers and we'll go
through them.
The first one which is about milestones or key points and I guess the main thing is
because it's a competition for Video Ranking Academy which is where I learned a lot of my skills
would be good if it could be highlighted somewhere.
Then the next thing is that all five of the channels are important.
I think maybe they're not but I believe they are so I'd like to list them.
The main thing is I've separated them out into three channels.
One channel that is just a personal challenge for me and then the last channel which is my
podcasting where I actually create most of my content to disseminate to the other channels.
Number three, how essential is it to include followers of speed and monetization?
It's not really that important from this sort of video point of view but number four it would
be nice if I could highlight the one channel and the one video that just blew my mind because
I was able to capture a trend I used concepts like trend jacking and clickbait keywords
and unique concepts and unique content points of view to monetize a channel really quickly.
So I think it's important that it tries to capture that detail but we'll see.
Lastly the 555 Manifesta which is really a future project is not really needed within this.
So let's just press enter and see what we get.
That GPT has written five different variations for me.
One of the things I asked it though was to wait until I said to write script so sometimes it
doesn't follow the instructions but let's have a look through the five variations.
Normally what I like to do is get the computer to read them to me either using 11 labs or
Revoicer or one of the other text-to-speech tools that I have.
What we'll do today is I'll just read through them all because most of them are off a little bit
on what I need and I don't yet have what I consider a final script.
Variation one through video ranking academy I mastered the art of content full stop.
That sentence just feels dead it just dies really quickly.
It then talks about the five channels three being tech one being a personal project
with my heart truly lying with apicast.
That last statement feels a little bit wrong to me it's not the way I would want to say it.
I will want to change this if I go with it.
The idea of gaining 2,000 followers in a week is just a highlight.
It's an all right statement the problem is it doesn't relate to the channel where it happened
which is api-dave so we may need to play around with that.
Let's have a look at variation two a variation two feels a lot better from skills
honed at video ranking academy I diversified into five unique channels
flow video winning prompts and api-dave catering to tech well carnival 90 is my health diary
but apicast is where my store is truly unfold.
So that whole sentences that feels pretty good to me this last statement did I mention
2,000 followers in a week a little bit of context there might be important.
Let's move on to variation three I've just read through number three and it's okay
but it has a lot of similarities to variation one from my point of view
and I can almost say no straight away let's look at variation four now this one has
a starting structure that's similar to two and probably okay for me to go with
thanks to video ranking academy I ventured into five channels fly video winning prompts and
api-dave for tech carnival 90 for health and my dearest apicast podcast I don't really like that
last statement the rest of it didn't really make any sense to me that the context is a bit vague
let's look at variation five now it just starts off really good my journey began at video ranking
academy leading to five dynamic channels at fly video winning prompts api-dave for tech enthusiasts
carnival 90 as a health diary it may be a little incorrect my journey didn't begin at video ranking
academy they've been a major player during my time creating videos the and intimate conversations
at apicast that's also incorrect in that what I'm doing right now is more of behind the scenes
this is where I figure out how to make tech do what I need it to do where I get a high to do what I
need it to do to call it intimate conversations is off the ball but I do the last statement
being monetized in nine days was a cherry on top okay so that's to me might be a
better statement than the 2000 followers in a week there was also that idea of getting 4000 watch
hours and I did it really quickly and so far I've been a one hit wonder I haven't been able to
achieve that since but I learned a lot going through that particular process so it'd be
good to highlight that having read through this I have a prompt here that I've filled in I basically
like variation two and I like variation four the section about apicast I've got a preference so I
basically say when talking about apicast I prefer a statement similar to and then the last thing is
from an achievements point of view these two statements but I only want one I don't want
both so I think we can finish this off with I'll just make five scripts using these new
criteria for guidance then we'll hit go and see what it comes up with but I'll just say started
writing some pretty good scripts but I did restart it again and I'll just show you why
and one of the things that you can do at any time is restart a conversation
by clicking on this little button here and we'll look at the second one essentially I wanted it to
note that the achievement was with api dave it started writing new variations again and in
particular I really like variation two now you can read all of them if you want to but essentially
thanks to VRA I ventured into five channels fly video winning prompts and api dave for tech
my carnivore 90 health challenge and api cast where I do behind the scenes podcasting
through many of the things I've learned I was able to monetize my api dave channel in just
nine days I'm grateful to Sean the think team and video ranking academy
personal note I've been a member of video ranking academy for over two years and I didn't actually
get started until November last year but if it's something you want to follow up on then I've left
a link in the description it's an affiliate link on the other hand if what you want to do is learn
techniques around chat gpt or automating your youtube influence then check out one of the videos
that I have up here in the corner
you