If you're like me, then you love using tools like ChatGPT, Gemini, or Claude. But
if you're not happy using the keyboard, you might find it a little bit limiting.
In this video, we're going to look at voice dictation and voice agents and see how,
over the last week, my own productivity has doubled just by implementing such a simple
system. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
For the last couple of years, I've been using dictation on the Mac and I've had mixed
results with it. It's okay, but it misses words like AppyDave or AI-TLDR, which are
part of my brand. It also has problems with the global hotkey not working. And a
week and a half ago I started watching this video by
a YouTuber called A Fading Thought. And this was a really good video and it talked
about different voice agents, voice dictation systems, and the pros and cons of them
all. So I started trying some of them out.
Now. The first software I used was Voice ink and straight up I went. This is a lot
better than the Apple dictation system. I looked at the pricing. It had a one time
fee of $25. It was pretty happy with that. The challenges I had using it was that
I wasn't quite happy with the way the keyboard global shortcut worked, and it was
a little slow from time to time. At the end of the trial, I decided, I'll go and
try another application and see how it goes, and that moves us on to Aqua.
Now Aqua worked pretty much the same way as voice ink. It also has a pretty good
pricing model. It's $8 per month for the Pro plan. I was just using the free version
for a couple of days. What I immediately loved about this particular product, though,
was that it had a different global hotkey that you just held it down when you wanted
to talk. You let it go when you were finished talking, and I found it just more effective.
I wasn't making mistakes as often.
Now. Once the trial for Aqua had finished, I started back out of fading. Thought
I was going to work through these tools one at a time. One of the things he actually
talks about in this video is that many of the tools meet different requirements for
different users, but the reality for me is that the next tool on the list solved
all the problems I wanted. And so what I'm going to show you is Ito and why. For
me, this is such an incredibly powerful tool to use.
So I'm going to talk about Ito from four points of view general access, extensibility,
voice dictation, and voice agents. Now the first one is general access. And the great
thing is that for most people this is a free product. Now they do have pro and enterprise
coming, but it's an open source project so you can download it.
It's really easy to install.
It's really easy to use.
Now the next criteria is extensibility. And what's great about this is it's a GitHub
repo. What that means is that all the code for this tool is available. You can download
it. They've got instructions on how to use it including a video. They've got all
the instructions for getting it compiling on your computer, plus a bunch of communication
flow and keyboard shortcuts that you can work with.
and what this means is that if you want data privacy or if you want to integrate
it into any of your own applications, it becomes really easy to do.
So for the first test, what I'd like to do is jump over into ChatGPT and I'm just
going to recite a phrase and I'll probably include AppyDave, which is my brand, and
also AI-TLDR, which is one of my other brands, and we'll see how well it works. Now,
the good thing is, all you do is you click into the text box, hold down
the function key, and then just start talking. When you finish,
you let go of the function key. And what you'll notice is that it's a really quick
system at turning your voice into text.
So let's get going. Hi, I'm AppyDave and you can find my community where I talk about
Context Engineering at AppyDave. Com or if you want to find out my community where
we do Context Engineering specifically for video generation and storytelling, then
you can go to AI-TLDR.
All I've done is let go and here it is.
And as you notice, that came through really quickly. AppyDave was done the way I
want my brand to be, which is capital A, capital D, no spaces, and AI-TLDR is all
uppercase with a dash before it and this just stands for too long. Didn't read.
Now in the video, you wouldn't have seen anything showing up visually, but on the
bottom of my screen there is a little voice icon and that was moving as I was talking,
but you might be wondering how did it get AppyDave and AI-TLDR. Now to look at that,
we need to go and check out the settings. So here you can see the average word speed.
The total words that I've done, I've been using it for a couple of days at the moment,
and it's got a dictionary. So within the dictionary I've got AI-TLDR AppyDave. I'm
always in context engineering, talking about the bmad method, and I've got some other
sorts of computing terms and my full name in here. The other thing is we've got the
settings, and this is where you can play around with the keyboard shortcuts. I'm
using the function key, which is the default, but we've got another one. And that's
the
control function key.
and that puts us into intelligence mode, where the large language model can intercept
whatever we say. Let's go check that out.
So when you're using standard dictation, it's basically Wysiwyg. What you see is
what you get. And this is really perfect for a large language model. You put it in
and then you get some information back. But what if you wanted to put in information
directly that had gone through a large language model?
So for the next example, I'm going to press control. And the function key and what's
going to happen is anything I say will go through a large language model before it
gets written into the text box. And since on the AI-TLDR channel, we do a lot of
movie making, one of the things that we've gotta do is create scripts. So let's see
how it can go with just a simple statement.
I need to create a story about a day in the life of a woman and her cat in New York.
It should be six scenes and it should be visually descriptive so that we can build
nice visual animations around it.
And I just let it go and we see what it types for us. So now we've got a whole lot
of information being made available. I might just submit that straight in. Now I
don't have to do that, of course, in chat GPT, because that's the goal of using a
tool like that. But the great thing is if you were doing an email, it could pre-write
a lot of the email for you.
And there we have our first scene for our story. Now the performance issue is not
with the human, now it's with Sora. That took about a minute and a half to do, but
the actual creation of this process is so incredibly quick because we can both do
voice dictation and we can do voice transformation through large language models.
So that's Ito. It just allows you to talk directly to the computer quickly, and it
works in other languages. I'm AppyDave what I do is I educate people on Context Engineering
specifically for coding, storytelling and business processes. So if that's of interest
to you, maybe you want to join the community, the links down in the description.
Otherwise I'm AppyDave. See you in the next video.