Welcome to 2024, where the key to exploiting your YouTube channel lies in harnessing AI.
Gone are the days when video creation was about recording and editing.
It's now a complex iceberg with many layers, from crafting the perfect title and description
to designing engaging thumbnails, but it doesn't stop there.
Your video needs a compelling intro, informative outro, captivating b-roll,
and captivating b-roll to truly stand out. In this video, I will unveil seven custom
GPTs that I've crafted to revolutionise these processes, helping you to automate and elevate
every aspect of your YouTube journey. Let's dive into how AI is reshaping content creation in 2024.
When you open up the chat GPT store, you have access to GPTs created by Open AI and by other
people. When you click on search, you can look for stuff by name, a bunch of recent ones are by me,
and then you can look through concepts like the featured and the trending.
And the big categories are Dali 3 for generating images, you've got writing, coding and research
sort of bots. But the area that we're interested in today are my GPTs. This is where we'll go
through seven of the GPTs that I use for YouTube automation.
Let's head over to my GPTs and you'll see that there's a bunch that I've created over time
and many of these are related to YouTube content automation.
Before going into detail on the seven YouTube automation bots, there's one other bot that
we should have a look at first. Whenever I create my YouTube intro or the SEO friendly description
or maybe even the Dali 3 b-roll images, I like to create everything based off exactly what I said
in the video. And the script abridger is an expert in summarizing transcriptions and making
abridgments. If we click on the commands, basically there are two concepts that I like to get out of
a full transcription. Going into detail, the role of this bot is to summarise and condense
video transcriptions. Now it can use natural language processing to extract structural
information from a transcript or it can summarise it without losing the detail.
What this means is I can take a 30 minute video that I've recorded and summarise it from say a
few thousand words down to a couple of hundred. Now it can do it either as a summary where it
condenses but keeps the meaning or it can do it as an analysis where it gives more of a structural
point of view. And both of these sorts of outputs can be useful for future bots.
To say an example, let's take this 200 lines of transcript from a 30 minute video that I did
earlier in the week. If we compare everything side by side, you can see the full transcript
over here on the left is 2,330 words. Now if we go over to the summary, it basically says
close to the same thing and it does it in 127 words. There's also the analysis which gives
more of a structural view of what the document has and it's in 270 words. Now both the analysis
and the summarisation of the transcript make for really useful inputs into other bots that might
generate a description or generate graphics for an intro and it's as simple to use as typing
over the summarise or the analysis command, pasting in your long form transcript and then
just letting GPT do its work. And as it goes, we can see that this video features a scripting
enthusiast demonstrating the use of a custom GPT agent, the shelf script helper. As we move through
the seven YouTube automation GPTs, we're going to find that the summary or the analysis of the
transcription is going to play an important role for each of them.
The test case for each of the bots that we're working with today will be around the
shelf script helper video. Now this video came out a couple of days ago and a few things to note
as you look through it is that there's a detailed SEO friendly YouTube description with keywords
and links to various assets. If we scroll down and click on the transcript, you'll see that there's
an intro that was written by one of the bots. We'll look at how I use GPT to generate YouTube titles
but also look at the text that it can create to go on a thumbnail which is quite a bit different
to the text in a YouTube title. We'll also look at the Dali 3 images that can be generated or what
I would call elements of the thumbnail. And if I get a chance, I'll even touch on how Dali 3
instructions can be generated directly off the transcript to produce B-roll images that look
exactly like what you're talking about. Most of the videos I create are from 5 to 25 minutes in
length. And once recorded, I take the transcription and I put it through the transcript of Bridger
to get my summary and an analysis. From there, I then go and generate a YouTube title using a chat
GPT bot. With that preliminary work out of the road, I'm then in a position to create my YouTube
intro and to do that, I use the YouTube Intro Generator. Now the role of this bot is to generate
tailored YouTube intros. The overview is that it can work with a transcript directly or it
can work with a summary or an analysis. And the main guidelines is that it creates concise
informative and compelling intros. The marketing frameworks, which in this case are either Paz
or Ada, are really just psychological triggers to get people engaged with your content pretty early.
So we've got the problem agitate solution framework or we've got the attention interest
desire action framework. Now from a structure point of view, we have concepts like problem
solution, which is one of the ones I like to use where there is a problem and I've got a solution
that I've developed. I'm also fond of the Q&A style, but other people might like more of a
storytelling style. And the idea of the bot is that you would configure it with the niche,
the topic, which might just be your YouTube title, some keywords, and then basically the
marketing framework and structure that you want. Using this sort of configuration and the transcript
helps you then generate the intro. Let's head over to my GPTs and we'll click on the intro maker,
create engaging educational YouTube intros and we'll just click on the commands to see what
we've got available. And you can see we can configure it. We can create an intro based off
a draft. We can also get some definitions around the marketing framework and the intro structures
if you need. So I've just put in the config command. I've said chat GPT for coding. That's
what the video happened to be about the Paz marketing framework Q&A style. And let's just see
what this comes back with. And so this is working on the idea that the niche will be chat GPT for
coding, choosing the problem agitation solution framework, Q&A structure, the tone will be
authoritative and engaging. And you can run a configure command again if you want to change
what it says here. But for that, we can now move on to create and we just type in create like this,
that's colon, and then we paste in all the information from the transcription. I also like
to put in the title so the title should be there as well. We got title unlock the power of GPTs
and we just press enter and we see what we get on the first attempt. It's written an introduction
for us and the one that's here is hello and welcome to today's video where we're unlocking the
incredible potential of GPTs focusing on a unique tool, the shell script helper for chat GPT. And
this example is quite accurate, but it's also way longer than I would want to do for an intro.
With a little bit of configuration with that GPT agent, you can get an intro that follows the
style and pattern that you want. And the one I went for for that video was do you want to simplify
the way you build terminal scripts? Join me on this unique scripting adventure where I'll be
using custom GPT shell script helper. So this little intro, it's quite short and to the point
and it was generated out of that, but with a little bit of extra tweaking.
Let's move on to a GPT agent designed to generate your YouTube outro.
So looking at the YouTube outro generator, the main role is that it can create an engaging
outro for your video. Now the overview suggests that it's about creating viewer engagement. You
want people to like and subscribe to do comments. Maybe you want them to click on an end card and
go to one of your other videos. Like the previous agent, the outro creator has a configure command
where you can put the capability that you want to see within the outro. And the main ones that
I like to use is a call to action, maybe like and subscribe. I definitely like to do a recap
of the video and have some sort of video end card that people can click on to go to related
content. And you can do that all through the configuration before you worry about creating
the outro. We'll come over to the GPTs and we'll click on the Tube outro writer,
craft engaging outros for YouTube videos based on summaries and settings. And we can have a look
at what commands we've got available. We can do a configuration, create an outro or look at the
capabilities. And we'll just run that one command. We're not going to give it any input. We'll just
see what it comes up with. So we have a pretty extensive list, call to actions, end cards,
and you could configure each of these pieces of information. But we'll go for something quite
simple. We'll just go brevity and thanks. So I put in config with brevity, thanks with like and
subscribe. I also added a configuration for apicast. At this point, we can just do a create and do a
paste. And what I've done is like before, I've included the title of the video and then the
full transcript. In this case, you can do it with both transcripts and summaries. I find for this
one, I like to do the full transcript. So it's gone through and created everything that we wanted.
I will read it in a moment. But what I'd like it to do is just the script. In this case, it's also
given a few extra instructions that could be useful for the video editor. But I just want to
read it. And so what we got was that's wrap on our scripting adventure with shell script helper.
So it understands the context of the video. Big thanks for joining us on this journey to
simplify shell scripting with GPT technology. If you loved diving into the tech with us,
show your support by hitting the like and subscribe to apicast. So this is basically following the
guidelines that we did when we configured the capabilities. I'll just play the outro
that was on the video I created two days ago. Wouldn't it be great if the words that you're
saying in your transcript automatically turned into beautiful scenes generated with say,
Dali three or mid journey. If you've ever used in video AI or maybe picture, you've already
seen this in action because what these tools do is take the transcript and match it to images that
it gets from stop photography and stop video. I created this video about a week ago. And if you
look at the transcript, there's ideas like creating a custom instruction in chat GPT.
There's the ability to look at video files that are put into a project folder. And I'm talking
about this. And what I want to do is make sure that the images that come up as I'm talking
match what I'm saying. So this is creating a custom GPT instruction. Here I am programming a
YouTube video application and putting the recordings into a folder structure. So everything
that you're seeing here is generated directly out of Dali using using a GPT agent. Let's have
a look at the individual images first. So the creating a custom chat GPT instruction was created
from this particular prompt here. And as you go through, we've got depict person demonstrating
video file organization on a computer screen. And then we've got here visualizer user working with
Ecamm live stream deck and Hazel. Now the video that those images were related to was about this
software I'm creating called fly video, which takes all my recordings and runs them through
various GPTs to solve the problems in a more automated fashion. But if we head over to GPT
and look at an agent that I've created for analyzing basically the transcription,
you'll see that I've got a bot here that looks at transcriptions in the form of scenes as scene one,
and it goes from three seconds through to 50 seconds. And this is basically the words being said in
the transcription. Then scene number two goes from 50 seconds through to one minute and 34. And this
is a regular file format for subtitles. What I've been able to do is take that information, keep the
numbers in place. So the numbers haven't changed. But instead prompts have been generated to replace
what was actually said. And then from these prompts, they can be taken over to chat GPT,
where you can just create a manually. Now you may not want to do it manually. And that's the reason
why I'm creating this software called fly video. So that now you may not want to create a manually.
And that's the reason why I'm creating this software fly video. And I'm just going through the
various episodes at the moment while I build it out so that I can automate the B roll creation,
whether it be images, which is great with daily three, or maybe you could use runway ML and generate
YouTube and and generate B roll video. The GPT agents that we've just looked at were all around
content creation, whether it be the YouTube intro, the outro or B roll. The next agent we're going
to look at is around the publishing of your YouTube video, where you've got to fill in information
like the description and the keywords. Let's take a look at the description from a video I did a
week ago. And the video is called build YouTube automation app with chat GPT. And the way it
starts is join me in the first episode of build a YouTube automation app with chat GPT. So it's
written an intro here in the description that matches the title. From there, we have four sections.
We've got what's inside, episode highlights, useful links, including affiliate links, and stay
tuned for more. And it finishes off with a bunch of keywords. Let's take a look at the GPT agent
for YouTube description writing. And the role of this agent is to craft engaging and informative
YouTube video descriptions. And the basic overview of this is that it specializes in creating YouTube
descriptions for videos focusing on SEO view engagement and compliance within the YouTube
guidelines. So with the additional guidelines around hashtags, around hashtags, links and
discoverability, we should be able to start using this GPT to create a new description.
And so the primary command for this particular GPT is create. And usually I would provide it
with a title and a summary. I might also have some special instructions if I need it. And I often
include extra metadata such as affiliate links or branding links to my social media channels.
Heading over to my GPTs, we've got a video description wizard, which is a friendly yet
professional YouTube description expert focusing on SEO engagement and compliance.
And what we'll do is we'll click on the I will give you a title, transcript and special instructions.
And at the moment, it's just waiting for the input. And at the moment, it's just waiting for input.
So we have all our transcript and analysis and structures here. So I have access to the
transcript, the analysis, the summary here. What we'll do is we'll select the summary.
We have access to all the information that's been constructed so far around the transcript.
What we'll do is we'll select the analysis and the summary. As we scroll up, there's also the
intro that was used in this video and the title. And we'll take it a little bit further and just
copy the brand details and just put that into the clipboard. From there, we should just be able
to go in here, type in the word create with a colon and just paste everything that we've selected
and see what it creates. And so it's just finishing here. It's got a title which has
unlocked the power of GPTs. And then we move into the description. So I would be copying from
this little emoji or the way down what you'll discover key highlights and stay connected
through some social media channels. There's a call to action to like share and subscribe
and following up with some keywords. Let's have a look at three GPT agents to share our video on
social media. We'll look at the we'll look at the tweet composer, the LinkedIn video post writer
and the Facebook teaser. When I created the shell script helper video, I tweeted it and it goes
dive into the future of scripting with shell script helper watch as I transform shell scripting with
chat GPT. And we've got a link and a couple of hashtags. Now looking at the tweet composer GPT
agent, its role is to create tweets for YouTube videos. It emphasizes on capturing the essence
of videos in tweet format. And when you use the create command, which I've set up for this one,
it expects a YouTube title, a link to the video and a couple of key highlights. We could also
pass in the summary. So let's try it out. Let's head over to the tweet composer and we'll see that
it specializes in creating engaging tweets for YouTube videos. And we'll click on the
commands to see what's available. And the primary command is create, which will create a tweet.
What we'll do is we'll paste in the information we have from earlier, which is a little bit of
metadata. We've got the title of the video. And then we've got a summary. Now we could also use
the analysis, which has got more structure and they would both produce different but useful
tweets. So let's just click on that and see what we get. And here's our tweet. Dive into the world
of GPTs with appy Dave, discover how the shell script helper GPT transforms shell scripting
from complex FF MP commands to chapter based video compiling. So we've got a couple of keywords in
here or hashtags. So we've got a couple of hashtags in here and we're going to link to the
video. Now it may be a little bit too long for the tweet. It may still need a little bit of
refinement, but it does a pretty good job of creating a tweet for your video. This GPT will
work with your how to video on YouTube and convert it into a LinkedIn post in a way that will
extract the highlights and make it engaging for LinkedIn professionals.
Before diving into the GPT agent, let's look at a LinkedIn post that was generated a week ago.
Now the video itself was build a YouTube automation app and I was doing the technical design for this
tool that I'm creating that mixes in the GPTs that we've been talking about with the transcriptions
from the videos that I record and just automates the process. But the interesting thing about the
LinkedIn post that it generated was not only did it pull out the useful information for
YouTube content creators, but it also isolated that there's an area in here about a programming
language that I'm developing for GPT. So this is a GPT meta language, maybe an advanced
prompting language, and it's been able to pull that information out as well. So from a LinkedIn
post generation point of view, this was a one shot post I put in the transcription,
the summary and everything and it came out. We've got areas like the hashtags and then I just
added the thumbnail at the end. Looking at the LinkedIn video post GPT, we can see that its
role is to transform a video transcription to a LinkedIn post. The key guideline of this spot
is to extract key highlights from the video and include relevant call to actions and insights
that adhere to LinkedIn standards. Heading over to the GPT store, what we can do is go to the
Tube LinkedIn transformer and what this does is specialise in transforming video transcriptions
into LinkedIn posts. Now there's a couple of starter conversations I think the one we'll work
with is use special instructions plus title and transcription. Here we have the summary and the
structural analysis from the transcript. Now we can use one or the other or we can even use both.
They essentially say the same thing, they're just said in different ways. Now if I copy all this
information, I've also included the YouTube title and a little bit of metadata. So it's just finishing
off the article at the moment but if we move up, we've got unleashing the potential of GPTs in
shell scripting, a case study with shell script helper. Then we've got a couple of hashtags
and some sort of introduction and we can go and watch the video. Let's actually see if that works.
Looks like it's loading up. That's great and it just goes on to talk about this video. Now
based on the way we use either the summary or the transcript analysis or even the transcript itself,
you will get different outputs but usually this is a one-shot prompt for me. I put the
information in, I get it out and tiny little bit of tweaking is ready to go. This next GPT agent
is to create a teaser on your Facebook profile for your YouTube video. Let's have a look at an
example Facebook teaser that I've done for the last video which was the shell script helper
and some of the things that you notice is there's no YouTube title as such. There's just a statement
unleashing the power of AI in shell scripting which is kind of more Facebook like and it's
made really good use of emojis. It's got a couple of hashtags going on and then a link to the video.
Now this is in contrast to the two videos I did just before at episode one and episode two in
Building Fly video where I've just manually written this sort of stuff. It's okay but it's a lot better
when we use concepts like emojis and hashtags to make this searchable and more engaging.