Now, before we go through the changes that the code's created for the presentation,
let's look at the original presentation. And this was done in the previous video.
And one of the things that emphasizes is the use of infographics. In this case I'm
using napkin AI to generate them. There's a link in the description and we can see
this all coming together. It looked good. Let's see where we are now.
So we go over to the new presentation, and the first three slides that we got were
the ones that I generated when I was first creating the requirements document. And
one of the interesting edge cases I wanted to deal with was images in four quadrants.
So we've got the four images being shown. They will need to be positioned, but then
we move on to the three slides that were created from the mocks. So we've got the
first one. The second one. You can see part of the image from that mock down below,
and it's pulled it in because this particular mock had an image and it just happened
to use the mock as the example. But otherwise the rest of the data came from this
slide deck. And we can see it here. We've got Byron, we've got CEO of and that's
coming from this information here, followed by the repeating groups which were social
media strategist and marketing expert. So the structure of our presentation looks
to be working okay.
Now we're about to start styling our slides using the mocks, but before we do, we've
got a little bit of setup so we can see over here on the right that we've got all
the CSS classes for Reveal.js all set up and ready to go, and that's what we've been
using throughout. We've also got our branding colors coming through. Now if we look
over here, we've got all these HTML templates that we've set up for each of the slide.
But what we don't have is a CSS selector that we can target in on.
Now I'm going to try the Aider watch files technique. I've had a few issues with
this. This doesn't always work for me, but we'll see what we get. And I'm just going
to put in a comment and paste in this prompt. Can you make sure that the template
HTML includes a template number class for each section? Now the important thing to
do here is just say I will also put in an exclamation mark and I hit save. And it
looks like it might be working through this particular request. So if everything
works okay, I'm hoping to see a template one, two and three over here. So let's see
what's happening here. We've got class template one template two three, four five
and six. So perfect.
Now it worked Okay. For code, let's see what happens with CSS.
Now we have our custom CSS file. It's all got standard reveal sort of formatting
going on. I'd like to add some templates to the bottom here. So let's just put in
a CSS comment. We'll go like that and we'll paste in.
Can you update with placeholders for template one to six using ai?
Now I'll hit save. And one of the things I notice is that in this particular situation,
nothing changes. When you read the documentation, it says that it's looking for hashes
or slashes at the beginning of a line. So what I'll do is I'll just put this in and
just see if this is good enough. Now it's not, and we'll try the hash just for good
measure and we'll cut this out and press save and go. Let's do it differently and
say, can you
update custom CSS with, and we'll just paste it in
And hopefully we'll get the changes this way
so we can see all the changes starting to come through at the moment.
And so it's put in a lot of CSS. This is actually not what I wanted because I really
only wanted some start placeholders, but I think since it's done it, we should at
least test it out.
So here's a side by side comparison. On the left, we've got the older version and
we've got the newer version on the right. So we'll just move forward and old. And
the new one is just looking a little bit different. We've got this gradient effect
going on right here. We'll go and have a look at these images. We wanna see 'em in
four quadrants, and that seems to be working okay. We move on to the fourth one and
it's just a little bit different look and feel. In fact, this looks good. This is
meant to be a footer. So the basic changes are looking
pretty good to me.
and if we move on to the sixth one, what do we get?
This looks quite a bit different. In fact, this is nice that it's showing the image
in a circle. Now the reality is this is not following the mocks, but this is a pretty
good starting point for our styling, for each of the different templates.
So here's the first design that we want to work with. We've got one dot jpeg and
we're meant
template number four so that it looks like and we'll just type in one dot jpeg and
we'll press enter and see what happens. So we've got changes coming through for template
four. There's a fair few coming in
and it's told us what it's done including the split color design. Let's go see how
it looks.
So here we have the old, which I really like. Let's go look at the new. And the new
is looking very close to the mark, except for two things. We've got this social media
heading, one which should just be above the line here. And this strategy should definitely
be down below.
I've taken a screenshot of the current example, and I've said the H1 should be slightly
higher and not overlapping the brown area, and the H2 should be the same size as
the H1, and it should be over the brown area.
So I've just taken a screenshot of this particular page
and I'll just see if I can paste it in. Now that's not working. So there's a bit
of confusion about how to use this.
Oh bloody hell.
So moving on to mock number two. We got it over here on the right and it's mapping
to template number five. So we'll just put in can you update template five in custom
CSS so that it looks like. And we'll just put in two dot jpeg and press enter. It'll
add it to the chat and it seems to have hung. So one of the things you might have
noticed is that there's been a few different bugs that I'm dealing with as I'm working
with Aider, so there's still some areas of improvement just in the basic usability.
So what I think we'll do is we'll just cut this all the way out and start again.
So new setup and we'll just say two dot jpeg. And that's looking good. We'll say
yes and we'll say yes. So that added in the custom CSS and added in the JPEG. And
the code that we're hoping will change is just in here. We can see it coming through
at the moment
and it's about to change right now I'm assuming. Oh look at that, I haven't. There's
another thing to be aware of. If you change things here, you you might have a little
bit of conflict. So if I hit save yeah. Let's just remove that altogether. And now
we do have a complete set of changes to template five highlighting. Yet another challenge
to be aware of is that if you have left some edits in some code but you haven't saved
it, then it's going to cause a little bit of a conflict when Aider starts generating
code.
So here we have a few problems. It's getting close. One of the things it's done is
it's missed the main topic. So we need to get that in. And everything should be on
the right and vertical. So we can see today's presentation in the middle. And we've
got the bullet points here. Also I think just the graphics itself with this little
yellow box got a little bit confusing for it. I'm going to actually describe everything
in a prompt and see if I can fix it.
Now here we have our reference or our mock image on the left, and we've got the updated
slide on the right. It's starting to look close to what I want, but the problem I
had was I actually had to use a whole lot of standard prompt engineering to get it
looking like this. I didn't find in this second example that the image to CSS was
working too well for me.