So for our third test we're going to try and get the HTML that's on the right looking
like the mock that's on the left. Now this is known as template six in the system.
And what I've done is I've got this image here of the mock. But I've also got an
image of what it currently looks like. We should be able to feed them both into Aider.
So I'm just going to start by adding a couple of files.
we'll add in 3.jpeg and we'll let that go into the system. And we will add in current.png
And that's my example of what it currently looks like.
So I'm just saying can you update template six in the custom
I've given the currently looking image and we'll see what happens. And I'm not sure
whether it's going to change CSS and template. But here it is starting to generate.
And so it's made a change to template six. Let's test it out.
So here's what it's come up with in both desktop mode and mobile mode. So we can't
see the yellow box there isn't the vertical alignment going
So I played around with a few prompts. And firstly I added in this current image
which is the top left hand image. And I also did a current mobile so I could see
different points of view.
then I just told it that I wanted it to notice the yellow in the top, the white in
the bottom, the image on the right and the vertical alignment of the different text.
Now it told me that it needed some extra information, which I gave it in the form
of the presentation JS and the custom CSS, and it generated a whole lot of code for
us. Let's have a look at what that looks like.
And now we're starting to look on point. Now there are differences, but in some respects
I like it the way it is. So let's put the image up in the top right hand corner.
It needs to be moved down to the middle. And these two areas need to be on top of
each other. But at the moment they look quite clean the way they are. So I might
actually leave this template the way it is.
As a recap, let's have a look at how they looked in Canva and how they look in Reveal.js.
So it's looking pretty good. It would need a little bit of work, but I like where
it's at. If we look at the next template, this one didn't work out so well when I
moved it over to reveal, so this would require a little bit of manual. Changing the
image to CSS was a bit problematic with this one, but the last one actually worked
quite well, though it gave a little bit different look and feel, but this is something
I could work with. So in this experience, the image to CSS for Reveal.js it worked
okay, but here's my final thoughts.
So here's a honest assessment of Aider in the area of converting images into code
and other data structures.
Mostly this was painful. This might have looked okay, but the video probably took
me three times as long as I expected because of the amount of backwards and forwards.
Where it was really simple and where I'd use it over and over again was data extraction.
If you're trying to get data out of an image, this is a great tool and because you
can automate it, there's all sorts of use cases, but converting it into CSS was problematic.
part of the reason it's problematic is because there's another framework involved
and that's revealed js. So I can understand some of the challenges that it went through,
but I ran into a number of bugs and a number of going, one path, backtracking going
down another path.
so at the moment it's got some useful features, but generally this is not a use case
that I'd want to try again anytime soon.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe. And in the next video I'm going to be continuing
my journey with Aider.