Aider is an AI pair programmer that you can use through automation. And this week
I've been experimenting with it, and I thought I'd extend the presentation system
that we did in the previous video and try the image to code generation technique
and see if I can create some templates. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and
let's get into it.
So here we have the Canva template. And when we put it into Aider using the image
to CSS, this is what we got for our template system. When we looked at the second
template in the system, which looks great in Canva, it didn't look quite so good
once the image to CSS had been done.
third template that you can see here looks really good, just with a slightly different
layout.
So in the last video we created this presentation on Reveal.js. The infographics
were designed using napkin I. There is a link in the description, but all the code
was done using a single prompt, using a requirements to code technique that I use.
was all done with Aider AI Now if you want access to the code, you can come over
to the AppyDave repository. It's an organization and we've got Aider presentation
tool available. But what I thought we'd do today is improve the styling of the presentation.
And what I've done is come over to Canva and I've just picked an off the shelf presentation
template, and then I've restyled it a little bit just using my brand guidelines.
So let's see if we can convert these images into styling on Reveal.js presentations.
I've opened up the Aider AI documentation, and I've found this link images and web
pages. And the two that I think we're going to work with today will be the add by
file name or add by pasting.
Now let's go over to Visual Studio. And this is the project we developed a couple
of things to be aware of. There is an assets folder where we were putting the Scalable
Vector Graphics. There's a data folder which is where the slide deck is. And I've
just added a docs folder. Within that we've got the requirements document from the
last video. But we now have a list of images. So if we'll just click on a couple
of them
can see different mocks that I would like to turn into CSS.
Now I just wanna make a minor change before we add images. What I think we'll do
is we'll go over to the CSS area right here. And I'm just gonna put in a comment.
And the comment is just some named variables that I would like to,
utilize in the CSS. And what we can do from there is pop on over to the terminal
where I'm running the,
browser at the moment, or the reveal JS website. We'll open up a new terminal git
status, we've got a modification type in Aider. This will connect to Aider and we'll
be using the sonnet, 3.5 model at the moment. And what I'd like to do is say, I would
like
to use CSS variables,
CSS custom.
It asks if we want to add this into the chat window. The CSS file,
we're saying yes, and it starts rendering information for us. Now we can see here
that we've got variables coming through.
We've got these brand variables, and it looks like we've got some semantic naming
variables going on as well. So we'll just,
let's test it. Just check that it's all working.
So I've got the original website there. I'm just going to change this to Red so that
we see it for sure and press refresh. And there we have AppyDave
image and there we have it. AppyDave channels, images generated using napkin. Let's
just undo that for a second and refresh. And we're looking good.
Now I want to start by looking at the slides and the data that goes onto the slides.
So I've just put together this simple structure and there's three different concepts
that I'm trying to deal with here. The first is that you might have data points with
semantic meaning like main heading or subheading. The next is that you have data
points that map quite cleanly to HTML elements. And then the third one is just talking
about positioning top left right bottom images, in this case provided as Scalable
Vector graphics. Now the next thing I want to do and this is where we'll use Aider
is I want to add three more templates. And these are the look and feels that I want
to work with.
Now I'd like to use Aider to extract the data that's in these images and add it to
the templates here. So we've got template one, two, and three. They actually represent
slides. This is more the template definition and I want to create template four,
five, and six as data and slides. So what we'll do is we'll come down to Aider and
how about we say, can you add a new slide to, and what we need to do is put in the
file name, it's the JSON New, can you add a new slide to slides new? Call it template
four. And use this image to find the data. And we'll just put in one and there's
the image that we want
and we'll press yes.
So it started adding the concept of a template four. And let's see what it's done
here. We've got template four, social media strategy, and okay, this looks good.
Now I'm not sure whether I wanted to do that as two fields or one that wraps, but
I think we'll leave it at that for now.
We'll try. With the second image. We'll say, can you add a new slide to template
five using Slide New and use two dot jpeg?
we'll say yes. And hopefully what'll happen is we'll see today's presentation main
topic and then a bullet list. And all of this is meant to go in here. So there's
all the information. It's come through. We've got this image being referenced which
well we'll leave that there the way it is.
And here we are on to template number six which is using our third image. We'll let
that go through and see what happens. Now this is obviously not the image I want
to use, but there was an image on the page. So the fact that it found that is also
pretty handy. So if we look at this, we've got a name and a title that's looking
good. We've got position and description based as roles and then we've got an image
again. So Aider is excellent at reading the images just to capture the data. And
it's formatted it into the JSON document just following the patterns that we've used
before.
Now we've got our updated slide definition file. There's six different slides all
using a unique template. And you can see an image down below of the last presentation
we did. Now that used a different structure. And this is the structure here. We've
got a H1 and H2. And then we've got this scalable vector graphic going on at the
bottom. There's other slides going on and we can see the code. Now what we need to
do before we get started is rewrite all of this code.
because we have rewritten the JSON structure. And it now needs to support this modularized
templating system. So what we'll do is we'll just take a copy of this information.
So what I've done is pre-prepared a requirements document and we're just gonna say,
can you update it with the following? JSON, it needs to add three new template files
and we're gonna paste everything in and then we're just gonna let it do its job.
Now let's talk through what it's doing.
the provided code samples are not mandatory to use. The reason for this is that I've
done all this in Canvas. It's a great system, but I do want Aider to write the code
the way it thinks. It shouldn't be constrained by what I've given it. I've basically
told her it needs a template class for each template that we're doing plus a base
class, and that there'll be a presentation. I've also described the uh, data structure.
And so a lot of this requirements is in very human readable format that you could
just give to a developer.
we got the first three that I'd already set up manually,
we got the four new ones being added here. If we look at the base template class
as an example, if we go down to template four,
which is meant to map a H one and a H two plus a footer message, and then we've got
the date, and let's have a look at template
So it's got a H1 and H2 and a looping through the roles. Finally there's also an
image. And then at the bottom we've got this presentation class. So this is going
to be the requirements document that we're going to feed to Aider. So we'll just
click on this little button here.
Now I've put the requirements document into a file called to create presentation
class. Now number one is from the previous video where we built the Reveal.js presentation
system. One of the things I'd run into a few problems was trying to add it into the
chat interface. So we'll just add right now and I think it's going to work. We'll
just go to and we've got the file name there. Now, the reason I was having issues
adding files was that they'd been added to VS code, but they hadn't been committed.
So make sure it's committed if you want to see it work within Aider. So from here
let's test it out.
So I've said, can you recreate? And we'll just go with presentation.js
this is an example of where it doesn't find the right document. So I'm just going
to grab the relative link to this file and let's see what happens. It's adding the
presentation.js to the chat. And hopefully we're going to get a bunch of new code
written right here.
So it's reported that it's added a base template class. We've got a presentation
builder replacement by presentation class. We've got slide rendering and initialization
code changed. And just so you know you can also see the cost. So that's costing $0.04
at the moment. And if we look through the code we've got a template template one
two. Let's go down to about four where we remember what they were like. We've got
number six was a complex one. So we've got a H1 and H2. We've got an image and we've
got the position and description inside of a loop. We can see the presentation code
going on here. One minor change that I'm going to do myself is that it should be
pointing to slides new. So let's just change that to new and we'll hit save.