Aider is an AI pair programmer that you can use through automation. And this week
I've been experimenting with it, and I thought I'd extend the presentation system
that we did in the previous video and try the image to code generation technique
and see if I can create some templates. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and
let's get into it.
So here we have the Canva template. And when we put it into Aider using the image
to CSS, this is what we got for our template system. When we looked at the second
template in the system, which looks great in Canva, it didn't look quite so good
once the image to CSS had been done.
third template that you can see here looks really good, just with a slightly different
layout.
So in the last video we created this presentation on Reveal.js. The infographics
were designed using napkin I. There is a link in the description, but all the code
was done using a single prompt, using a requirements to code technique that I use.
was all done with Aider AI Now if you want access to the code, you can come over
to the AppyDave repository. It's an organization and we've got Aider presentation
tool available. But what I thought we'd do today is improve the styling of the presentation.
And what I've done is come over to Canva and I've just picked an off the shelf presentation
template, and then I've restyled it a little bit just using my brand guidelines.
So let's see if we can convert these images into styling on Reveal.js presentations.
I've opened up the Aider AI documentation, and I've found this link images and web
pages. And the two that I think we're going to work with today will be the add by
file name or add by pasting.
Now let's go over to Visual Studio. And this is the project we developed a couple
of things to be aware of. There is an assets folder where we were putting the Scalable
Vector Graphics. There's a data folder which is where the slide deck is. And I've
just added a docs folder. Within that we've got the requirements document from the
last video. But we now have a list of images. So if we'll just click on a couple
of them
can see different mocks that I would like to turn into CSS.
Now I just wanna make a minor change before we add images. What I think we'll do
is we'll go over to the CSS area right here. And I'm just gonna put in a comment.
And the comment is just some named variables that I would like to,
utilize in the CSS. And what we can do from there is pop on over to the terminal
where I'm running the,
browser at the moment, or the reveal JS website. We'll open up a new terminal git
status, we've got a modification type in Aider. This will connect to Aider and we'll
be using the sonnet, 3.5 model at the moment. And what I'd like to do is say, I would
like
to use CSS variables,
CSS custom.
It asks if we want to add this into the chat window. The CSS file,
we're saying yes, and it starts rendering information for us. Now we can see here
that we've got variables coming through.
We've got these brand variables, and it looks like we've got some semantic naming
variables going on as well. So we'll just,
let's test it. Just check that it's all working.
So I've got the original website there. I'm just going to change this to Red so that
we see it for sure and press refresh. And there we have AppyDave
image and there we have it. AppyDave channels, images generated using napkin. Let's
just undo that for a second and refresh. And we're looking good.
Now I want to start by looking at the slides and the data that goes onto the slides.
So I've just put together this simple structure and there's three different concepts
that I'm trying to deal with here. The first is that you might have data points with
semantic meaning like main heading or subheading. The next is that you have data
points that map quite cleanly to HTML elements. And then the third one is just talking
about positioning top left right bottom images, in this case provided as Scalable
Vector graphics. Now the next thing I want to do and this is where we'll use Aider
is I want to add three more templates. And these are the look and feels that I want
to work with.
Now I'd like to use Aider to extract the data that's in these images and add it to
the templates here. So we've got template one, two, and three. They actually represent
slides. This is more the template definition and I want to create template four,
five, and six as data and slides. So what we'll do is we'll come down to Aider and
how about we say, can you add a new slide to, and what we need to do is put in the
file name, it's the JSON New, can you add a new slide to slides new? Call it template
four. And use this image to find the data. And we'll just put in one and there's
the image that we want
and we'll press yes.
So it started adding the concept of a template four. And let's see what it's done
here. We've got template four, social media strategy, and okay, this looks good.
Now I'm not sure whether I wanted to do that as two fields or one that wraps, but
I think we'll leave it at that for now.
We'll try. With the second image. We'll say, can you add a new slide to template
five using Slide New and use two dot jpeg?
we'll say yes. And hopefully what'll happen is we'll see today's presentation main
topic and then a bullet list. And all of this is meant to go in here. So there's
all the information. It's come through. We've got this image being referenced which
well we'll leave that there the way it is.
And here we are on to template number six which is using our third image. We'll let
that go through and see what happens. Now this is obviously not the image I want
to use, but there was an image on the page. So the fact that it found that is also
pretty handy. So if we look at this, we've got a name and a title that's looking
good. We've got position and description based as roles and then we've got an image
again. So Aider is excellent at reading the images just to capture the data. And
it's formatted it into the JSON document just following the patterns that we've used
before.
Now we've got our updated slide definition file. There's six different slides all
using a unique template. And you can see an image down below of the last presentation
we did. Now that used a different structure. And this is the structure here. We've
got a H1 and H2. And then we've got this scalable vector graphic going on at the
bottom. There's other slides going on and we can see the code. Now what we need to
do before we get started is rewrite all of this code.
because we have rewritten the JSON structure. And it now needs to support this modularized
templating system. So what we'll do is we'll just take a copy of this information.
So what I've done is pre-prepared a requirements document and we're just gonna say,
can you update it with the following? JSON, it needs to add three new template files
and we're gonna paste everything in and then we're just gonna let it do its job.
Now let's talk through what it's doing.
the provided code samples are not mandatory to use. The reason for this is that I've
done all this in Canvas. It's a great system, but I do want Aider to write the code
the way it thinks. It shouldn't be constrained by what I've given it. I've basically
told her it needs a template class for each template that we're doing plus a base
class, and that there'll be a presentation. I've also described the uh, data structure.
And so a lot of this requirements is in very human readable format that you could
just give to a developer.
we got the first three that I'd already set up manually,
we got the four new ones being added here. If we look at the base template class
as an example, if we go down to template four,
which is meant to map a H one and a H two plus a footer message, and then we've got
the date, and let's have a look at template
So it's got a H1 and H2 and a looping through the roles. Finally there's also an
image. And then at the bottom we've got this presentation class. So this is going
to be the requirements document that we're going to feed to Aider. So we'll just
click on this little button here.
Now I've put the requirements document into a file called to create presentation
class. Now number one is from the previous video where we built the Reveal.js presentation
system. One of the things I'd run into a few problems was trying to add it into the
chat interface. So we'll just add right now and I think it's going to work. We'll
just go to and we've got the file name there. Now, the reason I was having issues
adding files was that they'd been added to VS code, but they hadn't been committed.
So make sure it's committed if you want to see it work within Aider. So from here
let's test it out.
So I've said, can you recreate? And we'll just go with presentation.js
this is an example of where it doesn't find the right document. So I'm just going
to grab the relative link to this file and let's see what happens. It's adding the
presentation.js to the chat. And hopefully we're going to get a bunch of new code
written right here.
So it's reported that it's added a base template class. We've got a presentation
builder replacement by presentation class. We've got slide rendering and initialization
code changed. And just so you know you can also see the cost. So that's costing $0.04
at the moment. And if we look through the code we've got a template template one
two. Let's go down to about four where we remember what they were like. We've got
number six was a complex one. So we've got a H1 and H2. We've got an image and we've
got the position and description inside of a loop. We can see the presentation code
going on here. One minor change that I'm going to do myself is that it should be
pointing to slides new. So let's just change that to new and we'll hit save.
Now, before we go through the changes that the code's created for the presentation,
let's look at the original presentation. And this was done in the previous video.
And one of the things that emphasizes is the use of infographics. In this case I'm
using napkin AI to generate them. There's a link in the description and we can see
this all coming together. It looked good. Let's see where we are now.
So we go over to the new presentation, and the first three slides that we got were
the ones that I generated when I was first creating the requirements document. And
one of the interesting edge cases I wanted to deal with was images in four quadrants.
So we've got the four images being shown. They will need to be positioned, but then
we move on to the three slides that were created from the mocks. So we've got the
first one. The second one. You can see part of the image from that mock down below,
and it's pulled it in because this particular mock had an image and it just happened
to use the mock as the example. But otherwise the rest of the data came from this
slide deck. And we can see it here. We've got Byron, we've got CEO of and that's
coming from this information here, followed by the repeating groups which were social
media strategist and marketing expert. So the structure of our presentation looks
to be working okay.
Now we're about to start styling our slides using the mocks, but before we do, we've
got a little bit of setup so we can see over here on the right that we've got all
the CSS classes for Reveal.js all set up and ready to go, and that's what we've been
using throughout. We've also got our branding colors coming through. Now if we look
over here, we've got all these HTML templates that we've set up for each of the slide.
But what we don't have is a CSS selector that we can target in on.
Now I'm going to try the Aider watch files technique. I've had a few issues with
this. This doesn't always work for me, but we'll see what we get. And I'm just going
to put in a comment and paste in this prompt. Can you make sure that the template
HTML includes a template number class for each section? Now the important thing to
do here is just say I will also put in an exclamation mark and I hit save. And it
looks like it might be working through this particular request. So if everything
works okay, I'm hoping to see a template one, two and three over here. So let's see
what's happening here. We've got class template one template two three, four five
and six. So perfect.
Now it worked Okay. For code, let's see what happens with CSS.
Now we have our custom CSS file. It's all got standard reveal sort of formatting
going on. I'd like to add some templates to the bottom here. So let's just put in
a CSS comment. We'll go like that and we'll paste in.
Can you update with placeholders for template one to six using ai?
Now I'll hit save. And one of the things I notice is that in this particular situation,
nothing changes. When you read the documentation, it says that it's looking for hashes
or slashes at the beginning of a line. So what I'll do is I'll just put this in and
just see if this is good enough. Now it's not, and we'll try the hash just for good
measure and we'll cut this out and press save and go. Let's do it differently and
say, can you
update custom CSS with, and we'll just paste it in
And hopefully we'll get the changes this way
so we can see all the changes starting to come through at the moment.
And so it's put in a lot of CSS. This is actually not what I wanted because I really
only wanted some start placeholders, but I think since it's done it, we should at
least test it out.
So here's a side by side comparison. On the left, we've got the older version and
we've got the newer version on the right. So we'll just move forward and old. And
the new one is just looking a little bit different. We've got this gradient effect
going on right here. We'll go and have a look at these images. We wanna see 'em in
four quadrants, and that seems to be working okay. We move on to the fourth one and
it's just a little bit different look and feel. In fact, this looks good. This is
meant to be a footer. So the basic changes are looking
pretty good to me.
and if we move on to the sixth one, what do we get?
This looks quite a bit different. In fact, this is nice that it's showing the image
in a circle. Now the reality is this is not following the mocks, but this is a pretty
good starting point for our styling, for each of the different templates.
So here's the first design that we want to work with. We've got one dot jpeg and
we're meant
template number four so that it looks like and we'll just type in one dot jpeg and
we'll press enter and see what happens. So we've got changes coming through for template
four. There's a fair few coming in
and it's told us what it's done including the split color design. Let's go see how
it looks.
So here we have the old, which I really like. Let's go look at the new. And the new
is looking very close to the mark, except for two things. We've got this social media
heading, one which should just be above the line here. And this strategy should definitely
be down below.
I've taken a screenshot of the current example, and I've said the H1 should be slightly
higher and not overlapping the brown area, and the H2 should be the same size as
the H1, and it should be over the brown area.
So I've just taken a screenshot of this particular page
and I'll just see if I can paste it in. Now that's not working. So there's a bit
of confusion about how to use this.
Oh bloody hell.
So moving on to mock number two. We got it over here on the right and it's mapping
to template number five. So we'll just put in can you update template five in custom
CSS so that it looks like. And we'll just put in two dot jpeg and press enter. It'll
add it to the chat and it seems to have hung. So one of the things you might have
noticed is that there's been a few different bugs that I'm dealing with as I'm working
with Aider, so there's still some areas of improvement just in the basic usability.
So what I think we'll do is we'll just cut this all the way out and start again.
So new setup and we'll just say two dot jpeg. And that's looking good. We'll say
yes and we'll say yes. So that added in the custom CSS and added in the JPEG. And
the code that we're hoping will change is just in here. We can see it coming through
at the moment
and it's about to change right now I'm assuming. Oh look at that, I haven't. There's
another thing to be aware of. If you change things here, you you might have a little
bit of conflict. So if I hit save yeah. Let's just remove that altogether. And now
we do have a complete set of changes to template five highlighting. Yet another challenge
to be aware of is that if you have left some edits in some code but you haven't saved
it, then it's going to cause a little bit of a conflict when Aider starts generating
code.
So here we have a few problems. It's getting close. One of the things it's done is
it's missed the main topic. So we need to get that in. And everything should be on
the right and vertical. So we can see today's presentation in the middle. And we've
got the bullet points here. Also I think just the graphics itself with this little
yellow box got a little bit confusing for it. I'm going to actually describe everything
in a prompt and see if I can fix it.
Now here we have our reference or our mock image on the left, and we've got the updated
slide on the right. It's starting to look close to what I want, but the problem I
had was I actually had to use a whole lot of standard prompt engineering to get it
looking like this. I didn't find in this second example that the image to CSS was
working too well for me.
So for our third test we're going to try and get the HTML that's on the right looking
like the mock that's on the left. Now this is known as template six in the system.
And what I've done is I've got this image here of the mock. But I've also got an
image of what it currently looks like. We should be able to feed them both into Aider.
So I'm just going to start by adding a couple of files.
we'll add in 3.jpeg and we'll let that go into the system. And we will add in current.png
And that's my example of what it currently looks like.
So I'm just saying can you update template six in the custom
I've given the currently looking image and we'll see what happens. And I'm not sure
whether it's going to change CSS and template. But here it is starting to generate.
And so it's made a change to template six. Let's test it out.
So here's what it's come up with in both desktop mode and mobile mode. So we can't
see the yellow box there isn't the vertical alignment going
So I played around with a few prompts. And firstly I added in this current image
which is the top left hand image. And I also did a current mobile so I could see
different points of view.
then I just told it that I wanted it to notice the yellow in the top, the white in
the bottom, the image on the right and the vertical alignment of the different text.
Now it told me that it needed some extra information, which I gave it in the form
of the presentation JS and the custom CSS, and it generated a whole lot of code for
us. Let's have a look at what that looks like.
And now we're starting to look on point. Now there are differences, but in some respects
I like it the way it is. So let's put the image up in the top right hand corner.
It needs to be moved down to the middle. And these two areas need to be on top of
each other. But at the moment they look quite clean the way they are. So I might
actually leave this template the way it is.
As a recap, let's have a look at how they looked in Canva and how they look in Reveal.js.
So it's looking pretty good. It would need a little bit of work, but I like where
it's at. If we look at the next template, this one didn't work out so well when I
moved it over to reveal, so this would require a little bit of manual. Changing the
image to CSS was a bit problematic with this one, but the last one actually worked
quite well, though it gave a little bit different look and feel, but this is something
I could work with. So in this experience, the image to CSS for Reveal.js it worked
okay, but here's my final thoughts.
So here's a honest assessment of Aider in the area of converting images into code
and other data structures.
Mostly this was painful. This might have looked okay, but the video probably took
me three times as long as I expected because of the amount of backwards and forwards.
Where it was really simple and where I'd use it over and over again was data extraction.
If you're trying to get data out of an image, this is a great tool and because you
can automate it, there's all sorts of use cases, but converting it into CSS was problematic.
part of the reason it's problematic is because there's another framework involved
and that's revealed js. So I can understand some of the challenges that it went through,
but I ran into a number of bugs and a number of going, one path, backtracking going
down another path.
so at the moment it's got some useful features, but generally this is not a use case
that I'd want to try again anytime soon.
I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe. And in the next video I'm going to be continuing
my journey with Aider.