Now, as we get to the technical considerations, we learn that it's not really doing
what I want. We'll come back and look at why it's not working. But the reason for
this is that the Bmad method is designed, and particularly this agent that we're
working with,
the analyst agent is around creating applications. So you might want to create some
sort of C sharp command line tool. Or
you might want to create a web application using React and Convex as a database.
And for this
and for these sorts of problems, Bmad is ideally suited.
but when we look at the technical considerations, we see that it looks kind of okay.
But on reading individual lines, you start to see that it's fairly off the mark at
the moment. So let's go into what's wrong and then how we could maybe fix this.
So let's try and understand the Bmad method. So I have this second brain set up to
point at version four and version six of the Bmad method, and that allows me to do
some Q&A against either system.
And in version six we have access to something called the Bmad builder module,
and with it we could customize our agents, our workflows, or the modules that are
used under the hood.
And one of the things it has is the ability to edit a workflow, which is what I believe
I'd like to do today.
Now, understanding custom workflows and custom agents is a whole nother video, so
we'll do that in the future.
But let's have a look at what we could do with Bmad method version four. And in this
particular case it's the technical considerations, which is one of the workflows
within Bmad. For that we either need to edit or we're just going to override.
So let's get into the technical considerations and just see where it might have gone
off kilter. So firstly, the fact that it can run on cloud code as the primary with
a backup system being cursor or codex is correct. The idea that it's not a web application.
So no web browser requirements, just API requirements is not quite correct, but also
the fact that it's mentioned as a front end being Astro and the back end being TypeScript
is correct kind of, but this is actually a submodule. It's a tool really, that's
going to be used by the poem system. So the main application is not the astro concepts,
it's actually the poem framework. And then after that some extra tooling or a submodule
would be the astro application.
Then we get into the database. And a lot of what I'm talking about here is really
subtle, but it will screw up the system if we don't get it right. And it's the idea
that in the future there's a database, well, that's not needed at all. So we can
remove that. But all of these files being the backend sort of system isn't correct.
So if we think of an Astro application, it might have some backend data in the form
of Jason or Markdown documents. But all of these files are actually part
of a different folder called poem. This is where we create our templates.
This is where we create our different workflows for prompt engineering. And so if
they're used inside of the Astro application, it's because they're given to it, not
because they're part of the backend system or the database.
And then when we get to the infrastructure and hosting, well, this is not even relevant
the way we're
doing this sort of application. So what I've already seen so far is that this is
building it directly for some sort of full stack application, which is not what we're
trying to do.
Now when we get to the repository structure, this is pretty good. We've got this
monorepo concept with packages for the core and the app. There's also a location
for where poem is. What is not clear here is how it actually runs on someone else's
system. So how I develop the framework is one thing, but how it's installed elsewhere
is another thing. So we've gotta consider whether it's getting this correct at the
moment. Now we get to the service architecture. This is quite correct.
the only thing is that I would want it to say that this is an instance web server
that gets created for each individual poem implementation. So the fact that it says
configurable is correct, but there's not this clarity that this is an internal service
that needs to be made available. And if you're running two poem projects,
You need two Astro servers.
Now we've got integration requirements. Again, everything here looks good, but understanding
how the bmad method would work, it would start building each of these probably sequentially.
And this would be incorrect approach. So if we look at these support signal convex,
this will not be part of poem at all. What will happen is that when I'm using poem,
I'll want to be able to connect to external systems, and at that point in time, I'll
create one of these. So what we need is more tooling that allows us to create a provider
rather than an actual implementation of the provider within this framework.
The actual Claude code slash commands. This is interesting. We do need it, but this
is such a small little utility object. This is a small utility story that might happen
towards the end. It's like how do we connect it all up?
Now the handlebars js, this is important, but this is going to live with inside this
service architecture. So we just need to make sure that there's a clear separation.
the more I look at this technical requirements, the more I realize it might've been
useful to create two different Bmad PRDs,
one for the poem core and the other one for the poem app.
Then we consider faker, which is great. The only challenge we're going to have here
is that we don't fully understand our mock generation system. So this is quite a,
in the future sort of idea,
security and compliance, this is actually pretty good.
And then it's listing the trade offs. I'm pretty happy with these. So we've got astro
and
good developer experience. So this is great. We've got our assumptions. This is all
good. And we've got our technical risks.
So after talking for three minutes and reading through this, and I know that last
night when I looked at this, I thought this was all off kilter. The more I think
about it, the more I realize it's probably okay. And what I'm going to do is include
this video as a separate video, not part of the main video,