An hour ago this awesome feature got added to ChatGPT. Now I hadn't seen it I
hadn't heard about it but here it is it's called the app mention and what it's
done is allowed me to create the video you're watching right now in about one
hour using four or five GPTs all working in orchestration. It's just magical. So
we're in a brand new ChatGPT window and if I type in the app symbol we'll have
access to a bunch of GPTs that you've either used or created many of these
I've created so if we look at F Tube teaser this turns a YouTube video into
a Facebook teaser post got the same thing for tweets I can make YouTube
intros and recently I did seven GPTs specifically for YouTube content
creators you can check that out in the link I think we'll play around with
TweetTube. I learned about this feature about 10 minutes ago when I was just in
ChatGPT and a little dialogue came up talking about app mention. Now I hadn't
heard about it I don't know what it is just yet so we're going to use ChatGPT
to learn about it and if it does what I think it does we'll get it to create a
tweet based on the video I'm doing right now using one of the GPTs I've
already done. What's really interesting is that even though this feature exists
I'm not finding any references anywhere about it. My first spot of call has been
to ask a question within ChatGPT and get it to use Bing. Unfortunately the
specific details about app mention feature are not well known. Okay well
where do I go next and the best place would be to go to Google so I've headed
over to Google and what is the app mention feature in ChatGPT plus there's
the 27th of January 2024. One of the next steps I would go to is just look in
the news because news is the same as the main page of Google but it's very
timely. If we click here and use the same feature we've got some information from
a week ago we've got some information from November 15th. This feature is in
ChatGPT I've seen it but it's not been talked about just yet so I think we'll
move on to the next step and let's figure out how to use it together. I've
just started writing a prompt here called imagine you ChatGPT plus had a
feature built in whereby you used the app symbol to make GPTs that I have
created or used available for use when I'm writing prompts. Now this is a
hallucination now you've heard about hallucinations in GPT where it goes
off and does stuff that's not real. Well this is a human hallucination because I
have no idea what this feature does just that I've seen it. What I'm going to do
is kind of guess what I think it'll do put in this particular statement I
might just build it up and say how do you think I would use this feature what
problems does it solve and what are five use cases and let's just see what
ChatGPT might come up for this particular scenario. ChatGPT has taken my
hallucination of what this feature might be and written what I consider a
pretty compelling use case and feature if this is how it works. So if ChatGPT
plus had a feature that allowed you to use an app symbol to access and use
different GPT models that you've used or created it would be a powerful tool for
various applications. Here's how you might use this feature. You could quickly
switch between different GPT models tailored for specific tasks or expertise.
So recently I did seven or eight videos on GPTs that I created around content
creation. I wanted to deal with writing a YouTube intro based of everything I
said in the video or a YouTube outro based off not only what I said in the
video but other videos in the series that I want to link to. I've also got GPTs
that allow me to share my videos as tweets, LinkedIn posts, Facebook teasers
and even write the YouTube description. What is painful about using these GPTs
at the moment is that I've got to create a brand new chat window and load it up
with context each time. Now if we could do something like this switch from GPT
to GPT from the same conversation that would be an incredible feature. Now it
goes on with the problem set it solves to talk about some of the things I just
mentioned specialisation each of those bots that I like to create are really
specialised GPT agents. It's this one context management. Registers the need
to repeatedly explain the context or reorient AI. That would be an
interesting capability. What's I find interesting around the five here is that
the first four of them are based on GPTs that I've been creating so content
strategy and development I specialise in GPTs for YouTube content creation and
especially with SEO educational purposes. I'm in the middle of doing a series
called the tutors and it's basically a bunch of tutor bots for learning
complex software applications. I also have a programming language that I'm
developing called Clueless GPT meta language and I'm doing this sort of
stuff all the time though I don't have any GPTs specifically in this area. I
haven't done much here. If this works the way it's describing here I'm going to
be really happy with this new feature. What I think I'll do is I'll just use
speech to text and we'll just type a prompt right now. Everything that we've
talked about above is exactly what this feature is about. What I would like you
to do is take the information and run it through my Twitter creation bot and
create a tweet for me. What we'll do is we'll just type at tweet tube. Talking to
cheek tube is what it does and we've just got this prompt and press enter and
we'll see whether it does what I expect it to do. Wow this is it. It's writing
tweets the way my tweet tube bot does so discover the power of customisation with
specialized GPT models for tailored responses. Perfect for content strategists,
educators, tech pros, writers and polyglots. That's people that work in
multiple languages. It's putting a bunch of hashtags. One of the problems I tend
to have with my tweet bot is sometimes it's a couple of letters over the 144
character length. Sometimes you've got to modify a bit but usually this is a one
hit wonder. I'm really happy with this. This is cool already. I'm already sold
on this feature but maybe I could create an intro for this particular video that
I'm recording. I think what I'll do is I'll create the YouTube intro for this
video but I'm a little confused at the moment. It says I'm still talking to the
tweet tube so I believe we'll just press this cross. Looks good. Type in can you
take me over to the at YouTube intro GPT and allow me to configure it so that we
can create a YouTube intro for this particular video. Looks like I might have
to type this in so we'll go intro maker, press enter. It's taken me over to my bot
and my bot has basic configuration in it. The YouTube intro maker bot has a
configuration capability. Now it talks about it here. The niche we're going for
is GPT plus. The topic is that there's a feature announcement called at mentions
in chat GPT plus. Now the framework you can use marketing frameworks like AIDA
and Paz. Paz is problem agitation solution but I like to keep things fairly
simple so I'll go with none. Keep it simple and the structure I think we want
is problem solution. What's problem? Here's the solution and the tone excited. I
think this is an awesome feature but keep it professional. Just press enter on
that. I think we can just say create is one of the commands. I think we'll copy
from here all the way through fact sheet that you would want for a script on
this sort of video. We'll move down to the bottom and we'll just say create an
intro based on this concept. We have a Stata intro script. Welcome to the future
of AI customization and efficiency. Today we're unveiling an extraordinary
feature in chat GPT plus. The at feature is simply a powerful tool that's
changing the game. Problem highlight. Have you ever found yourself wishing for a
more specialized, efficient and integrated AI experience? This is my issue all the
time with chat GPT. One that understands your specific needs without having to
switch contacts or explain repeatedly. You're waited over and then the solution.
With the at feature in chat GPT plus you now have the ability to quickly access
various GPT models tailored for unique tasks and areas of expertise. Now it goes
on. It's got use cases. I wouldn't work with this because personally want to use
use cases that I've created myself. What we could do is just say this intro is
really good. I love the first three paragraphs but it's way too long at the
moment. Everything goes for about one minute and 30 seconds to two minutes. I
really need this to be a 30 second script. It's now writing a new script for us.
Welcome to a revolutionary feature in chat GPT plus the at tool. Transforming
AI interactions into tailored experience. Ever needed a more specialized AI
response? Instantly the at feature is your solution. Just type at followed by
your desired GPT models name and seamlessly switch between tasks and
conversations or within a single chat interface from at SEO model for marketing
insights to at Python helper for coding support. Embrace the new era of specialized
AI with chat GPT plus experience efficiency and customization like never
before. With a little bit of tweaking would be a good introduction to the video.
I think while we're at it let's just switch one more context. Can you create
an article for me on LinkedIn at link tube? And the idea of the link tube
article generator is it's a single shot prompt. It'll get it right most times.
It's designed specifically around turning YouTube videos into LinkedIn articles.
Now this was a little unexpected. I know what the issue is.
Certainly I can use the feature and need a bit more information like target
audience key message. I use commands to drive my GPTs and I didn't use a
command this time so it's gone into the automatic configuration options.
Don't really need that. I'm just going to say create and I'm going to paste this in
which is basically the script from earlier. Usually when I do a create command for a
LinkedIn post I would also give it the title and the YouTube video but we haven't
created the YouTube video yet so we can't do that. Just go create like that and see
what happens now. We've got a title which may be the title that we want to use.
I would usually use my title GPT to generate this revolutionizing AI
interactions the app feature in chat GPT plus. I think that might be good enough
for the video anyway. Introduction in the ever-evolving world of artificial
intelligence. We've got concepts problems practical use cases and conclusions.
Can you add emojis and hashtags please let it rewrite the article now with a
couple of emojis so that when I paste it into my LinkedIn page it just looks nicer.
We've got our LinkedIn article written. There's a couple of hashtags going on down the end.
Let's finish off the video and we might as well use the outro GPT to do that.
Tube outro writer and we're in it and we'll just go straight into a config.
So we'll just configure it and we'll go with a style here called recap so whatever
we've said in the video we want to recap it but I only want it to go for about 15 seconds
and I want to have a link to a playlist. I believe in this case I've done YouTube
automation GPTs. There's a bunch of them all in a playlist and that's what we should mention.
Let's just type create should be enough. That's a wrap on the revolutionary app feature in chat
GPT plus. Tailor your AI interactions with ease. Switch between specialized models and
unlock new levels of efficiency and customization. The future of AI is here and it's personalized.
Explore more on AI advantages in our YouTube automation GPTs playlist. Link displayed on the
side. Stay ahead with the latest AI trends. Usually when I do my outros for videos I use
a teleprompter and I'll read the script that we were just looking at. Now I'm going to do that
but I'm going to look at the script that I just created. I'm not going to pre-prepare it. I'm not
going to do any editing. We'll just use it the way it is. So it goes that's a wrap on the revolutionary
app feature in chat GPT plus. Tailor your AI interactions with ease. Switch between specialized
models and unlock new levels of efficiency and customization. The future of AI is here and
it's personalized. Explore more on AI advancements in our YouTube automation GPTs playlist.
Stay ahead with the latest in AI tech. I'm Appy Dave and I hope you enjoyed this
news release on the app mention feature.