Is it possible to create an AI pair programmer as code coding language? In this video,
I'm looking to hook up a domain specific language to an Aider application running
within a web server. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Now, if you don't know what Aider AI is, its essentially an AI pair programmer that
you can run either within a terminal or from the command line. And the first video
in this series I show how to install and get it running with a basic application.
I then moved on to the second video in the series, in which I created some presentation
software using Reveal.js and Scalable Vector Graphics, and you can find the repo
here at AppyDave.
We then took that presentation a step further in the third video, using Aider image
to code generation techniques, we were able to generate both data and CSS files based
off mocks that we'd created in Canva.
Now, in this video, I want to take a little application that we developed in the
fourth video, where we were iterating over dozens of files to create documentation
for id Software's Doom, and that particular documentation came out looking in markdown
format. But it's that particular tool that I want to hook up to a programming language
so that we can call a web server
So the web server that we created in the fifth video hosts Aider I behind a RESTful
endpoint. And today what we're going to do is create an AI programmer as code coding
language to talk to this web server.
So for this test case, I thought we'd create a folder called Aider Klue playground.
I'll talk about what Klue is in a moment, and we'll be working on creating some code
or reports,
where we should start is just go to the game of doom by id software. They've got
a lot of code files that we can work through. We've got header and C files. We've
got all the documentation that we created in the last video,
and
we can use our little programming language to talk with this repo and write to this
repo.
So I think how we can start is with the little web server that we created the other
day.
we'll just start that on a particular port, and we can test it with a curl command.
That's just giving some instructions and the location of the target folder.
We'll just copy the path from the playground. And we're going to put in some code
here. So let's just change that right there. And we'll create an instruction. And
the instruction I think we should go with is create reader JS. It should read the
column names. And the column names are going to come from this table of contents
CSV that I've put together. And from there we just want to print it out into a tabular
report. So we'll just bring it all into one line. We'll copy that and we'll come
over to this instruction and we'll paste it in here. And from this point we should
just be able to run it from the command line.
So we'll make sure that we're on the right port and we'll put everything onto one
particular line. And from there, we should just be able to copy it and paste it directly
in here. Now the curl request doesn't really matter where it runs. It just needs
to point at the web server and have a folder where it would like code to be written.
So at the moment it's writing some code. We've got a yes. So we'll want to automate
that in this particular video. We didn't automate it in the last one. And what should
be happening is we've just had a file created that's looking good.
a quick node install and we'll just put in some data. We'll put in one, two, three
and we'll just run this reader and see what we get. And we are reading the file.
So we've got a little bit of code running.
So what I want to test now is just the gathering of files. So we've got the documentation
for the doom application here. And if we look at the doom application we've got H
files C files we've got docs. And if we run a little GPT context tool, which is what
we're going to run the behind the scenes with the coding language, we should get
a list of all the files. Now, if we just run that one more time and we'll just do,
say the H files, we should just get a list of the files that are headers
and we can take this a little bit further and just say we want the IPX folder and
see what we get there. So we've just got four directories. So this is what we're
hooking up to our DSL.
When we were generating documentation for doom, this was the technique we used. But
instead of using tree format, we used the Aider format and we would build up prompts
basically on the same sort of files that we just saw listed there. But let's now
move this into a coding language, which will be a lot easier to work with.
Now to get started. We'll come over to our playground here. We'll go new file and
the file will go with is get docs, I think. Sounds good. We'll call it clue. This
will make sense a bit later. So we've got this new file and we'll just put in some
sort of structure. So I'll go with talk to Aider for want of a better word.
So next we'll go down to the terminal and we'll put in this command called Langcraft.
And I'm going to show you the video that this is related to. And we're just going
to watch the folder that we're on and format for enhanced output. So what happens
now when we come here and we hit save. We should get a new file created next to it.
So we'll just move that down below. And we can see that whatever we put in here,
if we say x-men and we say do and we say end and we hit save, we'll get a new value
called X-Men.
Now having a node called x mean is not very useful. But if we look at the doom with
dots folder, what we should be able to do instead is replace this with something
called file collector. And with that we just list the actual folder we want to collect
from. Now, if we hit save on this, what should happen is we get that information
coming through. Plus it's figured out where there might be files to work with. So
let's see if we can now populate this with a set of files.
When we run it from the command line, we did GPT context, we had the folder that
we wanted to work with and we did the IPX directory, *. H. What we'll do over here
is we'll put in our files node and we'll say include, and it's going to work from
the same folder as we have here. We'll just work with the C files. And for now, let's
do everything. So we get everything and we get all the files that are in the IPX
directory. We get all the files that are in the DOOM directory.
so if we come up here and we say IPX and we hit save, we should get a smaller set
of files. So we've just got three. And the good thing is we've also got the content
of each of these files. Now, just like the command line one, we can also do exclusions.
So if we type in exclude, and let's just go IPX,
and we'll just say Doom star and hit save. The one of these files should just disappear
for us. So we
We've got the IPX set up. And again, if we want to come out and get the MD files,
And I might want to exclude the README files that have the lowercase read in front
of them. So these two files that are just here should disappear when I hit save.
Now you may be wondering, where did this bin langcraft come from? So a couple of
months ago I did these videos on AI programming languages. Building one. We've got
one called Build Your Own Programming Language, where I work with the GPT context
gatherer. To do that, there's also the 1000 file changes, which is where I'm working
with Cursor, AI and Git diff to do bulk updates.
So check out those videos if you want to understand more how I'm going from coding
language to data using this little watcher.
The next thing I would like to do is take the information that we've got here and
make it available to our aider web server.
if we go back and have a look at the terminal where we're running the aider web server,
we can see that it's running on a particular port. Now I'm just going to take a copy
of that.
And this will be useful because one of the parameters is a webhook URL that we can
call. So if we restart this and we'll put in dash you and we'll just paste that value
in. And as it restarts now when we hit save it should pass it to an endpoint. Now
that's probably not the endpoint we want. Let's just call it X-Men for now.
We're going to have to handle this incoming data in the Aider web server.
So we'll come over to the Aider web server and we'll implement this X-Men routine.
So to start off with, we could have a look at the original Code Assistant, which
is what we'll use Aider to do the work, but we're not quite ready for that. Instead,
we'll just put in a stub, we'll call it X-Men, and all it really needs to do is read
the incoming data and check that. That's okay. So hit save on that.
So we'll hit save on that and we'll head over to the terminal and we'll restart the
server
it should get sent through to the X-Men folder. One of the things that should happen
along the way is this file should get updated. So what we'll do is we'll just clear
that out for now and we'll hit save. And let's see what happens. So it's been updated
with data.
it's come through to the X-Men endpoint and we can see that the information is coming
in here.
One of the things that you can notice is there's a clue type. It's called talk to
aider. So if we really wanted to change the nature of the programming language,
we might wanna call it AI pair coder, and this information could come through
We should see that coming in right here
Now I've made a few changes to the X-Men routine. I want to bring it into alignment
with the original code assistant, and it could take in an instruction, a list of
files, directories, etc. now, the only thing that we're interested in right now are
the files. So the files are being processed down here. As for an instruction, we'll
just go with tell me something would be useful
and we'll get it to just print out some information in the console. So if we come
down here we've got the IPX MD files. If we hit save on that we should get an update.
And we can see the files to be processed are coming through. If we get rid of the
IPX and go for the whole system, we should just get a lot more from multiple subfolders.
Let's try and expand this X-Men function. So it has more in common with the code
assistant. So currently it can take these various options in.
this has only got a fixed instruction and it will collect the files, but we better
go and update our little programming language, which is this one here on the left,
it can support these concepts.
we can just make this up and I'm just gonna call it rules for now. And within the
rules we might say that instruction, which we will have it mapped to something is,
tell me something more. So just a slightly different value coming in on that we could
put in the model, but I won't do that for now. I will do the directory 'cause I think
that will be a useful,
concept for us to put in place.
And I've just put in this value where we want to write code to. So this is where
we're reading information from. Then we're sending it to Aider. And Aider has been
given an instruction and the list of files that it needs to work with. And we have
the directory we would like Aider to work into. Now if I hit save at the moment,
what will happen is we will get an enhanced document that's now a little bit different.
It's got rules in it, it's got the instruction, the directory, it's got the file
collector. And if we look down lower, it's still got, the files that have been processed
are all going through to this endpoint. But the endpoint at the moment doesn't know
how to handle these two parameters. So we just need to hook it up.
So the code has been updated with a bunch of rules, and we'll just paste them in
and we can just restart the web server.
these values should come through and get printed out. So it's a dry run, meaning
we're not actually going to invoke Aider when we set this to true. There is an instruction
we'll just say whatever in here
and we can see that that's coming through. There would be the target folder or project
that we'd like to write to. And then there's the list of files. Now I've also put
in this model as default. We'll let Aider figure that out for itself. But we could
override it if we want. And the confirm is basically the idea of should it automatically
write files yes or no?
This will be the incoming path that we come in on. We'll start the Python server
that's now running. Let's go and start the langwatch. But let's make sure that the
web hook that it talks to is this new value called clue. And we'll press enter on
that and we'll leave dry run turned on
So we've got an instruction coming through, we've got a directory, which is not correct.
We're on a dry run, which is great. Let's just change the dry run to false and see
what happens. Especially considering we don't have a good directory name.
and it's reporting an error that no such file or directory exists, which is great.
Now what I wanna do is the first test. Now I don't think I've got the alignment quite
correct with this, but let's talk through it. We're going to read from this folder
here, which is the Doom with docs. And we're specifically looking at the IPX directory,
the markdown documents. There's three of them going on here. Now if we go and hit
save, we can see that the information should come through.
But if we look at the JSON document, we can see the content for each of these three
files. But this information isn't currently being used in aider only the file name
is being used. And this could be a bit of an issue. What we'll also do, we've got
dry run turned off,
we've got update the TOCs CSV file, which is this file here,
and we just need to change the directory. So we'll change it to this and we'll hit
save and let's see what starts to happen. So it says it's creating three files. Now
why is that? Because there's already three files that exist, and it's because when
we set the target, which is here, this is in an area
that doesn't have those files. So they're being created for us.
and it's telling me to please provide the contents of the TOC file. So the first
thing I think we need to do is bring it back to just one directory.
So where we read from and where we write to probably need to be the same with the
current state of the application.
So reading from here will
going to write into this project and we're going to read from this project. So we've
got the reading okay. But the writing is not in the right location. So what we'll
do is we'll change the folder that it's writing to. The other thing is that it will
want access to the TOC.CSV, but we haven't included it in our files when we're talking.
So let's just go include and we'll say TOC.CSV. But I'm also going to take a copy
of the one that we had in this project, and I'm just going to make it available within
this project.
we've got a bunch of information being changed.
So we've had some partial success. We can see the name of the file coming through.
We can see a description, but I can't quite tell whether it's a good description.
what I've gone and done is create a cat and a markdown document. We'll see what happens
there. Then in the prompt originally I talked about 25 words and it's kind of put
the 25 words here.
I've just modified this instruction a little bit, see if we can get better data.
And I might even just delete everything that's in here. Lastly, let's improve this
so that we're also getting all the markdown documents and see what happens. So
Now it's a little bit better on the descriptions. It's also got some numbers that
are looking closer, but they're not actually accurate.
and then it's got this opinion about the cat,
and then there's a story about a fox jumping over lazy dog and then moving over the
sleeping cat. So this all seems good.
so if we make this a double asterisk, we should now be able to work through another
60 odd files.
And so now it's working through all the different files that are in the Linux Doom
directory.
So at this point I hit a token limit
I've just gone and changed it to just the I underscore files
And let's just bring in anything that starts with a P as well.
Now you can see that we were able to read through all the markdown documents by just
saying, including star, star markdown. We said update the table of contents CSV,
and we're basically got a summary of each of the markdown documents.
I made a couple of syntax changes by loading in, for instance, prompts that we might
want to use from the file system. So there's a complex prompt that we're about to
go through. And it's just being interpolated into a pre prompt right here along with
folders being loaded in. I've also changed it from taught to Aider to just plain
Aider. And that just required that the web server be modified to deal with this new
node coming in.
we have our aider coding construct here, and it's going to read from the Doom Documentation
folder, which is here, but specifically it's only going to look in the IPX directory
for the C files. And there's about three of them listed in this area. And after that
we're going to do it as a dry run. So we'll only get data for now where it has a
prompt called Create code file text for each file based on a prompt. And the prompt
is going to be read from a file and we can see the information here. And this is
basically turning C and header files into a format that's readable by a non-developer.
So it's just a human readable context going on. And we've got a few other options.
we can see information from the file here. We've got unions, compact memory representations
here at the end of the prompt, we've got the folder that we are loading in from.
And we can notice that the three C files have also been loaded along with their content.
Finally, we can remove the dry run flag from the Aider code script. It'll run the
pre prompt plus the complex prompt, which is going to turn all the C and header files
into formats that are human readable. We're going to read from the doom with docs
folder.
specifically only get the ipx c files. So when we hit save on this, we end up getting
code being generated by Aider for each of the C files. We've also updated the JSON
document so we can see the individual files that are going to be worked with. We
can even see the content that's going to be merged into the documentation.
So the first file called IPX nets can be created. So we'll say yes and we'll say
yes to doom net and yes to IPX setup dot txt. And we can see the code getting generated
to go into these files.
The final output is three meta documents. We've got doom net with the function launch,
doom and three global variables, and then we go on to IPX setup where we've got check,
param and net ISR.
So finally we have our domain specific language called KlueLess, which is allowing
us to talk to Aider via a scripting language where it can read files from various
locations and call the Aider API using the web server that we built in the last video
to generate code.
is just a proof of concept to talk to the Aider AI pair programmer, but it's part
of a broader set of semantically friendly coding languages that I'm exploring so
that I can communicate with large language models in a more effective manner. So
if this is a topic you're interested in, please like and subscribe. I'm AppyDave.
I'll see you in the next video.