In this video, I'm testing how to do better prompts by using anthropics prompt generation
tool.
Back in May. Anthropic released a prompt generation tool within their console, and
they've got this blog post that says, you can now generate production ready prompt
templates using Anthropic console and using techniques such as chain of thought reasoning.
Now, if you head over to their documentation, they basically say sometimes the hardest
part of using AI model is figuring how to prompt it effectively to help, we've created
a prompt generation tool, and that's what we're going to explore today.
So I've been building a GPT workflow engine, and this morning I was releasing a video
and realized I didn't have the prompts prepared for creating a tweet or doing a LinkedIn
post. These are the prompts that we're going to try and develop. Basically, they
would take some inputs and the prompt would go in here. So how do we improve that
particular prompt?
Now, in the past I've used custom GPT to turn transcripts from my videos into LinkedIn
posts and also to convert 'em into tweets. But today we're gonna do it a lot simpler
to get started.
I've come over to consult dot Anthropic dot com and we've got this ability to write
some prompts and interact with a model. There's also stuff around a system prompt,
and there's this little button here that says, generate prompt and it'll make a better
prompt for you, hopefully. So what we're gonna do is just click on that and I'm just
gonna use a really simple statement, create tweets for YouTube videos, and we'll
generate the prompt and we'll see what it comes up with. So it's got a bunch of information
coming through. Looks like some variables. It put in some guidelines, and it looks
like it's going to produce three different tweets.
So the generated prompt starts with, you are tasked with creating engaging tweets
to promote YouTube videos. Your goal is to craft tweets that grab attention, convey
essence of the video, and encourage users to click and watch. Sounds great. We've
got a title, which makes sense. We've got a description, we've got a duration,
Let's read the guidelines a bit.
tweets should be concise. 280 characters. Yes. Main point and hook in the video.
Couple of hashtags.
it's got this mention the video duration if the selling point, eg. Quick five minute
guide
that sounds interesting. It's like something that might happen if it's useful.
then we've got the structure attention grabbing. We've got calls to action and we've
got the video link. So it's given a couple of examples. It's brilliant. Actually,
please create three different tweets.
this is good. We've got three examples and they're going into locations called Tweet
one, two, and three.
this is a pretty good start.
this was the video I was going to do a tweet about.
it's nine days old. I didn't do a tweet at the time, but I do have a title. We do
have a description.
So I've just bought up the workflow tool, which is around creating a tweet at the
moment.
the prompt that we want to do would go into here, but here are the variables that
we've got, which is a title that was in the prompt we were looking at. We got a video
link. We got keywords, which wasn't in the prompt we were just looking at, and we
got the
So we're in Anthropic console with the prompt that we need. I've made one modification,
so that used to say video duration, and I've also removed point number six that talked
about that. Now, one of the things I noticed, there's nowhere for the URL though
there are those square brackets down here saying video link, and that's in a few
places. So let's see what happens when we generate this. So we should be able to
edit it.
And I've gone and filled in the title, the description, and the keyword from the
video. I haven't filled in the URL, but we'll run it and we'll see what we get.
So we've got these tweet one, two, and three. Let's test this text. That's a little
bit easier to read so we can see what the first,
tweet will be, the second and the third.
I'm just gonna paste in video link.
We can click here to configure, paste it in, and let's see if that's all we need
to do to add the video link.
So that didn't work, but we could try one other thing and maybe change it so that
it's got these input
Now I was struggling for a little bit to get the URL in here. I kept seeing square
brackets, video link, and I wasn't sure what was going on.
then I noticed at the bottom it actually says to do that, remember to use video link
as a placeholder for the actual URL, which might be what you want. It's not what
I wanted. So I've just replaced it with this.
we'll just rerun the prompt again.
we should get three tweets
we've got one here. We don't have one here. Interesting. So we'll just undo.
So I'm also gonna change this little structure that it's got there and just say,
remember to add it to the tweet and we'll see if all three of them come up with video
links this time. So the first one does the second and the third.
one of the problems that I just noticed in having it generate a prompt for me is
that unless I go in,
and pick it apart, I might Miss Little things. This doesn't usually happen when I'm
creating prompts myself,
So I've come into a tech editor and put the prompt that Anthropics created over on
the left and over on the right I've got part of the prompt from my custom GPT. And
we can see here us specialized in creating tweets for YouTube videos, and we've got
different information. One of them is the 280 character limit that we've got going
on here.
I usually use the following three variables, the summary from the video, the video
keywords, and the video URL.
what I thought I'd do is just copy this information
I've come in to generate a new prompt and I'm just gonna paste everything that we
had from our old prompt.
what I'm hoping is that because I spend a bit of time figuring out what I wanted,
and it generally works the way I do want it to work, let's see if we can improve
it.
it's come up with a number of examples, which is great. We've got the summary, the
keywords, and the URL, so this looks like it might be a good way to start.
I'm happy with what it's done. One of the things it's done here is added in a couple
of keywords, which is something you'd want to do. There weren't any keywords coming
through on this, which is interesting. Look, both techniques are
fairly powerful. Obviously with this one, this was such a simple start. It was just
create tweets for a YouTube video and it got a big prompt going straight away. The
second one, it was more in keeping with what I wanted originally because I'd spent
a bit of time building a starter prompt.
So I'm going to try this new prompt in my workflow tool. So I've taken everything
that we just generated. I've just modified the variables a little bit right here.
And we've got a workflow engine here with the title, the link, the keywords, and
the summary, and we'll just paste everything in. And these insertion points, if I
show the values, should be
showing up. So there's a summary going on. That looks good. We've got the keywords,
we'll just close that down. Press copy, it's now in the clipboard. We'll head over
to GPT and just paste it in and see if it can produce a good looking,
tweet as well. And it looks pretty good. I probably wanna get rid of these,
notation that's from Anthropic, but the actual tweet,
the keywords also make a lot of sense. The good thing also, we've using an external
tool rather than the Anthropic one is that you could go and use other sorts of models
as you see fit for different steps in the workflow.
So with the tweet text available, I'm just going to create a tweet. I'll just drag
in an image here and we'll paste it in and hopefully it's not too big. It looks good,
and we can post it and we should test it, see whether the URL is working. So we'll
just click on that. I recently added by me a copy looks and it looks like we've got
a video coming through. Let's move on and just do the LinkedIn post as well
let's test the simple one First. You create LinkedIn posts based on a YouTube script.
Something's coming through, it's taking a YouTube script, and then there's a bunch
of points that it needs to do. We're just going to press continue on that, and then
I think we can just click on the YouTube script,
come over to the YouTube script, paste it in, and we'll run it and we'll see what
we get for a LinkedIn post.
And it's created two useful things. So it's got, its thinking how it's approaching
it, it's figured out generally the topic. And it's only done that from the abridgement.
I didn't give the title. And we've got some key points listed here and relevant keywords
from there. It's written a short but useful,
post. There's no link to the YouTube video in there, but you could start with this.
What we'll do is we'll update it
by using the YouTube transformer that I've got over here so we can edit it, go into
configure, and we'll just,
copy whatever's going on. Here
we are now on a new prompt. We'll say generate prompt and the information that's
from the GPT with a little bit of a modification is just sitting here. And all the
variables that I need are included or the, the variables I like to include for my
LinkedIn post, whether they're really needed. It could be debatable, but we've got
something coming through here and it's guidelines.
I think we're just ultimately going to work with something very similar to this.
Let's press continue.
So I've got my workflow tool. I'm just gonna be copying values from one tool to the
other and we'll test out how this all works. There's everything filled in. We'll
press run on that.
And we've got,
are you a small content creator looking to monetize, discover, game changing platform
that's helping creators earn from day one? We've got a bunch of things. We've got
some
steps that I did in the video. We've got a link not necessarily quite in the format
I want, but it's in the location I want. We've got some,
keywords. I think
that we will take this, we're gonna look at one other thing before we do, but I'm
just gonna take this information straight over to LinkedIn. The other thing it's
done is give us us a bit of an explanation around what's going on.
it can be good to read through this as well.
I've just gone over to LinkedIn. I'm just gonna drag in a thumbnail and we'll just
paste in everything we've got and it's looking pretty good. There is an issue here
with the link, I believe, and we'll press post
and
probably I would normally read this, but we'll go with that.
there's the first version of the LinkedIn post. Let's check that the URL is working.
It looks like it's working
let's just do one more test. I've got all the information from our prompt here. I've
got some placeholders, and we'll just copy the information, come over to the prompt
area.
that it loads up the insertion points from the data that we've got here. We can just
press the copy button,
bring up a GPT and paste it in, and we will publish both LinkedIn articles if this
one looks okay, just so that we can see them side by side in LinkedIn.
So we've come to LinkedIn, we'll just post in another image like we did before.
I've given a just a little bit of padding between lines that didn't come through
correctly and there is no URL, but we've got that in place now. We'll press post
and what we can now do is look at these side by side.
So here's the first LinkedIn post that we did, and the second one is going on here.
And ultimately they're both gonna be okay, whatever we've got. Usually I'll do a
little bit of human editing anyway,
and this just allows me to get a little bit more social proof out there in the form
of posts and do 'em quickly just using the transcriptions that we started off with
in the video.
Anthropics Prompt Generator is really powerful. I'm going to use it a lot in the
future. If you've got any questions, then drop a comment down below. Otherwise like
and subscribe because the videos that I do will either be on prompt engineering or
as I build out this GPT workflow engine. You can see the progress as I go. With that,
I'm AppyDave. See you in the next video.