If you've ever used an AI assistant like Claude or ChatGPT, then you've had to learn
a little bit about prompt engineering. Now, either you're writing your own prompts,
maybe you've bought one out of a template pack, maybe you've gone quite advanced
and you're creating your own custom GPT
so that you have this reusable conversation that you can start off with new information.
I am writing prompts and using custom GPT on a daily basis. But one of the things
that happens more and more is that I have these repeatable sets of GPT or agents
that I wanna run to solve specific business problems. And in this video, I want to
continue the proof of concept application that I talked about in the last video,
and we'll turn it into a minimum viable product, something that you could use to
solve your own GPT workflows.
In the last video, I talked about a proof of concept application that I'd put together
for my own use called GPT Agent Workflow. And the idea is that you would come up
with these workflows. Like here it's the YouTube script writer workflow. There'd
be a research phase, and you'd go from the basic idea. You would select an idea from
that. You'd develop some facts or details about the YouTube script that you wanna
write that could come up with some video ideas. And then you would select the
so on. And that would be part of the research phase. And after that, you would go
into a new phase, and that would be the developed script phase.
you can see them up here on the left. So if we click on the research and development,
you can see the workflow and that there's this idea that you go from left to right
from this idea to this one. Currently we're on the basic fact sheet, and as you get
to the last step, you would then move on to the next phase, which would be developing
the script. Now, the problem with this particular application is it doesn't work
if you click here, nothing actually happens because this was a proof of concept.
What I was really trying to do here is figure out,
what would happen if I had this prompt and we'll put a little variable called Idea.
if I said,
let's do a cool idea goes here. What would be nice is if I could go and click on
a button somewhere like Copy Workflow and put it straight into ChatGPT or whatever
AI assistant I'm using,
or maybe click the little start button down here to have it run the prompt for me.
So with the proof of concept now demonstrating how I see an agent workflow tool working,
let's move into the minimum viable product. And what we'll do is we'll just click
back to the overview and this is what we've currently got for this particular workflow.
And I'm just gonna change the URLA little bit on my system and you'll see that it
changes ever so slightly. So what we've got now is a agent workflow tool written
a little bit differently to the old one, and when we click on things, they actually
work. So we can now go from idea to idea. We can come down to the little arrows here
and as we get to the last one, it should say, let's move on to the next
phase. And that would be the developed script phase.
Now the good thing about the minimum viable product is it's configured exactly the
same way as the proof of concept. So what we can do here is we'll go and select the
selected idea, cool ideas, go here. Notice that at the moment it's on three and you
can't click on anything. Nothing actually works in this particular variation of the
tool, but we move to the new version and we can go and click on the basic fact sheet.
and there's this interpolated variable that we can put in called idea. Now I know
that this selected idea and this don't match, so I'm just gonna call this selected
idea right there.
what'll happen is if I paste in a value here, it should appear here, and we put it
in.
If we want it in another part of the prompt, we can just paste it in like that and
it just gets replaced
and the good thing is
There's a copy button here that when we click on it, we'll see this little copied
to clipboard, it's ready for me to use.
in the final product, I'd like to have a start button, and in this case it called
Claude. Or we could have it send it to two different large language models at the
same time, or just choose large language models based on the particular step that
you're on.
pop up the GPT window, we'll
we'll just paste everything in. So what it's got is I need you to gather detailed
and reliable information about, the cool idea goes here. So if we just pop into this
view and we've got cool idea again, and we'll just let it run.
from the prompt template and a couple of variables, you should be able to get your
detailed prompt, ready to go paste it into your large language model, and it goes
and does its thing. The next step from that is that whatever the output is that we're
seeing coming through right now becomes the input for the next step in the workflow.
I am calling this tool agent Workflow Builder, and I'm developing it and demonstrating
it as I go. Now, if you want access to some of the code, which will be open source,
or if you're more interested in using this as a SaaS application, then click on the
link in the description.
Now the way I'm building this application is with a technique that I call flow code.
So if you've heard of no code application generators, they're usually user interfaces.
You drag and drop and it produces code. For me, flow code just stands for a freaking
lot of code and it's taking small inputs and creating working sets of code that solve
problems.
So when I first started writing this application, this is where I started. It was
just a simple mind map around a workflow that I'd been doing every time I did a video
and I took a copy of that workflow and I just dropped it into chat GPT. I said, can
you read this information
Now I've just done a refresh on that window. And what you'll see is that it's quite
a long conversation. It went for a couple of days, usually just talking to the phone
to build things. But some of the stuff that it came up with was entity relationship
diagrams for different workflows. I was also testing concepts like data flow diagrams.
And what this allowed me to do was develop a schema. I was able to work through the
key components that I wanted in the application. So with that in place, I was able
to start a new application using Astro here, and I then developed a bunch of the
key components like the workflow, the prompts, the settings, et cetera. And I was
able to do this by just talking to the ChatGPT window here on
developing some data models in TypeScript.
Next, I use Tailwind CSS. I'm, I don't consider myself a good JavaScript or Tailwind
CSS sort of developer, but the great thing about ChatGPT is that it can do all the
coding for you so long as you know how to prompt it. And that's a lot of what this
video series is about, is just talking about how I solve problems as a programmer
who may not actually be a polyglot in the different languages that I want to use.
Now a lot of the information you just saw was about building the proof of concept
application in Astro with Tailwind CSS. But then I wanted to make it a little bit
dynamic and that requires getting into client side JavaScript. Now, my first approach
was to have conversation with GPT about integrating Alpine js. And it was working
a little bit, but it was getting a bit bogged down and I thought, well, maybe I need
to use a proper client side framework. So I decided to use felt, and the minimum
viable product that you're about to look at was written by converting the Astro components
to Swet components.
I am not going to go into detail on how I'm writing the application in this video.
If that's a video you wanna see, let me know in the comments below. But we're back
here at now, the minimum viable product, and we're going to put it through its paces
by developing a workflow today.
So let's quickly demonstrate a real world example. So here I've got a channel called
AI TLDR. It's about two and a half months old and I've created 30 videos. And one
of the videos recently was, is Flex one a better alternative to mid journey?
So here's part of the workflow that I use for the AI TLDR channel, and we're in the
research and development phase and I've got create five simple project ideas for
an idea. And the idea happens to be flu one versus Midjourney.
if
And if I head over to chat GPT and paste it in, we come up with a list of potential
project ideas for the video and I can copy them in and head over to the next step
where I've just pasted it into the ideas.
one of the future things that I wanna do with this tool is have the ability to select
an idea, but at the moment, that's not there.
I've put in the idea I wanna work with Art Generation Flux One versus midjourney.
I can click copy on this to get the prompt and then just head over to any AI assistant
that you are using, paste it in, and you'll get a whole lot of information. From
there, I've just copied all the information that you see.
Moved over to the next tab where I wanna get some video ideas and I've pasted in
the original idea and we've also got the fact sheet that we've just developed.
I can click the copy, get the new prompt,
I want to do a YouTube video
Flux versus Midjourney. And
we've got the basic fact sheet. And down below we've got a bunch of video ideas that
we can work with. So I tend to then select that information head back to the GPT
workflow. And we're on the expanded fat sheet where we've got the original idea,
we've got the basic fat sheet that we developed, and now we've got a video idea that
I selected that I wanna do information on. From there,
I can build out an extended fat sheet
that we're looking at right here. So all the information, background information
about the company, how users are using it, is it fast? What's, what's its pricing
model. I've got every piece of information that I might need for either the YouTube
video, which is what I used it for, but you could also use it for an article if that
was what you were developing.
I've just shown you how I use agent workflows to create a YouTube script. But what
if we want to come up with a new workflow altogether? Well, the good thing is I've
created a workflow called Agent Workflow Architect, and the idea is that you want
a workflow objective. What are you trying to achieve? What are the steps that would
be involved in achieving that target? Can they be organized? Are there groups of
steps that you wanna do? Let's come up with a cool name. The name in this particular
case is Agent Workflow Architect, and then develop a specification. There's future
phases that are coming along
the example,
workflow for publishing a video on YouTube.
this is my main channel, and here the steps that I need to do is I need to come up
with a thumbnail. There's the text that I wanna put on the thumbnail and the title
that I want to have for the YouTube video.
if we look at this particular video pong to Pacman, when I uploaded it, I had the
transcript, but what I then needed to do was create a whole lot of extra information
in the YouTube description.
so here we've got the overview of what the video is all about. We've got a little
bit of a call to action to buy me a coffee. We've got a headline going on. After
that, we've got the chapters of the video. From there, there's some branding information
about myself, social media accounts that you can go to, useful affiliate links. And
then we've got the visualization of the chapters that we just looked at.
There'll be a bunch of tweets that I produce and also a bunch of LinkedIn articles
and Facebook posts. So let's head back to the agent Workflow Architect. We'll click
on the objective and we'll put in an idea. And the first one will be YouTube Video
publisher. That's basically what
I'm also going to paste in a goal here and we can see that come down the bottom.
I don't bother to clean up the text.
if there's mistakes in it, that's okay. But basically I'm asking a set of agents
that will automate various aspects of the YouTube video release. When I currently
release a video, I have to come up with title and text on the thumbnail. Then I need
to create a YouTube description, and that's usually got chapters and brand information.
finally, I need to publish to LinkedIn and Twitter, et cetera.
I've put that information in, and from there we can just copy the button
head over to a new ChatGPT window or whatever AI assistant you are using.
we're passing this information in.
So we move on from the workflow objective to the list of steps. We've got an agent
objective, which we just got from the previous ChatGPT window. We'll paste that in.
We'll click on the copy button
and then we could paste it directly in. But what I'll do is I'll just start a new
ChatGPT window and I'll paste it here, because generally when I'm doing my individual
prompts, they have a enough context in them to do whatever's needed to be done. You
don't need to flow on from a previous conversation.
We're on organized steps.
I'm just gonna paste the information into the list step here. One of the things you
might've noticed is that I've got this bar down the bottom saying language model,
where you can select various language models that you might wanna send the prompt
to, and a start button.
that's coming in a future version of the software.
it's come up with a workflow that thinks that there should be a content planning
and creation phase with a bunch of steps going on. There would be the review and
optimization, and then finally the publishing and distribution.
I had a go at this yesterday, so I'm going to use some different information that
I've manually modified. So we can see the list here, which it came up with yesterday.
It was pretty accurate. But I went through and I manually modified a couple of areas
I tend to create a summary from the transcript, then I'll create an abridgement,
which is a different type of summary. After that, I want to get some metadata, like
potential topics, keywords.
we can
get a good title, get a thumbnail text, get optimized text, and then finally we create
the YouTube description
tweet, Facebook post, and LinkedIn.
it then developed a
grouping for me. That's the way it initially looked, but I went and modified it a
little
so that I could have additional information. So our final one is going to look like
video analysis and preparation title and thumbnail optimization and video and social
media creation.
head back over to our workflow, we'll move on to the organized list, and I'm just
copying that information in. From here, we can take a copy and let's get some potential
names for the workflow.
I could open up a new chat GPT window for today. We'll test it by just using the
current conversation. That should also work well.
We've got a list of potential names here. I generated a new one. Anytime I need more,
I can just press refresh from here. And these sort of capabilities I would like to
build into the tool. The one I ultimately went with, which was from yesterday, was
video launch optimizer.
we're over at the specification. I'm just gonna put in the name I like. We've got
our organized list going on here.
we'll copy it and create a detailed specification of the different phases of the
workflow, the different steps within the workflow, and what the input and the output
parameters will be. So we'll just kick it off
There's a structured shape that I'd like the output to be in, and we're getting all
the information ready.
As you look through it, we've got different phases, video preparation, title, and
thumbnail content creation. We've got different steps like summarizing, abridgement,
analyzing, and adding the metadata.
a description going on, and then it starts building out what it thinks the input
and the output parameters should be. So the transcript would be an obvious input.
And what
We get a video summary. The transcript and the video summary might be an input. Now
this is not correct. I would manually modify this and we would get a video abridgement,
because I see the summary and the abridgement as similar, but different pieces of
information that I want to capture.
So now I have a detailed specification of what the workflow should have and chat
GPT has come up with what parameters it thinks I need, but I'm gonna go through it
and manually change 'em. The main parameter I use all the time with my video workflows
is the transcript. Whatever I said in the video is what I want to use as a source
of truth. From that,
I want to get keywords After. After I've got these bits of information, then I can
go and generate titles and content using this extra information. So last thing we'll
do is we'll take it and let's turn it into a user interface where we can enter this
information ourselves.
the first five steps that we've done being around the agent workflow design are here
and we're on the last step and we can go down. Now I also have this concept of output
attributes. So anything here is where when the GPT is are being run and you're getting
information, it goes into these variable names. So hopefully we're gonna have a specification
filled in with the table we just created, and that'll happen when we go over to the
create DSL. But we can do that by pressing this down arrow. That takes us to the
next phase. And we've got our phase, it says generate DSL. We've got the original
name of the workflow that we wanna work with. We've got a list of the organized steps,
and we've got this table. If we open it up, we can see the table all listed here.
From that, we can just click on the copy button, head over to a new GPT window, and
we'll just paste everything in. And what this is doing is producing a programming
language that I created.
His only job is to recreate workflows. When we run this, we'll get a visualization
very similar to the screens that we're looking at here.
we'll let that finish. It's still going at the moment,
and we'll just press copy on it.
I've just pasted the workflow in here, and you can think of it as GPT agent workflows
as code and as code. We can see that we've got an agent creation. What are we creating?
It's the YouTube Launch Optimizer. I did change it from video to YouTube. There's
a description going on. It's got a place where the prompts are going to be stored,
and what default large language model do you want to use? I want to use,
ChatGPT 4o. Then the prompts are all listed here. This is where it will find them.
The attributes that we're being defining are all listed, and then there are three
phases. Phase one is the video preparation, where to summarize the video, we take
the transcript, we use the video summary prompt, and we produce the video summary.
And this is just repeating over and over for each phase.
when I hit save, it'll automatically create a user interface for me. Currently, it
says GPT Workflows. YouTube Launch Optimizer is not found, but the moment I hit save,
it becomes available. And here we have video preparation. We've summarized Abridgement
video analysis and add the metadata.
the good thing is because I use Chat GPT to create all of these workflow steps, it
only takes a couple of minutes to create this complex user interface
using the GPT workflow as code, as an intermediary system. Now, in the future, I
won't do it that way. I'll build this into a SaaS application where it'll be a little
bit more streamlined, but this is how I'm doing it today.
So now that the workflow is created, we could use it today, but the video that you're
watching, I'm going to edit it
With that transcript, I'll be coming through to this workflow and I'll be typing
it into this location. As for the prompts, now, I've already done some videos at
the beginning of the year called Seven GPTs to Grow Your Channel in 2024, and the
transcript summary that we talk about here is dealt with in that particular video.
There's also a video here called SEO, GPT Boosted, SEO for YouTube description. So
this is where I'm going to get the prompt for the YouTube description. I've got one
for the LinkedIn, I've got one for the Twitter, and I've got a few others that I'll
add in.
I will talk about how the agent workflow is code or the DSL actually works behind
the scenes. And we'll have a look at the script from this video in the next video
as it produces the YouTube description and the LinkedIn post and the tweets.
I'm AppyDave like to subscribe. If this is something that you want to keep following,
I've got a link in the description. If you wanna find out more about the project,
either from the SaaS application that I'll be launching sometime in the future or
from the open source code that you might want to use if you want to add to or extend
this particular project.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.