So I'm about to go and make a structural change to the slideshow. But one of the
interesting things when I opened up Ada is it said that there's a new video that
it said there's a new version, would you like it? It then came up with release notes,
and I started looking at the release notes. And they're very interesting. So one
of the features that I would like to try out soon is the watch Files, because I like
to use a requirements document first approach to coding, and the ability to just
watch that document and have it respond would be awesome.
Now I just read the documentation about the watch files. It looks pretty easy, so
let's just add it in from this point onwards. What we'll do is we'll come back to
Visual Studio, and what I've got in front of me at the moment is the presentation
JS in the left hand side, and we've got the original slides from the previous video.
Now there's also three images, which would be the first three sorts of templates.
And what I've done is I've just created a new JSON document called Slides New. Now
if we look at the code over here, we can see that it's currently reading from slides.
So I think the first thing we should do is just add in a comment here to see if we
can alter it so that it can read it from an incoming query string parameter.
So we'll come over to here and we'll just put in a prompt. I need slides, Jason,
to be configurable from query parameter and by default it should be slides, Jason,
but we should be able to pass in a custom parameter.
Now I'm just gonna bring in the terminal and I suspect that nothing will happen because
we haven't got the option in this comment to force a recompile or a reread of the
code. So what we should be able to do now is just add AI at the end of it and this
should be enough information. So now it's starting to do something. So let's have
a look at this processing. The request will say yes,
and it's saying it'll modify the load presentation.
So let's see what it has done. So
now the URL premise source is going to default to slides Jason, if not filled in,
and we'll be able to load from that file.
Now we have a modification to the code. What used to be slides dot JSON in this location
is now being defaulted to slides dot JSON if it's not provided on the query parameter.
So I've created this file called slides new. This is what we'll pass in. The current
attributes aren't catered for in our code at all.
What I'll have to do is just add in a backward compiler. Backward.
So what I'll do is add in a backward compatibility attribute. I know the image will
be used, but this way we can at least see the data. So we'll hit save on that.
Now I've just added a H1 because I know that'll be backward compatible. There are
a couple of other things, like the bullets that are probably going to be okay, and
we'll hit save on that. And I've got the old one here just working without a query
parameter. And if we go to the new one, I've got the query parameter in place. And
let's just refresh that. Looks like it's working okay.
Now I'm going to test a pretty complex prompt. This time I'm going to ask it to read
the Jason documents. So we've seen that it's got all the different attributes that
we might want for these three templates that are here, and we'll just paste that
in and it looks like it can find things. So we will put that and we'll say yes.
And then after that we will
take all of this information. So what I've said is it'll have three slides with different
attributes and a common attribute, which will be the template. I need that to be
an ID that it can look up. I want it to create a function for each of the templates.
And then it can call each function, and each function will just be responsible for
rendering the HTML elements. It won't be about star. We'll deal with that with CSS.
So if we just pace this in, and I don't know whether we needed to select
presentation js. It looks like everything's working. Okay.
So we'll click on that and we'll come over to presentation js and see what happens
to our code base.
So we can see the old code is still in place actually,
so we can see the old code here and the new code coming in. And it's looking at these
IDs and binding it to different functions. So we've got the first function, which
is working with date main heading, and it looks like it can also deal with a subtitle.
And then we've got function two and function three.
Okay.
Now if we look at template number one, we've got a mapping of date, main heading
and subtitle. There's a date main heading and subtitle. Now, this is pretty verbose
code. You wouldn't generally wanna do it this way, but this is going to get us started,
I think. Let's have a look at it.
So it looks like it's mapping to the data correctly. Let's go to the next slide and
we can see that that's today's presentation and that'll be built up by the second
function. So we've got the main heading mapping to here. So basically there should
be a one-to-one relationship between each of these if statements and the data elements.
At the moment, the bullets is interesting. It did figure out how to deal with the
fact that this is an array of data, and I wonder what about the image? Did that come
through? Yeah, we've got the image here, so let's move on to the third one. It looks
like we've got about five data points. So we've got main heading subtitle, headline
one, synopsis one, headline two, synopsis two. Okay.