Styling a Kajabi website.
In this video, we're going to add
in a brand kit, and from there
there'll be a logo, a favi icon.
We'll style most of the HTML
elements within our site, and then
we'll add in some custom fonts.
And on top of that, we'll
use the Kajabi GPT as both a
tutor and as a CSS generator.
I like the full potential of
Kajabi with a 30 day trial by
visiting appydave.com/kajabi.
This is my affiliate link.
So while you are paying nothing
extra, it supports the channel
at no additional cost to you.
But here's where it gets better.
Sign up through my link and you'll
gain immediate access to the
exclusive course Kajabi Accelerator.
This course is designed to
fast track the launch of your
online business using Kajabi.
And there's more.
You'll get a complimentary
coaching session with me.
We'll dive into the Kajabi setup,
tackle any marketing queries or
strategize on landing your first sale.
This entire package is at no extra
cost available instantly when you
sign up at appydave.com/kajabi.
Don't wait.
Let's jumpstart your
journey with Kajabi today.