To get started, we wanna set up the
branding, which is the logo, the Favicon,
and the default colors for our website.
Now, to find this area, you can
come over to the main website,
click the website button.
From here.
There's a button here called site details,
which will take us back to that menu.
the other way to do it is to come
down to the settings, and from in here
you've got all these different settings.
If you typed in brand.
You'd find branding in this area
here called marketing Settings.
This is not the area we want.
This is only related to
the email marketing system.
Instead, we can come to the site
details that are right here.
Now, if we scroll down a little bit, we'll
come to the area where we're just looking
at we branding, where we can set up our
Favicon and our logo and the colors.
let's go and have a look at our
branding guidelines document to
see what these values should be.
I like to keep my style guide in Canva.
If we click on the brand button,
we'll come to the different
brands that you might have.
I've got AppyDave, what
we're working with today.
If I click on that, you'll be able
to see some of the logos that I use,
my color palette, and also the fonts.
this is going to be useful as we
transition it over to the Kajabi website.
Looking at my current brand kit,
we can see that I've got these
logos and we'll click on this one.
One of the things I can do
here is figure out the colors
for my brand through the logo.
If we click on this, we can see different
colors that are going on within this
logo, but all I wanna do today is
click the download button on it.
Let's quickly look at the color
palette I've got and how I came up
with it so that you can recreate
a color palette that suits you.
I used one of the many color palette
generators that are online, and the
main thing you're looking for is that
you have a couple of primary colors.
Now these.
Colors go really well together, and
they work in a situation where I want
either a light color as a background
or a dark color as a background.
On top of that, I have a
couple of secondary colors that
compliment these two quite nicely.
Now, the other two colors that
almost every website needs to
have is a white and a black.
you don't have to go for pure black.
You don't have to go for pure white, but
these are really useful colors to have.
The only other color I've got here is
not really related to my brand, but more
related to my thumbnails, We don't need
to bring this over to the Kajabi website.
Moving down to fonts.
We can see I have two different
styles The first one is Bebas Nueue.
This is an external font, and we're going
to need to go and download that from a
website to make it available to Kajabi.
The other font I use is Impact, and I use
that 'cause it's a nice readable font,
when we do the fonts for the website,
there will be articles and articles.
needs something very clean and simple to
read, and it may not be these two fonts.
In the past I have used Bebas Nueue,
but we might pick a different font
specifically for our paragraphs.
Coming back to the site details and
branding, what we're going to do is
we're going to upload a new file.
one of the things to be aware of
is that we've got a logo already
on our computer, so what we can do
is click on the my device button.
And we'll be given our logo, and if
there's any padding around it that
you don't want, you can just remove it
From there, we click save.
Now, this hasn't put it into Kajabi yet.
We still need to click the
upload button right here.
I quickly converted my
logo into a Favicon.
Now if you dunno what that is, a quick
search would show you that it's the
logo as it appears in the browser you
just search for resize to Favicon.
I've gone to one of the many
websites and just dragged my
logo into here and downloaded it.
it came back with many different sizes,
but the one I selected was the 32 by 32.
next step is to change the
colors for the default palette.
this won't change anything on your
website just yet, but we'll make
colors available a lot easier.
what we can do is come over to our
brand kit and we'll just select one of
the color codes right here, and then
click on the first one and paste it in.
And all we do is we repeat
that for each of the.
Colors that we've got.
So we've got our first primary
colors being the dark brown
and the light brown set up.
Now in the top row I have five
colors here, dark brown, light brown,
and then the two secondary colors.
And I've also put black,
every other color.
I've just set to white because I
don't want to use an another color
that's off brand by accident.
I.
I wanna point out a mistake that
you may make while doing this.
So we have our logo, our Favicon, and
our brand colors, but if you don't click
the save button, they will disappear.
make sure you go down to the
bottom and click the save.
bring up our website and talk
about what we're going to do next.
We've got these colors here, like
the buttons that are going on.
We've got more buttons.
We've got fonts that might want to
change both in style and in color.
We've also got areas.
Like icons that we want to see.
And then of course there was the logo.
So what I'm going to do now is just do
one refresh and we'll see what changes.
And the only thing that should change
is the logo that we've uploaded and
the logo that's down the bottom.
the reason that other colors didn't
change is that this is only about
changing the default color pickers.
It's not about changing
the elements themselves.
We'll do that in the next section.
Let's create a page for our brand
kit, and we'll also use the Kajabi
GPT to generate the content that's
going to go onto the brand kit.
So I've just come over to the website
design and I'll click on the pages.
what we really want is a landing page.
So click a landing, and
then you can create one from
scratch with this button here.
we just want a blank page.
we're going to call it brand
kit and we'll hit create.
And it'll create this
page for us with a hero.
We're going to get rid of that because
we're going to write our own content.
Most of the brand kit is going to
be text, we'll go and add a section.
We'll click on text and what'll
happen is it'll show up here,
but for it to be fixed in place,
you have to press the add button.
From there, we'll just go back one
and we'll add one more section in
and we'll call that one text as well.
We now have two text areas.
This is where we're going
to put our headings and our
paragraphs and our block text.
This is where we're going to put other
sorts of information like code blocks.
Let's look at the content
we want to create here.
Now, if you click the edit button, you'll
be given this area, and I'm just going
to remove all the information for now.
From there, I want to talk a
little bit about the Kajabi GPT
that I'm putting together now.
This is a work in progress
But essentially the Kajabi site
assistant is designed for helping
me build my Kajabi site, build my
content, show me how to use different
features, and if you look at it, you
can set up these concepts called goals.
And the goal is really a context that
you might wanna focus on as you're
developing your Kajabi website.
Maybe it's email driven marketing.
Then there's how do I
use a particular feature?
Do I just wanna short synopsis?
Do I wanna step by step guide?
And that's what the
cover and focus is about.
then there's this area that we're going
to use right now called content, and
that's a topic or an area of concern.
And today the topic will be the brand kit.
We'll use this GPT to create the
content that we saw and would like
to put back into this edited area.
We're over on the Kajabi assistant,
and we can click on help, which will
give us detailed information, but
if you click on the commands, you'll
just get the basic commands that
you can use within this KajabiGPT.
the one we're interested in
will be the content or write.
So I'm going to type in write,
We're doing a brand kit.
Now this needs a little bit more
of a complex prompt in this case,
What I specifically need are
two separate markdown documents.
They're going to focus
very much on my brand.
In this case, I want the brand kit
to also look like it is part of my
brand, so not just filler a text.
The main thing is that it also adheres to
writing the different HTML elements that
would be on a regular Kajabi website.
the reason there are.
Two markdown documents is that
the second one will also be for a
code block, which is a specialized
way of viewing text on a site.
we just press enter on that and
what we should hopefully get is a
couple of markdown documents with
all the different structures that
we need for our brand kit webpage.
It's created all the markdown for my brand
kit, and I'm just going to copy this.
There's also another one, which we'll look
at in a moment, but if we move over to any
product that convert markdown into rich
text, we'll probably get what we need.
this is called Dillinger, and I'm just
going to paste in the information.
markdown format is where you can say
three hashes, means it's a heading level
three, or one hash is heading level one.
you can see it all visualized
over here on the right.
when we copy directly into Kajabi,
it should look very much like this.
just copy from the top of the
document all the way to the bottom,
move over to the Kajabi website
that we were looking at earlier.
Click on the edit button
and just paste it all in.
It looks like all the text
that we need is in here.
Now the second markdown that it created
was for some code and on my particular
website code is important, but for
you, it may not be, but this is still
useful to see how this can work.
go over to the brain kit and
we paste it in, it'll firstly
not really look that formatted.
What we can do is just put in these
three little ticks above and below.
We get it in a format that
looks a little bit like coding.
copy that head over to our webpage,
now we're going to edit the second
block just paste it in as we see
it Got this code area, we can
hit save and we can hit preview.
Now we're in our brand kit preview.
We can see at the bottom we've
got the code has been added.
It's not very styled, and that's something
we could deal with in a future session.
the main areas we're looking for
is just the general text that
would be part of the brand kit.
We will style it soon, but for now
we look at it and we've got six
different sorts of headings from the H!
To the H2,3,4,5 and 6.
Here we have what's called an ordered
list, and that's why it's numbered
one and two, and we have an unordered
list that's listed with bullet points.
We can see some bold text, italic
text, a hyperlink, and right here
we have what's called a block quote.
Let's now create a little
bit of basic styling.
That'll be global to the site,
but we'll see it on our brand kit.
Now we're back on the brand kit and
I've added in one extra component
just so that we can see what a
form and a button could look like.
what you can do is head over to
settings, and from here we'll
click through to Style guide.
pop up the webpage variant of this.
This is what previewing and as we
change it over on the left, he should
update fairly quickly over on the right.
the first setting to look
at the primary color.
when I was testing this out and I
was looking through different pages
trying to see the primary color
get changed, I was a little bit
confused about what it actually did.
I went over to the Kajabi assistant
and I used the how command and the how
command allows you to learn a little
bit how a feature within Kajabi works.
I just said in the style settings,
I changed secondary body font,
color, and primary color, and
nothing seemed to get affected.
And so we have this information over here.
I'll just point out that the secondary
body font color over here was what I
was also playing around with, and it's
pointing out that some of this might
only be related to certain themes
and areas like say a placeholder
text, which is one of the reasons
why I put a form onto the system.
when it came to the primary color,
it pointed out that concepts
like links might be what change.
we can see that on the
AppyCast channel link.
What we'll do right now is we'll go
to this primary color and we will just
change it to something odd like red.
We'll also take the background
color of a button that might
be useful to have a look at.
We'll just set it to green and
then we'll scroll all the way
down and we'll play around with
this secondary body font color.
Let's go with a bright
yellow and the placeholder.
Font color, and we'll
go with this lime green.
hit the save button.
When we refresh the page, we can see
that the hyperlink here is red, and
that's matching to the primary color.
This lime background color is showing up
within the button, so that looks good.
We've also got this other sort of
green, which we saw down the bottom
was the placeholder font color and
the secondary body font color has not
shown up in the page that we've got.
if you've been playing around with
that one and struggled to figure
out what's going on with it, it's
probably related to a specific theme,
not to the theme that you are using.
Now I'm just gonna set a cup of.
Brand colors as we go.
The one color that doesn't have a brand
color as yet would be my hyperlinks.
I'm gonna leave it as a basic blue
because that's the sort of color
that you generally see on a website.
We'll come to the background color
button, and we now have our global
colors that we previously set up.
I'm just gonna set that
to the dark brown color.
scroll down and we have a look at.
The secondary text.
This can go to just a gray, the
placeholder text, which is just here,
will set that to the light gray.
Will now click the save button
and refresh our preview here.
And we have a blue link.
We have light gray writing right
here, and we have a dark brown button,
which is in keeping with the brand.
I.
let's have a look at the text
labels within different areas.
So we have the button
that we've just done.
It's currently showing as white,
the color from my brand, the light
brown, should work pretty good.
we'll put that in place and then we'll
come down to where the heading font is.
And the heading front
should be any of these.
Bigger text items, but not the bold
text, we'll click heading font.
Let's just change it for red now
just so we can see what it does.
And we'll change the body
font to lime green here.
hit save.
a refresh shows a high
contrast, red and a lime green.
down the bottom we've got the light
brown on top of the dark brown.
I'll come back to the body color and I
should be able to press undo command+Z
so this will go back to a dark gray and
if we click on this, We could undo if we
want, but what I'll do instead is just
set it to the dark brown from my brand.
We can then hit save.
We are very similar to before, except
that this is a different color to gray.
It is a brown down the bottom.
We've got the light brown on top
of dark brown for the button.
You might have noticed that the color
controls for the fonts here is a little
bit limited, but what we'll do a bit
later on is just the Kajabi GPT to
create some color codes and CSS for us
so that we can make it more effective.
what I'm thinking is that
if I look at my KajabiGPT.
The way I do GPTs is I use
a font called Bebas Nueue.
We'll want to include that on the
website, but I also have the ability
to have, say, dark brown on light
brown or white on light brown.
And I also have others where it's
light brown on dark brown, and
we'll see how we can use CSS to
make that change on our website.
Something I didn't notice earlier was
that I accidentally changed the button
shape, so at the moment it's full width,
we have concepts like the width, and
I'm going to put that back to auto.
The other thing that we can do
is maybe make it a bit larger.
press save, and we'll just refresh
and have a look at what we get.
we have a button that's auto sized,
so there's a bit of padding around the
text, but it doesn't take up the full
area that it's within and it's large.
I don't personally like it to be large.
I'm gonna bring it back to medium,
and while that's happening,
we'll refresh this page here.
This is looking good.
We could also, if we want,
play around with the radius.
this is not something I'm going to do
for my own website, but we can at least
have a look at what that looks like.
it's not too bad, so I might just bring
it back to about an eight and press save.
Let's also have a quick look
at fonts while we're here.
Now the fonts I wanna do are going to be
custom, but if you do need to change font.
You can come down to this area and
change either the body, which will
be the text over here or any of the
headings to have a particular font.
So let's just play around with something.
We'll go with dancing script, press save,
and we'll also refresh our sample preview.
And now all our headings are
in this running writing format.
later on, we will change
this with a custom font.
In this section, I wanna quickly go
over another global element that's
not quite related to style and
design, but is on most pages of a
Kajabi site, and that's the footer.
At the moment, we have the brand kit
page open for editing, and one of
the things you'll notice on the left
is the ability to modify the footer.
But the problem is that if you scroll
over and look at the brand kit,
whether it be in a wide landscape
mode like we've got at the moment, or
a portrait mode, there is no footer.
Now, the reason for that is that
this is a landing page, not a
regular page on the website, and
landing pages don't have a footer.
So even though we can go into
footer and we can do modifications
here, it won't make a whole lot of
sense doing it from this location.
come out to the pages area, but
we'll click on website instead and
we'll just go to this about page.
And this will just make it a little bit
easier for us to see what we're editing.
We can have a look at it as
a HTML page preview in both
landscape and portrait mode.
we're here on the footer now.
We've already talked about the logo
in the site settings and on the
video that I did, on site structure
is where we looked at this menu.
we're not going to play around too much
with it other than to state that we
can do things like move stuff around.
if I just move the logo down a
couple of points here and we press
save, and we'll refresh the view
We should see the logo move to a.
Different location.
I've reset that and what we'll do instead
is we'll play around with the color.
So the foot of background, I'm
just going to set it to my branding
dark brown for the foot of text.
I'm going to change it to the
light brown from the branding.
I'm also going to do the same
thing for the copyright text.
Let's leave it as white for now.
hit save and we'll also refresh
the preview of it, leaving powered
by Kajabi and White will be fine.
One of the things I do is I leave Kajabi
and powered by on my site because that's
actually a link to your affiliate link.
One area I do wanna change is the fact
that it says 2024 Kajabi, and what we
can do is just click on the copyright I'm
gonna change it to AppyDave we'll go back.
There we have some basic
styling changes to the footer.
this also then highlights another
issue when we look at our brand kit.
we'd set up certain structures and we
played around with a few colors, one of
them being the buttons here, but notice
that the buttons have not transferred
over onto the main pages over here.
Now let's have a look at the styling
differences between a landing page
and a standard page in Kajabi.
over here on the right
we've got our brand kit.
This is a landing page.
Notice that when you go to
settings, it's got four available,
one of them being style guide.
Whereas here we've got the main.
Application, one of the general
pages of the site, and there's a
different set of settings going on.
if you go into the style guide for
both of them, they both have the same
setup, but you can modify the colors
individually what we'll do in the case
of the primary color here, we'll just
copy the value because I made that
a custom one, and we can just move
over to this area and paste it in.
When it comes to the bottom color,
we've already got that set up
in our global values, so we just
play around with them as we go.
I'm going to make sure that the
border radius is set to eight we'll
just use the spinner here, and
while it look similar for heading
font, this is slightly different.
That's a black.
What we'll do is we'll change it
to our brow, and now we'll just
press save and see what happens.
Now there's been a slight
change to the headings.
They've become the dark brown.
It's more noticeable in
our call to action buttons.
Let's have a look at how we set up a
custom fonting Kajabi and the selection
process that I go through to pick one.
This little picture here represents
the differences between a Sans
Serif font and a Serif font.
According to Google, a serif
font is easier to read in
newspapers and magazines.
the word serif has meaning and it
means a slight projection, finishing
off the stroke of a letter while the
word sends is a French word, meaning
without or lacking, so without a serif.
Now to look at that in pictorial form.
You can see the Serif over here on
this letter, and you can see without
a Serif on this particular letter.
let's move over to Google fonts
and custom fonts in general.
if you type in Google fonts and
just click on the link, you'll be
taken to this page where you can
select custom fonts to download.
you'll see here there's 1600
fonts listed at the moment.
The first three here are Sans Serif fonts.
The next one is a language specific
font, and here we have another.
Now, if we go down a little
bit further, we can see three
fonts here that are Serif based.
the idea of Serif is that they were
good for newspapers, but for lots
of digital publications, they're
not necessarily the right way to go.
Because my website is a tech site,
I will go with a San Serif website.
the one I've chosen for my
body text is called Oswald.
I'll just type in Oswald
this is what articles on my
website are going to look like.
What I'll do is come up and click on
it and we will go with Get Font, and
currently it's in a download list.
we'll just click fonts here and we'll
come back and we'll look at the next font.
Now when I'm creating my GPT
agents, I use three different fonts.
we have a standard Sans-serif font.
called Impact.
the reason I've gone with Oswald on
Google fonts is that it is the closest
font to impact, and then the last font
down the bottom here is the Beba new,
and that's what we'll go and load next.
we'll just type in Bebas Nueue.
We'll click through and I will
even type in AppyDave and you can
see what it looks like we can just
press get font, and download all.
I just wanna talk about an oddity in
Kajabi that you might find confusing when
you're trying to work with custom fonts.
I.
I went to the Kajabi GPT, and I
just asked it how is there a central
location for uploading HTML assets?
Like the TTF file we need for custom fonts
or PNGs, JavaScript files, CSS files.
it came back with a little bit of
information about going to settings
and finding the files section.
Now this is a hallucination.
And when you are using chat GPT
in general, you do need to be
aware of this sort of concept.
I just asked it one quick question.
I need to confirm that what
you just said is accurate.
I find this style of context
writing to be a great way.
It's come up with all this I.
Really useful information, but it's wrong.
And so then you just ask it the
simple question, is this accurate?
Can you use Bing to find the right answer?
it comes back with an answer, which I
knew to be true, but I went to the GPT
helper just to confirm, because I find the
whole way of uploading assets to Kajabi
to be very different to most CMS systems.
We're back in Kajabi and we're on the
landing page called Brand Kit, I've
created a new empty section called.
Font downloads.
We'll just click through
we can add some content.
the way we work with fonts with Kajabi
is that you can upload them to the
system through something like a download
button, and that's what we're going to
do here now to add a button to Kajabi.
The easiest way is to use the call to
action element, and then you've got
this little button that we can add.
we had two fonts, we'll just call
this one Oswald ttf, We're going to
change it from URL to download file.
earlier we downloaded Bebas Nueue
and Oswald from Google Fonts and
I've put it into a font directory
the file that you want in particular
will be the one ending in TTF.
we'll click pick file Brows, my device,
and it's added it into this button.
Let's just go back one section.
And we'll add another content area called
Call to action I'm going to call it Bebas
Nueue, we'll go for, download a file.
My device, Bebas Nueue new is now
uploading My two fonts have been
uploaded to the system Oswald.
If I was to right click on it, there
would be the ability to copy the link
to this particular font file, the way
they're going to apply is that anything
that's considered a paragraph or we have
ordered lists, we have unordered lists.
we have hyperlinks.
They're all going to use the Oswald
font and anything that's a heading,
we've got a H1, which is, there
should be one H1 per page that you do.
you've got level two, level three, level
four, level five, and level six headings.
They're all going to use the Bebas font.
The way you make 'em available in
Kajabi is here on the brand kit.
If I back up to the settings page,
there's an area called custom code.
If we click on that, we can either put
in overrides for CSS, which is what
we're trying to do, or for JavaScript.
You might not understand CSS.
I'll show you a simple
way of dealing with this.
So if we move over to the landing
page that we've done a sample code,
I've gone and added a CSS template,
that can start with, and we're going
to run it through our KajabiGPT, to.
Input the correct values
into this template.
This will just be a starting point,
the main things going on here is that
I've given it some parameters around
the idea of a font name, A URL Now.
It won't be the URL that's there.
It'll be the URL that we'll
find when we right click on
these buttons and copy the link.
The other area is that.
By default, it'll use a font weight
of normal, and that just gets
inserted into different locations.
So the heading Font, which we've said is
Bebas, will get applied to the H1 through
the H6, whereas the Oswald font will get
applied to the paragraph, the unordered
list, the ordered list, and the anchor
tags, then we can decide what we want to
put in for buttons that are either call to
actions or buttons that are on the form.
Let's turn this CSS template into an
actual working CSS file using Kajabi GPT.
just select all the information
that's available and we'll pop
over to the Kajabi assistant.
I already have a bunch of commands
that I've set up, what you can do
with this is you can figure out
how to use different features.
You can set a goal for what you
wanna achieve within Kajabi.
You can write content, or in this case
we're going to use the template command.
what I'm gonna do is type in template with
the colon and paste in all the information
that I grabbed from the other URL.
what this will do is give us the
option to fill in a few parameters
if we want to, and then write the
CSS file for us, which we should be
able to copy Directly into Kajabi.
Now we didn't define any parameters,
it's just gone with default values.
Everything looks okay.
But what we'll do is we'll jump
back here and make sure we copy the
links to these two font files come
back here and we'll just paste in
a little prompt that says heading.
B, a new and a URL to where
that font file happens to be.
Plus a paragraph called Oswald and a
URL to where that font happens to be.
for buttons, use Bebas Nueue we'll
just regenerate this and hopefully it's
going to create the CSS file we need
and we can just copy and paste it in.
it looks like it's followed the
instructions correctly, we've
got font face, Bebas Nueue, and
we've got font face, Oswald.
We've got a URL definitely to my website.
If we scroll all the way to the
right, we've looks like we've got
the right file for Bebas Nueue.
We've got the right file for Oswald.
We come back to the left.
We can see that all the headings are
going to use this Bebas Nueue font.
All the paragraphs and lists are going
to use Oswald and the buttons are
also going to reuse the Bebas Nueue.
we can just click on the copy code here.
We're back on the landing page.
We've gone to settings.
We'll click on custom code.
we should just be able
to paste everything in.
we'll have to press the save button.
as you can see, we've now got the
Bebas Nueue for all of our fonts, and
we've got Oswald for our paragraphs.
Let's look at them side by side.
here we have our landing page.
In the old style, I haven't updated
the page, but if I hit refresh,
it'll now come to look like this.
personally, when I look at it,
I'm not quite happy with it.
I like the fonts, but they're not
working for me the way they are today.
But this is something
I can improve in time.
At least now I have the ability
to really easily change the font
and the style Using the Kajabi GPT
to do a lot of the heavy lifting.
Let's make some basic changes to
our CSS using both the Kajabi GPT
and a little bit of manual editing.
The current design is using
two fonts for all the headings.
We're using Bebas Nueue, and for all
the text we're using Oswald, and it's
the text itself that's lacking clarity.
let's go talk to regular GPT and
see what we can do about that.
Now I've come over to a regular ChatGPT
session and I've just asked, is there four
fonts that it recommends readable on the
web and the for it's come up with look.
All right, I've used Roboto before,
so this is the one I think I'll use.
But I asked the question, is
Roboto installed on most computers?
Because if it was, then I
don't have to do anything more.
But it's saying here that
it's more for Android.
I've gone to Google Fonts and I've re
downloaded BBAs, Oswald, and now Roboto.
if I look in the fonts folder, you'll
see that it's a little bit different
to the others that we downloaded.
With these two, we only got
two regular fonts with Roboto.
We got a large variety thin black italic,
and the one I'm really interested in
is just going to be regular, which
will upload into the Kajabi page.
I've gone and added a new button.
we look here and we've got Roboto.
We can right click on that
to copy the URL, which we
are going to need in the css.
Now let's use our Kajabi assistant to make
the changes we want to see in the style.
we already have two font faces set
up, one for Bebas Nueue and Oswald.
We've got all the headings set up, all
the text set up, and all the buttons,
and we need to make some modifications.
I'm gonna do is start
writing some prompts.
So the first one is, can
you introduce a Roboto font?
paste in A URL, which we
got off the previous page.
The next part of the prompt is, can
you use the BA new font for the H one?
So I only want it for the
H one and any buttons.
we wanna see it for this element here, and
we wanna see it within these two elements.
The next part of the prompt
is can you use the Oswald font
for all the other headings?
can you make sure they're in uppercase?
the other headings is H2 through
H6 and we need something to say
that this is going to be uppercase.
Just point out that the Bebas
Nueue font, by default, is always
uppercase, but the Oswald isn't.
And it's because we're making
it Oswald That's why we're
introducing this uppercase section.
let's introduce our new font being the
Roboto font, and we'll just do that for
the paragraph list and link elements,
and that happens to be these four.
Here we got a paragraph, an
unordered list, an ordered list,
and an anchor tag or a link.
Let's update the CSS template.
with Roboto font for paragraph list of
links, Bebas Nueue for H1 and Oswald
for all other headings in uppercase.
as we look through, we can
see that a new font has been
introduced being the roboto font.
The H1 is the only one using Bebas Nueue,
whereas the H2 through H6 is using Oswald
and it's transforming it to uppercase.
All our text elements are using Roboto
and our buttons are using Bebas Nueue.
We do not need to make it uppercase
because that's one of the default
capabilities of this font, so we should
be able to go and click the copy.
Just grab that and we'll head
over to the CSS code and paste
it in and click the save button.
Here is the updated brain kit with
the Bebas Nueue font, the Oswald font,
and everything in text is in Roboto.
If you're happy working in a little bit
of CSS, and what you could do is go quite
specific and change exactly what you need.
if we look at the hyperlinks here, let's
say we wanted to use a format similar
to what I use with my KajabiGPT, whereby
I do things like having white on light
brown or dark brown on light brown.
Sometimes I also have rounded edges,
So let's go and manually update the
CSS for this hyperlinks or H6 element.
Here we have the CSS file that was
generated by the Kajabi GPT, and one
of the areas is H2 through H6 being set
with Oswald normal and uppercase font.
we don't want to change this directly
because what we're after is altering the
H6, but we don't wanna affect the others.
we can just go straight after it and
we'll just paste in this block of code.
And it's basically saying that
the H6 will already have these
concepts, but then what we're going
to do is either add or override.
So the example of an override
would be the font weight.
So the font weight for H2
through H6 is set to normal.
But for the H6 specifically,
we are going to make it 700,
which is just a bit thicker.
We're also gonna set the color to
white, the background to the light brown
branding color, the border radius, which
is the curves on the edges to 10 pixels.
we'll put in a little bit of paddings.
we'll copy this file and just
update it here and press save.
Here we are on our brand kit.
That's the old version
of hyperlinks or the H6.
And with a little bit of an update, it's
now got the bolded white on a light brown.
Or we could do other variations
like not bolded, and using the
dark brown on the light brown.
If you're happy with the CSS that you've
done for the brand kit, then there's
one other change that you need to make.
The moment we've got all this styling that
we've added to our brand kit, but if we
go through the other pages of the website,
you'll notice that the styling hasn't been
updated on any of these pages as of yet.
What we've gotta do is go from the
landing over to the website section and
we'll just pick the very first page and
click the customized button on that and
we can click on the settings here, go
to custom code of which this has never
been updated, and we'll just paste
in all the new code that we've got.
Click save.
We've now updated our website
with the Favicon and the logo.
We've got our branding guidelines put
in place, and we've altered the HTML
elements so that they're styled the
way we want and with custom fonts.
I've also updated the Kajabi GPT so that
it's more effective as a tutor, so that
you can also use it to generate CSS and
CSS templates for your Kajabi website.
This video is part of a masterclass
on KajabiGPT, and you can find links
to additional videos over here.
I'm also putting together an academy where
people get to work in small groups with
me to develop their skills With chat.
GPT, there's a link in the description.
I'm AppyDave, and remember to
like and subscribe and I'll
see you in the next video.
Unlock the full potential of Kajabi
with a 30 day trial by visiting
AppyDave dot com slash Kajabi.
This is my affiliate link.
So while you are paying nothing
extra, it supports the channel
at no additional cost to you.
But here's where it gets better.
Sign up through my link and you'll
gain immediate access to the
exclusive course Kajabi Accelerator.
This course is designed to
fast track the launch of your
online business using Kajabi.
And there's more.
You'll get a complimentary
coaching session with me.
We'll dive into the Kajabi setup,
tackle any marketing queries or
strategize on landing your first sale.
This entire package is at no extra
cost available instantly when you
sign up at appydave.com/kajabi
don't wait.
Let's jumpstart your
journey with Kajabi today.