Have you ever traveled from a Western
country to somewhere like Thailand, and
when you did a Google search, you saw
this thing called BE or Buddhist time.
In this video, I'm going to show you
how to deal with the Buddhist era
number showing up in your Google search.
Today I'm AppyDave, and last week I
moved to Thailand from Australia and I'm
here to do a little bit of videography.
when I got here I did a search
in the local area, which is
Chang Mai for things to do.
one of the things I noticed was that
a lot of the references had a date and
time in it that I didn't understand.
So here we've got August 6, 2566
BE or the one below it, 2567 BE.
last week when I did the same sort
of search, everything was showing
up in my local date format, so 19th
of February, 2024, or January, 2024.
So I wondered what's going on here.
I.
In the Western world, we
use the Gregorian calendar.
When we show dates in Australia,
it might start off with the day
followed by the month in America,
the month followed by the day.
But when you go to somewhere
like Thailand, they use Buddhist
era or the Buddhist calendar.
Now going to other countries, you might
have other sorts of calendars working
out, and hopefully this video will show
you how to solve that problem as well.
let's have a look at how we can
fix this particular problem.
Now, the first thing I tried when I
arrived in Chiang Mai this week was
I headed over to my settings within
my Mac computer and I played around
with the date and time settings.
I set the time zone to Indo China time,
Bangkok, Thailand as the nearest location.
Then I headed over to the
region settings, and from here
I left the region as Thailand.
But I set the calendar to
Gregorian and the date format to
what I'm used to in Australia.
With my settings in place, I headed over
to Google search and typed in what to do
near me, and there was a bit of an issue.
What I noticed was that the
date was set to 2566, BE.
So changing the settings didn't
solve this particular problem.
So a little bit of a Google search
led me to this article here.
The dates on Google search
results are in Buddhist era, and
someone had an answer to that.
The answer was, you need to change these
settings within Google preferences.
So let's head over to the preferences.
We go to google.com/preferences
and you'll see a screen like this.
Now click on the first menu item
under it called Other settings,
and you'll notice an option
there called Language and Region.
Now, if you click on that, you'll
come to this area where there's
the Results Region, and it's
currently set to current region.
Current region in this
particular situation is Thailand.
So what you can do is click on
the Results Region and change it.
So I've typed in Australia and I've
selected Australia, and now the setting
is changed within Google preferences.
Now let's head over to Google search
and we'll type in what to do near me.
And the first thing you'll notice is that
the dates are now showing the way I like.
We've got the 25th of January, 2024.
If you look closely, you
might notice there's a pretty
big problem going on here.
When I did the search, everything that
was paid search was in the region that
I'm in at the moment, which is Chiang Mai.
But the organic search was
all showing up from Australia.
And the reason for that is because we've
set the results region to Australia.
Unfortunately, the solution that I'm
showing you can be one way or the other.
There may be a better way, but
this is how I've figured it out.
For me, I prefer to have Western time
show up against documents because
usually I'm searching for information
where time relevance is important.
If, on the other hand, you really
need region specific searches
all the time, you might not want
to put this setting in place.
Let's say you want the
best of both worlds.
You can get it in a subtle way.
You can have it set to Western
time like I have now, and just
alter the way you do your search.
So in this case, I've said what to
do in Chiang Mai, and this way I'm
getting both the western dates where
the articles were written and they
are pointing to the location I need.
I'm AppyDave.
I hope to be creating videos
here in Chiang Mai for the
next three to six months.
But if you are interested in what I
do, I either do videos on artificial
intelligence or prompt engineering.
Please select to subscribe if that's
the sort of content you're after.
And check out some of the
videos here in the corner.