G'day, it's David and in this happy cast, I'm going to go through the planning stages
of creating two faceless YouTube channels.
This is part of a YouTube automation channel that I want to do over 90 days.
In the previous video, I did some research onto the channel names for two particular
channels, and I also just created the channels, but here we'll just do the rest of the
planning around the whole project.
Okay, let's have a look at the structural requirements of a YouTube channel.
So there's going to be two channels, and we'll need a, I guess we'll need a description.
Probably need to know what it is about.
Now a banner would be a requirement.
So what it's called a channel banner, I believe.
Put that in there.
I'll need a logo.
I'll need some tags.
Does that mean keywords?
We'll say keywords as well.
There's generally a settings area.
I'm not sure what goes into the settings, but I know it'll need to be configured.
And what I might do is take us over to ChatGPT and ask YouTube what it thinks.
What I might do is take us over to ChatGPT and ask it what it thinks we need for a YouTube channel.
Now I've just come over to ChatGPT, and I've asked the question,
when creating a YouTube channel, what would be five or six things that we would need to set up the actual channel?
It's gone Google account, name and identity.
We've worked that out.
Description and about section.
I have the about section.
We'll just change that to say section.
Channel trailer.
I haven't thought about that.
This is another way of describing what the video, what the channel is about.
Layout.
We will definitely need a channel layout.
This is where things like the shorts, the long form, the podcast where they show up on the front page.
We got video upload defaults.
We'll call that settings.
Keywords and tags.
They're the things that we've got to think about when we do the structural requirements for both of these channels.
Trend 10 and Magic of 10.
What we'll do now is we'll look at the team.
I'm going to need a team to build out the videos for this particular channel.
What am I going to need?
I'm going to need a script writer.
We'll work out how to hire these people as we go.
I'm going to need a video editor for sure.
I'm going to need someone to do thumbnails.
I think I'm going to need someone to do voiceover.
The videos will probably be aimed at the American market.
I wouldn't use my own voice for this sort of stuff.
I think from there we could go into the mechanics or the process for creating each video as well.
We'll call it process.
Drag that over there.
What would be the first thing?
We need to do some sort of niche research.
Process is both at a video level and a channel level.
We'll do a channel level process.
We'll do a video level process.
At the channel we need to do niche research.
Before we start that means we need to look at other channels.
Identify if there are any channels that are relatively new but growing, like viral, stuff like that.
I'm probably going to need a list of categories, like topics.
We'll say categories, maybe topics.
I don't think they're different.
Probably need a list of videos that could create video titles.
I will say video titles list.
There's not so much titles because that comes later.
Video list.
Then after that, let's look at the research for a video.
A video would be about a keyword most likely from there.
We probably need a title from the keyword.
We should develop the title.
The title should be something that will convert maybe a little bit click baity.
But so long as it actually delivers on a promise.
The title probably should be made up of the keyword.
We would do keyword research but I'll write that down.
We'll have a look at some tools that we can use for keyword research.
That would derive a keyword.
The keyword would then help to derive the title because part of the keyword would be in the title.
As I said a moment ago, it would be a keyword plus click bait, something like that.
The click baity aspect of it could be a double banger title.
Something like an awesome AI tools would be the keyword.
Then the click bait bit might be comma or yeah comma that you didn't think you needed.
I know that's a little weak but the idea of a double banger title is that you got the keyword
and then some sort of a motive statement or something to make you think.
Now the next thing is we would need a thumbnail and I'm thinking that thumbnails need to be done
even before the content and that because it helps to derive emotive information that you need
for the rest of the video from the thumbnail.
We could write an intro and a call to action.
We'll just type intro CTA.
I'm not sure how long this is going to be.
Five seconds would be ideal but it kind of depends on the videos I believe.
And then from there we would write I guess the content or maybe it's called the script.
There'd probably be an outro which might also include a call to action.
Now if I break down what's going on there and we say we've got keyword and title and we've got a team
and I think part of the team is me so I run the channel.
And stuff like keywords and titles might come from myself and that would help me to create a brief
because from that brief I could give it to a channel manager or I could give it to a script writer.
I don't have a channel manager, I'm the channel manager so I think it would go to the script writer.
I might just change that so it says channel manager.
This is probably a role I would like to have someone take over from me at some stage
so as long as I'm thinking about that.
Now I picture that after the keyword and the title are done that the thumbnail happens
so I'm also going to change the order of the team.
We put in the thumbnail.
I think it would be, there's kind of a catch 22.
Do you want the script first or the thumbnail first?
The thumbnail is the most important thing from a click through rate
so getting it well thought out ahead of time is important.
And the video, the script, the content can be driven directly off the thumbnail that way.
And from there it would pass over to a script writer that would use the brief
and we used the term brief here, we didn't but it would be in there.
Once the script is written give it to a voiceover person to create it.
Maybe I'll use artificial intelligence for voices, I'm not sure yet.
And from that it would be all given to the video editor to create.
We might, this is not part of team but we'll just create a section called video production.
In fact what we'll do is we'll create a section called production
and we can break off concepts like videos and we'll say script, we'll say voiceover
because we need to expand on each of these and we'll also say research.
So the script, read, video, voiceover.
So let's look at the video.
The video requires a voiceover of course and it will require a script
and then the video editor will put in a lot of b-roll really.
Stop photography sort of stuff because I don't think there's not going to be
a custom content created from cameras.
So it's either going to be video footage or it's going to be images
and maybe it's going to be slideshows and titles, something like that, slideshow title.
Now is this b-roll or is it a-roll?
It's kind of a bit of both.
Call it a b-roll.
And the script itself will also drive the lower thirds.
So whenever you're doing, especially YouTube shorts,
lower thirds are incredibly important.
I'm not sure how important they're going to be on a long form video.
They can also appear as two different ways.
It's like, do we want to show all words or do we want to just highlight key main words?
Like power words would be a good term for it I think.
So power words and lastly there would be an export.
So now the export is also interesting because the main video that would be created by the video editor,
I don't know how long it'll be, but let's say it's 10 fastest cars in the world.
Maybe each part of the video is 30 seconds long.
So you end up creating a video somewhere between 5 and 15 minutes.
And from there, if you've got 10 things, you might as well create 10 shorts.
So we'll say shorts and we'll call this long form.
And so the person that creates the long form will also create the shorts.
And when the shorts are posted, they would need to link back somehow, create a back link back to the main video.
Now, just the fact that I've said upload and linking back means that there's probably another team member needed.
Now that team member is probably going to be me, the channel manager.
But it's managing the actual uploads and the descriptions and stuff like that.
So that is actually another part of the production we need to add in.
And what we'll do is we'll call that video SEO for one of a better word.
Search engine optimization around the video would include the description.
It would include keywords.
Funnily enough, those keywords probably should have been dealt with over in the research.
So we'll just put that in there for a second and probably a link strategy.
So as I just said above, the 10 YouTube shorts all linking back to the primary video to drive traffic.
So that's pretty good breakdown of the flow.
I think for the video production, video SEO, we can expand on this later.
The voiceover, I think this person just needs to read a script and deliver the file.
Give me the file, something like that.
Script writer, this is a bigger process.
Let's think about that.
Let's have a look at what would be needed with the script production.
Now, obviously I need a writer, so there will be a writer.
But the main tool that both myself and the writer should probably be working with is GPT.
It's a great research tool at the very least.
Is it a great writing tool?
It's a good writing tool.
It's a better writing tool than me.
Is it a better writing tool than my writers?
Don't know.
Another part of this production process are using tools like Grammarly.
This is something I rely on to get my grammar correct.
We'll just move that down there.
And let's also look at the research area.
Now, I might bring this back up to the production and say we've got keyword research and we better list the sorts of tools that we would use there.
Actually, that just got me thinking with script.
This is where another key metric in any video would be important.
It's called the retention rate.
So if you look at the intro CTA, that's really good at getting people to start watching your video.
But you want people to watch the video through to the end.
So retention rate is both a key metric and something that can only come through good quality.
Good quality writing and writing that matches the intro, writing that matches the title.
Do you deliver?
We go up to keyword research.
Now, a basic technique is the ABC technique.
That's where you just go into YouTube or Google and you type keyword A and whatever gets filled in should be a good keyword.
Keyword B, keyword C.
So there's that technique.
It's free.
It's pretty good because those tools are returning what they believe are the most popular things.
And since it's Google, it's a good technique, but it doesn't give us numbers and it doesn't go and find things on bulk.
So other techniques for keyword research would be answer the public.
I like it from a visual point of view.
I think it's a bit expensive for what it does.
So I don't know that I'll end up using it.
I've been hearing a lot from a YouTube point of view about having vidIQ.
So I may end up paying for a subscription of vidIQ because it's not just about keyword research.
With that tool, you can create titles, create descriptions, do other sorts of metrics and analytics for me.
Now, I'd also just say research, which is a little different to keyword research.
This is just general research.
So for the trending video channel, things like Google Trends and maybe Exploding Topics.
And there might be other sorts of tools like Exploding Topics.
It's really a curation tool for Trends.
It also gives a synopsis and a graph.
So it can be pretty good.
It's a bit expensive, but for this sort of channel, it might be a worthy investment.
And another one that would work for either channel is just YouTube Competitors.
And a lot of that you can just do through YouTube, I believe we'll have to look into that.
So that, by the way, can also be part of the niche research is using YouTube to find other channels and see what they're doing.
Now, let's just look through.
We've got two channels, Trend 10, Magic of 10.
They're similar, but different.
And we got niche research.
We'll have to look into the competitors, a list of videos, a list of categories.
And that's going to have to be done for both.
Then let look at other channels.
Well, that's YouTube Competitors.
We can remove that now.
So we have the channel information.
Then the individual videos or video categories, you would do keyword research.
You would do researching on the topic.
This could be done by myself as the channel manager, but it probably is done by the script writer as well.
Then from there, we should be able to come up with titles.
The title should create a thumbnail.
We'd better just go down here and look at our thumbnail person, because this is the production.
So how are they going to do it?
So I probably want someone who specializes in thumbnails.
And generally, I probably want two or three thumbnails for each video.
Kind of A, B test them.
So A, B test the thumbnails.
And how are they going to create it?
Well, the obvious tools are things like Canva, but then there's a more professional person would use Photoshop.
I would use Canva, but they kind of always look the same.
So I don't know that that's the best way to go.
I've got a tool that I bought a couple of years ago that might be used for.
It's called, I think it's called Thumbnail Blaster.
I might try that out, Thumbnail Blaster.
And that looks good.
So we've got our titles, our thumbnail, intro call to action.
Another thing that's probably going to be needed in the process is GPT scripts or robots.
And basically this is training bots to do individual tasks.
So title generation.
Now, if I get vidIQ, maybe I don't need title generation.
Maybe I can let vidIQ do it.
But for now it can be there.
Probably create bots for descriptions.
Again, it's something that you could do with vidIQ.
Definitely structure of the article or well script is something that we could train.
But then this leads into, well, should we do it in chat GPT?
Or should we use a tool specializing in YouTube scripts?
Now, I don't know what's available.
That's a little bit of research I'm probably going to have to do.
So we'll close that out.
Intro call to action.
So back to the bots.
So intro and CTA is something that you can train a bot on.
So that's that's good.
And obviously that that makes sense for the outro CTA as well.
Quicker to type that.
Now retention rate key metric and click through rate.
Another key metric.
So.
And, you know, one thing that with forgotten in the process.
And is it part of the process?
It's separate.
I'm just going to put it in and I'm going to call it monetization.
And I'm going to close out this section.
This is enough for this video.
As we move forward, we'll look into things like monetization.
And in fact, let's add in a couple of other things to explore in the next video.
So building a team.
So where to find them.
Where to find them.
How much.
And, you know, you get you can use different online platforms, up work, online jobs, PH, fiber,
but certain platforms are probably geared towards certain types of staff members.
So we'll have to do a bit of research for now.
I'm going to need a project management tool of some sort, project management.
And probably a Trello board, I think.
Sorry.
And probably something like a Kanban board, I believe.
So Kanban board tools like Trello or ClickUp might be the go.
I'll probably look into both of them and try and create a Kanban board.
That can work through the workflow of producing one video at a time and see which tool I want to use.