Do you want to create avatars of yourself in various styles, maybe Disney art, comic
book, photorealistic, and maybe you want to have an API so that you could automate it
in the future.
Maybe you want to check out this tool.
Digital doubles are nothing new, but this little replica to end point will get you started
quickly and easily.
If you head over to replica.com, Tencentark slash Photomaker, you can find this playground
where you can create photos, paintings, and avatars of yourself just by uploading a couple
of images.
Looking through the examples here, you'll find that there'll be a prompt and within it
will be a keyword called image where the image you're uploading would be inserted inside
of this prompt.
If we started with this sort of image and we wanted photographic, then this is what it
comes up with.
Next example is a photo of a woman with the image placeholder.
Now this is the woman that's going to go into the placeholder and in this case the
style is Neopunk.
Here the image has changed to Neopunk.
Now you can also upload multiple images.
So in the case of a photo of a female painter in her studio and clearly this is
photographic, it's the default one.
What we can do is take these paintings that are here and convert it directly into a
photographic image.
Now that you've seen the examples, let's just have a quick look at the API.
So the API, they show multiple ways that you can run this particular model.
And if we look at the node version, we've got the ability to install it and then just
one set of code with the input image that you want to use to generate a new avatar.
Now if you want to be notified when that avatar is generated, then you can set up the
second set of code, which is a webhook to call the URL that you set up.
If you come over to the playground, you can then go through and drop any image that you
like.
Now I just picked a bunch of images of myself and filled in various prompts where the image
placeholder would be located, selected some output styles and then run the generation.
To use this, go over to replicant.com and put in Tencentark Photo Maker.
When you've got your images, just drag them into the input image area.
From there, you just need to fill in a prompt here.
We've got a picture of an image playing chess and they're coming up here.
We can move on and look at a Disney character image as a muscular man.
And then here I am at the beach.
Maybe you want to showcase of how good you are at dancing tango in a digital art style.
Lastly, you can change prompts where you go from male to female or vice versa.
So here we have a neo-rock band.
There's a female lead singer going on or a male lead singer.
Remember that each image that you upload will go into the IMG placeholder of the prompt.
So a fantasy picture of image writing a unicorn would look something like this.
Like and subscribe or click one of the links next to me for videos on chat gpt or prompt
engineering.
If you would like to see more tools like this AI tool investigated,
then drop a comment down below.
I'm Appy Dave.
Thank you for watching.