Is there a quick and easy way to write professional engaging articles for LinkedIn that promote
YouTube videos?
The videos I create often target professionals who want to learn about chat GPT, prompt engineering
or writing code with GPT.
Now the place to find these people is LinkedIn, but you can't just drop a YouTube description
or a transcript into a post and expect it to be well received.
In this video I showcase the LinkTube Transformer, a GPT that writes polished and professional
articles for LinkedIn that promote YouTube videos.
Oh and by the way, I rarely need to edit these articles.
Let's dive in and automate YouTube influence in 2024.
This GPT will work with your how to video on YouTube and convert it into a LinkedIn post
in a way that will extract the highlights and make it engaging for LinkedIn professionals.
Diving into the GPT agent, let's look at a LinkedIn post that was generated a week ago.
The video itself was build a YouTube automation app and I was doing the technical design for
this tool that I'm creating that mixes in the GPTs that we've been talking about with
the transcriptions from the videos that I record and just automates the process.
The interesting thing about the LinkedIn post that it generated was not only did it pull
out the useful information for YouTube content creators, but it also isolated that there's
an error in here about a programming language that I'm developing for GPT.
So this is a GPT meta language, maybe an advanced prompting language, and it's been able to
pull that information out as well.
From a LinkedIn post generation point of view, this was a one shot post I put in the transcription,
the summary and everything and it came out.
We've got areas like the hashtags and then I just added the thumbnail at the end.
Looking at the LinkedIn video post GPT, we can see that its role is to transform a video
transcription to a LinkedIn post.
The key guideline of this spot is to extract key highlights from the video and include
relevant call to actions and insights that adhere to LinkedIn standards.
Heading over to the GPT store, what we can do is go to the Tube LinkedIn transformer
and what this does is specialise in transforming video transcriptions into LinkedIn posts.
There's a couple of starter conversations I think the one we'll work with is use special
instructions plus title and transcription.
Here we have the summary and the structural analysis from the transcript.
We can use one or the other or we can even use both.
They essentially say the same thing.
They're just said in different ways.
If I copy all this information, I've also included the YouTube title and a little bit
of metadata.
Unleashing the potential of GPTs in Shell Scripting, a case study with Shell Script Helper.
Then we've got a couple of hashtags and some sort of introduction and we can go and watch
the video.
Let's actually see if that works.
Looks like it's loading up.
That's great.
And it just goes on to talk about this video.
Based on the way we use either the summary or the transcript analysis or even the transcript
itself, you will get different outputs.
But usually this is a one shot prompt for me.
I put the information in, I get it out and tiny little bit of tweaking is ready to go.
Thank you for joining me in this look at one of the GPTs I used to streamline content
creation on YouTube.
To dive deeper and discover how I leverage a GPT swarm targeting YouTube automation,
check out my detailed video, 7 GPTs to automate YouTube influence in 2024.
Just click the link on the screen or in the description.
If you are interested in more innovative AI tools for YouTube, don't miss out on my
custom GPTs playlist where I showcase a variety of GPT powered solutions.
I'm Appy Dave.
Thank you for watching.