I just noticed that OpenAI Sora got released. So why don't we sign in and figure
out how to use it? So I'm going to come down to this link for Sora right now, and
we'll just click on the start now. And from there account creation is unavailable.
So what do we do. Looks like we're going to have to wait a little while.
I tried signing on with my normal OpenAI account and it's also failed, so let's just
give this a couple of hours, see what happens.
Out seems only needed to wait a few minutes, and so we can now put in a valid date
here, which you're going to need to get started.
So it brings us to a usage page and we can have a look firstly at the GPT Pro. And
you can see that you can get 10,000 credits, 500 videos at 480p,
one by one aspect ratio of five seconds.
relaxed mode allows you to cue multiple videos as you generate them. Now since I'm
using plus, I'm going to have access to 1000 credits, about 50 videos at 480p So
let's just press continue.
It's asked for a username. So I'm just going to put in AppyDave And you've got access
to a little helper video and explore your feed. Now what we'll do is we'll close
out of that.
So before I get started, I thought I'd come into ChatGPT and just ask the question
about whether there are any tips that I need to follow when writing a prompt for
Sora, which is OpenAI's video editor, and I've been explicit about that so that it
knows to pick the right product. So we've got a whole lot of information here.
So I thought I'd try out doing videos on a cafe in Thailand called Kozi Kafe, and
I've put in this prompt walk up to a cafe called Cozy Cafe. We'll upload this image
and just mention that it's a cafe that caters to tourists and shows local artisan
products, stuff like that. But we won't just write that prompt directly. What we'll
do is we'll come back into ChatGPT over here and say, can you use this and create
a five second
video concept? And we'll just paste in the rest of the information, and hopefully
it's going to infer from the information above to give us a prompt.
Now, the prompt I thought I'd do with an image is called walk up to a cafe called
Cozy Cafe in Chiang Mai, Thailand. It's a cafe that caters for tourists and local
artisans, and we've got this image here that I'd like to use. But before we do, what
we'll do is just run it as a prompt to see if it can come up with something cleaner,
based on the guidelines above. So I've also said, can you use this to create a five
second video concept? And it started writing something for us. So what we'll do is
we'll just open all of this and we'll come back to here.
So we'll come down to the prompt and we'll just paste it all the way in. And let's
have a look at a couple of the options here. So we can generate five and ten second
videos. Maybe if you've got a pro plan you can do more I don't know. And we can do
720p. Now if I do this I'm going to use up more of my credit. So I'm just going to
stick with this one for now. And we can also play around with the aspect ratio. So
let's also upload an image.
And when you do that it will first come up with a media upload agreement. So I'm
going to tick them all off. I've read through
Now I've got this message that you can't upload photos that have people. Now the
photo we've got doesn't have a person, so that should be good.
So we come down to this button here, it says, create video, and we click on it and
let's see what starts happening. So at the moment, it's generating
video image, prompt opening frame, and we've, it's talking about what it's doing
480p five seconds and it's 8 55
modern bakery experience opening frame. The video starts with a scene of a street
view in Chiang Mai lined with lush greenery
And it would've gotten that local bakery experience from the fact that it says all
about bread here.
'cause as you can see, we didn't have the word bread here in the prompt.
Now there's no timer telling us how long this is going to take. So far, it's been
over a minute,
so I'm about five minutes in at the moment. I just thought I'd do a search on perplexity
to see what's happening. And many users have reported slow generation time, so often
seeing a loading circle without successful video output. So this could be the experience
I'll have here. I will try again if this happens after 10 minutes.
Now there's also a couple of other pieces of information good to know. So it's going
to struggle with realistic physics and consistency in log longer videos. So something
to be aware of. You might need to clear your browser case, check the status page,
or try a different browser or device.
So seven minutes in. We're still uploading, as you can see here. But what I thought
I'd do is just have a look at the uploads capability. So I took a bunch of images
from this Kozi Kafe. We've got this outdoor scene. That is what the first video is
about. We've got a variation of the outdoor scene, some indoor scenes, some product
displays, soaps and a grassy knoll to the side of the cafe. And also potential sort
of infographics around pricing. One of the things I noticed when you upload images
is if you upload two by accident, which I did, you can't delete them. So they're
all listed here at the moment. And I've got no real way of changing this, so keep
that in mind.
So working on the assumption that this might have hung. I'm just going to try clicking
on this storyboard. And what we'll do is we'll paste in the same prompt as before.
And when I went to pick the actual image, it only allowed it from the file system,
not from those uploaded files. So that's something else to be aware of. I don't know
whether I can even move this around, so the aspect ratio that it's showing here has
been determined by OpenAI. But what we'll do is we'll click on the storyboard and
we're taken to this area where we can now see things as different scenes. So these
look like the scenes that we saw in the original one being generated. And let's just
click create and see what happens here. And it's saying we can only do one generation
at a time. So I'm on a plus account. I think that's different if you're on a pro
account.
But while we're looking at this storyboard, here's another interesting thing. So
you can regenerate the scene text. Now, I didn't find a way to be able to edit it
manually, but we should just be able to click these
here's scene three coming through as a new scene.
What now has happened is that this is starting to change and we're at 91%. So I think
we're going to finish okay.
So the lesson there is to be patient. For me, that took about 15 minutes, I think.
And here we have two images and it looks like the right one. Let's see what happens
if we hit play. Oh look at that. It's put real people into this shot. Now there's
our physics issue going on. We're seeing the glass reflection not working. And it
just looks like people are walking through a wall here.
So let's not upload an image for the next video. Let's just describe a scene. So
what I'm going to do is paste in an image of some soaps that are for sale at this
particular Kozi Kafe
So what I'll do is I'll paste it in here. And this time I will use the storyboard
just to see what's going on with this. And we've got these four scenes. So the camera
sunny morning in Chiang Mai. The light filters through lush greenery. Then we've
got inside the shop. A person walks past wooden shelves lined with vibrant, carved,
fragrant soap.
Now I'm going to press create here. It's been added to the queue. It says the person
reaches the carved soap section and gently picks up a soap shaped like a blooming
lotus flower. And then we've got the camera zooms in on the soap, capturing the delicate
carvings and soft pastel colors.
So you'll know it's running, because you'll see this little activity counter over
here. But we should be able to click here and come back to see the generation over
here as well.
I'm a bit slow on the timer, but we'll just start one. We've been going for about
one minute at the moment, maybe two minutes.
Now it seems stuck here on 99%, but it's also told me that it's ready to watch. So
what I might do is just do a refresh on the screen and see what happens next. And
so what I had to do here was actually click on this to bring up this new view. So
can we hit play on this. And not yet. We are currently about 14 or 15 minutes into
this generation.
So here we have the video. In fact, we've got two videos and I might need to go back
and check the other one, because there must have been a second one on the left that
I didn't notice. But if we hit play on this, we'll see these. Looking at the soaps,
it's coming up to the stand where the soaps are available, and then we zoom in on
them.
So I've just come back and I have noticed that this is another video. So if we just
hit play on this, there's just not a lot going on other than the tree is moving with
this one.
So let's do one more use case. What I've done is this daily generated infographic,
and I've just asked it to describe the infographic. Then from there, I've put in
this question, can you do a video description about an ebook that teaches people
how to set up and run a cafe in Thailand listing the cost, pricing, models, and sales
and marketing materials? So that's starting to generate a prompt that we should be
able to put in with this one. I think we'll do this as a storyboard as well.
So it's just writing that out. And what we'll do is we'll copy it straight into the
describe your video. And I'm going to go with the storyboard concept one more time
just to see how that looks. Let's click on storyboard. I'm not going to be changing
any of these items just yet.
and you can see them all listed here. So what we'll do is we'll press create, and
we'll just kick off a timer to see how long this is going to take.
And there it is, complete. We've taken about ten minutes. So let's just go over and
test this out. Discover. And we can't read the text, which is pretty normal with
generations. It's got a few errors in it, but this is actually looking interesting
as an idea for an e-book. Let's just go and have a look at the other one we've got
here. Learn in the successful who and strategies who have trusted in Thailand. A
bit of a challenge there as well,
maybe this zoom in effect is pretty good with this particular video. What was the
effect here? This was more moving in different directions. And this like expanding
circle is pretty cool.
Now just to finalize off, if you go up into settings, there's an area called My Plan.
And from here you can see that I've used up 150 of the thousand credits I've got,
and that my plan will reset in about five days. Now how what is the timing on this?
If you click on the Learn More, you'll be taken over to the costing. And if you look
for the word reset, you can see that it's going to reset based on your monthly
but if you want to see the costs, they're all listed right here.
Well, there you have your first look at Sora video generation system from OpenAI.
I'm happy Dave. I usually do videos on AI agents or automating processes using AI.
Please like and subscribe. I'll see you in the next video.