Hi, are you trying to create videos for YouTube and you struggle with either the
intro or the outro component of the video? I'm AppyDave, and in this video we're
going to look at an AI agent workflow to help improve both our intros and our
I've been creating videos on this channel for about a year now, and I've never really
been able to create more than one video every three to five weeks. Now, at the beginning
of the month, I decided to get a video editor, and I've seen the quality of the production
go up in my videos, and I'm now getting to about one a week, which I'm happy about.
But I was analyzing just what I was saying in the videos, and I thought my quality
of what I say is going down.
a lot of that has to do with what I'm doing right now is an ad hoc script. I'm just
saying what comes to my mind, and that just doesn't come across with the impact,
the clarity, or the snappiness that would happen if I had a script pre-prepared.
This morning I was about to create the third video in a particular series that I'm
doing, and I realized I didn't know what the video before it was about. I had a vague
idea, but I didn't know the details. And in the intro of the video I wanted to do,
I wanted to reference the ideas from the previous video.
last week I also did a video based on something from Vid IQ where they talked about
doing the other end of it. How do you create an outro that gets people to move to
the next video in the series? So today I thought I'd expand on that particular workflow
and we'll look at how can we do an intro that talks about the previous video as a
context for the video that we're watching.
So let's have a look at some formulas for intros and outros. Now, recently I did
an outro formula based on getting 4,000 watch hours quickly, and this is from a video
by Vid IQ.
What I did was I reverse engineered their ideas and came up with my own flow. But
essentially what it is, is you've got a video that you're talking about and you want
to introduce the next video with a call to action so that people go on, what's that
next? And the technique is called the outro formula.
the basic information you need to make this work in an automation is that you need
the current video script and you just need to know the goal of the next video, and
it writes the script for you.
So I built this workflow called the YouTube Outro Bridge,
it would take the abridgement or the transcript of the current video, the next video
goal,
run it through a prompt so it could figure out all the details that it needed to
gather.
from there it could move on with the next goal and the content analysis that it just
built, and write a script that I could then read out.
Now if you want more information on that video, you can go and watch the video on
the Vid IQ strategy, which was the video at the top that I reverse engineered into
a GPT automation.
Now let's look at the intro formula because it's very similar and it's designed for
when you've got a multi-episode and you wanna do a recap on the previous video and
bring it into the one that people are watching.
the flow is simply in the current video
episode recap, call to action based on the last video. So the technique, I'm just
calling the episode recap formula and the information we need is the last episode's
transcript and whatever the current goal or the current script, if you've already
done that for the video, we're on.
Now I'm going to extend the old workflow, which was called YouTube Outro Bridge.
It had a content analysis phase and a writing of the outro, and it looked like
steps. And what I've done is I've gone and created a new one called YouTube Intro
Booster, and it should have the same steps for the outro. There's slight naming conventions
going on. We've got the outro booster, but then after that I now have an intro recap
content analysis, and we're going to have to put in a prompt here, and then there'll
be the right outro booster script. So let's go and look at those prompts.
Now sometimes when I write prompts I'll use the anthropic
prompt generator. I find it to be very powerful and that's exactly how I created
the last two prompts.
I'm going to take the last two prompts 'cause they are very good. They're designed
for the outro bridge. We've got number one, which is the analysis, and if we go down
a bit further, we should have number two, which is for the script.
make a slight modification to the top of this. We'll inject a prompt that says I
need you to create the intro recap episode, both an analysis and a script.
given a slightly different goal. Main goal is the intro recap is to provide a brief
overview of the previous videos content and set the stage for the current video.
I want it to be short, only one to two sentences. 'cause unlike the outro bridge
where it's really clear that you want people to move to that video, it's not necessarily
clear that you want people to go back to a previous video. So I'm keeping it fairly
simple
and telling it what three variables are available.
So instead of using the anthropic, I'm going to use the o1-preview, which is incredibly
powerful. I've pasted in that prompt, and we can see that after a while, it starts
thinking we've got 19 seconds
a chain of thought going on here, and we've got two prompts that I can work with.
We've got the oh two one intro recap episode. The only thing I've gotta do is make
sure I remove this information and we've got it repeated again.
copy those and we'll head back to where we've got number one and two, which are not
yet filled in, and we'll just refresh the page. And now we've got number one filled
in for us. We've got number two filled
Let's go find the information that we want to do a recap on.
I generally talk about four different topics. That's either YouTube, automation,
AI agents, which is what we're looking at right now, coding or general purpose topics.
And what happens is I'll end up doing things in a series, and the series might be
Fli-Video If I'm doing either YouTube automation
and I tend to do my YouTube automated content over on the AI-TLDR channel. This is
videos that are generated using AI
or I'm working on workflow automation, which is what we are looking at
that I use all the time in my own videos. And the one that we were just talking about,
the outro booster being here, I stole video queue's, 4,000 watch hour strategy is
what I use when I go want to go to the next video.
but in this case, we actually wanna link back to this video. So if we come back to
the mind map where we've got the agent workflow builder and the series goal is building
automations and standard operating procedures for businesses, we can see that the
current video I'm working on, I've coded it as number 79, but the previous one was
video number 71.
I'm just over at a document that I created last week. It was for
Vid IQs 4,000 Watch hour strategy. I've got all the information that I collect in
my GPT. It's available to me here, and one of them happens to be the transcript.
will come over to our workflow. We've got the intro recap, content analysis, and
it's the last video abridgement or transcript that we want. One of the things that's
occurred to me as soon as I've done this is that I'm missing the title of the previous
video, and that might actually be useful, but we'll keep this for now and let's come
up with a quick little goal.
I've just typed in the current video goal of show people how to write a script To
recap the previous episode in the series. That's going to get merged in down here.
All this information, we can just press the copy button, head over to A GPT, we'll
just paste it, press enter.
What we should start seeing is an analysis of what it believes the key themes are
in the previous video and how to transition it into this video.
I've just taken a copy of the recap analysis. We'll come over to the recap intro
script and we'll just paste that information in and press copy, come back to GPT.
I've pasted all the information in and I've let it run. So we've got an intro script
and GPT workflows. That did go on in the last video, but that wasn't the main thing
I want to talk about here. What I wanna talk about is the reverse engineering of
the Vid IQ,
for the transition between videos. I also don't need the explanation, so I'm just
putting in another pro.
In the last video, we explored how to reverse engineer the strategy for creating
seamless transitions between videos. Based on insights from Vid IQ,
we broke down the process Step-by-step using GPT workflows to automate those transitions
and keep your audience engaged in this video. We'll take that step further by showing
you how to write a compelling script that recaps your previous episode and perfectly
sets up the next one.
There's another step in workflow automation for YouTubers, and I have dozens of these
automations in place. And if you're interested in the software that I'm demonstrating,
which is the agent workflow builder, then check out the link in the description.
It's software that I'm developing and I'll make it available soon. I'm happy. AppyDave,
please like and subscribe, and in the next video we're going to look at creating
AI programming languages.