I have a script that I can say in
60 seconds and it took me about
three or four hours to write.
I did it for a competition and
I've just found out that I need
to say it in about 30 seconds.
So what I want to do is see if I can
create a prompt that will maintain the
value of this script, but cut it in half.
Here's the idea.
Can you take an awesome script?
Cut it in half, keep it awesome.
I've already created a video and
here's the transcript from it.
Now, the main things that are in here
that are making it go a bit longer is
that I'm talking about this 555 manifesto,
both at the end and at the beginning.
I also talk about the journey
of five different YouTube
channels that I've worked on.
And the problem is I probably go into a
little bit too much depth on each of them.
the idea is, Could we get
ChatGPT to rewrite this script
for me in about 30 seconds?
Currently it takes 60 seconds.
to get started, let's paste in a
little prompt that I've just prepared.
I need to take this 60 second
script, get five variations.
I want to test them all by listening to
them using AI voices, but I want each of
'em to be 25 seconds or less and this part
of the prompt is essentially setting up
the goal of what we're trying to achieve.
But there's one thing that's missing.
'cause if I run this prompt
on its own, it won't take into
account what I think is important.
And I've already stated that the 555
manifesto is not actually important.
So I'm going to write another
prompt and we say, before you
proceed, can you make sure to ask
questions about what is important?
We might even add to.
That just added this section here.
Keep asking me questions about what
is important until I say write script.
So I need it to interrogate me,
have a look at the script, and then
come back with a set of questions.
I'll answer them and when I'm ready,
then I'll ask it to write the script.
Now we can just check it all.
It looks all good.
Let's hit go and see what we come up.
With now, I like what's come up here.
It's talked about having five
different questions that it needs to
ask me what are the key milestones?
Are there any specific channels to
highlight, which is not the case.
I don't have any.
They're all important.
How essential is it to include details
about followers, speed of monetizing?
It's important, but I can get
rid of it, if that makes sense.
Do you have a preference for
mentioning certain achievements?
Not really.
is the essence of 555 manifesto important?
Not at all, because that I
can do in a different video.
There is one thing.
That I also need to add to this is
that it's done for a competition
by video ranking academy.
It's a course that I'm part of and
I'm trying to create this 30 second
video to submit to that course.
I better try and include
something like that.
let's see what we can add as
answer to these questions.
Now looking at the questions, what
I've done is written five different
answers and we'll go through them.
The first one, which is about milestones
or key points, and I guess the main
thing is because it's a competition
for video ranking academy which is
where I learned a lot of my skills.
would be good if it could be highlighted.
Somewhere.
Then the next thing is that all
five of the channels are important.
I think maybe they're not,
but I believe they are.
So I'd like to list them.
The main thing is I've separated
them out into three tech channels
one channel That is just a personal
challenge for me, and then, The last
channel, which is my podcasting, where
I actually create most of my content
to disseminate to the other channels.
Then number three, how essential
is it to include followers
and speed and monetization?
It's not really that important from
this sort of video point of view.
You, but number four, it would be nice
if I could highlight the one channel
and the one video that just blew my mind
because I was able to capture a trend.
I used concepts like
trend jacking and click.
Bait keywords and unique concepts
unique content points of view to
monetize a channel really quickly.
So I think it's important that it tries
to capture that detail, but we'll see.
lastly, the 555 manifesto, which
is really a future project, is
not really needed within this.
So let's just press enter and see what.
We get.
G P T has written five
different variations for me.
One of the things I asked it though
was to wait until I said to write
script, so sometimes it doesn't follow
the instructions, but let's have a
look through the five variations.
Normally what I like to do is get the
computer to read them to me, either using
eleven labs or Revoicer or one of the
other text to speech tools that I have.
what we'll do today is I'll just read
through them all because most of them are
off a little bit on what I need, and I
don't yet have what I consider a final.
Script Variation One through Video Ranking
Academy, I mastered the art of content.
Full stop.
That sentence just feels dead.
It just dies really quickly.
It then talks about the five
channels, three being tech, one
being a personal project with.
My heart truly lying with @appycast.
That last statement feels
a little bit wrong to me.
It's not the way I would wanna say it.
I will wanna change this if I go with it.
the idea of gaining 2000 followers
in a week is just a highlight.
It's an all right statement.
The problem is it doesn't
relate to the channel where it
happened, which is @appydave.
so we may need to play around with that.
Let's have a look at variation.
Two, a variation two feels a
lot better from skills honed.
At Video Ranking Academy, I
diversified into five unique channels,
@flivideo, @winningprompts and
@appydave Catering to Tech while
@carnivore90 is my health diary.
But AppyCast is where my story
is truly unfold, so that.
Whole sentences that
feels pretty good to me.
This last statement, did I
mention 2000 followers in a week?
a little bit of context
there might be important.
Let's move on to variation three.
I've just read through number
three and it's okay, but it has a
lot of similarities to variation
one from my point of view, and I
can almost say no straight away.
Let's look at variation.
Four.
This one has a starting structure
that's similar to two and
probably okay for me to go with.
Thanks to Video Ranking Academy,
I ventured in the five channels,
@flivideo @winningprompts and @appydave
for Tech @carnivore90 for Health
and my Dearest @appycast podcast.
I don't really like that last statement.
The rest of it didn't really.
Really make any sense to me
that the context is a bit vague?
Let's look at variation five.
This one starts off really good.
My journey began at Video Ranking
Academy leading to five dynamic
channels @flivideo @winningprompts,
@appydave for tech enthusiasts
@carnivore90 as a health diary.
It may be a little incorrect.
My journey didn't begin at Video
Ranking Academy, they've been a major
player during my time creating videos,
the and intimate conversations that
@appycast, that's also incorrect
in that what I'm doing right.
Now is more behind the scenes.
This is where I figure out how to make
tech do what I need it to do, where
I get AI to do what I need it to do.
to call it intimate
conversations is off the ball.
But I do the last statement being
monetized in nine days was a charity.
On top.
Okay.
So that's to me, might be
a better statement than the
2000 followers in a week.
there was also that idea of getting 4,000
watch hours and I did it really quickly
and I, so far, I've been a one hit wonder.
I haven't been able to achieve that
since, but I learned a lot going
through that particular process.
So it'd be good to highlight that.
Having read through this, I have
a prompt here that I've filled in.
I basically like variation
two and I like variation four.
The section about @appycast,
I've got a preference.
So I've basically say, when talking
about acast, I prefer a statement similar
to, and then the last thing is from
an achievements point of view, These
two statements, but I only want one.
I don't want both.
So I think we can finish this off
with can you make five scripts using
these new criteria for guidance?
And we'll hit go and see what it comes up.
Up with that G P T started writing some
pretty good scripts, but I did restart
it again and I'll just show you why.
one of the things that you can do at
any time is restart a conversation by
clicking on this little button here.
we'll look at the second one.
Essentially, I wanted it to note
that the achievement was with
@appydave, it started writing new
variations again, and in particular,
I really like variation two now.
You can read all of them if you want
to, but essentially variation two.
It's kind.
Kind of the sweet point for me.
Thanks to Video Ranking Academy,
I ventured into five channels, fly
video, @winningprompts and @appydave
Tech @carnivore90 for Health and
learning with Dave @appycast.
Oh, and a quick brag @appydave
was monetized in just.
To nine days.
To me, this feels the way I would
say things and I'd be happy to go
with this as a testimonial video.
The only thing that might have
been a little bit nicer is if I
included dive into behind the scenes
trials and errors at @appycast.
Though as I say it, it doesn't
really roll off my tongue, I
think I've got a winner with very.
Variation two, and this is
the script that I'm going to
submit for a little competition.
See how I go.
On a personal note, I've been a member
of Video Ranking Academy for over two
years, and I didn't actually get started
until November last year, but if it's
something you wanna follow up on, then
I've left a link in the description.
It's an affiliate link.
on the other hand, if what you wanna do
is learn techniques around chat G P T
or automating your YouTube influence,
then check out one of the videos
that I have up here in the corner.