Aider is an AI pair programmer that you can run from the terminal. In this video
I want to download doom, which is by id software and using scripting. Let's document
that complete project so that we can potentially create a new application in a different
programming language. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
Aider is an AI pair programmer that you can run from the terminal. In this video,
I want to download doom by id software and using scripting capability. Let's document
that complete project automatically so that we can potentially turn it into a new
version using a different programming language. I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
So we can get started by heading over to AppyDave on GitHub. And we've got this doom
with docs. Now, what it is, is the original doom software that I've just forked,
and I'm going to add documentation to it using Aider.
So before we get started with the scripting, let's just run Aider and we'll use it
from the terminal point of view. And what we'll do is we'll make sure that the repo
has been added in. We'll check what's new in the new version. I like pressing yes
to this every time I start Aider, because it just gives me access to new capabilities.
And the new capability that I'm seeing here today is that there's a copy context
where information from the Aider session can automatically end up in your clipboard.
That can be really useful.
I just want to find out what is this repo about. So what sort of code, what's it
meant to do. And let's just see what it comes up with.
Now it's worked out that this is the 1.1 release on Linux of Doom, and it's got a
little bit of information about the code base. Now, this cost money to do so. We
can see the cost here. It's $0.02 and we're on the first part of the session. Now
if you use the same prompt again, you would hope that prompt caching kicks in and
that we would reduce the cost. But I ran this again with exactly the same prompt.
And if we go to the bottom, we're still being charged $0.02, though we do have a
little bit different information. So just one thing to be aware of there.
So let's have a quick look at what we've got in the repo. So we've got these four
folders. So this one called send serve. If we go and click on the Readme file it
says it's something to do with a sound server. Open up the serve source and we read
the Readme file. And it's something to do with
modem driver
we read that and it's IPX network driver, and it looks like the main code is going
to be in this area here. So we've got a bunch of old Readme files going on with various
information about the doom game. So where I think we'll start is we'll go with the
simpler folders and just generate some simple documentation in a readme markdown
file using Aider.
So we're in the terminal and we've got this IPX directory here. And what we'll do
is we'll come down to terminal type in Aider and we'll put in message. And what we'll
say is create a read me file.
And after that we just need to put in the location of the file. So I'm just gonna
say, read me
MD and we'll press enter and let's see what it generates for us. Now while that's
happening,
we'll bring up Visual Studio. So we've got this new file being created and let's
just put it into a more readable format at the moment. And it says here, this directory
contains the IPX networking implementation of Doom. We've got an overview, we've
got features, technical details, and historical note. So we've got a bunch of information
that it's gathered out on its own. Now let's see if we can improve that documentation
by maybe reading each of the individual files and seeing if we can create something
a lot more detailed.
So I have a little tool that I built for myself that allows me to see files and also
the content and make them available for ChatGPT. So what we'll do is we'll just run
it on the current folder, and we can see all the files that are made up of the doom
software here. Now if we just bring it down to the IPX directory, we should have
C and header files. And if we just put in a dot h we should just have the header
files. Now from there, if I get rid of the dash f tree I'm going to get a list of
those files plus their content. And it's in the clipboard. And so what that means
is if I just paste it in we've got there's the last file right there and the content.
And as we scroll up we'll have additional files going on. So there's the third file
and the content.
let's format it. So it's designed directly for Aider.
Now, we already know that if we run Aider from the command line with a message and
a file, it will run against that. But you can list multiple files. But since we've
got our new tool, which is the GPT contest, what we'll do is we'll use it to find
a bunch of files based on a wildcard, and we'll just put in a format, we'll say Aider
and I'll put in a prompt. Tell me something interesting about this file. And what
this is going to do is just construct the Aider command for me, put in the clipboard
so we can test this out. Now the ID software is not written in an encoding that works
on my machine. So the first thing I'm seeing is a few errors as this comes through.
And you can see here that even though we got information, it's also dropped certain
files. So what we'll do is we'll just run it again. And I'm just going to go to the
beginning and I'm just going to put in this encoding option, which is part of the
Aider, because I figured out that this would be the way that it would read it through.
So now it's added the files and they're not being dropped. And we're going to get
clear information about each file.
Now, what I'd like it to do now is create some complex documentation just based on
these four files, and we'll put it into create documentation.
in EIP slash.
read me.md, and let's put in a more complex prompt here. So to get my more complex
prompt, I just came over to Anthropic prompt generator said create clear documentation
about a single C file aimed at a programmer who does not know C, and we end up with
this complex prompt going on here. From there, I've just taken the complex prompt.
It's here and just turned it into a single line so that we can just paste it directly
into our terminal.
So we've got the terminal create documentation in Ipcs readme
dot M.D., and we'll just paste in all that information. We're working on the four
files and let's see what it comes up with.
So at the moment we've got a bunch of information being written. Hopefully we're
going to see a new file get created in this location.
It looks like it's got the file name location correct, but it's asking us to generate
it. So we'll say yes. And now we have a new file. We should be able to go into markdown
format and see what that looks like. And we've got a lot of complex data that's being
created for us using the scripting process. Now, I'm not going to make any claim
that this is great information right now, but what you can see is how we can write
complex prompts, iterate over multiple files, and bring it back into one documentation
file.
Now I've come back to the GPT Context command and I'm just gonna change the pattern
to the C files, and I'm essentially gonna paste in the same prompt except right at
the very beginning. I'm gonna have it right out to the read me C rather than the
read me H file. And we'll let that generate the ADA command. We can paste that in
and it says ADA message, create documentation in the IPX reme C MD file. And so we'll
just press enter on that. Now this may fail again with the encoding issues, so we'll
see what happens in a moment.
It looks like it's working. Okay, as we read through there, we can see the doom CIPX
set up and IPX net C coming through. So this is all the documentation that we're
writing
and it's finished. We've got a file that's going to appear right next to the H file.
We can open it up, go into
a marked down format, and we can see now a bunch of information about the IPXC files.