Now, what I'd like to do now is create a complete documentation readme for the C
files in this particular folder. So what we'll do is we'll go down to the GPT context
tool, and we'll just make sure we've got all the files listed. They all look to be
good. Let's see just how big this will be. So I'm going to get rid of the format.
And it's going to give us both the files and the code. We'll just paste all of that
in. So we've got 43,400 lines of code across all of those files. If we go to the
top, we can see the files listed as well. And this is important to know because this
is your context and it's going to cost money.
So we're running the same GPT context command, but this time I've said the format
is ada. And we'll put in the prompt here. And what we'll do is we'll just come over
and have a look at a prompt that says, create documentation in the Linux Doom Read
me C file. And then we've got this complex prompt that we built using Anthropic prompt
generator.
so we can see we've got a command ready to go aider message, create documentation
in the location we want. We've got the complex prompt going on after that.
we will just let that run and see what happens.
So many files have been added. Warning it's best only ad files to set. You need for
the chat. Well, we do need 'em all. It's a lot going on here.
And we can see here we've hit a token limit. Now this is a more than fair thing and
we probably wouldn't wanna run this many files through one lot of documentation generation
anyway. So what we'll do next is we'll just split it up into four separate passes.
So what we're going to do is look at all the C files that are in this particular
directory, and we'll iterate over all of them and just run Aider on each file. Now
one of the things to keep in mind is that if we do a git log, we want to make sure
that as we're iterating, we're not creating a new commit each time, because we probably
want to do that at the end of the run.
So let's assume we've got a starting command that looks like this. Aider. And we
don't want the commit. So we've said no auto commits. We've got a message. And we're
going to assume that some sort of file is going to come in. We want to write to the
MD file, and we want to base it off the incoming file.
do you want to create the new file. We'll say yes. And we should get a new file just
created here. And now we've got documentation related to the file above.
so we can see the individual file and the documentation related to it.
Now, if we come down to the terminal and we do a formatted git log,
we can see that there's one file ready to go. So if we did this in a loop we would
have everything ready for a single commit at the end. And I'll show you the Aider
command for that later on.
So what we have here is the file we just ran, which was Aider. No commits the message.
We want to a particular file using an input file. And what we'll do is we'll just
paste in a loop so that we're just looping through all the files in that folder.
And we're just interpolating the file name with MD. And we've also got the file name
coming in. But let's make it a little bit more complex. And we'll take this complex
prompt that we did earlier. And we will just go dash and paste that in as well. And
from there we should be able to run this and run the complex prompt and create a
markdown file for every C file.
So I kicked off the command. We can see where the, it starts here and so far it's
run for about 15 minutes and we can see individual files being updated.
Then it moved on here. It both created and opened the d_items.md So we've got that
going on and this goes on for quite a while. Then at one stage it decided to create
files in a dots directory. Now, it didn't always do that. It would sometimes do it
in this
directory and sometimes do it at the level of the original file. So This's just a
change that's going on as we go. Now if we just go to the bottom, it's still operating
at the moment, so we'll just kick off the next one and we'll say yes.
And this one looks like it's going to be created at the root level, which is where
we wanted
that instance when it said open the file, I said no in this case.
So we do have a little bit of control whether we create them or open them in your
IDE. So for this one, we'll just say yes,
create the file,
So I'll let it run to the end and then we'll see what's being created and calculate
the prices.
let's check out a couple of metrics here.
So we've got all these markdown files in various levels. And that's quite concerning
to be honest, because we've got some at the root level. We've got some where they're
meant to be, which is in where the code was then we've got a bunch that are in a
subfolder called docs, and then we've got two that are at the root level plus docs.
it seems like it generated all the markdown documents, but it didn't always get them
in the right location.
So what I've done is brought all the files into the docs directory,
So if you go down to the chat history, you've got a whole lot of data that you can
use to figure out various things. So I'm not sure whether there's a way to get the
exact cost of the session,
So there's 84 lines averaging around about 3 to $0.04 per call.
We can see that the 84 calls cost $4.11.
And I got that information from the chat history. Now if we look for the create new
file we can see that all listed here.
for quite a while it's putting them into the right location. And then it just changes
for about three files. And then it goes into a high level docs folder for some reason.
then we're back to where it's meant to be. And then later on we've got a few examples
here, here and here where it's done it down at the root level.
So most of the time when it created a file, it gave you the option to open it, which
is not something I actually needed. It also, from time to time, would do a cat to
the screen and then ask a question. Would you like to add it into the chat conversation?
Now, I'm not exactly sure whether this was going to be useful or not. I don't believe
it would be because I was on an iteration of looping through and calling Aider each
time, so I'm not sure if it was in the same session. Then from time to time it would
ask to make a docs directory,
So the interesting thing about doing this level of analysis is that there's an unpredictability
to what was going on with the creation. Now, we haven't looked at the documentation,
so let's have a look at that next.
No Aider will normally take care of doing the commits for you. But I said no commits.
So what we're going to have to do is just add them and commit them
what I want to do now is get a tree of all the documentation files that we've created
under the doom folder, plus the ones that we've got at a higher level. From there,
we'll run this command one more time,
and we'll put in some sort of prompt that hopefully can create
broad markdown file that can take us to each of these documentation files.
So here's the prompt that we're going to use. We'll just run this. We've now got
it all set up. We can just press paste and let Aider do its job of looking through
all the files, creating a 10 to 15 word description for each file, and putting it
all into a table of contents so we can see information coming
So I've just pushed the documentation up. We can see it here. Code documentation.
We click on that. And we've got this long documentation table of contents going on
with individual files. Let's just go and open up a couple of core systems. We'll
do a rendering file a game logic, and let's go down to a user interface. And as we
go across we can start to see the documentation going on for the core logic
And then there's a little bit of user interface information going on here. Now I
can't tell you whether the documentation is 100% or it's the right way to go. The
main thing I'm relying on at the moment is that we can script to generate information
on bulk,
was great information in these files, such as just how it's meant to work as part
of the whole system, and also information for Non-c programmers.
Now that brings us to the end of scripting. Aider. From the command line we've looked
at single line calls. We've looked at how to do a prompt against many files at the
same time, and also how to loop through files.
Now, in the next video, I want to look at a programmatic way of working with Aider.
Now, one of the things that we can see from the documentation here is that they have
an unofficial way of communicating with this using Python, so hopefully we'll explore
that in the next video. I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see you
soon.