just watched this video Genius shortcut to 4,000 watch hours on YouTube, and I thought,
could I take the ideas that he's talking about here and run them through a GPT automation
of sorts and get to 4,000 watch hours myself? Now he talks about the idea of titles
and hooks and thumbnails being good, but there's something else that you can do.
And he encapsulated all the information in this video. So I thought, can I take that
information, reverse engineer it into a chat GPT workflow and execute it myself on
any topic I like. Hi, I'm AppyDave, and we're going to reverse engineer this three
step formula from the video. Now, if you've been paying attention to this series,
you know that I'm in the middle of creating some software for automating the different
GPT workflows that I do. And often I start off from this architecture where I design
them and we have this concept of a objective and an idea that we would like to automate
with GPT.
the simple workflow here is that I can list the steps, organize some, come up with
some ideas. So vidIQ have already come up with a formula for doing the hooks or the
bridge that transitions a video from one video into the next video. And I would love
to understand that formula so that when I'm recording a video, I can transition people
into the next video and myself. Now to get started, what we need to do is get everything
that was set in this video, and under every video there's a description and if we
click on there and expand it, what we should be able to come down and find is the
show transcript button. So we'll click on that and now every word that was said and
the time it was said is showing over here on the right.
what we'll do is we'll just click on this little button and we'll toggle off the
timestamps because they're not that relevant for us.
then we'll go to the very top and dragged to the bottom. And I've just copied it
into the clip. I've come over to the agent workflow builder, and in particular I've
gone to a workflow I use whenever I'm launching a video because it's gonna be really
useful with the transcript. So when I'm preparing a video, I'm trying to build things
like YouTube descriptions, thumbnails, titles, et cetera. And one of the areas I
can deal with is a bridging the transcript. This is about shortening it down to.
So I'm just gonna go over to this transcript field and put it through this prompt.
So we just click on copy here, bring up a GPT, and we're just gonna paste everything
in. So what we're looking at right now is the transcript from the vidIQ video merged
in with an instruction to give us just the raw information in detail. So it's all
coming through right here. We're already at the first benefit of this process alone.
So we've taken a five minute video and we've boiled it down into the key components
that matter to me, and I can read it in about 30 seconds. So in it he talks about
the bridge, a curiosity hook, and the promise of transformation. This is all about
from one video to the next video in the series. Now, a problem when I look at this
is that I've watched the video and there may be a couple of details that are missing
from this abridgement. So let's just take this one step further.
I've copied that response and I'm just gonna move on to the next step that I use
myself.
that's taking the original transcript from vidIQ, the abridgement that we've just
created and doing a quality assurance check on.
I'll pop up the prompt or the chat window we've been working on. I'll just paste
this in and if there's anything in the original transcript that I don't have in my
abridgement, we're going to at least have it clarified, whether we need to do anything
with it is up to us. So when we look at the differences between the transcript and
the abridgement, the first one, a mission of the game changing strategy is really
only his own emotional hook to keep us engaged in the video. So this is not adding
value to the process, but when I looked through the next three, the missing emotional
appeal details on viewer engagement and repetition for emphasis, especially the fact
that it gave some examples, I thought these would be interesting. Now they're not
part of the main process. There were three points to the main process, but they're
certainly guidelines or points of interest that would be really useful for any GPT
or prompt that you are writing to know about. So I think we want to include those
bits of information. Now, as I moved through and I looked at the other four going
on here, I thought they're great, but they don't really add any value to the process.
Again, they're more about creating engagement for the person watching the video.
So I've just taken that information and I've put in a prompt that says, can you ensure
the abridgement includes information on?
I've said, can you include three pieces of extra information, mostly guidelines and
points of interest and the original abridgement?
hopefully what we're gonna get is a three point abridgement plus some extra guidelines.
And this is gonna be really useful to us as we build out our workflow.
it's done a great job. It's kept the three sections, it's just given a little bit
more depth and nuance to the information. So with this, we can go and copy all of
that information 'cause this is going to be seed information into our new GPT workflow.
Now I've just brought us over to the agent workflow architect, and this is where
I'm building the different workflows in the GPT builder. We'll click on the workflow
objective. What we need is a simple idea and a goal. Now, because we already had
a lot of rich context from what we've been doing so far, I've just asked for the
idea. So we'll paste that in here and we'll create a goal past it in here, press
copy. I think we will start a new chat GPT window and paste the information in. What
we're looking for is just an objective for this agent workflow.
So that looks very clean to me. We'll copy it and we'll just to the next step in
the workflow, which is getting a list of steps that we might want to do, and we'll
press copy on that and paste it all in and see what list of steps it thinks we need
to do to get this. What we've got here is a list of seven steps that seem to make
sense when you are doing a bridge from one video to another. Now, in the workflow
tool, when it's fully operational, you will click this little button for start, and
those steps that we just saw will show up in the steps list attribute, and I'm going
to have capabilities to modify, merge, delete, or add to that. But for now, what
we'll do is head back to the GPT that we've got, and I've just put in a little prompt
to say merge the first two steps because they are one, I like the next three. I want
to drop this one here and I just wanna rename this one to quality assurance. So we'll
just run that and we'll get a new list of steps and we'll just move on to the next
workflow, which takes a step list. The idea is to convert it into a hierarchy. So
we can click on copy here, we'll paste it in and we'll let it run through. I only
want one phase called YouTube outro bridge. In this case, it's not a complex enough
workflow to need multiple phases just with one step in each of them. So we'll do
it this way and we're gonna copy this information in. Move on to the next step. This
is where we're going to come up with some workflow name ideas, like what are we going
to call it? Press copy and paste the information in, and hopefully we're going to
get some good names that we can call the workflow by. I've liked the first one, I've
just tapped on the word YouTube to the beginning of it, but now I think we can build
a specification, and this is how all the steps will fit together and the sorts of
information we need to collect along the way. We'll just press copy and we'll just
paste the information in. We have our workflow specification with it's the phase
we're in is the YouTube outro bridge. There are three steps involved with descriptions,
and we've got some inputs. Obviously the video content, what I'm going to call the
transcript or the abridgement is going to come through and it's gonna pull out key
themes using various bits of information we'll collect along the way. We'll get the
final outro. Now, everything we collected for the YouTube outro booster is now visualized
as a workflow with content analysis, writing an outro script and just checking the
script and putting some cue points. So if I just want to talk about it without narrating,
I can do that. Now, I did skip a little section because it won't be needed in the
final product, but if you were interested in how it created an automation script
to automatically create the particular pages we're seeing with areas for the content
analysis, writing the outro script and the cue points, then you can look at the last
video, which talked about this file structure. Let's test this out by actually creating
an outro. The irony is that the outro that we are creating is for the last video
to point to this video. So the next video goal will be this workflow will help you
get 4,000 watch hours. Quickly, the transcript to the last video, which is going
to have this outro, is here. So we'll copy paste it straight in here, and we'll click
copy. So I've run that prompt and down the bottom I've got the key themes from the
video that I want the outro on, and they're all listed here. There's information
about the bridge, the curate hook, and the transformation promise. Just copy the
information, go back to our application and paste in the content analysis with the
next video, copy this, and we'll see what sort of outro script we'll get. And here
we have it. Now, if you've seen how domain specific languages can streamline your
YouTube launch strategy, imagine taking that to the next level. What if you could
achieve 4,000 watch hours faster than ever? So this is a pretty good outro script.
If I don't like that, I might be able to do a refresh and it better one might come
together.
that you've learned how to create seamless transitions between your videos using
agent workflows, let's take it a step further. What if your thumbnails could capture
the same level of precision and engagement? In the next video, I'll take you through
an agent driven workflow for designing thumbnails. The idea being that you can create
compelling visuals, emotion capturing text, and a layout and system that'll get people
clicking on those thumbnails and watching more of your videos. So stay tuned for
the next video, and please like and subscribe or drop a comment down below if you
want to learn more about GPT workflows. I'm AppyDave. See you in the next.