you've ever tried to configure an agent framework like Crew ai, auto Gen, or Lang
Chain, or you're trying to design a workflow of GPTs that solve a specific business
problem, you might be wondering, is there a simple instruction language that you
can use to configure or come up with these designs? This is the third video in the
developing an agent workflow builder software. And before I even started developing
this software, I came up with this agent as code sort of idea. What I needed was
a simple instruction set that I could generate workflows quickly using a domain specific.
So let's start by talking about DSLs or domain specific languages. And if you've
ever used something like Terraform, then you've come across a DSL, which is sometimes
called infrastructure as code. And if we look at a scenario here of deploying a scalable
web application, you can see there's a bunch of tasks that would need to be done
to deploy that application. Now you could go onto something like Amazon Web Services
and use the configuration screens, but you can also turn that into code. And here's
an example of what the code might look like. So it says that the provider is Amazon
Web Services. We've got a bunch of resources that we need to set up and then you
just can continue on. You've got security groups, EC2 instances, databases. Now if
you run this script, you could automatically deploy and provision your scalable web
server, but you might also wanna visualize it. And if you visualize it, you might
wanna see it in some sort of graphic. And this is the problem I'm trying to solve
using agent as code. So when I'm releasing a YouTube video, I go through this workflow
and the last thing I do is I create some social media posts. I've got the YouTube
metadata that I need, I create a title and a thumbnail for the video. I'm analyzing
content building the chapters that you see in the description on the video and preparing
the video right at the beginning. And all of this is part of the YouTube launch optimizer.
And as far as agents go, it's made up of 22 different steps. There's 33 data points
that I'm collecting along the way, 21 prompts and six different phases. These are
the phases that you're seeing here. Now let's do a bit of an overview of the agent
as code setup that I've got here. So you can see I've got this agent creation node
and I've called it YouTube Launch Optimizer. And it tells us what it's about. This
workflow optimizes video launches by analyzing, preparing and generating content
for various places. This is how I release a lot of my videos onto social media and
any other writing that I need to do. And what that looks like. This whole process
is right here. We've got the YouTube launch optimizer with a bunch of sections, attributes,
and prompts. So as we move through this, we can see there's a couple of settings
that are in place. Where are we going to put the prompts and what's the default large
language model we wanna work. Now when I wanna make changes to this, I just make
the changes and save the file and everything kicks in. So let's say the YouTube launch
optimizer is not the name we want. And instead we want to go with something like
YouTube post-production. What I do is I press save and it's kicked off some processes
and changed the title here to YouTube post-production. So if I undo that and hit
save, we're back to Launch Optimizer. And the good thing about this is that you're
seeing a visualization from the agency's code, but this could be configured to produce
outputs for say, Lang Chain or Crew ai. So let's come back to the domain specific
language and we can see we've got a bunch of prompts. Now, according to this number
here, we've got 21 prompts and you can see them all listed when you click on the
prompts menu. And they're all loaded into the visualization tool right here. The
next thing we see is a bunch of attributes that I'm collecting along the way, and
those attributes are being configured as strings or indis or whatever they're needed
to be. Keeping in mind that large language models will only work with strings anyway.
But I have the concept of types so that I can configure the interface to limit the
sort of values that come in. Now because this is a section, when we get to the last
point in the section, we can go down to the next phase. And if we scroll down here,
this should be the building of the chapters. This is how I do the chapters in my
YouTube description. So the first thing I do is using a transcript that I type in
and an abridgement, I go and track down or identify the potential headings and what
was said at the time. From that, I'm moving through and refining it and then ultimately
creating the chapters in a format that's probably listed right here. And we can see
these prompts back at the top by navigating to the create chapters prompt. And the
way that looks is it's just a text file that I can alter. We'll just put in X, Y,
Z right here. We'll hit save on that and we'll hit save. Our prompt has been updated
to reflect what the configuration is. Now if you're actually interested in seeing
the repositories around this code, I'll leave a link in the description. Keep in
mind, this is a pre alpha release. This is me eating my own dog food and using these
applications. They're not ready for anyone to actually use, but you can have a look
at the code. What I thought we'd do is create a workflow from scratch and we'll work
with law and order to see law is something I know nothing about. So I dunno what
we are going to end up at the end of this. And search engine optimization. So if
you were a media agency dealing with legal, this might be the sort of workflow you
wanna work. So let's head over to the agent builder and I've come to something called
the Agent Workflow Architect, and we'll use this to create our new workflow. And
I've clicked on the workflow objective and I need a goal and an idea. What I've done
is just typed in a idea, I've called it SEO Agency for Law and Compliance. I've said
a workflow for SEO agents that specializes in content marketing for lawyers and statutory
compliance field. I don't know whether any of this makes sense, but this is the sort
of stuff that I would come across if I had to deal with a new client in Law and Order.
And I want to do SEO sort of work. These are the sort of simple statements I can
come up with. And we can just press copy. This prompt has been merged with these
input parameters and we can just see them down here. We can see the workflow idea
and the goal. And we can simply head over to GPT at the moment and just paste the
information in and see what sort of overview it thinks we need. We've got this overview
is designed for an SEO agency specializing in content marketing for lawyers focused
on statutory compliance. And there's a bunch of other information going in here.
Now you might be wondering why did I use chat JPT and not use the agent builder?
'cause the agent builder actually has a button called start, which would then work
with whatever large language model. But this is a proof of concept application. So
that sort of stuff isn't working yet. So what I've done is I've selected all the
information, copied it, headed back to the workflow tool, and we'll just move on
to the next one, which is listing the steps that you might want in a workflow. So
we're just gonna paste the information in right there, press the copy button, come
back to chat, GPT, paste it in and see what sort of steps it thinks we need. Now
we've got a list of items, identify key compliance topics, legal keywords. This is
all making sense. We could have a conversation with the GPT to expand on it, but
for now we're just going to copy it and head over to the next step, which is about
organizing the steps into some sort of hierarchy that might happen in an SEO agency.
So we're clicking here and we've got these research and planning, content creation
and optimization and publishing. I've just put in this statement to get rid of the
phase one, two and three. I don't think that's very relevant for us. And we'll press
copy and just move on to the next step. What would be useful is how do you name these
workflows? So do you name them based on their function or do you use something cutesy?
'cause imagine an agent workflow as being like a staff member or a team member that
solves a a problem. We might have legal Leon, compliance Christina, but here we'll
just go with a practical name. We'll press copy and we'll see what we're ultimately
going to call this workflow. And we could play around with this, but I like either
the compliance content marketing strategy or the SEO for legal compliance. If I move
into the last step, this is a specification. So this is hooking everything up. So
I'm just going to put in this, we've got the list of organized steps. And what we're
trying to do now is figure out what are the inputs for each step and what are the
outputs and how do they all flow together? And that's what the specification is about.
So we'll come back to our GPT and I've just pasted in everything. It's got an example
of what this should look like. And we're ending up with these phase names, research
and planning, content creation, optimization and publishing. We've got different
steps going on, we've got descriptions, and if we move over to the right, we should
have the inputs and the outputs. So for the first identify topics, we've got an input
of some legal documents and current trends. The output is compliance topics, the
input for the next one, it is the compliance topics from the output here, plus some
search data. Now this may not be right, this doesn't get it fully right, but I use
it as a starting point. So we're just gonna press copy on that. So our agent as code
for SEO and legal compliance is ready to go. If I was to press save, we should get
a new static page created using Astros. So at the moment it currently says SEO for
legal compliance is not available. Now I have links in the description below around
how I created the initial agent, static proof of concept, and then how I made it
more dynamic, which is what we've been using today using the minimum viable product.
But what I'll do now is just hit save and when we come back we should be able to
refresh. We are looking at the visual user interface compared to the agent as code.
We can see that it's called SEO for legal compliant, which is matching the name that
we created. There's also a URL to it. The description is in the agent as code, but
I haven't visualized it in the user experience. Then if we go to settings, we've
got a location for the prompts and we've got a default large language model. So we
can head over to settings and they've been filled in. The next thing we've got are
the prompts. And if we click on prompts, we can see all the prompts. Now the prompts
are not filled in with any information 'cause I haven't done that part of updating
'em in the files. In the SaaS application that I'm building. This will be stored
in a database. If we scroll down, we can see the attributes that have been set up.
And these are the data points that we're collecting. And we can see that by clicking
here. And we've got the list of data points in this place. We've some of them filled
in as I started through this. So I'm just gonna clear one of those out. I'm gonna
keep this one and head over to the overview. So with the overview, we'll click on
identify topics. That was the first thing that was thought of with SEO for compliance.
And we've got agent workflows filled in. And I'm also gonna put in some legal documents.
So let's say you've got this legal document, A, a, A, and we'll put in a space and
we'll just repeat that many, many times. So this is coming in probably from a PDF
document. What you can see here that I've put in a prompt that says, tell me more
about the current trends, which would be agent workflows, the legal documents that
showed. And then we go, make sure you give me the current stats on current trends
again. And if we open up the interpolated prompt, we can see those values being loaded
in in various locations. Now the other thing we can see is that we've got three different
steps going on for the research and planning. And so as we move through our agent
of code, we've got section research and planning identify topics. The input is current
trends or legal documents. The prompt is identify topics that would be read in from
up here, one of the files. And then lastly, there'd be an output, which is compliance
topics. Now, if I was to add in another one, we'll just put in A B, C, just as an
example, and we'll see that there's a new output attribute called A B, C. 'cause
the goal of this sort of tooling is that we should be able to give one or more inputs
and get one or more outputs in various formats, such as just raw text, rich text,
markdown, copy, Jason, or all the sorts of data formats that you might want for more
automated sort of workflows.
that you've seen how DSLs can streamline your YouTube launch strategy, imagine taking
that efficiency to the next level. What if you could achieve 4,000 watch hours faster
than ever before? So drop a comment down below and like, and subscribe because in
the next video we'll reveal advanced techniques to maximize your workflows impact,
and get those watch hours rolling in in no time.