GPT workflows are repeatable instructions that you might see over and over again
in your personal life or in your business life. In my particular situation, I do
automated YouTube videos where I have scripts based off information that I research
on the internet and that workflow I repeat over and over again for each video. The
other place that I personally do it is when I publish this video, I'll have to come
up with the title, the text that goes on the thumbnail, the design I want for the
thumbnail. And then when I do release the video and I have a transcript, I'll want
to get the YouTube description, the LinkedIn post, maybe a medium article, and definitely
a tweet. So in this video I'm going to show you a proof of concept application that
I'm building for building GPT workflows.
If you're wondering what a GPT workflow is, it's essentially a
of prompts that you might run over and over again. And back at the beginning of the
year, I did seven GPTs to grow your YouTube channel in 2024.
what it did was take the transcript summary that I would do in a video, and from
that, produce better intros, produce better outros. Here we would have the ability
to create a YouTube description based on the transcript, and then to share it on
Twitter or LinkedIn.
Because I'm doing GPT workflows all the time. I started putting together a little
application. And the idea of it is that you have a prompt over here and you have
some input variables. So create five simple project ideas on an idea. And we might
go with Gen Mo, which is a text image generation system. And if we show the Interpolated
prompt, we can see create five simple project ideas on Geno. And with that, we could
just copy that straight into the clipboard and use it in chat GPT.
Now, from there you would get five different ideas. You would select an idea, and
from there, make a basic fact sheet. So let's gather a whole lot of information about
this product. And the selected idea might be using Text to image in gmo. And so now
you've got this new prompt that you can use in chat GPT or in a future version of
this application by clicking the start button.
Now when working with GPT workflows, you often have different phases that you're
going through. So in this example, there might be a research phase followed by developing
the script where in the research phase where you can see the bunch of steps that
are going on. And where I've used this quite effectively is in a channel that I've
got called AI-TLDR where I'm creating different videos. And one of the videos in
here
called using GMO
is already an outlier with 41 times the channel average. And the interesting thing
about this channel with its 28 videos is that it's only about two months old and
I'm using GPT workflows to build all the scripts and they're good quality scripts
and they're good looking videos.
So let's have a look at how I was doing my GPT workflows. Now, I love using mind
maps. They're a great way of organizing structure. And when I was doing a YouTube
video script, I'd have this general stuff that I'd do every time I, there'd be a
bunch of information that I'd want to collect, we'll call it parameters here. And
there'd be certain large language models I'd want to use. Usually it'd be Open AI,
but if I needed search capability, I'd use perplexity. Now, from there, I'd go off
and do a little bit of research. There'd be basic metadata about the video. Let's
develop some facts and information in the fact sheet. Select the type of video that'd
be appropriate to the fact sheet we've built, and then expand on it, go into more
detail. With that, we could get metadata. And so examples of the sorts of inputs
and outputs would be for the expanded fact sheet and input might be a simple title,
plus the basic fact sheet that we got here and the video type that we're focusing
on, which would've come from here. The output being the expanded fact sheet would
then become the input for the expanded metadata. And that's where I might get a list
of engaging titles, keywords and topics. With all the research phase completed, we
could then move on to
the script writing phase would be create a script,
clean it up,
fact check it. So one of the big problems with writing any sort of information for
an article or a YouTube video is, is the information accurate? So there'd be a section
in there.
lastly, a human would finish the job.
so all the ideas that you're looking at in the mind map is what we're trying to achieve
with the GPT workflow. Just a bunch of steps in a bunch of phases.
Another more complex workflow that I do is when I create a Medium article. And what
I'm doing with this is collecting a bunch of information. I start from the transcript
of one of my videos and I'm building out extra information. And the way I do that
is running through a bunch of GPT steps, such as doing some research, developing
outlines, getting better intros, stuff like that. And how that looks in the real
world is that I've currently got two drafts for different articles. I've got, I recently
did a video on getting started with
and then
this article, but how I built 10 classic games in just an hour using WebSim.ai and
chat GPT. And I went through and I created these different games like Pacman and
Asteroids, and I talked about the other tool that I created. And it's interesting
to look at this because that screenshot that you see has been integrated into the
Chat GPT workflow software that we're talking about today.
So if we quickly look at the quality of the article, we've got how to use better
prompts in GPT to improve storytelling. Built off a transcript and after a month
and a half, it's already got nearly 400 claps to it, and we go through it. It's got
the prompts, it's got good paragraphs, intros, outros, and graphics, all going on.
And much of this was done using the GPT workflow that I just showed in the mind map.
Now, when I was doing my first proof of concept for the agent workflow software,
this is the workflow I started with building a YouTube script. And we've got the
research of the basic idea, the fact sheet, video type, et cetera. And you can see
all these bits of information across the top here. But we also had what we would
call phases. So we got the research phase and the developed script, and if we go
and click on the overview, we can see there's a research phase and these are the
steps that you would go through
followed by the developed script phase, and that would have a set of steps that you
go through as well.
Now let's move over to the workflow that I want to build today, and that's for the
YouTube publishing of a video. And what I've put in place is the idea that I create
a title. I need text for the thumbnail, and that shouldn't be the same as the YouTube
title, and there'll be some design guidelines. After that, I'm going to take the
transcript that I've got for the YouTube video and create both a summary and an abridgement.
And these are two different ways of summarizing text. From that, we should be able
to create YouTube descriptions, LinkedIn posts, send off tweets, and then move on
to the medium articles.
So we have our workflow name, and we have a list of steps here and how that could
look in the application is that the workflow name should go here and the steps should
be listed in this sort of area. But there's also this other concept going on called
the phases, and we can see the phases listed here. So it might be useful to go and
change
so I've come over to my mind map and I've just added a section called Phases, and
I can see three different phases. The first one would be getting the thumbnail correct.
The next area would be about getting the summary and the abridgement. We call that
research, and that occurs to me that there are two other areas that would be interesting.
So usually the chapter timestamps need to be worked out and they're useful for the
YouTube description coming up. The other information that's useful is just my brand
information. So it's one thing to talk about a video in a YouTube description, but
if there's nothing in there to talk about the brand that's creating it, that's a
little bit of a challenge, and that information needs to be fed into future workflows,
which we'll call, say the social media content. So what I've done is taken the phases
and we'll just expand it out. We've got thumbnail design and we will just move these
three items down and attach it right there. With that, we've got all the information
around the fact sheet, which is the abridgement, the chapters, and the brand information.
And lastly,
the post-production where we are building social media content.
so I think the name of the workflow going here will come from here, followed by three
different phases. We've got the thumbnail design, the fact sheet, and the social
content. And after that, there'll be three steps within this phase, four, within
this phase, and four within this.
Now let's talk about how I'm quickly designing these GPT workflows. Now, you've seen
here that I've created a simple mind map. And a mind map is a wonderful way of explaining
structure. But where it misses the point is that there's a lot of extra information
that you want in, say, a GPT workflow. In this case, we've got some input variables
and it should be simple to use and maybe a basic fact sheet. In this case here, I
want to create a DSL that produces GPT agent workflows in minutes. Now, that's where
I'm going to introduce the concept of a DSL.
what is it? It stands for a domain specific language, and it's really a way of writing,
just like we might write with a prompt where you've got both the information that
you want,
maybe a list of slides for a PowerPoint presentation, but also the semantic meaning
the fact that there are slides and that a slide might have an image on the left or
the right, and three bullet points. So a domain specific language is this beautiful
text structure. It can be written like a prompt, but it has both the semantic meaning
and the informational meaning. So examples of them in the real world are things like
sql, lasik, latex, and RegX.
So let's have a look at how a DSL could work. So I've created this little image here
called GPT Agent Workflows, and it's a bit of a storyboard that we could say was
done in PowerPoint of understanding the workflows, key considerations, et cetera.
And the way I created this was with a DSL. So I said, here, here's an example, DSL
for creating a PowerPoint presentation about the topic we're we're dealing with in
three slides. And it said presentation. So this is very easy to understand when you
are putting it into GPT. We've got semantic meaning the concept, that there's a presentation,
that there's slides, and that this slide has a title and some bullet points, and
we just keep repeating the information. And this was the user interface that I initially
decided I wanted to create
my GPT workflows, as you see right here. And the reason for that is twofold. From
a
point of view, it's way quicker for me to develop this little,
DSL language and make it very flexible. But because it is all text, I can generate
GPT workflows really quickly, just using chat GPT.
So over on the left, I've got the DSL that I've created for the YouTube script writer.
And remember that a DSL is a domain specific language and it's about solving problems
in terminology that's easy to understand and read.
what we've got here is the idea of an agent that we are creating. And the agent would
be a large language model sort of automation. And we're just naming it YouTube script
writer. We've given it a little bit of a description. Now, some of the things that
I'm trying to solve is I want concepts like settings that are configurable for each
workflow that I do, a list of prompts. And I don't want to write it into the language
here 'cause it's just too hard to read when they get big. So in this case, I'm just
reading them from files. Then there's a list of attributes or variables that I want
to collect along the way. And then there's just the sections or the phases. So the
research phase with a bunch of steps going on and that those steps can take some
information and they can produce some information. And after a while you'll go on
to another
phase. From that, the information is written out to a file and all of this happens
when we hit save. So let's have a look at that.
Now as I'm writing my DSL and I'm hitting save, what it does is it takes a file here
on the right and it updates it automatically.
so if I come up to the description and I'll just put in AppyDave, I'll hit save.
And what's happening on the right is that that file is changing automatically. And
every section of this,
workflow is actually represented on the right. So if we look at the sections, we've
got a research phase, and we could come into here and change this to research and
development, and we might go into here and change this to something like Claude.
And when we hit save, this value should automatically change. Plus now the default
language model is Claude.
So with that little change in place, the user interface has updated. We're seeing
research and development here on the main screen and also on the mobile version of
it. And let's have a quick look at how this is set up.
So for the proof of concept or first version of this application, there's the DSL
here. There it reads in the prompts from little files. So we've got examples of different
prompts just sitting in the file. And when you press save, it just writes out this
little J document that represents one workflow that's then automatically picked up
by a simple astro application that's rendering everything that we see on screen using
Tailwind CSS.
So the first thing I wanna do is show how easy it is to take a simple mind map structure
like we've got YouTube publish video and convert it into an agent workflow.
so what I'll do to start off with is I'll go get an email template DSL. I've written
a programming DSL for Rails and one that I've done for my script writing workflow.
And I've copied all three of these, started myself a new,
GPT workflow, and I've just copied all the information in. And I'm using a command
called Read that I've set up as a custom instruction so that it just absorbs the
information and asks what to do next. I then just go to my mind map and copy the
information and I've started a prompt that says, can you create a new DSL using this
structure? And I paste everything in.
it's in the middle of generating
it's got an area for attributes. Now this may be a little bit more complex than I
need at the moment, and I will edit it, but let's just see what this looks like when
we finish it.
So to get this working, what I can do is just copy the code that's produced here
and we can paste it in and it's seems like it's put everything in place. I have a
little bit of a concern around this loading of the files because these files don't
currently exist. So what I'll do is I'll go and create a sample prompt, we'll call
it create prompts for publishing your YouTube video.
And I've just manually updated it so that that's commented out and we're only going
to see the same prompt. And now when I hit save on it,
we get this new GPT workflow. I'll just click on the thumbnail design. So we've got
three items here and they match the information that we've got in our DSL. We click
on the fact sheet, we've got four there, and we'll go to the social content where
we've also got four.
another thing to look at is we should have attributes, prompts, and they're all going
to say the same information 'cause we're reading it from the same file each time
and some settings.
So we'll just have a look at two of the attributes that are here. One's called Summary
and Abridgement, and they're basically the outcome from the transcript in two different
formats. And if we move into the,
social content section, and we'll look at the tweet, they're inputs. So we've got
the summary and the abridgement. Now generally I wouldn't have both of them. I'd
only have one. So we will change that in a moment,
but let's have a look at it here. So we are currently on the attributes where we
can see summary and abridgement are two values that we're collecting. And if we go
to the social content currently on the tweet and we can see input of summary and
abridgement. So let's go change that.
Now, I find that Abridgement are really good for YouTube descriptions. They've got
a whole lot more detail than a summary. So I would remove the summary from anything
that's complex writing, but something like a tweet, which is simple, I would just
call it like that. So I'm just gonna hit say And because Astro refreshes automatically
when files change, it's just made it summary.
Now if you were paying attention, you might have noticed that when I went from social
to fat sheet to thumbnail, we were always on 0.3,
and that's because this is a proof of concept project, not a fully working, minimum
viable product. Now, I do have a minimum viable product and it's here. And if we
look at the same information from this point of view, we can go into individual areas,
click on them and see what's going on. We go back to the overview. We might go to
the transcript abridgement as part of the fact sheet, and now we can see that. Now
that's all part of the next video, not this one. The first idea for me
was the ability to get the DSL, generating the look and feel for all my designs and
being able to create GPT workflows really quickly.
But I'll just show you this quickly while we're at it. So let's say we put in a variable
and we'll call it transcript because that's what we've called it over on the left.
And we show the interpolated prompt right here. If we say hello, it should just go
straight in. And if we wanted to see hello multiple times, we could just paste this
in multiple times and we'll see it. The other thing that's going on here is that
there's the ability to select different large language models. 'cause the way I envisage
the software working is I should be able to pick the large language model that makes
sense for the task I'm on. Another area that's going on is the output attributes.
We didn't go into 'em in the DSL, but they do actually
work from the point of view that when output comes out of this system, maybe it can
be split up into multiple variables to be stored for future use.
you should just be able to go from step to step. And once you're at the end of a
workflow, there's a little down arrow saying that we're moving on to the next section,
which is the social content. And we just can move all the way through until we get
to the end.
And one last part is this copy button. So what we can do is change the variables
here. We'll call this my summary, and we'll go abridgement
in action and we'll just say AppyDave for the brand information. Now when we hit
copy that's now in the clipboard, and we could just paste that directly into chat.
GPT. I'm going to paste it here. And so suddenly we get this really long one. So
when we press copy again, we've got a lot more information coming for.
Now, when I first started this project, I did it all using Chat GPT from my phone.
One afternoon I'd done some mind maps around how I wanted GPT workflows to work for
my business, my YouTube channel. And I decided can I convert this into a database
diagram or an entity relationship diagram? And I basically did it on the phone while
riding the motorbike, I was riding the motorbike to a user group and I'd pull off
to the side of the road and just make another statement that I'd been thinking of
to the phone press, go and let it start generating information. And then I'd write
on another half a kilometer.
And as I was going, I built up a data flow diagram, an entity relationship diagram.
I started having a conversation with it around how the domain specific language should
work.
All that evening I spent in cafes and also at this group. And whenever I had spare
time, just having a quick conversation.
Now I've misplaced that conversation, but I'll show you basic ideas. So what I've
done here is what is a simple ERD or DFD in ask E for the following structure? And
I've just pasted in the structure we've just been working with. And what it then
does is start writing entity relationship diagrams around what the agent is, prompts,
attributes, sections, et cetera. And you can also get a data flow diagram. And so
it was this simple conversation backwards and forwards for many hours, but I was
able to work out the way my domain specific language should work.
So this was one of the early draft DSLs. It's using a YAML sort of format. From that
it wrote an AST, an abstract
syntax tree, which would allow programming to read that structure. We just looked
at, I think this is in Python, which is not what I needed because I was working with
Ruby. So I continued the conversation and here I got a cleaner, more human looking
looking DSL to work with.
what I like about a structure like this is that if I was to make this application
work fully in the cloud from a little text box, this is something people can work
with. In fact, let's have a look at
this product called DB diagram, which I think is a great example of how DSLs can
effectively create visualizations. This allows you to write simple little structures.
So I'm just going to put in hello and the hello is now connected up visually and
I was able to use this tool to create the entity relationship diagram as an actual
database structure.
so I spent a whole lot of time then getting it to create code for me. So this is
the actual code for how the reading of the data from that domain specific language
happens and concepts like writing it out to Jason and YAML were all written as code
as we went through this and you can see all the Ruby code here. From there, I was
able to create the Astro application and all the code got written again in chat GPT.
The only time I'd use handcrafting to fix things was when Chat GPT just was going
into circles. It does that from time to time, but a lot of the errors I was able
to just diagnose directly in this particular chat window. Now, if you want me to
go into more detail of how I'm using Chat GPT for coding, and definitely in the future
how I'll be using the GPT agent workflow to write coding and this has been quite
effective, then I'm going to be dealing with that in the next video where I've built
the minimum viable product and we can see some of the Svelte code being created right
here.
I am AppyDave and that has been a proof of concept around GPT agent workflows. Now
if you wanna see this turned into a real product, then check out the link in the
description. If on the other hand you wanna know more about either the coding, the
GPT way of building code or just the GPT workflows, then drop a comment down below.
And in the next video what we'll do is we'll work on the minimum viable product.
So please like and subscribe and see you soon.