I love using ChatGPT to write my code, but of late I've been experimenting with the
other tools. So we have CursorAI, Aider, and recently we've got GPT canvas. And what
I love about all these tools is that they can do really good code generation, but
they're only as good as the context you give them. And the context we're talking
about is documentation.
So in CursorAI the way you give context in the form of documentation is you head
over to the settings and you'll see that part of the context will come from your
code base.
then another part of it will come from the documentation you provided by uploading
or providing URLs.
So what I'd like to do today is take two open source repos. The first one is Handlebars.js.
The second one is cmdlet. And with cmdlet, it's just wrapping function calls within
the command pattern, and Handlebars.js is wrapping those same Commandlets inside
of handlebars. Helpers.
Now, these two public repositories are actually internal projects that I use myself.
I don't usually tell people too much about them, and what happened this morning was
that I was creating a new project called k_template, which I wanted to have use those
two projects. And when I went looking at them, we've got cmdlet here and we've got
Handlebars.js. They've both got similar version numbers because they work in tandem.
I went looking through the code for both of them, and we can see that it's a couple
of years since I've worked on these projects. And then I thought, well, let's have
a look at the documentation. So I've come down, I've got stories, I've got usage
examples. And when I opened it up, there was no documentation here. When I went over
to the cmdlet and I opened up the same files I saw, they too had no documentation.
since I need documentation from these for the k_template system, I thought let's
go and generate documentation today.
I've opened up the cmdlet project within Cursor AI. And what we'll do is we'll start
by just creating some documentation area.
we'll create a folder called docs.
within it we'll put in a file called usage.md. Now to figure out what we want to
do usage on I've got this little tool that I have GPT context. And it's just going
to gather files and present them in a tree format. And we can see here that we've
got say a area called case. And this is where things like camel case, title case
or making it upper or dash case can all be done using individual commands. We've
got all the comparison operators greater than or equal to. We've got pluralization
and singularization. And what I'd like to do is create documentation around all of
these on how you would use it.
Now I've just come over to usage and I'm going to press command L.
what that'll do is open up a chat window focusing in on the file that we were looking
at.
I'll just paste in this little prompt. Can you read through the following files and
give me documentation, format or structure that can help convey usage instructions
to developers.
from here we can press the @ sign
the folder we want will be the lib directory. So what I'm basically saying is this
is where you can find the code. We can already see visually what it should look like.
So it's reading through that at the moment. And it's now going to start giving us
some ideas.
Let's have a look through it. So Commandlet usage guide. And we've got introduction
installation configuration and then available cmdlets.
good thing is it looks like it's grouped them by the subfolders we're talking about.
we have array operations going on here. We've got inflection. Is that listed. It
certainly is miscellaneous which is showing up here. This looks good. We've got an
introduction installation and configuration.
we've got a little bit of an issue here. Not sure what's going on.
then the list of them are all available in markdown format.
I think we can just go to the top here and press this button. Can we exit out of
that? We can and we'll just accept it.
it's taken over the first section.
where this error was, it didn't know how to read it. So we'll just manually put that
in. And I think it needs to have three ticks like that. So we'll just close them
off as well.
Let's click on
apply to usage. We'll press continue and we'll see whether it gets added to the end.
It does. We'll press command Y.
let's have a look at the documentation. We'll close down the chat. I think we'll
close down the explorer. And I've got a little button here that allows us to visualize
it as markdown. And we can see our documentation has started to come together, at
which point we might be wanting to expand on this information. We can write it ourselves
or we could use Cursor in this case.
I've come back to the same chat window with the usage.md,
we'll head to the bottom and put in a new prompt. Can you give me code usage examples
with sample inputs and outputs for each cmdlet, you should be able to find the examples
here.
give it a folder for where it could find some. So we'll type in folders and from
there we'll press Spec unit tests and it should start reading through the unit tests
which exist for each of these cmdlets.
hopefully there's good examples in here. Usage instructions.
it looks like we've got some information coming in.
if you wanted to join some values together with a delimiter between them. So we've
got one two, three. It's doing the comma separation. It's got ABC with pipes and
we see the pipes coming through.
Let's look at the dash notation.
the quick brown fox. And we've also got the ability to deal with numbers correctly.
So there's no dash between the five and the 666 which is exactly what I want to see.
let's press apply and see what that starts to do.
Now, this is a great time to point out the problems that you can have with Cursor
AI. So at the moment when I press apply, nothing is really happening. If I press
continue, it looks like something's going on. We should see an accept. Well, look
at that. We got it.
So nothing was happening for a few examples, until I started recording again
What I've decided to do is go and take the example. It's just written, and I've wrapped
in some extra structure to the document here, and we'll just move down to this location.
Hopefully we can see the join post come through at this location, and hopefully it'll
also follow the format that we're seeing here.
it looks like that's worked. We can press command. Yes,
yes. And I don't know that I need the example for join. So we'll remove that from
the system. We'll remove that and we'll come down to here I'll press save and let's
work on the next one.
So let's go back to the top and we're missing the join pre. So that's a little bit
of an issue as well. But I'm just going to work on the next one in the list. So this
is case transformations. We'll press apply and we'll go with continue I'm hoping
that we'll see something here. Now again this is looks like it's going to fail
So I've manually put in another heading for the next group case transformations.
I've started off with backslash and we'll do an apply on that. Press continue and
see if it figures out where to place it looks like it has. We'll press command Y.
We've got another example coming through. Then we'll go to camel. We'll press apply
on that and continue.
And we'll press command Y on that.
So I'm two in and I've run into another problem, which is interesting. I think we
can fix it. When we look at the code that's coming through on the right. It's not.
It's cherry picking the files from that particular folder. So what we should be able
to do is head over to the terminal and we'll just run this little command here, which
is going to find all the files that are in the case changing folder. This is really
the order I want stuff to go. So that's now in my clipboard. Now that I've run that.
So we've got two here and we've got everything in the right order. Now it's in alphabetical
order. So let's just apply this first one. Press continue and see what happens. Now
I'd already tried doing multiple at the same time and it doesn't provide a good user
experience. So I'm just going to let them come through one at a time. So now we're
on to dash. We'll press continue and we'll get ready over here. And that's the right
location. We'll press command Y and we'll move on to Dot and press continue.
Let it come in and onto double colon. There's a little bit tedious the way this works.
I'm still getting used to using Cursor. I think there are better ways that we can
solve these problems, but it's still pretty decent. Go on to human press. Continue
still waiting. Command y. And then all of a sudden it just jumped ahead. And that
gave me some indication of what could have been the issue. I've seen this before
with Cursor, that maybe it was still writing files down in the chat window and it
couldn't move ahead as quickly. Or maybe it's a different issue, but looks like we've
got most of them in place for that one particular section, which is the case. Transformation.
Now circling back to the array operations. It had missed one of them. And we can
press command I in this case just to work on this particular area.
we'll put in a prompt. Can you add documentation for join pre. And hopefully it will
find the right information. And this is looking good. We'll just press command Y
on that. There's an accept all. Let's press that and see what it does.
Let's just have a quick run of the documentation. We've got the complete examples.
And here's the array operations currently only three. They're all joins with delimiters.
And some of them the delimiter can be at the end or it can be at the beginning. If
we move into the case transformations we've got things like backslash camel case
constant sort of notation dash dots double colons. So all of this I use generally
in handlebars helpers. But I also use this within other libraries within the system,
which is why it's isolated out to its own command.
So we'll come back up to the index and we'll just move on to the next section. We'll
try and do it all in one go. So we'll press command L,
we should actually go back to the last conversation that we were on. We'll say can
you add to the documentation misspell there. That's okay. We'll just paste everything
in and see what it comes up with. And we'll also move down where hopefully it's going
to come in in around this particular location.
You can see here using the chat window that has come through malformed again, and
this is going to be difficult to copy over manually. I'll try another approach. What
I'll do is I'll put in comparison operations. That's the next section. In this case
I'll press command I and I'm just going to go can you add to the documentation. And
I'm just listing the actual commands that are related to comparison.
Now it's just finished generating. I don't see anything. I'm expecting line 311 for
information to be loaded. Let's just move up. Look at that. It's pasted it up here.
Now, I could accept it, but the problem is it's going to clear this area out. I wonder
if we can say code is okay
but in wrong location, and we'll just say should be at 311. Press enter
now it's finished. It didn't really do the right thing, but it is better because
at the moment it's not going to delete this section. So what I think we can do is
just press command Y, we'll accept all that information and we'll just find the end
of it. And that's the end there. We'll press command X and we've just cut it and
we'll just paste it in here and press save before it goes and destroys any code on
me.
let's take what we learned from that last one. I'm going to move on to trying to
do the last three all in one hit. And we'll go down to the bottom. And I've said,
put it here. We'll press command I and say, can you continue with documentation.
then I've said and place it at, put it here and we'll paste in all that information
we've got. And what's interesting with the user interface here is that I've pasted
lines that have carriage returns in them, and you can't see anything here. I'm not
sure if it works. So we'll press enter. Yeah. Look at that. It hasn't put the information.
Now if I paste it here you'll see that it was in my clipboard. It just doesn't go
into the chat window for some reason. So I don't have any faith that this is going
to work. Now. Luckily I've been proven wrong. So everything has worked. What's been
a bit of a problem is the user experience is a little challenging because you can't
see what's going on. I'm just going to press accept all on that. Do I need to press
save all? Let's do a save all, see what it does and we'll and we'll come back. We've
got the information operations going on. And if we move down a bit further we've
got the miscellaneous operations.
So let's go check out the final documentation. So before we had page not found for
usage. And if we do a refresh we are on 13.2 at the moment. If we refresh this now
we're now up to 14.0.
with that there should be new usage information going on. So let's just click on
that
We've got documentation. Now the hyperlinks that we've got going on probably need
to be added into this area as well. But we can see the different sections.
here's the pluralization which is inflection operations.
what happens when you want to get the ordinal of a number. So first second third
or including the number 21st the 11th. How do we pluralize. How do we pluralize numbers.
How do we singular rise? How do we get rid of the plurals. So books becomes book
And then there's some miscellaneous operations like converting into JSON safe and
padding.