In this video, we're testing out what happens when you load too many files into a
ChatGPT plus project folder. And this came about for me this morning because I'd
loaded up all these files and I got this message saying responses may be of lower
quality due to the number of files used in the project. And I thought, can I work
with this and give it information so it uses the correct files? And that's what we're
testing today.
So for context, I have this project called 555 brand. Dave and I have a bunch of
conversations around how I do my marketing, my branding, my mission statements, that
sort of information. Now, I also follow a structured program from DENT international.
This is Daniel Priestley and the key person of influence. And I'm in the startup
accelerator program. And this morning I was doing one of the workshop lessons, and
I ended up having all these files that I thought, I need to get this into ChatGPT.
So I just loaded them. And the trouble is that we're seeing that message that says
lower quality responses.
So what I did was I quickly went into another chat window and I just asked the question
using the project files that are available in ChatGPT plus, can I deal with the fact
that there's a message like this? What do we do to mitigate it? And it's given me
the idea that if I actually specify the name of the file, I should be able to get
it to use that effectively. So that will be our starting point. But what I think
I'll also do while we're here is write a couple of prompts so that we can get this
more into the custom instructions. 'cause when you're working with projects, you've
got this area called instructions and I've already got instructions in here about
my brand. But what would be useful is that if I already had a list of the files that
are available and a little bit of metadata or instructional data about when it should
pick these particular files. So we will continue with some prompt engineering over
here and we will test it over here.
Now what I've done at the moment is set up a little prompt designed to iterate over
the 11 files I've got. I think that numbers are relevant really, but the fact that
there are PDF documents is true and we're trying to describe the main purpose. Now,
I was specific not to make this a synopsis. It's not about getting the summary of
the document, but getting it in a specific format.
And that format is known as a functional summary or retrieval guide. And the reason
for this is that we don't want to just know what's in the files, but we want to know
when it would be useful to pick those particular files. So what I'm gonna do is select
everything that's here and we will come over to our little document here and let's
just test what happens.
Let's just run this and see whether it can iterate through the PDF documents
and write a functional summary for each particular file. So the first one, it's only
done one of the files, so I think we might need to specifically state each file as
we go. But the good thing about building this information is that we should be able
to use it to create our customer instruction a bit later on.
Now I've just noticed that the bottom that it's suggesting that it can move on to
the next file. So we're just going to run that. And it looks like we can just iterate
through these one at a time.
Let's look at this document here DENT value canvas. So a structured worksheet for
articulating a value proposition by mapping pain points to emotional drivers. Now
I was working on this particular document this morning. So that all makes sense.
And so we have a guideline of what it does how it helps people. But more importantly
from the retrieval point of view, it tells us when to use this particular document.
So I've just gone through and done all 11 documents and they were pretty easy. All
I had to do was press yes. Each time it would tell me the next file it was going
to do. And that's what it's done here. DENT Origin Mission, we've got what the document
is about and when you would use it. And as I was moving through, this was all working
perfectly. I did get to a specific file of one of the people that is already a member
of the DENT program. This, her name is Colette. And I thought, this can't be written
that way 'cause I don't necessarily want to use this as a source of truth. This is
more an example. So I just made a simple statement
that it should go back to this version and mention that it's one of the members
and not a specific instruction from DENT. And this is great because it's come up
with when you would use it.
so it's come up with the fact that it's for a high impact person. This is actually
a really good example, but it is only an example being described. The last one that
was also important was that I'd done a bunch of deep research using open ai. And
that particular document is really good. It's really comprehensive, but it's not
the direct instructions as per DENT.
so I also ensured that when I asked it to process it, I gave it extra information
to let it know when to use it.
And we can see here that it will be used if I'm ever working on my pricing structures,
which is actually how I
used it manually a couple of days ago.
but also
that it's not authored by DENT directly. It serves as a complimentary resource.
Now I've put together a prompt that will help us prepare the custom instruction.
It's going to go through the PDF documents, describe when to use them. Keep a summarized
brief. We need a brief, but it needs to be quite small and emphasizes the retrieval
relevance. So I'm going to take this information as we see it here. We'll come back
to our main conversation. Everything is here. But I will actually paste in the exact
values. So if we just come down here and say
use
the following, something like that.
And the reason I'm doing that is because I've made changes as I was doing the conversation.
So I don't want it to use the past. So we'll come down here, we'll press enter and
we paste in all this information and let's see what happens.
And here we have the custom assistant instruction DENT project file index. And this
is looking great. We've got all the files listed. Look at this. It said this one's
not from DENT. Use it for pricing model comparison which is great.
and we've got
as not a DENT template but a real person example.
So what we should be able to do is take all the information from here.
if we go back to the project, we can click on the custom instructions and we'll just
pop down to the bottom.
We'll just go up to here and paste all that information in hit save.
So let's test this out. I'm just going to copy a few words from one of them. This
is Ideal Client Profiles. We'll head over to a new chat and I'll say, can you create,
and we'll just paste that information in using the following,
information. And the information can come from my brand, information from my mission,
and
maybe my content,
maybe the pillars that I work with.
And now it's just a case of paste in a mission, paste in some pillars. So I'll come
over to this document here. We've got a little bit of a mission going on. We'll copy
that down and paste it in.
we'll come down and let's look at the system. I use it's scale framework. I can either
do the short version or the long version. I'll go with the short version. And we
can already see that that's part of my mission anyway. But now we have a bit more
of a definition to it and we'll just run this. And hopefully what it's going to do
is look within a particular document.
And it certainly has, I'm pretty impressed already 'cause I, I've been working through,
this tutorial on this at the moment. So we've got ideal client profile, AI driven
creator. That's the sort of person that I'm marketing to because what I do is I create
AI workflows specifically for content creators, very much like myself. And that's
what it's saying, creative systems thinkers, aspiring YouTubers, creators,
solo content teams. So the client profile looks good,
the core pain points look good, the deep fear and the desired outcome. And it also
mentions my signature method. And one of the things to note is that I never use the
term signature method.
I know that that comes from DENT International, so I'm already really happy with
this.
So that was just a little quick walkthrough on how you can improve your interaction
with ChatGPT files, especially when you've got a lot of them. What we did was essentially
just take a go through them and build up a custom instruction, put it into the custom
instructions area so that when we're communicating with our project, it can pick
the right files automatically. Anyway, I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe. And
if you want to work with me, I've got a link in the description. You can book a call
and we can talk through whatever challenges you have. Anyway, see you in the next
video.