Are you interested in creating art with AI but you don't want to use VEO-3 orSORA-2?
You're not really interested in the generative AI. You want to go back to old school
techniques like using programming, maybe games development. In this video, we're
going to use context engineering to do a little bit of artwork and then potentially
show some business use cases where we might project it directly onto a building.
I'm AppyDave let's get into it.
I've learned a thing or two about AI art generation. I even have a faceless YouTube
channel where I explore concepts like avatars and face swaps. And we've got all sorts
of tutorials that have been written,
on how to do animations and video creation. In fact, I've even got from about a year
ago, a fancy video that I put together for 90 seconds. I'll just let that play. Legends
are forged in the fires of the YouTube battlefield. Only the strongest, the most
persistent, the most clickbait driven warriors will survive
that's a little video that I did about a year ago for a presentation, and I've loved
what we've been able to do with AI Art and video movie creation. But in this video,
I wanna focus more on a different style of art that can be really useful for generating
graphics for your videos. It can be used as something that you can project onto a
building, do advertising.
and the way we're going to do it is just write
a couple of little programs quickly using context engineering. And we are going to
do it simply using Claude Code.
So what I've done is set up a simple environment for us to start our project. I've
got Visual Studio and I've just got a terminal and in it I'm going to just start
writing Claude Code. And this is using Claude Code from the command line. Now, the
good thing about Claude Code, it's relatively easy to use once you get through a
few basic hurdles, and once you've got it going, you can run it within Visual Studio
yourself. Or I like to run it from the command line like this. And I think we'll
just start off with a basic context prompt to get us going.
So with a little starter prompt, I've just said, this conversation will be about
generating AI art,
things like word clouds, polygons, all the sort of computer graphics that you might
see in a game. For example. What we'll do is
we'll just tell it up front that we're going to do a little bit of prompt engineering.
We're gonna have to do a little bit of research on styles, and then ultimately it's
about building micro requirements documents and little applications that can just
run in the browser, some sort of HTML, JavaScript, et cetera. Now with this, I'm
just giving it a little bit of pre-contact and then I'm probably just going to write
in it. And this is just going
to build a Claude MD file, which is basically like a system prompt for this particular
project.
So the good thing here is we've got a bunch of tech stack options we could work with.
We've also got some popular techniques and it's just reading the folder structure.
And remember there wasn't much going on at the beginning. We've got a very empty
setup, but in a moment we will have a Claude md.
So the CLAUD.MD file has been created. We'll just click on that. We can read it this
way, or we can put it into a markdown preview. Just makes it a little bit easier
to understand what it thinks it needs as a starting point. So this concept, do the
NPM run Dev probably isn't going to be needed. I don't know that we're going to run
applications from NPM just yet.
we'll we'll see as we go, but we've got a starting document to get going with our
process.
So one of the interesting things when we are doing prompt engineering or context
engineering is that when you give a starting statement and then you end up with ideas
on how it's going to run, it's got ideas on the technology stack. It's becoming a
little bit prescriptive.
it's said, this is what we'll use, but I want a little be a little bit more artistic
and free flowing. So what we'll do is we'll just put in an additional prompt that
says, this is great.
but one of the problems I have with the Claude file at the moment
it's already decided on NPM and tech stacks. And what I want it to do is just be
a little bit more free flowing in its thinking. And this is really just going to
modify the system prompt slightly
because while all this information like the tech stack is great, we don't really
want to set that in stone right now.
So now things have changed in a really positive fashion. We've got common techniques,
generative,
animation techniques and visual effects. We got a little bit of a coding structure
going on.
So we can see it's modified a lot of the document. Basically it's removed the prescriptive
text stack. We've got no architectures. We've removed code examples. And we're just
emphasizing that this is
an experimental and discovery session.
so when we go back and have a look at our CLAUDE file, it's a much simpler document.
And this will be the system prompt as we move forward.
So let's move into this experimentation and research phase. And I've just started
a little prompt here that says, I want to create artwork that's animated. It has
bold contrasting colors, and I wanna make sure it's designed for use with a projector.
Now this could either be for wall art in a city, it could be for shop art, it could
be for advertising in a shop. So we'll let it just start running and do a little
bit of research
on different techniques that would work. And you'd notice that the first thing it
starts doing is searching the internet for ideas.
Now, just point out that when you're using a terminal, it's a little bit different
to using chat GPT or Claude in the websites in that it doesn't look quite as nice,
but it's still fairly easy once you get the idea of it. But it has this benefit that
it can read and write from files directly on your system. So any sort of context
or what I would call a document island is really easy to create, really easy to reference.
So it's written up a research document for us. I've just put in a prompt to ask it
to write that research into the dots folder for us. But let's have a quick look.
We've basically got five
graphic systems, I guess. So we've got the neo brutalist geo metric morphing. I've
no idea what that is. We've got kinetic topography. This could be really good for
advertising. We've got liquid fluid gradient animation, so we, and maybe stuff using
various gradients could be good. And then we've got a particle system. They're always
interesting and we've got anamorphic 3D illusion, so I'd be interested to see whether
that's around silhouettes or stuff like that. Silhouettes are a style of art that
I like using in business animations,
and if that isn't what that is, we can always add it in later. So at the moment,
it's writing out a document for us. Let's see what's happened in Visual Studio. We've
got a dots folder. We can go and have a look at what it's written and we've got all
our information ready to go. So the great thing is with this document here, we can
pull it in as we need it. We can modify it anytime we like.
Now, if you want access to any of the prompts or the instructions and documents that
I'm creating, they're all available in my community, and I'm going to be making that
link available soon on the YouTube channel. So check it out there if you want the
actual prompts. That said, let's keep going.
So we've got a great little document. I'm just going to kick off a new prompt. And
what the document says is that we've got detailed descriptions for each of the styles.
We've got why they would work for the target that we've got advertising, maybe a
bit of artwork, we've got colour palettes. My question is what sort of technology
do we want to use?
So I want to use something consistent across all five, but I am open to it. Having
specific ideas around potential styles, it might just make sense to use a particular
library.
I'm not sure if we want pure JavaScript, whether
we want something like D3 for JavaScript, or whether
we want something like tailwind for CSS, so it's just coming up with ideas at the
moment.
Let's bring up the document as well. So we've got the tech stack analysis going on,
and we'll visualize it
in the markdown document here. But the basic things, it's said that each demo can
be a self-contained HTML file. We'll use the HTML canvas, minimal, raw CSS and vanilla
JavaScript. So this is great. We could run
this in Gemini, we could run it
in Codex, we could run it in Claude, which we're going to do today, or the Claude
Artifact system up in the cloud. And each of these individual requirements documents
should just
come up with something unique. By the way, one of the reasons I like to run these
across different environments is because you can use the same input requirements
and get different styles
based on the large language model you use.
And I think one of the really great things about what it said is that these awesome
libraries are overkill for what we're trying to do. And this was one of the reasons
why I wanted the Claude MD not to describe any architectures up front. I wanted to
see what this system would come up with. And this is part of the contest engineering
approach.
Now with our tech stack analysis done, I want to go and figure out what the next
step is. Now, I'm not sure if we want to build requirements documents for the five
different styles or whether we need an intermediate document. So I'm letting it have
a think about it.
And the main reason for this is I want to build an AI agent, I guess. So I've got
this little section in here
and giving it extra context about the fact that we need an agent that can do AB testing.
In other words, create more than one version of each animation style from the same
requirements document. Now it's come up with a document strategy, so let's read that
and see what it's thinking.
And this is perfect. We've got, firstly, the human sort of document. The document
strategy is the style guide, and this is where we can consider all the different
aspects of each individual style and let it go a little bit deep into it. The second
one is the requirements document. This is what the agent will use to build the website
or the animation.
So it's given us a proposed structure, five different
style guides. We'll have a number of requirements documents. It's given a template
for how the
style guide would work and a template for the requirements documents. But it's come
up with two options. I usually go with the recommendation, but let's just have a
quick read
and I'm glad I did read it. So for this video, we will go with option A, because
I just want to test out the ideas, but if I was doing it for an actual project, I
would use option B. I want to go deep into anyone's style. So we can just say option
A, or I'll say Go with the recommendation
like that, and it will start building out the documents that we want. We are going
to see them come through on our Visual studio area, and we'll just pop up the explorer
and see new concept coming in here.
So you can see it's done a make
dash piece. So whether it exists or doesn't exist, it'll create the Style Guides
folder. It's there. We've got our first file being created. It's the template, and
what else? We can see all the different steps that it wants to do right here. One
of the things that you can do is press Control T to hide that, but I like to see
what's going on.
So our first document has been created. One of the things is that it created the
template first so that it could use that as a guideline for future documents. So
if we click in here and go for the geometric morphing,
we've got the visual identity of what that's all about. We've got visual characteristics,
we've got some color palettes, and we've got some motion language. Now,
when we get to the end of this, I'm probably going to get it to review all the documents
to make sure that they're created in such a way that they're good for projections.
Now, I'm not sure whether it needs to be done in the styling documents or whether
we could just do it in the requirements documents, but we'll write the prompt and
see what happens.
Okay. We've now got five different style guides that we can work with. What I think
I'll do next is create an agent, something with a role. And the role will specifically
be around software architecture or business analyst. And what I want it to do is
create the first agent
who understands how to work with the tech stack,
understands how to work with any of the style guides, and can produce a requirements
document. It's also got a little bit of a special capability, and that's at any graphics
that we generate should be designed for projectors. So when you're projecting on
a wall, if you have an edge to the graphic, like say, a box, it really stands out
on the wall. Whereas if you have a black background, then it kind of blends in and
you don't notice that it's a graphic on top of a wall, it can make it look a little
bit more realistic.
So we have our first agent name is Maya, requirements Architect Agent. Let's go and
have a look what she looks like. We'll click in here and there we have Maya. So the
main things is understands the tech stack, the requirements,
style guides, how to write a requirements document, and it's got this critical feature
that it understands how to draw edge management. So make it look nice against a background
like a wall or of a shop,
and we can see what's included here. So as we scroll through, we should see the role
definition, project design principles going on,
knowledge about the tech stack and the agent workflow. So the input process and output
sort of concept. Let's look at this. We've got a little bit of technical implementation
details that it's already pre-trained with. It's not the developer agent, but it's
got basic ideas that it can pass on to the developer agent. Looks like we've also
got a requirements document template for us.
Now, I will point out that I'm a big proponent of the bmad method. For most of my
coding. I use a proper context engineering framework. But as you can see, you can
build your own frameworks pretty quickly with just some simple context engineering
prompts.
So the next step, I wanna start building requirements documents. I also want to find
out exactly what structure it thinks we should come up with for the requirements
documents. And then at the very end, I wanted to suggest the sort of software developer
we need to implement these requirements. And that's so I don't need to actually tell
it what to do. It'll come up with a good idea of what the software developer should
look like. And then after that we can simply say, create this as an agent. But let's
see what it's come up with
So this is a great structure. There is one problem I can see already, but we've got
our style guides, we've got our requirements documents that we are
going to be creating. We've got our mayor requirements agent, and our new agent is
going to go in here. The problem I have is with the demos, this all looks good, but
I want to do AB testing, which means that for any one style or requirements that
we're going to work with, let's create 3, 4, 5 different versions of it just so that
we've got variety.
So I've just confirmed most of the statements that's come up with, I've said to go
with Kai, let it build an agent. I've made sure that we've got this variation number,
basically a number of variations starting hopefully from one, I didn't specifically
give the number, but it should be able to work that out. And then I said, go ahead
and create all five requirements and the agent, so when we look at
the to-dos,
the control t, to see that, we can
see that it's going to create five different requirements and then
it's going to create the Kai developer agent.
Now here we are with an updated project structure and we've got our new agent and
everything's looking a lot cleaner. So we still have our style guides and requirements
as before. The demos folder has just become a read me document with a naming convention
guideline.
Now, when we look at the agents, we've still got our existing agent Mayor with the
key feature being Albert to work with projection style setups for graphics generation.
And we've got Kai, who is a developer, very specialized in what sort of work this
agent does 60 frame per second,
performance optimization, single HTML, contained pages. And we're using the Canvas,
API
and essentially just reading, reading and writing simple documents. So as we go through
this, we can also see that the demo output structures have been reformatted a little
bit, so that we have the AB testing area in here. So we might be able to do three
different animations and we can see them all through the A, the B, and the C.
And if we just go down to Visual Studio, we can see the new documents or the, we've
got the demos, we have all the instructions on how this is meant to work. It's also
given now a couple of examples of how you could run these pages directly from JavaScript
or
from Python. And we've got the Kai developer going on in here. Let's visualize it
properly.
we've got the full role and identity core responsibilities being listed, the code,
formats and standards that the developer works to.
And of course, if you need any of the prompts or the structures here, it's all available
in my community. There's a link down in the description.
Now we're nearly at the point where we can start testing the system to see how the
animations work. But before we do that, let's have a little bit of an audit of the
system just to see how the prompts and the structures are holding up. So what I've
done is just started off with a little prompt asking for
a holistic review of the system. We want to look at the agents. We want to look at
the style guides. We want to look at the requirements documents. And all of this
is to make sure that everything is structurally sound. And then from there, hopefully
we can move on to just generating our HTML animations or if there's any feedback,
we can operate on that as well.
Now, just as we're going. I saw this little tip here. I'd. I've been able to add
images into Claude Code all along by referencing them by file, but I just found out
that one of the things that you can do
is if you've got a picture in your clipboard, like I do right now, I can press
control V. Now I'm on a mac and the normal paste operation is command V, so this
has never worked before until I just saw this tip right now.
Anyway this is finished the comprehensive system audit. Let's go check it out.
So the great thing about an audit is that if there's any slight discrepancies, and
we can see one in the naming conventions here, it can be fixed pretty quickly.
there's going to be some questions that need to be answered. So what I'm gonna do
is go down to the bottom where it's got a number of questions. It's asking me, I
just want to apply the fixes and I want to do a little bit of a review. So let's
just see what it comes up with. And so far, Claude is doing pretty good. I'm gonna
press three. This is just a bit of a feedback mechanism.
So we've had a little bit of improvement in the naming convention. It knows about
the AB testing here in the particular agent. It was already in the documentation,
just not in the agent.
So we've got misunderstanding and confusion resolved in both of our agents. And we've
got a little bit of a automatic automated decision making framework going on here.
So when open questions come up, it can autonomously deal with it using documented
decisions. So what that means for me is that as I have different ideas that I want
to become solid and true, I can document them and they can be used automatically
by the agent. So with that said, let's move on and create our first animation.
So we have our first generation complete, it's called a geometric morphine. We can
see one of the things it can work with is a bunch of parameters if you want to change
the way the morphine happens,
and it gives various,
versions with different parameters that we can play with right here. Let's go have
a look at what it could look like. So this is the default version, and I'll just
show one of the others that are available. It's just going a little bit slower at
the moment.
And so with our first animation created, let's just go over and see if it can do
two other variations. And this is a great thing about working with either Codex,
Claude Code, or Gemini. In the CLI like we're doing, this is all Claude code, which
is my favorite. We can just start running a new agent,
And this time we're going to generate two different animations in two separate files.
So variation B and C are being created. It gives us a bit of information about how
it works. And then if we move down the bottom, we can see how to open each of these
demonstrations and also potential parameters. If we just head over to the web view,
this is variation B going on at the moment. And if we move on to the next one we've
got variation C here.
Now the one of the things that we can notice about everything that we're doing is
that there is no edge at the side of the screen. And this was one of the important
rules of this particular developer. And of the styles that we were producing, is
that it should look good on a projector, on a wall without having any images to the
edge. And this is something I've just noticed using projectors on walls is that if
you've got this edge, it just looks a little bit odd in the animations.
So now we can just finish off with a bulk running of the system. So I'm just going
to kick off the prompt and talk a little bit about what's going to happen next. So
we have four other styles that we haven't looked at at the moment. And we can see
them coming up here. We've got kinetic type fluid gradients particle system and anamorphic
3D. And what I've also asked for it to do is generate the three variations per type.
Now we could add other custom instructions. We could make statements like we want
it to have a Christmas or a Halloween theme or whatever we want, but for now, we're
just keeping it simple. This will take a little bit of time to run, but at the end
of it we should have 12 new HTML animations that we can test. Hopefully we've got
reports.
and we'll have a look at everything once this is complete.
Now here we are at the end of the generation. I dunno how long it took. It was going
for about five minutes. I went out for a coffee. And that's the good thing about
using Claude Code. You can pretty reliably believe that it'll end up with a good
solution. So long as your requirements documents, you processes are well written.
So what I did was I let it run through and I also kicked off a prompt before I left
for the coffee and I just asked it to create a little bit of an index HTML file,
because I wanted to be able to see all the different,
types of generations, but also the variations. So as it went through, it started
building out documentation. We've got a demo's reference, we've got a quick reference
and we've got the primary file that I'd like to open. So what we'll do is we will
open that file right now, and here we have it. It's got the AI, programmatic art
gallery. We've got 15 projection ready demonstrations.
let's see what this text along the top does.
it's just taking us down to the different areas. Okay, that's interesting. So
What I'll do is option, click on each of these and just make sure that I'm opening
up variations just to see how they all work and let's go check it out.
Okay, and here we go. We've got our first one that we were working with earlier and
a variation from it. As I was going through and just checking these out, I noticed
that not all of them worked nicely and this is the reason why it's really good to
have variations. The variations are the same requirements document, but it's a different
interpretation each time. So let's keep going. This is where the kinetic text kick
in and this just looks wonderful. This sort of,
text. You could use it on your YouTube channel. I would use it on my YouTube channel,
to change different concepts. So here we've got kinetic topography. I wonder if we
can change any of the words.
And I was able to change the words programmatically. There's a actual variables up
the top of this URL, but they're not working. But I've got AppyDave, I've got AR
A-I-T-L-D-R, which are two of the channels that I have. And if you're after any of
the prompts that we're using here, you can join the community. There's a link in
the description, but let's move through. We've got these gradient fluid effects coming
through a few different types. I noticed that a lot of them were quite similar here.
And then we move into the particle effects, which are pretty cool actually. So
other particle systems going on, just variations here. And then we've got these anamorphic
3D objects coming through.
So the same thing done with text. So this is excellent. This is sort of stuff that
we can now go out and put on the walls of buildings using the projector. Let's try
that next.
Before we finish up, I decided to create some documentation and a new agent. So the
new agent that we've created is Iris. And Iris will be able to create new design
documents for us. We've got Maya, who will turn it into the technical architecture
guidelines or the requirements documents. And then we've also got Kai. And Kai is
the one that will do all the development. Now what this means is that if you wanted
to create dozens of different styles, you can use Iris to do that, and then Maya
and Kai will turn it into the HTML version, the canvas, the animations, this sort
of stuff.
Now as you're watching this, you might also start seeing the projector versions of
these animations. So this is something I'm doing later tonight. I don't know how
they're going to look, but you are seeing,
for the first time right here.
and consider this a simple and easy way to create
animations that you could put onto a shop front. You could do it for an arts installation,
anything like that. Now, I've also updated the documentation. It's in the middle
of doing that right now, so that it has a startup guide, and this is available to
anyone who's a member of the community. So please click the link in the description.
I'm AppyDave. I'll see you in the next video.