Could you create a programming language for AI pair programmers or maybe as an agents
as code sort of system using the new OpenAI strawberry?
In this quick video, I'm exploring flexible based programming languages, specifically
document style programming languages. We're looking at grammars and passes. Let's
get into it.
For context, I'm building an AI workflow designer, and we can see one of the designs
here for my YouTube launch, which is when I'm publishing a video.
for instance, I might want to find the chapters in a transcript and then turn them
into clickable links in the YouTube descrip.
As an example, I've got this video from last week where I have a YouTube description
with chapters and related videos, and all of this was done through the workflow.
Now the workflow was created using this little document that I created called YouTube
Launch Optimizer, and I'm just showing the old version. It's basically a coding language.
It's an internal DSL. And as I would change values within this language and press
save, it would generate the screen that you're seeing down below.
I wanna build dozens of coding languages or domain specific languages designed for
working with large language models. So what I did was I started writing a new version
of it, and I used my GPT workflow engine to write a lot of this code based off this
one as an example.
the key differences is that the one on the right is an internal DSL. So it has access
to variables. It has access to methods. The one on the left doesn't, it's an external
DSL. So that sort of stuff wouldn't work. But there's benefits in that I now have
control over how the language looks. If I want to add new concepts to the language,
it's a lot easier with the version on the left.
When I'm working with the older technique, these methods actually get called. This
would save the document to a database and to adjacent file in an Astro website and
just re-render the screens, whereas the one on the left is going to use more of an
action space approach, which will still have the save and the saved,
and we can add in other concepts like Save to CrewAI If I wanna automate a workflow.
Now after building this DSL using a workflow that I developed specifically for creating
DSLs, I thought it'd be time to start looking at the documentation.
I created both an examples of how different things are meant to work and a rules
document. And we can see a visualization of the rules document right here where I'm
talking about different data types, how parameters are meant to be dealt with in
different elements, how containers work.
I've developed all this information and we're going to use it as seed for open, AI's
strawberry model.
Now we came over to chat GPT, and I've got this o1-preview set up and I've put in
the word read, and then I've taken the documentation that we've got. Here's all the
DSL rules
and here's all the DSL examples.
Now I haven't written anything else, but we can see here we've got a chain of thought
for 18 seconds.
in my last video that I did six use cases on strawberry, one of the things I noticed
was that not always did it do much better. It'd do a little bit better, it'd go a
bit more detailed. But the one thing it does so well is this area the reasoning.
Because this allows you to check how it's thinking. And at any point in this, you
could also make the decision they made a mistake here and that's what we'll ask them
to rectify on.
as we look through this, we got analyzing the DSL details. So it's examining the
content to understand my intent,
Then it's reflecting on what's probably the hardest area of this DSL. It's the parameters
because they support positional named splats, double splats.
all sorts of structures that have to be dealt with,
being looked at at the moment.
So it's crafting the code, crafting the workflow, looking at the YouTube strategy.
I've only given it rules in this area around parameters and
data types. Then I gave it the argument rules, which is the positional, the optional,
the splat, the keywords, and the double splat.
This is where it started to diverge from Ruby, which has concepts of blocks, but
I'm seeing that structure as just being a nested hierarchy or a container. And I've
taught, told it about the order and the constraints. So how can parameters
on a method definition be set up?
really simple snippets that associate a rule to an example.
for instance, a single node that might have a list under it is being shown here.
So we've got a workflow, there's a single node called settings, and then there's
a list of setting underneath it. And this is how the definition would look.
I added one other thing into this prompt, and you can see here the definition workflow.
where that first came from was a GPT
4o definition,
which was designing a definition, so this is kind of like a grammar for the DSL was
firstly designed in ChatGPT 4o
got a few mistakes there, so I took that over and manually altered it over here.
So for instance, the workflow should be able to take a name, a parameter called name,
and it should just take up the first position. After that, there can be a node called
description, which will take a parameter called description as well in the first
position.
we've got the settings. And after that, a node called setting should repeat, and
it's declarative, meaning whatever the key is, will be derived directly from the
method name. And after that, there'll be a value.
Now we've got a generated DSL and it's looking very good. I could almost use this
the way it is. I'm going to click copy here and we'll head over to Visual Studio.
I have an example that I hand wrote and I put in concepts like multiple sections.
We can see section one and two and multiple steps. Let's go and put the new one,
the strawberry one into the system. And here we have them side by side, the old one
on the left, the new one on the right. So it's modified, a little bit of text, which
is great. It is taken more my placeholder, prompt ideas and filled 'em out with useful
names. And it's noticed that I've called it content, which in my older one before
I would load that from a file. So I have file concepts here, but it's thought, no,
this is content. So it's going to do more of a prompt sort of approach. And then
it's still done. The sections and the steps, it's got good naming conventions for
section steps, input parameters, what
a link through to the prompt, which would be up above and the output. And if we go
down to the bottom, it's just made it a little bit cleaner in the file. Name saving.
This is looking great.
let's look at the main prompt that I now wanna work with, and I typed a lot of this
in by talking into the computer, so there's some grammatical issues.
I said when I gave you the definition file, which was its own DSL for defining DSLs
a grammar, I said, the goal is to build other DSLs. And the DSL you've produced is
spot on. So I've told it or affirmed that what it did above is actually correct.
Next I wanted to explore parsing libraries written in the
Ruby. So 30 words per item. I need to know whether any of the repositories are old
because I don't really wanna work with old code that might be unmaintained. I've
then gone on to tell it that the goal of DSLs is really just to convert it into a
data format that can be read by a machine. In this case, JSON.
Next, I wanted it to think about merging the data from the DSL with whatever the
user generated content is with the metadata, such as should a value be an integer
or a Boolean?
I've said, ultimately it needs to be used by a JavaScript application because this
is going to be embedded into Visual Studio and Monaco. So I can use this technology
either in a web application or within the IDE, but what I don't want it to do is
start exploring this.
I've told it explicitly that to think about it, 'cause it needs to know about
ASTs, LSPs, code completion, linting, all this sort of stuff. But I don't want it
to go deep. I just need it to be informed.
I've also told it in the next two lines that I'm probably going to build my own engine
from scratch. And that means I'll either take inspiration from three or four different
libraries that are already out there.
part of the reason is this is quite a simple parser in some respects. It's not like
a programming language where I need to understand variables or method calls, or even
the mathematical conventions of three plus five times seven.
This is more like A XML structure or adjacent structure. It's a hierarchy or document.
the chain of reasoning, it went for 34 seconds. Let's expand that and see what we've
got. We're examining the definition file
it understands that. I liked what it came up with. It's evaluating different libraries
and weighing the pros and cons. It's worked out that it's converting a DSL to JSON.
It'll craft a parser. It will consider the fact that the schema structure needs to
be included. It's made itself aware of the JavaScript wrappers for IDE use specifically
around,
code completion and syntax highlighting.
it's now assessing whether we should reverse engineer an existing tool.
I notice in a lot of the chain of thoughts that it's always doing. This response
needs to be compliant with OpenAI policies.
it's probably trying to deal with jail-breaking issues here or other sorts of,
compliance issues.
now it's crafting a plan for three libraries. It's evaluating
tree top Palet and Ripper. It's looking at the maintenance status
it's basically found this library. We've got a GitHub repo, we've got rack when we've
got treetop.
what I liked when I saw this was that this is the sort of grammar I really wanna
work with. Something really simple and easy to extend.
Now with the evaluation out of the road, it's looking like it's getting into the
coding itself. So transforming the json, crafting a parser.
So it's now explored three different libraries. We've got Parlet Rack and Treetop.
We've got pros and cons. Most of them are actively maintained,
It then did the transforming of the DSL to JSON,
I've written adjacent format already called YouTube Launch Optimizer,
and we'll just copy over the strawberry version
The one on the right is strawberry.
you look at this and it goes well, it doesn't have a type of root and it doesn't
have a type of node, but it doesn't need 'em because it's implied through the fact
that it's got a
definition and it's got nodes. So that's kind of implied just through the wrapper.
here's where it gets really powerful. So one of the things it did here of having
the type of node and the repeat, this was actually done by GPT four and it's way
more accurate in the strawberry. Take for instance, the repeat. You can see what
this is meant to be. There's settings followed by a bunch of key value pairs. Now,
the thing that's actually repeating are the key value pairs, not the settings node.
And in the GPT four, it's got repeat as true to the settings. Whereas here it's got
an array of nodes of which they have typed setting. It is repeatable and it has a
declarative key. The declarative key means that rather than saying setting plus a
key and a value, the actual method name is the key,
and then it's followed by a positional value that we can see right here. And then
we see a lack of information purely because we're now not including the actual values
that were found in the DSL.
let's look at settings versus prompts. 'cause there's some subtle differences going
on here. The first is that there is a repeating prompt here. There is a repeating
setting, but in this place, the method name becomes the key. Whereas this doesn't
happen in this one. It instead takes a name as a positional parameter, followed by
a named value called content, which will take a value as well.
if we move down and we look at what it's done, we can see that it's removed node,
which is great, and it's moved repeat to the correct location.
this time, rather than being declarative, it's positional.
followed by that it's got a named type with a default value of empty string.
One of the simplistic rules that I have in my documentation is that there's no need
to state whether something's required or not. If it has a default, it's optional.
closing off this analysis, we've got the sections, we've got the steps, and we can
see that being mapped correctly
simpler because we don't have the extra versions going on. And then if we get down
to the bottom, let's see what it's done with actions,
and this is great. It's just got an array of nodes. One is called save. It doesn't
take any parameters, and one is called Save. Jason. It does take a positional parameter
called path.
Let's now move into tokenizing and passing
Now it's given us some starter code, but there's no logic going on here. This is
basically identifying the strings, the tokens,
when a block starts, when a block ends, and turning it into a list of tokens that
can be used by
the passer, which is down below. So it takes as a parameter, a list of tokens, and
then the rules and the rules are embodied in the schema
So let's have a look at how that fits with the existing code. So with the tokenize,
what we're trying to do is work with the particular DSL that we've got in this case,
the workflow one. And we're trying to separate the concepts like the first definition
node, which is called workflow. There's a field or a value going in here. There's
a start of a block.
at the very bottom, there should be the end of a block. So these are the different
tokens we're trying to get. Do we have a method? Do we have a string? Do we have
a symbol further on if there happened to be integers.
count is three and active
is true,
we would want to be able to read that out and notice when we've got a Boolean
value,
an integer sort of
when we've got a positional parameter
this is what the tokenize is designed to do. But if you move down a bit further and
look at the paer, again,
it's going to take the stream of tokens that we got from this particular file and
work through the schema definition. And the schema definition is going to be read
out of this file. So it's going to look for a concept like definition, which has
workflow and try to match it to the DSL, which also has workflow.
if we zoom in on this section here, what we can see is that there's a search for
a due block and there's an expectation that there's an end block after it and there's
a recursion going on. The parse node is calling back through to this method.
hopefully it's going to split out each of these do blocks and the end blocks and
capture all the information in between. A bit further on in this particular parser
is other information like parsing the parameters.
there would need to be a mechanism in here to make sure that the parameters coming
through in the DSL match the rules coming through in the DSL definition.
as we scroll a bit further down into this
code that's been generated, we can see how it would be called. So the DSL code would
read through from the DSL that we've written, and from there it would be tokenized
that the tokens would come through. They would then be passed in with the schema
which would pass it. And then we could have a look at the output stream after that.
the considerations that we're seeing here, they're going to be really useful
in the future of this project
this is going to be written using cursor and Cursor will rely on a lot of this documentation
and ideas to write the correct code.
I was looking through this, one of the areas that I didn't notice was the ability
for it to deal with self-closing nodes. So I have no,
such as the three that are listed here, or any of these ones that don't have a do
or an end block, they just have a carriage return at the end of the
that's the end of that node.
But what's interesting when you come back to the code that's been generated, they've
got a fourth area writing a parcel without external libraries. If we zoom in on that,
we can see simple DSL parser,
and there's a case statement going on with three different areas. It's looking for
the do block, it's looking for the end block, and it's looking for the self-closing
parramater.
I'm not exactly sure how this simple DSL parser that we've got here relates to the
tokenize and the parser above, but at least it's thought about these codes and we
can analyze it a bit further if we move on. It also gives a whole lot of extra information
that'll be used by the pair programmer when I'm using Cursor or Claude Dev to generate
the code.
it's giving further insight, which is
represented in the requirements document, but also added to this area around passing
parameters, the position or the named and the declarative. It doesn't talk too much
about the splats or the double splats, but that's in the requirements document. We've
got the repeat flag, which is when a node can be repeated multiple times.
and then we've got a pros and cons in using this particular technique.
now the additional considerations are more useful for the JavaScript wrapper. That'll
be used by Visual Studio, but it's good that the information is kept here.
finally, we have a conclusion and next steps.
So I've grabbed all the information here and we've come over to Visual Studio. I've
got a file called Brief and we can see all the information that was in the original
chat. GPT window has been made available in a markdown document. This will be good
for when I use Cursor to build the application. And I've gone and started the implementation
by just copying the code and just wrapping some name spacing around it. So we've
got the pa, we've got the tokenize, and I've just left the sample usage right here.
Now this particular project that we are looking at, I've just gone and uploaded it.
So there's a new version. I did it as a feature. So if I just go to my gen, we should
be able to see a new version of it. We're at version one. If we click on it, you
should be able to access it yourself going to the GitHub repo.
So the feature six minutes ago has been added. You can find the documentation here.
You can find
the code within this section.
Other things to notice about this is that I use DSLs all the time for different problem
domains. For instance, I
story cards. And the project plan is written creating a DSL.
gets visualized using Draw io, which is a graphing tool.
we can see some of the things that we wanna work on in this particular project being
displayed right here.
you can just come and pull it from this
Git repo.
in the next video what we're going to do is continue building this sample project.
It's part of a bigger project where I've got visual studio code extensions, we've
got Monaco extensions and a programming language that I'm developing called KlueLess,
where the clue is to do less.
I am Appy Dave, please like and subscribe and I look forward to seeing you in the
next video.