G'day it's David and on this appycast I'm here with my mate Pat and he's got a
screenplay or a movie concept maybe even TV series we're not sure that we're
going to work through with ChatGPT and see if we can flesh it out into
something more real so Pat can you just tell me what what's the goal what what
are you trying to do okay the goal for the goal is actually to to get us get a
synopsis together character analysis and also to assist with the plot for a
pilot episode of this show okay cool so we'll get straight into it I think so
I've got I've set us up with a my map here and we'll build from here and I've
received this email from Pat called blazed animized so let's just take a
copy of all this and I'll go into visual studio I've set up a folder here we'll
go into visual studio I've set up a folder here and we'll just paste to
everything that we've got so blazed and amazed so new folder new file we'll call
it scratch pad this is where we're just going to put our raw information take it
out of here put into here and rather than me asking Pat exactly what this is
about I think this is where we'll start using ChatGPT so we go into ChatGPT and
I'm going to pick the GPT for model for today's session and let's give it some
context today you are an expert today comma you are an expert in creating
screenplays comma movies comma TV series full stop I am going to need your
help to develop a project that has come through as an idea from a writer full
stop just wait for the first draft and then give me a list of actions that you
come up with so while that's going let's set up a blaster we use this to talk to
us during the session so whilst this is going I'm just going to play this to us
so that we can hear what it's told us to do play script development the characters
okay we've got an audio sound problem sound output let's go through the JBL
essential hit play script development the characters and plot are well outlined
but you would need to flesh out dialogues scenes and situations further for a full
script consider hiring or collaborating with a screenwriter to fully develop the
screenplay character development Dex and Oz need further backstory to develop
empathy among viewers and to allow for further character growth this could
involve detailing their home life relationships and why they chose to
study under professor Allen create a show Bible develop a show Bible which is a
comprehensive guide that defines your show's mission statement character
breakdowns episode summaries and future storylines it's a key document to share
with potential producers networks or streaming platforms to give them a
comprehensive overview of your show location scouting start identifying
shooting locations that would suit the environment and aesthetic of your
series think about where Dex and Oz would live where professor Alan's
classes would take place and where Veronica Hartfield's office would be
located assemble a production team start identifying potential directors
producers and the cinematographer consider individuals who have a background
in comedy or satirical work you'll also need to consider the post-production
team for editing music and sound design casting start scouting for actors who
can bring your characters to life they should be able to handle both comedic
and dramatic scenes and should have chemistry together since Dex and Oz
will spend a lot of time together storyboarding once the script is
finalized start storyboarding key scenes especially those that involve the
clues and the detective work budgeting create a detailed budget plan for the
entire production this would include production costs cast and crew salaries
location costs post-production costs and contingency funds legal aspects ensure
that all legal aspects are covered including copyrights for the script and
music contracts for the cast and crew and permits for the shooting locations
marketing and promotion develop a marketing strategy to promote your series
this could include creating a trailer social media promotion interviews with
cast and crew and sneak peeks of the episodes distribution plan research
potential networks or streaming platforms where your show could air prepare a
pitch for these distributors explaining why your show would be a good fit for
their platform okay so this has gone too broad so what we'll do is we'll just
pop in the three areas that I think make sense for now and that's script
development character development and storyboarding so pop in over to chat
GPT and say this information is way too general comma what I need is a list of
actions just to cover these three concepts
okay I'm going to take this this is not quite what I want I do like one and two
I think one needs a little bit more information in it I think three is
premature so we'll go back to our document and we'll create something
called script we'll go with zero one it's just the first concept we're working on
and we'll say script development like that we won't go zero zero one dot mark
down and we'll paste this information in and we'll give them all headings
back story and your storyboarding
looks like I've missed that a little bit so outline script development character
development so I'm going to undo this a bit so we have script development we
have character development and we have storyboarding let's make them all
headings and wherever we've got a colon like this let's move the text down and
turn them into another heading like that think we've captured everything we need
let's take every variant of three hashes and make sure there's a space between them
and go to the top we call it script development so let's go over to our
mind map which is over here and give us some goals so we've got script
development and we got back story now the script development is break down the
story into access seems write the dialogue create conflict resolution
cooperate okay so what I'd like to do go back to the scratch pad where we've got
all our information and can you tell me in 60 words or less the basic premise
of this story shows about two stone I'll let I'll let this do it to neurodivergent
stoners decks and ours who despite their cluelessness stumble into real crimes
and solve them unintentionally exposing hidden truths their humorous adventures
and unique perspectives unfold within modern-day setting offering comedic
satirical spin on traditional detective stories that's about right great so what
we'll do is we'll ask the question what five movies or TV shows that have a similar idea
to this go with that
okay so I don't know broad city or dude where's my car though I think I might have
seen it but the other ones like Bill and Ted's excellent adventure and pineapple
express seem quite accurate what do you think sorry Bill and Ted pineapple
express I'd say Bill and Ted pineapple express and broad city maybe the closest
have you seen any of those I've seen I've seen psych dude where's my car
Bill and Ted's excellent adventures and and I haven't seen actually I haven't
seen pineapple express or broad city but the last three I've seen them all but
just looking at the the storyline behind all of them or five of them I'd say
that the first actually the first one number three one and three actually are
the closest okay cool let's just expand on this and say do you know who the
Kevin Smith clerks mole rats okay would you say that the way Kevin Smith
approaches doing these sorts of movies would be similar to what you think it's
it's on a similar path to where we're going with this but also
like a more even more modern satirical approach okay you don't need to lean
forward that'll pick up I'll just bring it to you okay okay so let's just work
through a couple of days you like dude where's my car yeah I liked it it was a
little bit too of you know a little bit too crazy but it was it was funny as hell
so you do do where's my car was more like a dumber and dumber thing whereas
these guys are not dumb don't really want to go the dumb and dumber direction
psych it's great it is funny it it is smart but you said to me you wanted like
there's more stoners these are stoners so what they're doing is is that they're
sort of they they're stoners they think that they're solving they think that
they're solving one crime but inadvertently actually find real crimes
let's go with that but let's add in that statement so I just want you to say that
statement directly any in a moment sure so these two guys think they are solving
crimes but inadvertently find real crimes and are able to solve them okay so we
got that now pine apple express let's just type that in
good bad or otherwise I don't know that I've seen it so I can't give input yeah
you know psych yeah that's that's correct so I'm not sure about this one as we have
not seen it don't know about this not seen it so you are broad city
bill and Ted's excellent adventure this is yeah on point now you also mentioned
skibby do and other stuff so what so why skibby do just because of the content
where the age group the age of the guys around the same age as the skibby do
okay look what wonder around solving crimes but also they kind of stumble especially
especially
skibby and shaggy was there another show the hardy boys of course was too too young
guys around the same age as well that I never saw that but they weren't stoner
but think of it's basically the same type of thing as skibby do it's sort of like
like they're ghost and supernatural mysteries that turn out to be somebody you
know like a real person okay causing a crime trying to scare everybody off by
right here so Ken what was the question can I get five more shows that fit the
positive examples within this list in my opinion we got two negative examples
because we don't know about them I just want to see if we've got more
Harold and Kumar is that show up big there's a female there's this there is a
female sleuth character that I'm thinking about who is about 15 years old
what show would that be
don't remember it being Veronica Marce that Nancy Drew what about Nancy Drew
okay I don't know though that Nancy Drew fits in with the the style of thinking
that no it's it's it's more like a take the hardy boys and skibby do and cross
it with Bill and Ted and Jane Silent Bob comma so that we get the fun-loving
sleuth accidental sleuths accidental detectives
with the irony of stoners
the one I'm thinking about I just want to bring it in who is the female
shellok homes that is on Netflix
anola home have you seen that it's a good it's a very good show so we could look
into that yes okay oh yeah that's go out of stranger things can you take the
information that you just wrote for us and also include anola homes as an idea
okay what I'm gonna do I didn't like the direction that that just went so I'm
gonna come up to our original question and alter it and that should then alter
this in the shape that we want sure so
we'll just go with that I don't know what else to ask
okay what I'm gonna do that still didn't give what I wanted exactly so I'm gonna
copy that information we'll we'll call this philosophy so it's kind of like the
we'll take that line we'll pop back one we'll take that line we'll take this
information and we're gonna come back to it and say I have some ideas for the
show philosophy comma some of the ideas overlap here but what I would like you
to do is break it down into five separate sections and an overview each section should
describe information relevant to the particular section comma a section would
be scooby-doo see where we go with that
okay this is pretty good let's just
show show philosophy all the way down you know just pop it into this document here let's
get rid of those we can use this now as a second brain for driving a lot of content
can be driven from this particular information the only other thing I would want to question is
is there anything from psych that you want to bring into this I like how the insight I like
his focus and intelligence when it comes to you know he thinks the thinking outside the box
okay could you also bring in the good doctor you know the show very interesting so let's
I met Sean Murphy when he was 14 years old just act like a normal human being he was and he
still is an extraordinary young man autism difficulty in communicating his high
concepts does it sound like I'm describing a surgeon he's breathing he saved his life who are
you I'm Dr. Sean Murphy I'm a surgical resident at San Jose St. Bonaventure Hospital and you
thought that this board wouldn't have any doubts about hiring a surgeon diagnosed with autism
justify your decision he also has Savant syndrome genius level skills in several areas he sees
things it's his heart Adam needs an echocardiogram no behave yourself or you'll be removed from
the building the echo is normal show them and analyzes things in ways that we can't even begin to
understand again again there looks normal to me it's not normal this kid was sprayed with
glass shards what if a piece of glass erases bloodstream what could be looking behind the heart
you were right why were you rude to me when we first met and now you want to be my friend
which time was it that you were pretending it's got a serious deficit child is alive today because
of that deficit tomorrow one may be dead because of it we hire Sean and we give hope to those
people with limitations that those limitations are not what they think they are that they do have a
shot never forget you're the smart one you can do anything
I love the Savant aspect of it where where especially Dex can sort of
see things that others can't and Alan is often the guy who who sticks up for Dex knowing that he's
usually right but I'm gonna come back to that have you seen the Queen's Gambit okay so let's
go with this one hey I'm Harry on 23 years old and I'm from Sydney Australia I've just moved
into my new apartment men are gonna come along and want to teach you things
doesn't make them any smarter you just let them blow by and you go on ahead and do just
what and how you feel like someday you're gonna be all alone so you need to figure out how to take
care of yourself tell the readers of life how it feels and to be a girl among all those men
I don't mind it chess isn't always competitive chess can also be
beautiful you're an orphan bet I'm fine being alone I feel safe in an entire world of just
64 squares I'll create I'll creativity and psychosis often go hand in hand
or for that matter
genius and madness I feel safe in an entire world of just 64 what I want to point out here is that
what happens in the Queen gambit what happens in the good doctor it happens a little bit in psych
I don't think it happens in the mentalist too much but it happens in these is that they are seeing
things that are not real that give real meaning to the story so for her she lays down on a bed
and she sees the chessboard on the ceiling and she can just see where all the moves are
in psych he sees stuff like that all the time in the good doctor you've just always got him
seeing these things that other in virtual in his head that other people can't see and that's what
yeah and that that's absolutely that's subatism yeah leads you know through through traits of
asperges and yeah here a divergence so what I what I want to do is come back to what we've got here
say
I need you to give me three more
short sentences on these different movies comma what we're really looking for
is the savant capabilities within these tv shows
so they're not movies
so they say the good doctor
Queen's Gambit
and we've only got two there we could bring in
um
we could bring in the mentalist maybe maybe like there's a there's a little bit of it but it's um
I mean those two examples that you pulled up
I'm gonna say it but the other one that comes to me is uh limitless limitless that'd be more
so than mentalist right that yeah because limit yeah and limitless yeah okay yeah so go limitless
let's see what we get
again so the good doctor and the Queen's Gambit make two statements that I think are relevant
is that there's this visualization visualization in 3D is how he does it she does the same thing
visualize and plan multiple moves ahead okay so
let's get back to our document and add these in
I'm gonna cut take that out
I'm not sure what those are so let's uh that oh that's from the that's from the previous area
so let's just add this colon colon colon
add that move on down and we've got this
so let's get just a general idea of well let's get a synopsis and what we'll do
is we'll go back to our original document that you gave me
we'll go to scratch pad and say
using the original idea comma and show philosophies I would like you to come up with a 250 word
synopsis for a show here we go original idea like that and we'll also say show
philosophies now we'll paste in the original idea here and we will go to the show philosophies
and we'll paste them in here
I'll just hit stop because it looks like I pasted it into the wrong spot
press edit original idea is here
go down to the bottom cut that out
so
as they uncover as they
okay we'll just put that in there
press generate response
now that's about an hour into the session I think we've got a good understanding of themes
what we'll do now is we'll play this back just to see whether it's what you like
and then we might end up the session
sure
play
Blazed and amazed is a vibrant and engaging television series that follows the amusing
and unexpected adventures of two neurodivergent stoners, Dex and Oz, as they unwittingly become
entangled in solving real crimes. The duo, reminiscent of a modern-day Hardy Boys crossed
with the whimsical goofiness of Bill and Ted, bring a fresh take on the classic mystery-solving
genre. Inadvertently, Dex's keen eye for patterns and Oz's unbounded creativity often
lead them to stumble upon genuine criminal activities within their seemingly mundane lives.
Taking inspiration from Scooby-Doo, their shenanigans often start as innocent fun but morph
into daring escapades. Enriched by the influence of Jay and Silent Bob, their witty and lighthearted
banter conceals their raw ingenuity and resourcefulness. Dex and Oz's neurodivergence, akin to the
brilliant minds and the good doctor and the queen's gambit, gifts them with a unique lens through
which they view the world. In the debut episode, their favorite professor, who channels existentialist
philosophy reminiscent of the philosophy of absurdity, is wrongfully accused of professional
misconduct. Driven by a sense of justice and loyalty, much like Enola Holmes, Dex and Oz
put their eccentric detective skills to the test. They embark on an adventure full of clever plot
twists, hilarious encounters, and moments of genuine heart. Blazed and amazed masterfully
weaves comedy, mystery, and the untapped strengths of neurodivergent individuals into an enthralling
tapestry that captivates audiences from all walks of life. Through laughs, risks, and the
unraveling of enigmas, Dex and Oz prove that heroes come in the most unexpected packages.
What do you think? It's pretty cool. It's a good start. I think the next step we should do is buy a
domain name. Right? Because I think we could convert this into a blog and just we maybe have a landing
page who knows. So what we'll do now is go to GoDaddy, I think.
Let's go Blazed and Amazed. Is that it? Yeah, Blazed and Amazed. Yep. Press search.
It's available? Yeah. Okay. Do you want to also look at Blazed and Amazed?
What one would be would be easy? Like if somebody was searching that, Blazed and Amazed or Blazed
jump back and just say Blazed and Amazed.com. Great. So I'll buy it? Yeah. Okay. So make it yours.
We'll just
press continue.
No domain protection for now. No professional email. Continue to cart.
Okay. Why is it so expensive? Let's just do it for one year.
$16 Australian. I'm ready to pay.
Okay. We own a domain called Blazed and Amazed.com. So if we go back to our
mind map for a second, let's say domain Blazed and Amazed.com. Throw that in.
If we go website, give it a domain now. Blog. What we can do is take say these
apicast videos and create a chronological view of how we develop the set. So chronological
show development based on apicast. Now we've got a show philosophy at the moment or show synopsis,
I think. There must be a Y in there, I think. We've got a show philosophy as well. We could
say show philosophy needs more input. Show synopsis. Looking good, in my opinion.
As we go in here, we'll just give ourselves some emoji marks. So show synopsis will be
good. Show philosophy will be okay. Domain name is done.
Okay. Now let's just talk a little bit about next steps. Backstory, character development.
So we've got Dex and Oz. Okay, that's cool. So we've got Dylan, Dex Richards, and we've got
Alan, Oz, Cooper. So we need to expand on these guys.
Let's just throw in a few things. Let's go storyboarding.
For now, we need to do some mid-journey work to develop out these characters,
just how we think they'll look.
We'll leave it at that. I'll have a read through everything. In fact, you have a read
through it all as well. What I'm going to do is share this mind map with you.
Okay. Krastamusic.com. You got edit capability on this. So we hit share.
So you can look at this. You can even expand on it if you want to. We'll take the script as it
stands today and we'll hit the share button here. Okay. So we copy the link. We'll just see what it says.
Copy the link and rather than sending it to you as an email, what I'm going to do is go
to the mind map. I'm going to create a concept called resources.
And I'm going to say chat GPT. And I'm just going to paste it in as a hyperlink for you. Okay.
So you can just go here, click on that and it'll take us straight to that. Okay.
And that'll do for today. Yeah. That was good. Yeah. Okay. Let's hit stop.