Today, I'm going to develop a custom instruction in ChatGPT and the goal of it is to take the
video transcription of the content that I create and use that as the source for building
an intro to the video.
In a previous video, I used ChatGPT custom instructions to develop a research assistant.
That particular bot would act as my research helper.
It had commands that would work with it, would respond in a certain way, it had an objective.
And what I'm looking to do today is build a YouTube intro, is to build a video, is to
build a YouTube video introduction.
Before I get started with the custom instruction, I want to do a little bit of research.
Essentially, I want to find out what the best practices are around YouTube introductions.
Before I do research like this, I do like to come into my custom instructions and make
sure they're empty.
I want it to have a clean slate whenever it's doing any research for me from this point
of view.
I think how we can start is letting GPT know that it's an expert in writing YouTube introductions.
I'm really looking to develop a list of best practices.
They need to fit with my style.
So it might come up with intros that someone like MrBeast would do.
I'm an educator, I'm not an entertainer, so the way I do intros has to be different to
say MrBeast.
But what we'll do is figure out what other people are doing by running this particular
prompt.
GPT has given me 11 bullet points that we can work through.
One of the things I noticed as I read through them is that some of them are related to visual
branding and music and none of the stuff that's relevant for developing this custom instruction.
What I need to do is whittle away this particular list down to the points that are related purely
to script writing for an intro.
Now, as I've looked through here, I've taken out the information that I think is relevant
and I'm letting GPT know what to focus on.
And it's really anything to deal with the writing, not with the branding.
Where it says keep it short and snappy, I've said leave that how it is.
Where it talks about hooking the viewer in immediately, I need to develop a style that's
for me, maybe a few different styles that make sense to tutorials or how to videos.
So I'm asking it to guide me in that regard.
This next point about maintaining consistency, this is like taglines and other brand statements.
It's maybe a little bit of out of scope of what I really want to achieve here today.
But with the different channels that I do, like winning prompts, I have a tagline of
is that a winning prompt?
Or with Fly Video, it's about automating your YouTube influence.
Now, I do want to go down this path a little bit today, but I wouldn't.
It's not strictly speaking a part of this custom instruction.
This next section on staying relevant.
This is probably the crux of what I want to achieve out of the custom instruction.
Generally, for an intro, you want to identify the main point that you're trying to get out
of the tutorial or the video, and that should be what the intro is about.
When it comes to engaging emotionally, it's really important to have emotional hooks.
But for me, I want to stay away from click bait or over sensationalized sort of intros.
Now, since there are a number of points within this list that aren't relevant for the custom
instruction, I'm just going to paste in a statement that says, this is what I want to
leave out and use in a separate conversation because I'll develop custom instructions for
different areas.
I like to follow a concept from programming called single responsibility principle.
And the only responsibility that this bot needs to have is create a YouTube intro, not
worry about the brand set up.
So let's just run with this and see where we get to GPT has come up with what looks like
a pretty good four point outline.
There's a bunch of sub points in here.
What we need to do next is take this contextual information and utilize it as the basis around
the custom instruction that we're developing.
But since this video is about developing the custom instruction, let's move over to there
now.
Let's move over to there now.
So set up this document with a custom instruction I want to create called YouTube intro builder.
I've given it a role of creating YouTube intros.
And the basic objective is that you will use a video transcription as input and help me
build various introscripts targeted at that video.
Now if we're going to work with video transcription, we're going to need some sort of input, detailed
video outline.
Now the actual transcript itself may be way too long.
So it needs to be summarized, but not too summarized.
We still need the details within the document.
And I use a different custom instruction to deal with that.
The other thing that is really important is that we get more than one variation of an
intro script.
I've found through experience that if I just work on one output from chat GPT, it can be
pretty good, but there's things that are missing.
If I ask it to do it five times, I end up finding that the exact information that I
would like happens to be a combination from more than one output.
So we will work with the idea of having multiple variations when we develop the commands for
this custom instruction.
Now I've added this line called you respond to the following commands.
And if we take this idea of input, I've given it a command called add and told it that it's
to add provided transcription and to use that to develop our intros.
I've developed three commands to get us started and they are essentially the add command where
we'll add the transcription into the bot that it can use.
There'll be a timer.
So I think most intros that I want to do will be about 10 or 15 seconds long.
And I need to be able to let the bot know how long it should try to create the intros
for.
And how many do I want?
Five variations, three variations, et cetera.
I've added in four new commands and essentially they have come from looking at this document.
So there's an area called question teaser.
Start with a question related to a common tech problem or need ever wondered how to get
the most out of a new GPU.
And this sort of information may occur one, two or three times in a transcription.
So the command that I've added is called teasers designed to identify one or more teasers.
The next one is facts, having access to facts or statistics from the transcription would
be useful.
They talk about it as begin with a surprising or intriguing tech related fact or statistic.
Did you know?
Then the next one we've got here is a highlight feature.
Whenever I'm doing a video, there's probably just one main point that needs to be extracted.
The idea is if you're showcasing a product, highlight one of the more impressive features.
If you're doing a how to give an example of what the main thing is that you're trying
to achieve.
So here we've got highlights, identify one or more features or highlights.
And the last one is tagline.
I've called it tagline, but in here it's part of the brand identity.
This would typically be a concise sentence or two that communicates the essence of the
channel.
Give you a tech, given you're a tech how to showcase, it might be something like unveiling
text potential one tutorial at a time or discover, learn, master the future of tech.
Now, for me, if it, if it was fly video, it would be automate your influence.
If it was appy Dave, build an app a day.
And for my winning prompts channel, it would be, is this a winning prompt?
And this is not so much that we need to, and you can see from this command that this is
something I would supply to the bot.
I've made some minor corrections here and made sure that these three commands are separated
with just the idea that the following commands list one or more examples based on the transcription.
I have moved the tagline up because it's not related to that particular concept.
And I've added a help section.
What I hope will happen when I type help is that I will get a list of the commands and
I'll get an overview of how this bot works.
At the moment, I haven't given a full overview into the bot, but there's pretty much enough
information to get started here.
Another thing to be aware of is statements like this list one or more examples based
on the transcription may stay where it is, but it can also go into the response section
of a GPT custom instruction.
Now, I think another thing we can probably do is just start testing this out.
So I'm going to copy this over to the chat GPT custom instructions and we'll give it
a whirl.
Come over to chat GPT, I'm on GPT4 and we will start configuring this custom instruction.
What we do is we click on this icon and then the three little dots down here, you'll see
custom instructions and this is where we're going to put the information.
We'll head over to our document YouTube intro builder and we have a role create YouTube
intros and we have a role create YouTube intros.
After that, we've got a list of commands and I've added in one other section called guidelines.
Now this is basically the original information in fact, let's go over there.
Britain, this statement, I want you to take the following information and turn it into
YouTube instructions and turn it into an YouTube.
I want you to take the following information and turn it into instructions for my YouTube
introduction script writer.
The problem is I only have 200 words that I can use.
I've given it all the information that we'd already accumulated and it's just given
me this quick sentence.
So that quick sentence has now been added in here and we can go up and select all the
information, click copy and head over to the other chat GPT window and we'll paste it in.
And I've got it down to 1498 characters.
You've got a limit of 1500 characters.
Basically this information could have been supplied in the standard bot that you're using
if you really need this sort of stuff.
The other thing that we can do to shrink this list a little bit is maybe move some of the
information that's in here out into the response and I'll be doing a little bit of that anyway.
Now we'll hit the save button and close this down and let's go and have a look at what
we're going to do.
And let's go and look at what problem we're really trying to solve with this custom instruction.
So I've brought us over here.
We have a video project in Premiere Pro.
It's four and a half minutes long.
And the good thing about the information here is that it's great to publish on YouTube,
but it wasn't designed for YouTube.
Essentially this information was done in a Loom video that I sent off to someone just
showcasing some of the technologies I was doing.
And I did not think about the intro at all.
So the intro here, if we play it, sounds pretty bad.
Okay, I'm going to show the studio layouts that I've been working through to say you're
aware I'm just seeing.
So that's what it is.
No good for YouTube, but the rest of the information in this video is what I want to derive from
to build a brand new intro.
Heading over to the transcription, which we got here and I've put this through Whisper
AI to create all this information.
The first line is not needed.
So everything up to about aware.
I'll just delete that.
The rest of it I'm going to copy.
And this is what we're going to be processing our YouTube introduction on.
Here we are at empty ChatChopT window.
One of the commands we had available was called help.
So I think this is where we're going to test it all out.
We'll just type help.
And it's giving us the following information.
And it's pretty much just repeating everything that we put into our GPT custom instruction.
I think we can now use the add command.
Let's just bring up our text, our transcription, which we've copied.
You can see it over on the left.
But if I type in add, might just press enter.
And I'll paste in the information minus that first sentence that was in the transcription.
And we'll press enter.
Let's see what happens.
Now running this information on my custom instruction has highlighted a problem I've got.
One of the things that I've been looking to do is set up these commands down here.
We've used the add command.
We've used the help command.
And my expectation was that the teaser facts and highlights command would be something
that I would type in to get that information.
And instead, it's just come out as a consequence of running the add command.
The thing is, this is not a bad outcome.
I kind of like the information that's in here.
There's a couple of problems such as Chris Bay eye is actually spelt with a K.
And that issue comes from my translation.
And that issue comes from my transcription.
So I fixed it there.
The other thing I like about this is that I could almost write my own intro just by reading
through a few of these and incorporating them.
And that's what I've.
So what I've done is I've actually gone ahead and done that.
I'll just paste it in here.
I could come up with an intro that said these tools help me to create a video daily.
I use these tools to eradicate background noise, create dynamic layout and transition
effects and remotely control my record pause controls as I focus on creating content,
not editing content.
Now, ideally I want the GPT instruction to produce something like that for me,
but it was very easy to write that just based on the information I've already got.
But if I think about why it came up with these answers just by using the add command,
it's because I didn't put any constraints around what the add command should do.
I told it what I wanted, but I didn't put in any constraints.
Now, I could go and add those constraints.
But as I look through the complexity of the commands that I've created in this first version,
I realize I could simplify this and make it an easier flow anyway.
So let's go and have a look at version two.
In version one, I had a role, an objective and a list of commands.
And essentially they worked out to be that there would be a help command.
How would you use this bot, an add command to add in a transition,
a couple of settings, one for the number of intro should like to get back and the number
of seconds each intro should go for, the ability to feed it some sort of tag line,
and then the ability to extract certain information like the teasers, the facts, the highlights.
The simplification of this would be that we still have the same role and objective,
but our commands just become help, add and intro.
And with intro, what we can do is add in some parameters that might be available.
So with an intro, by default, I might want to get five intros.
I might want every intro to be 15 seconds long.
And I can control the instruction to do that by default,
or to have them as parameters that can be added in.
There's also generally going to be extra instructions that you might want to provide.
That also got me thinking about how I wrote.
That also got me thinking about how I was able to write my own introduction.
And I'm not a great writer.
I can come up with an okay introduction.
But at least if I came up with something that I liked,
I might be able to feed it to the bot and say,
build a better intro, but use this one as a starting point.
So what I'm thinking is that there would be a suggestion command,
could be the way this goes.
And from that, I can add suggestions.
And they're a little bit different to the extra instructions.
This might be like, this is what I think an intro should be.
But then it becomes a question of, should that even be a command?
Or is that just another part of the parameters that we put here?
So we might have some sort of parameter called suggestion.
And I could let the GPT instruction know that if it encounters that label,
suggestion that it uses as input to create new intros.
Now the version two role objective commands and guidelines would start to look like this.
We have create YouTube intro.
We have the objective.
And our commands now say help add.
And rather than seconds and intros, what I think we could do
is just have a command called intro that takes a number like five by 15.
What we would do in this scenario if we used this as a command,
it would create five YouTube script variations of about 15 seconds long.
So now we can just delete these out of it.
The tagline, I think we could get rid of this command.
And it could be some sort of extra instruction that we include.
So we can simplify that by just removing it.
And the final complexity of having three separate commands to deal with
teasers, fats and highlights should be something that happens automatically
as part of the add command.
So if the add command currently says add provided transcription,
you will use this to develop intros.
Then if we move down to where the responses are for this, we can go with.
Responding to the add command is that you extract a list of question oriented teasers,
a list of features or facts, and a list of highlights.
So now just at the time of pressing add and putting in your transcription,
that information is available.
We can then use that in what I would call the special or the extra instructions.
And that now then leaves us with how do we respond to an intro to command.
With the intro command takes certain parameters like how many intros,
how many seconds, any extra instructions, and what I am now going to call sample.
Everything in here is really optional.
And we make that a statement.
We say by default create five intros 15 seconds long.
I may change the numbers.
Example, intro three by 30 for three intros at 30 seconds.
To deal with the preferred teasers or the tag loans or any other information,
we can supply that as an instruction.
And this last label called sample is basically if it sees the label,
it can use it as the starting point.
Now, generally, I don't want to do that.
Generally, I want it to come up with five great intros for me.
But once I've found the one I want, I can then feed it back into here as a starting point.
I can feed it back into here as a starting point for an even better intro.
Let's test this new custom instruction.
I've got a new GPT chatbot.
We'll go into custom instructions.
I think we can delete this one.
And from here, we can go and copy the information, including the guidelines,
and paste it in here.
For the response, we should be able to take that information, paste it in here.
We'll press save.
Close this down.
Let's try help.
I really love what this has come up with.
Let's hop over to the GPT view.
We've got help, the display, which is what we...
Help has provided a detailed view of what this bot can do.
And we see the add command will add a video transcription,
analyze the text, and extract these highlights, features, fats,
and the primary question that would be asked in an intro.
We've got our command for creating intros,
and by default, there will be five of them at 15 seconds each.
It can accept other concepts.
It's come up with examples of other commands,
which is a little odd because that's from the previous GPT instruction.
I'm not sure whether this is good or bad.
If I don't use it, it won't affect anything,
but it's interesting that it's come up with it.
And then it's got the guidelines.
So far, I think the instructions that I'm seeing here in the help file
are exactly what I need to turn my transcriptions into introductions.
I'm over at my transcription.
I've renamed the word CRISP with a C to CRISP with a K.
We'll take a copy of all this information.
We've got our add command.
We can just paste it in, press Enter.
Now, I know my video, and this is almost a perfect analysis
of what's in that video.
We have the three pieces here.
Want to know how to isolate your voice from background noise in recordings.
Curious about how foot pedals can transform your streaming setup.
Ever wondered how to switch seamlessly during a live stream.
You may have noticed that I'm doing all of these.
I live next to a road, and you can't hear the noise from that.
I'm pausing and re-recording as I go, and I'm changing scenes.
And that was what this video that we're doing an intro for is about.
It then, based on those pieces, gives us three facts,
which is how this is actually happening.
And then the highlights are really just those sentences reworded.
It's just in a different format.
It's just in a different linguistic format.
What I'll do now is create an intro.
I'm going to go with the default parameters.
We'll see what happens.
So we just type in intro, we press Enter,
and hopefully we're going to get five intros
that are around about 15 seconds long.
Now, we do have five intros.
It's hard to tell how long they really are.
I think what we can do is we'll just start a timer,
and I'll just start talking whatever the first one is.
So we'll go.
Ever struggled with background noise in your recordings?
Today, we're diving into how Chris May I can silence the distractions.
Plus, I'll show you how foot pedals can level up your streaming game.
Unveiling text potential, one tutorial at a time.
And that took me about 17, 18 seconds without practice.
So I think it's hit the 15 second mark.
Okay, whether I like that intro is debatable.
Let's try one last example of the intro.
We'll go back to the standard timings,
but we will enter them in and I'll give it a sample
or a starting intro and see what it can build from it.
So if we go intro three by five, then we put in the word sample.
We pop on over, we pop on over to visual studio.
We have our transcription here,
but we also have the handwritten intro that I did before.
Take a copy of that and paste it in.
Now that's way too long for 15 seconds, I believe.
So I'm not sure what's going to happen, but let's press enter.
So we have three good intros here, I think.
I say good, I haven't read them.
And what I like to do is have the computer read them to me.
And we might as well trial that out.
So I'm just going to copy one of them.
We'll head over to the two tools that I use.
I either use Revoisa, I do like using it.
This is where I've got a new project coming out
and I was testing how it sounds.
So you could use Revoisa, but for this one,
I think I'm going to use 11labs.
And we'll go with Charlie, an Australian voice.
We'll just paste that in and hit generate.
To create content without the hassle of editing.
Today, we're diving into crisp AI and foot pedals.
Tools that help me eliminate background noise
and control my setup effortlessly.
Unveiling text potential.
One tutorial at a time.
Looking to create content without the hassle of editing.
Today, looking to create content without the hassle of editing.
Today, we're diving into crisp AI and foot pedals.
Tools that help me eliminate background noise
and control my setup effortlessly.
Unveiling text potential.
One tutorial at a time.
Looking to create.
There you have the intro red bat toast by the computer.
It sounds perfect.
What I like about doing it this way
is it's much easier to gauge a script by listening to it
than just saying it yourself or just reading it.
Well, it is for me.
One of the other things that goes on here
is that you can see the time that it would take.
Different tools like Revoisa,
you can even speed that up if you like.
And if you like either of those tools, 11labs or Revoisa,
they're both great.
Probably 11labs is a little bit better.
I'll leave a link in the description.
It will probably be an affiliate link.
I will leave an affiliate link in the description.
Now, if you want to learn more
about using chat GPT for programming
or any other sorts of automations,
then maybe check out one of the videos
that are here in the corner.