In this quick video, I'll show you how to host N8N on DigitalOcean. I'll also show
you how you can get two months of credits so that you can use it through the testing
phase. Look at a couple of challenges I had when getting it set up, and just finally,
how I've hooked it up to a little micro application to do AI agent workflows. At
the end, I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
So let's get started setting up N8N on DigitalOcean. Now, the first thing to realize
is that the starting price of a droplet is about 4 USD a month. The one we'll work
with is around $6 a month. But at the moment, if you click on the link down below,
you'll get $200 worth of credits that you can use over the next 60 days. So no matter
what workload you're under, you're probably going to have it for free for the next
two months.
Now when you use that link, it should take you directly to DigitalOcean and you should
get a $200 credit.
So we'll click on Get Started
From there I'm going to sign up with an email
We've press create. It's given us the $200 credit. We just need to verify our email
address.
Fill in a little bit of marketing information here if you want to.
Now, because this is a new onboarding, we come up with these options. We could pick
deploy a virtual machine. But in this case we're just going to go to explore the
control panel.
Now we already have our first project. We do want to create a new one, but before
we can do that, we need to deal with this action needed. So we'll click on the billing
right here.
We won't have any prepayment because of the credits that we've added, but we are
going to need to add a payment method. So we've successfully added a payment mechanism.
And now we've got 59 days and $200 remaining credit.
So let's head up to the projects menu and we can create a new project.
And I've just called it N8N server. It's hosting Nadine Workflows and my use case
is for APIs and service oriented architecture. So we'll just create the server.
Now I don't currently have an app or a droplet, so I'm just going to click Skip for
now.
So at this point, what we need to do is install a droplet. We also have to configure
N8N. And we're going to use a really simple technique. So what we do is we come back
to our server and we spin up a droplet. And we need to decide where we're going to
run it. Now this is for an Australian client. So I'm going to pick Sydney. And as
we scroll down you have these computers that you can select. But we don't want to
do it that way. We want to go with the marketplace instead. Now when you go to marketplace
you'll have all these preloaded Docker images that you can work with. One of them
is called N8N. Now if you can't see it there, you can at least type in N8N like this.
Click on the button here. It'll become available. Now when you move down, you'll
be able to set a size of the.
Based on this image, we'll go to regular and we'll go to $6 a month.
Now, as we scroll down, what we'll notice is that there are other settings we can
go with. There's a password which we will fill in in a moment. And then down the
bottom there's the create droplet. One of the things that we do need to change is
the host name. So I'm going to call it N8N droplet. And then we're going to come
up to the password. And I've put in a pretty strong password. We can now create the
droplet. Now it'll start spinning it up right here. And when this is finished the
IP address will show.
Now we can see it's Sydney, one gigabyte, 25GB of disk space. This is the IP address.
We're just going to click copy on that.
And the reason we did that is we now need to configure an A record. Now I'm using
Cloudflare. So I'll head over to Cloudflare and I'll scroll down and press add a
new record. From here I'll select type A, I'm going to put it in as N8N, and I'll
put in the IP address right here and press save. Now with my subdomain in place we
can come back and click on these three little dots here. This is going to give us
access to the console. So the first thing you'll do is you will click on the launch
console right here.
And if the A record is propagated, this should work. So we'll put in n a to n, we'll
put in a domain name and everything will work.
And if we get a error message like this, then we just need to wait for the a record
to propagate.
So a particular issue you might also want to check is this proxy value. You do want
it turned on but
to turn it off here. Hit save on that.
Now, once that's registered, if you come and you see a page like this one and in
my case, I have a brand new domain name. So there's a little bit of a history issue
with Google. What we can do is go and click on the. Let us know that this page is
safe. We can say this page is safe as the report type. We've got the domain name.
We can say it is a new domain, something like that. We'll hit submit. Now there is
another way that you can do it. There's a little button here and that'll take you
over to the transparency report. And from there we can paste in the URL right here.
And so now when we put in our domain name and we run it, we should get N8N running.
And you can now create a new account.
I've just filled in the marketing material here.
And then just put in your email address to get a license key.
The activation key will come in an email. Go over to settings. And then you can click
here to enter the activation key.
I'm now activated. We can go back and from here we can create workflows.
Now, I've been doing the N8N workflows so that I can build in backend AI functionality,
and the idea is that I should be able to put information into this little application
that I'm building, and then when I press next, it's now talking to N8N directly to
get a bunch of related questions to an incident that just happened. And then people
can go and fill in extra information. So that's how I'm using N8N workflows.
So that's how you host N8N on DigitalOcean. And all of this came about because recently
I did a video on Vibe coding landing pages for websites such as the one that you're
seeing right here. And from there I went into a more detailed context engineering
example on building an application. So if you want to see how I'm building this application,
how as I load it in with different information, and I'm using the live button here
to talk directly to the N8N workflows that we just created. We can see this information
hitting that server and coming up with dynamic questions based on the information
earlier in this form. Anyway, I'm AppyDave. Please like and subscribe and I'll see
you in the next video.