G'day I'm Appy Dave and last year I did a video on mid-journey versus Dali 3 that
got 21,000 views. This year I'm focusing on all the other sorts of image
generation tools such as Hotpot and currently I've just done a video on
16 competitors to mid-journey. Now I also have another channel called AITLDR
which is a faceless channel and on that channel I go in and look at these
individual tools specifically for two to three minutes. Now what I'm interested
in doing is showcasing Hotpot and basically with the video I just did on
mid-journey I was testing these individual prompts against mid-journey but
one of the things that I noticed as I went through this was that there are a
lot of other features within Hotpot so I'm looking to go a little bit deeper
into the tool and what I'm looking for is A is there something about this tool
that you would like someone to do a video on and B would you have access to
premium access to Hotpot that I can use for about a month so I can go deep into
the capabilities and features of your tool. So if you can you can respond to
daviday.ideasman.com.au and hopefully we can have a relationship where I
start creating some videos for my channel and your product.