I had a wonderful
relationship with MidJourney.
We've shared many experiences and
created a lot of memories over the last
12 months, and even one month ago, I
renewed our commitment costing $300, so
I was shocked, dismayed, and a little
bit angry when I found myself banned
and when I tried to communicate with
them to find out what had happened to
our relationship, they just ghosted me.
Hi, I'm AppyDave, and I'm going to share
what happened, the ban that I got, the
$300 that I lost, what I believe is a
misdiagnosis, and the frustration that
I had dealing with MidJourney support.
And then after that, I'm going to show you
16 beautiful alternatives to MidJourney.
I've been using MidJourney since
March last year, and I've created
thousands of images that I've used
a lot within my YouTube videos.
But last year I did end up switching a
fair bit over to DALE 3 mainly because
I found it easier to work with within
chat GPT, and I'd already done a
video showcasing 200 image comparisons
between the two different products,
across 50 prompts, and in my opinion.
DALE 3.
While not as good as MidJourney
was a worthy contender.
Last month I was talking at a tech
summit and I needed some pretty good
images for the presentation I was doing.
So I ended up reactivating
my MidJourney account.
Now, one week later, I found myself
having to upgrade because I'd
used up all the credits that I had
there and I ended up spending $288.
But it was great 'cause the images
I was able to generate for the tech
Summit presentation were just wonderful.
Now, two weeks ago, I moved countries.
I came over to Thailand and not long
after arriving, I started getting
this particular error creation
failed on my MidJourney account.
I headed over to Discord and saw this
error that's saying accessing our
services via automation scripting.
Or third party tools created a ban.
Now, I started doing a bit of research
to figure out what was going on because
I hadn't done any automation or third
party scripting, and people had come
up with these issues banned due to
billing, not matching the home address.
Okay?
Not my situation.
Someone has taught about losing a $60
subscription and not being refunded.
My situation is.
$288 'cause I spent it for a full year
and I haven't been refunded either.
Then we saw other sorts of issues
with banning going on, and then this
next one gave me a little bit of
a clue to what might be the issue.
This includes IP and
email bans from discord.
I headed over to an email and I
wrote, I can't sign into MidJourney.
I've checked the images.
There's nothing that meets the fraud
or the other issues that they listed.
I'm an influencer and basically all
the images that I do for YouTube.
And that's important to
understand because you can't do.
Bad quality images on
YouTube and get away with it.
And what happened was I got this reply
straight away from them saying severe
repeated violations of terms and
services, use of automation, scripting,
APIs engaging in reselling services.
So none of this stuff was going on for me.
And then we had this one.
You should have received
notifications in discord.
Informing you of this, that they
would have appeared that you've
interacted with a bot and copies
should have been sent to you.
Now, I've not received a direct
message regarding that, so
I'm not sure what's going on.
The other thing that they've stated
here is as per the terms and conditions,
refunds are not issued on band accounts.
So I thought, okay, where do I go now?
So as I reviewed the forums, again, it
got me thinking about this IP address ban.
And the reason it got me thinking about
it is that a year and a half ago, I came
to Chang Mai for six months, and while
I was here, I signed up to an American.
E-commerce platform.
About two weeks later, they sent me
an email saying that I'd been banned
and that I'd been banned for life.
I could not get an account again, and
I ended up in that particular situation
sending details of my passport and my bank
account details, and then funnily enough.
Four months later, when I was back
in Australia, I got a reversal.
So that was a misdiagnosis going on.
Now, two weeks ago, I found myself
moving again back to Chiang Mai,
and I was going via the Philippines.
So the three places that I find
myself in are Australia, where
I'm either in Sydney or Brisbane.
I find myself in Philippines,
and I find myself in Thailand.
I ended up sending a reply email to
MidJourney stating that I hadn't violated
any terms or conditions that I was
aware of and that I travel, and that
means that I open on different computers
with different ips, my MidJourney
account, and all they did was reply
stating We can't provide you with any
additional information about your band.
Band Users are not eligible for a refund.
So to be honest.
I was a bit gutted by all of that, and
quite angry that I'd spent money only
about three weeks earlier and it was all
lost, and they won't even do the courtesy
of communicating with me about it.
Rather than get caught up in the
resentment of dealing with Mid Journey
support, what I thought is it's
time for a new relationship and the.
Good thing is there are many great
alternatives out there at the moment,
so what we're going to do is look
at 16 different AI art generators,
and we're going to use three
images that I've used in the past.
I've created these in MidJourney,
I've used them in my videos, and with
each of them we are going to run 'em
through the 16 AI art generators.
We are going to need a prompt.
So what I thought I'd do is take
each of the individual images and
we'll drag 'em straight into DALE 3.
Once they're in DALE 3, we can actually
ask DALE 3 to tell us what the image
is about, but I'll give it a little
bit extra context by giving it the
original MidJourney prompt as well.
And then when we run it through.
Darly three.
We get a prompt like this.
So in this particular case, create
an animated illustration of a smiling
30-year-old blonde man with eyeglasses.
And then a bit later on it says,
the style should be similar to
modern animated illustrations
with a clean and simple design.
And what we'll do is we'll take
that prompt and the reference image,
and we're just going to run it
through all 16 AI Art generators.
So the first two we'll look
at is Night Cafe and Ideogram.
Now, night Cafe has a nice clean user
interface where you can select different
styles, whereas Ideogram is really good
at doing symbolic art and Ideograms.
we've got two images here.
They're looking pretty clean to me.
Next we'll look at open
art and designs ai.
So open art has the ability
to use multiple models.
I think it has something like a hundred
different models that you can use.
designs.
AI can be used for images, but it can
also be used for logos and videos as well.
Next to our blue willow, which
is by Limewire and Adobe firefly.
they're both producing
really great images.
We would expect that from Adobe.
But this blue willow
product is also pretty good.
I.
Better mention too, that
we have a Adobe Firefly.
It's like Canva, so you have
the ability to do a lot of other
design tooling with that product.
And that then brings us
onto photo and crayon.
And photo is an interesting one
because it's a graphics editing
software and their implementation of
generative art is pretty good, I think.
Then we've got crayon, which.
I had a lot of trouble trying
to get good images from it.
So this is the first time we've come
across an AI art generator that wouldn't
compare to MidJourney, but everything
else has been pretty good so far.
I.
Next we have Dream Studio and
Imagine and Dream Studio has the
ability to have multiple models
as well that you can select from.
And Imagine Art is a
detailed illustration tool.
Both of these are producing great images.
Next, we're looking at
playground and hotpot.
Now, playground has advanced
editing features while hotpot also
has some editing capabilities.
One of the things I noticed with this
particular image is that to me, it
didn't feel like the illustration
style that was described in the
prompt, but they're still great images.
The next two to look at is
Lexia and Microsoft Copilot.
And Lexia in the past has
been an AI Art search engine.
It's a great place to get inspiration,
but they also have creation
tools and we've used them here.
And this is a tool I do want deep dive
into and there will be a video on that.
As for Microsoft copilot, it's essentially
daily three, so whatever you're doing
in chat GPT you can do here as well.
the last two in the list are worlds apart.
So we've got Leonardo
AI and Diffusion Bee.
Now, Leonardo AI has a lot of
advanced tooling and creativity
that you can do within it.
Diffusion Bee, on the other hand,
is a local computer implementation.
So in my case, it's running on the
Mac and it is a stable diffusion, and
I wasn't really able to get any good
images out of this particular model.
So for the prompt of the 30-year-old
man creative animated illustration,
we've got 16 different variations
here and there are plenty of
great contenders to go up against
MidJourney in this particular case.
What we'll do now is we'll move on
to the next reference image, and I'll
give you a little bit more detail about
each of these applications as we go.
Start by dragging the reference
image over into DALE 3.
We'll also use the original prompt
from MidJourney, which had things
like the style raw stylized 500.
Now this won't be able to be used
effectively in the other art generators,
so the generation of the prompt is
here, create a realistic illustration
of a woman in her thirties shown side
profile, and we got all that information.
And this is what we're going to
feed into the 16 AI art generators.
moving over to the final overview
with this reference image, we've
again got a lot of great examples.
Now, if there's a particular tool that you
want me to do a deep dive in, let me know.
Now, I am going to do a two or
three minute video on pretty
much everything that's here.
But there are a couple here that I'm
going to use professionally with my
YouTube videos, and they're the ones
that I'm going to deep dive into.
So let me know which ones you're
interested in and I'll do a video on them.
The first example we've got here is
Night Cafe and Ideogram, and both
images are pretty good in my opinion.
Let's talk a little bit about Night Cafe.
This tool you can use
Stable Diffusion or DALE 3.
You've also got access to print on demand
and can select different art styles.
I'll tell you more about Ideogram when
we look at the third reference image.
But moving on, we can look
at open art and design ai.
we've got interesting styles.
Maybe the one from Designs AI isn't
as good as the MidJourney one, but
the open art one is quite impressive,
the thing about this particular tool
is that apart from image generation,
it's pretty good with anime characters
and it's also got a image upscale.
Moving on to Blue Willow
and Adobe Firefly.
Blue Willow is great as a tool.
It has many different styles
that you can work from.
It's got some tools like background,
removers, blurs, 3D models, and
one of its key advantages is that
it's quick at generating images.
Let's now have a look at photo and crayon.
Now, crayon light before doesn't really
do a great job of generating images,
but photo is really interesting.
'cause not only is it generating a good
image, but it's a really powerful tool.
I.
We've got photo enhancement, like
upscaling background removal in painting.
It's also got realistic human face
generation, so it can do things like
skin tones, hair accessories, those sorts
of features, which are really hard to
do with general tools like MidJourney.
It's got all the different styles of
art that you might want to do, which
you would expect from a lot of the image
generations, but it can also do transforms
from one style to another overall.
If you want image generation, but
you also want image editing, this
might be a great tool to look at.
Moving on to Dream Studio and
imagine we've got good images being
generated based on the prompt.
Let's talk about Dream Studio.
It's by stability AI using
the stable diffusion model.
Now it's got all your text to
image sort of capabilities.
It can also do image to image, so
you can take an image and alter it.
And it's got capabilities
like image upscaling.
Looking now at playground and hotpot.
So in this case, the
images are pretty good.
the playground has this really nice
user interface and a very generous
usage limit on a daily basis.
It uses different models.
It's got various tools and
customizations, and you can also do image
combinations combining images together.
Moving on to LLexicaand Microsoft copilot.
So Microsoft Copilot, which is DALE 3.
We're showing that here.
Lexica is a search engine now.
It's got image generation tools.
It's got a lot of ability to customize
things and look at the history
of images and adapt over time.
Moving on to the last two.
For the Japanese girl, we've got Leonardo
AI and Diffusion Bee, and at this point
I was nearly giving up on Diffusion Bee,
but Leonardo is an incredibly powerful
image generation and AI generation tool.
You've got capabilities like in
painting, out painting and magic erasers.
You've got control net, which
gives intricate image guidance.
The real time canvas allows
you to make modifications to
the image quickly and easily.
Now moving on to our last reference image,
which is a line coming out of the clouds.
Now you might have noticed in the last
section that I talked a little bit
more in detail about each of the image
generators, but I only did one of them.
Now I'll do the other
half in this section.
So with the image, we've
dragged it into DALE 3.
The original prompt was
actually quite simple.
It was an.
An angel lion emerging from ash, but
with the image being dragged into
DALE 3, what we finally get is create
a powerful and dramatic illustration
of a lion with angelic wings.
Create a powerful and dramatic
illustration of a lion with angelic
wings emerging from a cloud of ash.
So this is the prompt we're going
to use for the 16 generators.
So moving on to Night Cafe and Ideogram
in this particular case, I really love
the image that Ideogram has created.
Night Cafe is not too bad.
Now, the thing about Ideogram
is it's a powerful tool.
It's designed for both
amateurs and professionals.
It's got preset image stars 3D rendering.
It's got community engagement and all
the sort of options editing that you
would like to do, but additionally.
It's got a diverse range of
visual elements and icons.
And the other thing that you can
do with it is work with text.
So you can combine text, fonts, colors,
and different styles with the generation.
Let's have a look at
open art and designs ai.
We've got pretty good
images going on here.
Designs AI is an interesting tool
developed by the Imagine Group.
It's got a bunch of
makers, so it's got a text.
It's got a logo maker, a video
maker, design maker, and speech
maker, so something like the speech
maker can be used for voiceovers.
The other thing it's got are
these pairers, so it's got
font, pairer, and color matcher.
So an interesting range of tools
with this particular product.
Best we'll look at Blue
Willow and a Adobe Firefly.
We've got two great
images going on here now.
Adobe's going to be a really powerful
tool moving forward, so I guess its
main competitor is Canva, but it
has the ability to integrate into
the rest of the Adobe products.
One of the things that's got is
this ethical ai, so it's all trained
on images that it has the rights
to, and then being a design tool
has Generative fill and expand.
you can also do veto graphics with it.
move on to photo and crayon.
Now, crayon has been a tool that I
didn't get a lot of success out of
it, but it might still be a useful
tool for you to use for these reasons.
It is a free tool and it has prompt
predictions and suggestions, and with
a little bit of work, you can get an
image close to what you might want.
Next we'll look at Dream Studio
and Imagine Art, and they're
both producing great images.
Now Imagine Art is a pretty powerful tool.
it's got different styles, image
remixing, and advanced configuration.
It can also do background
removal and in painting.
So we're looking at playground and
hotpot again, and these are now
becoming leading contenders for myself.
But let's talk a little bit about hotpot.
So it's quite a versatile tool that
you can use for image generation,
but you can also use it for photo
editing, headshots, and avatars.
One of the other things
it can do is text writing.
So you can use it for your brainstorming
and copywriting and like tools like
Canva or Firefly, it has templates that
you can customize for social media.
I.
moving on to Lexica and Microsoft
Co-pilot, the Lexica image is really good.
The Microsoft Co-pilot for me is something
that you would use just the same way as
you would use DALE 3 within chat GPT.
Now, if you are using Microsoft Co-pilot,
you might not want to go any further
than this, and if you really wanna see
a great set of examples of MidJourney
versus what Microsoft Copilot could do,
you could check out the video that I've.
Did last year where I did 400 images,
50 prompts, four images per prompt
for MidJourney, and four images per
prompt for DALE 3, where you can
get a good side by side comparison
between these two different products.
For the last two, Leonardo
AI and Diffusion Bee.
So the Leonardo image is pretty
good, the Diffusion Bee, the thing
about this tool is that this image
that's done is okay and it's free.
It runs on your computer, so you
have a lot of capability to produce
images, but it doesn't necessarily
create the best results, but some
of the tools that are built into it.
Include in painting, out
painting and upscaling, and you
can plug different models in.
So if you know what you're doing, you
might be able to get this to a much
higher level of capability and just
run it locally on your Mac computer.
In the case of Diffusion Bee for
Windows, I'm sure there's a tool
that does something very similar.
So there's 16 great examples of
the lion coming out of the ashes.
We've also got the lady in her house,
Japanese background, and the man
in his thirties illustration style,
yellow background with his thumbs up.
So even though I've been
banned from MidJourney is um.
Fortunate, I wish they
would look into the case.
I've found that there are 16 awesome
alternatives out there, so please like
and subscribe and if you are interested
in videos about prompt engineering or AI,
then let me know in the comments below.
Otherwise, I'll see you in the next video.
Have a great day.
I'm AppyDave.