AIDA is an AI pair programmer that you can run from the terminal.
In this video I want to download DOOM by ID software and using scripting capability,
let's document that complete project automatically so that we can potentially
turn it into a new version using a different programming language.
I'm Appy Dave, let's get into it.
So we can get started by heading over to Appy Dave on GitHub and we've got this DOOM with docs.
Now what it is is the original DOOM software that I've just fought and I'm going to add
documentation to it using AIDA.
So before we get started with the scripting let's just run AIDA and we'll use it from the
terminal point of view and what we'll do is we'll make sure that the repo has been added in or
check what's new in the new version.
I like pressing yes to this every time I start AIDA because it just gives me access to new
capabilities and the new capability that I'm seeing here today is that there's a copy
context where information from the AIDA session can automatically end up in your clipboard that
can be really useful and I just want to find out what is this repo about.
So what sort of code, what's it meant to do and let's just see what it comes up with.
Now it's worked out that this is the 1.1 release on Linux of DOOM and it's got a little bit of
information about the code base.
Now this cost money to do so we can see the cost here.
It's two cents and we're on the first part of the session.
Now if you use the same prompt again you would hope that prompt caching kicks in and that we
would reduce the cost but I ran this again with exactly the same prompt and if we go to the bottom
we're still being charged two cents though we do have a little bit different information.
So just one thing to be aware of there.
So let's have a quick look at what we've got in the repo.
So we've got these four folders.
This one called send serve if we go and click on the readme file it says it's something to do
with our sound server.
Open up the serve source and we read the readme file and it's something to do with a modem driver.
We read that and it's an IPX network driver and it looks like the main code is going to be in this
area here.
So we've got a bunch of old readme files going on with various information about the DOOM game.
So where I think we'll start is we'll go with the simpler folders and just generate some simple
documentation in a readme markdown file using ADA.
So we're in the terminal and we've got this IPX directory here and what we'll do is we'll come
down to terminal type in ADA and we'll put in message and what we'll say is create a readme
file and after that we just need to put in the location of the file.
So I'm just going to say readme md and we'll press enter and let's see what it generates
for us now while that's happening.
We'll bring up visual studio.
So we've got this new file being created and let's just put it into a more readable format
at the moment and it says here this directory contains the IPX networking implementation
of DOOM.
We've got an overview.
We've got features, technical details and a historical note.
So we've got a bunch of information that it's gathered out on its own.
Now let's see if we can improve that documentation by maybe reading each of the individual files
and seeing if we can create something a lot more detailed.
So I have a little tool that I built for myself that allows me to see files and also the content
and make them available for ChatChimp ET.
So what we'll do is we'll just run it on the current folder and we can see
all the files that are made up of the DOOM software here.
Now if we just bring it down to the IPX directory we should have C and header files and if we
just put in a .h we should just have the header files.
Now from there if I get rid of the .dashf tree I'm going to get a list of those files
plus their content and it's in the clipboard.
And so what that means is if I just paste it in we've got there's the last file right there
and the content and as we scroll up we'll have additional files going on.
So there's the third file and the content.
Let's format it so it's designed directly for ADA.
Now we already know that if we run ADA from the command line with the message
and a file it'll run against that but you can list moddable files but since we've
got our new tool which is the GPT context what we'll do is we'll use it to find a bunch of
files based on a wildcard and we'll just put in a format we'll say ADA and I'll put in a prompt
tell me something interesting about this file and what this is going to do is just construct
the ADA command for me put in the clipboard so we can test this out.
Now the ID software is not written in an encoding that works on my machine so the first thing I'm
seeing is a few errors as this comes through and you can see here that even though we've got
information it's also dropped certain files so what we'll do is we'll just run it again
and I'm just going to go to the beginning and I'm just going to put in this encoding option
which is part of ADA because I figured out that this would be the way that it would read it through
so now it's added the files and they're not being dropped and we're going to get clear
information about each file. Now what I'd like it to do now is create some complex documentation
just based on these four files and we'll put it into create documentation in ipx slash readmeh.md
and let's put in a more complex prompt here so to get my more complex prompt I just came over
to Anthropic Prompt Generator said create clear documentation about a single C file
aimed at a programmer who does not know C and we end up with this complex prompt going on here
from there I've just taken the complex prompt that's here and just turned it into a single line
so that we can just paste it directly into our terminal so we got the terminal create documentation
in ipx readmeh.md and we'll just paste in all that information we're working on the four files
and let's see what it comes up with so at the moment we've got a bunch of information
being written hopefully we're going to see a new file get created in this location
looks like it's got the file name location crap but it's asking us to generate it so we'll say yes
and now we have a new file we should be able to go into markdown format and see what that looks like
and we've got a lot of complex data that's being created for us using the scripting process now I'm
going to make any claim that this is great information right now but what you can see is
how we can write complex prompts iterate over multiple files and bring it back into one documentation
file now I've come back to the GPT context command and I'm just going to change the pattern to the
C files and I'm essentially going to paste in the same prompt except right at the very beginning
I'm going to have it right out to the readme C rather than the readme h file and we'll let that
generate the ADA command we can paste that in and it says ADA message create documentation in the
ipx readme C MD file and so we'll just press enter on that now this may fail again with the encoding
issues so we'll see what happens in a moment it looks like it's working okay as we read through
there we can see the doom C ipx setup and ipx net.c coming through so this is all the documentation
that we're writing and it's finished we've got a file that's going to appear right next to the
h file we can open it up go into a markdown format and we can see now a bunch of information
about the ipx C files now what I'd like to do now is create a complete documentation
readme for the C files in this particular folder so what we'll do is we go down to the GPT context
tool and we'll just make sure we've got all the files listed they all look to be good let's see
just how big this will be so I'm going to get rid of the format and it's going to give us both the
files and the code we'll just paste all of that in so we've got 43,400 lines of code across all of
those files if we go to the top we can see the files listed as well and this is important to know
because this is your context and it's going to cost money so we're running the same GPT context
command but this time I've said the format is ADA and we'll put in the prompt here and what we'll
do is we'll just come over and have a look at a prompt that says create documentation in the Linux
doom readme C file and then we've got this complex prompt that we built using anthropic prompt
generate so we can see we've got a command ready to go ADA message create documentation in the
location we want we've got the complex prompt going on after that we'll just let that run and
see what happens so many files have been added warning it's best to only add files to set
your need for the chat well we do need them all it's a lot going on here and we can see here
we've hit a token limit now this is a more than fair thing and we probably wouldn't want to run
this many files through one lot of documentation generation anyway so what we'll do next is we'll
so what we're going to do is look at all the C files that are in this particular directory
and we'll iterate over all of them and just run ADA on each file now one of the things to keep in
mind is that if we do a git log we want to make sure that as we're iterating we're not creating
a new commit each time because we probably want to do that at the end of the run so let's assume
we've got a starting command that looks like this ADA and we don't want to commit so we said no
auto commits we've got a message and we're going to assume that some sort of file is going to come
in we want to write to the md file and we want to base it off the incoming file do you want to
create a new file we'll say yes and we should get a new file just created here and now we've got
documentation related to the file above so we can see the individual file and the documentation
related to it now if we come down to the terminal and we do a formatted git log and we can see that
there's one file ready to go so if we did this in a loop we would have everything ready for a
single commit at the end and I'll show you the ADA command for that later on so what we have here
is the file we just ran which was ADA no commits the message we want to a particular file using
an input file and what we'll do is we'll just paste in a loop so that we're just looping through all
the files in that folder and we're just interpolating the file name with md and we've also got the
file name coming in but let's make it a little bit more complex and we'll take this complex
prompt that we did earlier and we will just go dash and paste that in as well and from there we
should be able to run this and run the complex prompt and create a markdown file for every c file
so I kicked off the command we can see where the it starts here and so far it's run for about 15
minutes and we can see individual files being updated then it moved on here and both created
and opened the d items md so we've got that going on and this goes on for quite a while then at one
stage it decided to create files in a docs directory now it didn't always do that it would
sometimes do it in this directory and sometimes do it at the level of the original file so there's
just a change that's going on as we go now if we just go to the bottom it's still operating at the
moment so we'll just kick off the next one it will say yes and this one looks like it's going to be
created at the root level which is where we want in that instance when it said open the file I said
no in this case so we do have a little bit of control whether we create them or open them in your
IDE so for this one we'll just say yes create the file so I'll let it run to the end and then we'll
see what's been created and calculate the prices let's check out a couple of metrics here so we've
got all these markdown files in various levels and that's quite concerning to be honest because we
got some at the root level we've got some where they're meant to be which is in where the code was
then we've got a bunch that are in a sub folder called docs and then we've got two that are at
the root level plus docs it seems like it generated all the markdown documents but didn't always get
them in the right location so what I've done is brought all the files into the docs string so if
you go down to the chat history you've got a whole lot of data that you can use to figure out various
things so I'm not sure whether there's a way to get the exact cost of the session so there's 84
lines averaging around about three to four cents per call that we can see that the 84 calls cost
four dollars 11 and I got that information from the chat history now if we look for the create new
file we can see that all listed here for quite a while it's putting them into the right location
and then it just changes for about three files and then it goes into a high level dots folder for
some reason and then we're back to where it's meant to be and then later on we've got a few
examples here here and here where it's done it down at the root level so most of the time when
it created a file it gave you the option to open it which is not something I actually needed
it also from time to time would do a cat to the screen and then ask the question would you like
to add it into the chat conversation now I'm not exactly sure whether this was going to be useful
or not I don't believe it would be because I was on an iteration of looping through and calling
AIDA each time so I'm not sure if it was in the same session then from time to time I would ask
to make a dots directory so the interesting thing about doing this level of analysis is that there's
an unpredictability to what was going on with the creation now we haven't looked at the documentation
so let's have a look at that next now AIDA will normally take care of doing the commits for you
but I said no commits so what we're going to have to do is just add them and commit them so what I
want to do now is get a tree of all the documentation files that we've created under the doom folder
plus the ones that we've got at a higher level from there we'll run this command one more time
and we'll put in some sort of prompt that hopefully can create a broad markdown file that can take us
to each of those documentation files so here's the prompt that we're going to use we'll just run
we've now got it all set up we can just press paste and let AIDA do its job of looking through
all the files creating a 10 to 15 word description for each file and putting it all into a table of
contents so we can see information coming so I've just pushed the documentation up we can
set it here code documentation we click on that and we've got this long documentation table of
contents going on with individual files let's just go and open up a couple of core systems
we'll do a rendering file a game logic and let's go down to a user interface and as we go across
we can start to see the documentation going on for the core logic and then there's a little bit
of user interface information going on here now I can't tell you whether the documentation is 100
or it's the right way to go the main thing I'm relying on at the moment is that we can script
to generate information on BOL there's great information in these files such as just how
it's meant to work as part of the whole system and also information for non-c programmers now that
brings us to the end of scripting AIDA from the command line we've looked at single line calls
we've looked at how to do a prompt to guess many files at the same time and also how to loop through
files now in the next video I want to look at a programmatic way of working with AIDA now one
of the things that we can see from the documentation here is that they have an unofficial way of
communicating with this using Python so hopefully we'll explore that in the next video I'm Appy