Wouldn't it be great if you were on a Zoom call or Facebook messenger and you had gestures
that could give some sort of animation?
In this video, I'm going to talk about eight different reactions that have been added to
the latest version of the Mac operating system Sonoma.
My name is happy Dave.
I usually talk about chat GPT, but as a content creator, I thought it was interesting to see
these new effects built directly into the operating system.
Earlier today, I called up Apple care because of a problem with my Mac and they noticed that
I was on version 13 of the operating system and they suggested that I upgrade to Sonoma
version 14.1.
And I've done that today while getting set up.
I found out that there were these cool reactions that you could add to your videos.
Since for the last couple of days, I've been sick.
I've had a really bad flu.
I thought I'd test them out and see what they might look like in a live video.
I just upgraded my operating system today and when I went to start recording a video on
chat GPT, I got this warning about this new concept called reactions presenter overlay.
I thought, what is this?
And essentially it took me to this little article on the Apple support site where you
can use concepts like love hearts, two fingers up for balloons.
We've got thumbs up, thumbs down, and we've got things like confetti and lasers.
So in this video, I'm just going to show them all in action and see whether they might be
a use case for me in the sort of videos that I do.
You might have noticed in the introduction that when I put two fingers from both hands
up, you end up getting a bit of confetti coming up through the screen.
But if you only use one hand, what you'll end up with is balloons.
Hands coming up.
Let's say you're talking on Messenger and a friend of yours says something a bit stupid.
You can give them a thumbs down emoji and that's going to show up.
But on the other hand, maybe you're watching a video like this and you're learning some
really cool concepts, then you can go down below and click on the like button.
Or if you found this video really interesting, you could go down below and click on the subscribe
button.
Now, to be honest, I found all of this to be quite amusing.
I do love what it can do, but it's not that easy to use if you're using it for a live
video like what I'm doing at the moment.
This technology is great if you're doing a Zoom call or a Facebook Messenger with friends,
family, work colleagues, and you just want to be a bit funny.
If you're using it for content creation, then this was a no.
I found that putting my hand into place sometimes I'd get it, sometimes it would take a fair
bit of time.
And that's just not very useful when you're trying to do a video for YouTube.
Today's video isn't my normal content on ChatGPT, but if you're interested in that sort of
information, then why don't you subscribe or like the video and I'll see you in the
next video, which I promise will be on ChatGPT.