Today it's Dave and in this happy cast I'm going to be continuing on the YouTube
automation challenge that I was working on. I've developed this mind map and what
we're going to do today is just have a look through and make sure everything is
in place and then develop a project plan. Now I'm going to also do that by
testing out the same project plan on two different tools. I'm going to try Trello,
I'm going to try to click up just to see which one I like using the most. There
will definitely be some sort of can-band sort of layout going on. Now let's work
through this mind map we have here. So we worked out that we have some channels.
We have trend 10 which is going to be about trending topics, probably 10
concepts per trend and the magic of 10 which is going to be some sort of
evergreen videos. Now I do know I need to expand on this idea a little bit further
and we might come back to that one. There is then a process that we're going
to work through. So with the channel there'll be niche research of categories
and topics, getting a list of videos, figuring out what the YouTube competitors
are and doing niche valuations and that's kind of what's going to be
required when we come back and look at the evergreen videos is there'll
probably be a sub-niche that I want to focus on and understanding niche
valuations which it can be things like just the I think it's called CPM, the
monetization per thousand. I don't know what CPM stands for but it's something
like that. And then we've got the video research of the process where we have
identified that there'll need to be keyword research for each video then
there'll need to be research on to the topic. This will generate a title from
that will create a thumbnail and then we'll pass it off to script writers who
will probably use GPT bots to help give consistent information for scripts
and this stuff will then create the intro, the script and the outro and where
it says CTA there's the idea that there should be a call to action in each of
these as well. Now the reason it's been important to get the process and what
makes a part of today's video is that I'm going to create these project
management plans and essentially it's just going to be the information that
you see in here especially when I create the project plan template. Now we'll
move over to this section called structural requirements and what I've
essentially done here is listed all the concepts that would be on the YouTube
page itself, description about channel banner logos trailers and what I've
done is I've created a concept of channel branding and I could just copy all
these and paste them over here so that when I'm developing my project plan
that information is already associated with the channel branding. There may
actually be just one task called channel branding and a bunch of subtasks for
each of the channel branding concepts and then the good thing is I can delegate
these out either to myself to work on or to one or more team members. Next area to
look at is building a team, going to figure out where to find them, how much
and who the different roles and responsibilities are, thumbnail, designer,
scriptwriter etc. Now I'm doing this on a budget at the moment so to be honest
this will probably be myself and my friend Adam will work through these but
we may outsource some things that just totally make sense to be done by
someone else. What I'm also starting to see here as I develop this mind map is
that rather than move this around I'm just going to add a section to the
process called build a team and we could call it HR as well and this what
we're calling a process is now starting to become the project plan. The say
project plan for now it really is the process but I'm going to use this
information to develop my project plan. So that then brings us into the area called
project management and this is just a little holding point that I said for
what sort of tools and format I want to use. It's likely that the stuff in the
channel or the channel development and the building the team would probably be
some sort of list project management tool but the actual videos themselves
because they go through a bunch of different states so they go from
ideation through the titles and thumbnails and scriptwriting and video
development and then it's all cleaned up and closed off and then it's
published and then it moves on to things like social media sending and this
happens to happen with each and every video. You have this state flow that
videos need to go through and this will be where a cambeam board would be a
better technique. So we will check out Trello and click up I know Trello is
probably a really good tool for this but I've used click up a fair bit more of
late and I just want to know for myself which tool would be the best to work
with. So I think from a process project plan point of view we can just say
PM tool investigation is something we need to do and that's part of today I
think and then we get on to let's look at what production is about.
Dutch and will be the actual implementation of these technologies like
how do you do the keyword research and I have a good idea of a lot of this but
I'm developing this on the fly as we go as we work through the behind the
scenes. So a lot of these processes will be developed in the next couple of
weeks as I work through all of this and lastly we have monetization and it's
at the moment it's just an umbrella term we have not identified anything like
affiliates or other sort of monetization strategies to use and a lot of that
can't really be worked through until I know the actual videos and video types
that we're going to work on because once you know the sort of video topics
and videos that you're creating you can then go and identify particular
affiliate sort of systems maybe it's maybe it's the Amazon affiliate system
or maybe it's one of the others that are out there I'm not an expert here this
will require a lot of investigation by me.
What we'll do now is develop the content for the project plan.
Now the project plan is essentially got the information that we've been
developing on this mind map node so what I can do here is click on the node and
press copy and at the moment that information is stored in the clipboard
in a hierarchical point of view so if I move over to a product like visual
studio I can just paste that information directly in and everything will be okay
there is one link a hyperlink back to the mind map that I don't need here
and we can look through this information now the data here is a in markdown format
and the good thing is there's a plugin or within visual studio to see that in a
more visual sort of format it can handle things like hyperlinks and other
sorts of HTML formatting but at the moment we just need the bullet points the
first item that will be working on project management tool investigation
that that's something we're doing in the next 10 or 15 minutes I don't really
need that as an entry into any project management plan but working on the
channel is and whatever we do needs to be done twice because it needs to be done
for the magic of 10 and it needs to be done for trend 10 and the same sort of
process needs to be run but it needs to be run twice within that there'll be a
ticket for niche research and we're looking here at what is the channel
gonna focus on who is the target avatar so who is this channel aimed at what
are some topics and categories what are a list of videos who are the
competitors and how can we get maybe some predicted niche valuations and this
will be important as we decide well exactly which part of the niche should
we focus on and to put that in really simple terms if I was doing top 10
trends top 10 trends on poetry would not pay as much money as top 10 trends on
crypto trading or artificial intelligence and that's the sort of stuff that I want
to work out for the channel so that it's not just relatively easy for us to
implement the competition is okay that we can get into the market but if it
became successful is it actually going to make decent money say something like
10 or 15 dollars per thousand views versus 2 cents per thousand views now I'll
look through here we've got the videos and we've got the building of the team
I'm going to just take this information and I'm going to move it up and open it
up into here and the reason for this is that I see the video project management
as quite different to this section of project management because the video
project management is a repeating system you might do a hundred videos exactly
the same project management routine will happen for all hundred videos but these
other things are kind of one-offs and building a team we're going to have to
work out where to find a team or whether myself and my friend Adam work on it
together part of that will be determined by how much it would cost working with a
team this is really this challenges a test it's not I don't know whether this
works there are so many people selling this idea of YouTube automation you'll
get you'll make millions of dollars if you do it but maybe I don't know at the
moment I wouldn't invest in something that I don't at least have a gut feel
that it's going to work but as we develop a channel there'll be what I would
call the channel manager that would be myself and then there will be the
thumbnail designer the scriptwriter what else we got here the voice over artist
and the video editor I think the only other thing missing that could be the
scriptwriter is the keyword researcher or just researcher in general now when we
look at all of this it's really just a list of tasks the tasks that are going
on here are going to be repeated twice I don't think I talked about this but this
is really developing the molding media assets whether it be text assets such as
the description and the about us page or whether it be visual ones like the logo
and if we go down to the video this is where we see the detailed ideas of what
will go on I won't go into it too much now because I think it'll really gel
even for myself as I develop the project cards and start writing what would go on
in every task now what we can move on to is having a look at the two project
management tools that I'm thinking of one called Trello one called ClickUp but
before I do let's just talk briefly about the difference between list or task or
Kanban board let's head over to a web view and I'm going to do is bring up a
to-do list so everyone knows what a to-do list is you put write it down on a
piece of paper it's a list of tasks and most project management tools can do
this and this is how I will organize the one-off tasks that I need to do around
the channel development but not everyone knows what a Kanban board is and
these Google images here kind of show the idea of a Kanban board where you
have a concept of these columns and you can name them however you like and you
can put as many columns in as you want but if you go too too many columns it
can become a little bit challenging to manage and so you might have a back
video ideas they would probably go into a back list or a backlog I should say
and what happens is when you're ready to work on a video you would just drag one
of the ideas into work in progress but this is where if we go and look at the
content plan that we set up earlier where for videos we had the idea of keyword
research general research title is no if you look at the column headings that
are here backlog work in progress validating complete how you can come
up with them is quite simple if you go back and look at your original list of
tasks that you need to do for the video so here we would have the concept of a
image we just saw backlog would be another thing that we need and in okay
100 videos let GPT fill it in for us another term for backlog in this case
could just be ideas and that way when you're passing off information you can
just pick one of the ideas that you like and see what happens and then you
would have a column for the keyword research one for the general research
then someone would after this is done develop a title for what the video is
going to be from that we can create the thumbnail and each of these just become
part of now we will take the information that we've got as headings here and when
we get to our camp and board we will make sure that there's a column that just
has each of those now let's go and have a look at the two tools that I've used in
the past and they're both okay and let's make a decision we'll get over to the
internet and we'll just search for the concept of Trello and we'll also look
for the concept of ClickUp and it should take us to websites so there's Trello
looks like ClickUp is logging straight in for me and we'll come back to Trello
and just click on the official website you can see there's a few
boards and stuff that I've set up before I haven't used this for quite a while
and I think I stopped using it because I don't like it but I do want to test them
out properly with more than one or two people that are using it just to see
what they feel is the most efficient it's it's good that I have visibility of
projects but it's better that my team can use the project management tasks
efficiently so for the first one or two videos or concepts I will test both of
them and make a decision so from Trello we'll just click create a board and what
we'll do is we'll call it trend 10 and we'll just say create and as you can see
it doesn't cost any money for under 10 by the looks of things and I believe I
can just click this little button here and I will say magic I'll put a dash
between these words dash of 10 and we'll create that board as well says create
start with a template I don't maybe I needed to do that as well we should test
this so we'll just create one called ABC and start with the template and see
what's available for us and there's already this concept called can ban
template we can do that and just go create see what it comes up with and
we're already now I don't think we need this I think you can just change it up
here and we will see so come back to our trend 10 I'm just gonna come back to
Visual Studio and I will just copy this block of information I'm not going to go
down into individual tasks I think the task will just be niche research and I'll
keep these items they'll probably go in the description they might go into sub
items if that's supported by this tool so we head back to the can ban or to the
Trello board and we've got this concept of a board here if I want tabular sort of
formats or other formats I'd have to pay for this product so I believe we just
have board and I'm not going to paste in anything until I see what happens so
let's just go with ABC and how do we do it we press add list that's put in my
name instead let's do ABC add list AB XYZ so under my name it can be do this
add a card do something else add a card and ABC can be we'll do a card called one
we'll do a card called two X will do a card called three and we'll do an X card
called four and let's just see whether these just move they do they move all
the way through now what that then leads me to think is that these lists that
would be created are the can ban board ideas so this would probably be a
backlog this one would probably be an in progress and this last one might be a
complete sort of concept and as I look at it I think well I actually want
different sections because I want a section that would be the list of tasks
that are in backlog and we were just looking at a couple of them and then
they go into progress and then they get completed and then a separate section
which would be all the workflows that we need to produce a video and that would
be a bigger set of lists and if I understand the use of this software
correctly and we'll come back to here so you can see what I mean by a bigger set
of lists where things go from the backlog to design and into to do I would
almost need a magic of 10 project management overview followed by a magic
of 10 video video project management setup now a lot of people love this I
don't like the way this is coming together so at this stage I'm just going to
abandon it this is part of my investigation as to what project
management tool I want to use and the fact that I probably need to have a
workspace for the general tasks versus a workspace for the video tasks I'm not
sure that I feel comfortable with that but you might feel really comfortable with
it so if you love Trello if you've used it in the past and you're trying to do
YouTube automation I encourage you to take this further than I'm going to take
it in this session today let's just move it straight over to click up and I've
used it in the past here this is fly video let's just see whether we can add
a new workspace here we will call it trend 10 and I'm not going to worry
about the magic of 10 until I've tested this out a little bit and we'll just give
it a color I think blue will be good when I get a logo that would have gone
there but we don't have a logo just yet so I want a little bit of marketing
information I filled in a little bit of extra information I also included
Adam's email address which I won't show in the video and we're taken directly to
this list format and there's things called to do what I believe I can do is
just paste the information now it's noticed that there are multiple lines
detected and it's going to create eight tasks now most of these are actually
sub tasks of the other ones so let's just see what that does I thought that
would be the case I wonder if we can do an undo an undo would be a nice thing
right now but we can't so we might just select them all and I wonder if they can
just drag as sub tasks under niche research looks like they can so one of
the things I could do is have niche research as a task to work on and then
I could work through all these items another way of looking at it though is
that I could go into niche research we'll just get rid of this information at the
moment and call it one task and what happens we go down here and we just
paste in the information I think this is probably going to be a single task that
I work through some of the features you can do is I can add Adam as a watcher so
anything I do on this task he would see it we can do time tracking and etc now
let's come back to the list and I'm going to delete these little tasks that we
created I believe there is a button up here and it's just here it's called
delete and we can delete all eight of them at once to our visual studio and
we'll come back to our visual studio and we will select this information it's
called channel branding and get back into click up we'll add a new task I'm just
going to put a C here for now if I pasted all that information I'd get the
split and we don't want that so we'll just go in here paste all the information
we got here take channel branding out of there and put it into the heading so
these are a bunch of things now this because these are actions that would
really need to get taken care of one at a time I've just made a decision on the
fly here that while I will leave that there they do need to be subtasks as
well now how do we do that we have a concept of subtasks so if we click in
here I'm just going to paste everything I just come in here there's this
concept called multi cursor in visual studio that allows you to select
information and miss other information so we really only want to copy these
pieces of data go back to our application and paste them straight in and it's
saying eight tasks and they're all being created and you can see that they're
there they are tasks but they're subtasks of the main channel branding concept
and we can then expand this out now this is not going to be a Kanban board so
we'll come back to visual studio we've got build our team and that's the heading
we want where do we find them I think in this case this is all one task what I
might do is take all of this information as a copy we can head back to our
website to click up in this case I will just call it build team like that we hit
save and I'll go into the description and write down what it is we want to do
we can do that back to visual studio and this is where we get on the video and
this really needs to be a Kanban board rather than a list like we're doing
should we start it yet we won't start it yet instead we will come back and make
sure we've got a little bit more segmentation so the current segmentation
we have is that things are to be done like a backlog I guess now I believe if
we click in here we can create a new status I do not know whether this creates
a new grouping we will test this out and we will call it in progress I guess in
progress give it a color I think blue would be a good color for something that
you're working on I always like the pastel blues and I don't fully understand
the the the two different styles here I think it's only for the list that we
need to do so we'll just add that in we have any progress and what that means is
that if you were to start work on this if I was to start work on it I could just
drag it up into the in progress and if Adam who was working on this project was
to do it I'd get notified which is part of the goal of project management now we
can go and add one more status and we'll go in here we'll say new status and we'll
just say complete so we're keeping it very simple the set of things that we're
going to work through says it already exists
you
okay so I had an issue with the complete task but I saw what the what it is let's
save and I'm just going to click on this little button and there is already a
complete by default I don't know how configurable this is but when you throw
a task into complete we can see it right now and that's because it's being shown
but by default it's not being shown so that was partly why I was confused
because there was a closed status I put it into close and then I went where did
it go well it went into an area not visible unless you quickly show the
closed task and I don't know whether it's appropriate to delete yes you can
delete so we will delete that one because it was just artificial the other
thing I've noticed is we have this concept called list inside this concept
called space so they're such generic terms that they don't make any sense now
since the tasks that I have here are all around the channel set up I guess I'm
going to rename this list and how can we do that so you have a little list
button here we'll click on this let's see if we've got looks like we've got a
rename view so we'll click there change it to
it's a bit long but maybe that works okay and that was incorrect I'm gonna go and
change that back to list and I'll try it from this point instead rename and we
go set up might be the right way to go okay well that's changed that and it's
showing up in here now then there's this idea of space and since I'm going to be
creating two channels trend 10 and magic of 10 currently I've called the account
trend 10 it might be better off that I call this account YouTube automation
challenge and then I can have a space which I'll rename and we will call that
trend 10 so we have a space called trend 10 which currently has a concept called
channel setup and channel setup currently has three separate major tasks the
channel branding the building a team and the niche research the channel
branding currently has a bunch of sub tasks whereas the other two tasks that
I've created they are just considered one task with a whole lot of things that
might go on within it this may not be right yet we may want to build these
out to sub tasks I wonder if it's appropriate to rename this right now so
it's called channel it's called trend 10 right here and there looks like there
are settings at two levels on this screen there's either for me the owner of the
account or for if it's not called a space I don't know what it is I guess it's
some sort of other naming convention we'll just go to settings and we will call
this YouTube I might just go YT automation and it's a challenge but if I have too
many words you won't be able to see it so we can close that out hit the back button
and now we have YouTube automation I can change over to other accounts I have like
where I work one of my major channels that I do some stuff on we've got the
YouTube automation again it'd be really nice if we had a logo showing here and
we have trend 10 and now the next step is let's create a Kanban board for the
video production now what we'll do is we'll set up the Kanban board for the videos
what we can do is move on over to the web interface we have trend 10 now we have the
channel set up there's an ad button let's see what this gives us we can do a list
and this time we'll name the list as we go and we'll say videos we'll create them
and we now have this concept of to do now if we want to go from list format to Kanban
format we just click the board button and we can see things going from left to right
we can come back to here and I'll jump us over to visual studio code and what you will see
now I have a list of the ideas or tasks that would need to be done when
creating a video I'm just going to copy that and create a new window now we don't need this
first one because we've already got the list created called videos and I'll select them all
and shift tab them in now the idea of this little bit of information about what each task goes
do we need that within our tasks we probably do but they're not easy to just copy and paste
from this format into click up so I think I'll just I think I'll just remove these little bits as
we go and now what we've got is just a list of tasks that would happen in order I will rename
one of them so this is definitely keyboard research this is definitely keyword research
and this is more the video research that's the backlog or the to do might be a better word but
we'll go with backlog then we've got the youtube title we got the thumbnail we've got a concept
we've called GPT bots but a better way of thinking about this and that might be what
a staff member might be using but this is really just
part of the script editing but we've already got a script so we won't do that now if I was to do
things in order would I do the intro before the script this is a hard one to decide it kind of
depends if you do the intro first which is kind of like when you do the youtube title it really
informs how the script should be written but then there's probably a time where the intro
needs to be redone after the script because you never know what direction the script is going
to go down so I might just put in another thing called intro edit so that will cover the situation
that the intro has been done the script has been written driven off the intro but now the intro might
be a little bit wrong so let's recreate it and the other thing that I've kind of missed when
thinking this through and partly this is because I'm moving into a youtube automation process where
other people will kind of dictate how they want to do the flow versus how I think about it if I
was doing it purely myself and the script writing gets done and there is this backwards and forwards
that goes on during that time and then the video gets created and you can kind of see here I've
maybe mixed in a few concepts so I might just move the script up to here and then these can really
be the video creation intro outro and video body this might make a lot more sense in the workflow
that I'm seeing coming to life now I'm just going to use the multi cursor to get rid of all these
dashes we don't need any of them I can press command a to select everything command c to copy
and then I can just go over to pick up where I'm going to paste these in now I'm
potentially a little confused around this I don't think they're tasks let's just paste them in it
should allow us to create modable tasks which is great but I don't think this is going to fit the
canband board style that's right because now we've just got it to do with what is meant to be well
these items are all meant to be across the top so we can come back I'll come back to list format
and just select them all now is there a way of selecting them all up here not really so we'll
click them this way I think you can press shift click to do this we will delete them
so instead we need to look at these statuses we'll click here and there's new status now I don't
know whether I can bulk create statuses this is really what I want to try and do here so new status
status name let's paste them all in and I bet this won't work okay unfortunately we're going
to have to add them in one at a time so let me just go and do that
you
now I've just been adding a couple of these tasks manually and I thought this
feels wrong it doesn't feel like the right way to do it you can see if I go to the canband board
that things are starting to come together the order may or may not be right but I thought well
how do you solve this and just had a quick look over on Google search and it told me to go try
this area we can find that I think it's in views list settings look at that we got a list of statuses
now this means we can alter them I wonder if we can change the color here this is also a good
thing so the backlog would probably be gray and then I could probably color code them because
there's so many of them just by section I think and I've pressed a button what have I done
now I tried a couple of attempts to get lists statuses right for the canband board
and didn't realize that there was a section called statuses I was creating some in a odd
fashion I think what I'll do is I'll delete this I don't know whether there's a way of
deleting them easily what we're looking at is a custom set of statuses for this space
but I believe it might be nicer if I just created a new template and I think we'll call it video
production that might be a good name for it and from here okay that's where we're at they got rid
of the word custom this one is definitely going to be back backlog rather than to do
because we don't know whether it's going to be done or not it needs to be evaluated and you can
add statuses now you can't add multiple statuses at once so I'll quickly just be going backwards
and forwards between the visual studio section and the status section and just paste them all in
one at a time now I've just finished now I've just finished off putting in the statuses manually
I didn't have to set the colors as you add a new task I'll just show this press a for a status and
it just automatically picks the color and I just went with whatever it decided we'll just delete
that one one of the things I'm thinking with the colors is that I might just have the same color for
say the role so there's a different role for a person who might be researching the keywords
and the video idea versus the person who's doing the thumbnail versus the person who's doing the
script writing there may be modable steps in the script writing process both before and well at
different levels and the video editor and one thing we also haven't put in here is actually the
publishing of the video like how does it get up on to YouTube when does the description the
thumbnail and the title get pasted in is there a follow-up process for say AB testing of the
thumbnails etc so there's more statuses we can have and they are for different roles different
types of people and this is where I feel the color of each of these statuses might make sense to be
based on the role and that way if you are the thumbnail person you might just look at the
blue ones you're the video editor you might just look at the green ones and you work through them
but this is for future let's now hit save and see where we are at and I've created these
fake tasks called abcde and we'll just go to cam band board and now things are starting to make
sense so this goes from left to right let's check they're in order so a backlog a whole lot of video
ideas and one of the videos has gone into keyword research and from there it's going into video
research so since this might be the same person they can be blue and then we move over and once
this video research and of course the keyword research is done it can go over to the person
whose only job is to do titles and they do the job when they're finished with it they would move it
over to the thumbnail person and now the thumbnail person would have different information provided
the keyword that was initially thought of some research about the video the title that was decided
upon and that person then can create a thumbnail based on all that knowledge and where is that
knowledge well it would be actually inside the task there'd be comments like I did research
for the keyword and I came up with xx man versus spider man might be what it is okay and then
another person or the same person would add in another comment and say
here is a lot of info about x man and that would just go on and on they might have used chat
EPT they might have done other sorts of research and now that it's with the thumbnail person and we
can see the status that it's out here they they can draw an image so what I did was I just took a
screenshot of here and let's just paste it in and we'll add that as a comment and now there is a
thumbnail ready to go now this we may have additional statuses later on for whether I accept
the thumbnail like I'm the channel manager I guess or the owner of the site do I like this
thumbnail and that might go off for me to review now that's probably not going to happen because
it's way too much micro management for what I'm trying to achieve here but it's just one of the
video along the lines is moved into video research and if we set up the emails and the roles correctly
we should be able to notify those people automatically but that's for another part of this video I think
and from here the thumbnail person well let's just do it from within here they can just click this
little button and that just takes it to the next status so it's now with the script person
and we can see it's moved to the script person they write a script then they can send it all
over to the video editor now the video editor has that collective set of information as well
they have the research about what the video is going to be the keyword the title and the script
and hopefully at this point because I haven't broken down script into having an intro and outro
component just yet they will just record an intro and that might be something like the title just
zooming across the page it might be a little bit of a talking head where someone's saying the intro
may be in a diagonal section so they're over here and there's a title page here once that's done
the it can move over to video body they they create the video and after that it could move over to
the video outro now as I talk this through even in my own head I can see areas that are really
micro managed they're probably is just going to be a concept of video the video editor doesn't
really want to do project management where they're just changing statuses because they went to
different sections this would only really make sense if you had specialists there was one person
who did the intro there was another person that did the body there was another person that said
did the outro or maybe things like the lower thirds then we would want to do it this way
so let's just go back and modify that this is what I love about a cam-band board and taking
things through statuses you get to think about is this actually practical or is this just way too
much work for the team this is the balance we're trying to solve now I think we can come back to
list settings and it was list statuses and we can come into here and I like the color of the green
one I don't like that one so I'm just going to pick on the delete status here and the delete status
here and just rename this to video only and here's that complete status that I was talking about earlier
now it's called custom why have why does that happen why is it not part of video production
I'm just going to hit save and one of the things that picked up was that I'd already put a task
into a status that now doesn't exist so we just need to state what it's going to be it's just
going to be video we'll hit done here and now that's part of done now there was an issue I
noticed we'll come back to list statuses it's called custom I wanted it to be called video
production why did that not happen I'm just going to copy that and I'm going to are you sure you
want to delete video production I do and we come to custom which is all of this and I do not
understand how I can rename the one used in the space and see the word custom here but if I click
on that that's just something else altogether so what I'll do is I won't worry about it for today
in another session I might go and create a new template and work through what the issues are
but I do want to move on and I want to create videos for the youtube automation challenge
this is not meant to be how does click up work sort of video it just seems to be where we're
going at the moment we'll hit save come back to the beginning now if you find this view to be
a bit awkward I think I am zoomed in a little bit let's just see you you can zoom out and you'll see
a little bit more of the display we can go left and right but you can change it back to
list view and look at it this way this is as a software developer I usually work in this sort of
mode because the tasks they're not really related to one another but in the case of tasks where
there's a whole lot of steps this cam-band board is just a really good way to work now to just recap
on this section what we have is we have a space called trend 10 we will have a space later on
called magic of 10 and within that we have the channel set up with three major to do items there
could be some rearrangement going on here then we have another section it's called a list actually
called videos and when we do start creating videos and we can I think we can just delete
these quickly I wonder if there's a nice bulk way I can't see it but this might be a good time just
to switch back to list we go back to list and from there we've got this little radio button
and you can just select everything you like including that one and we'll click the delete
button now everything's back to a clean set up ready to go and so that's the end of this section
in the next section what I'm going to do is start delegating tasks probably to both myself
and Adam who I'm working with and this will be in the area of the channel set up
now Adam wants to work through graphics he's always been good at just drawing and art and
stuff like that and his learning skills in the area of digital stuff like using mid-journey
and adobe photoshop and photopea and camber and all that sort of stuff so anything that's in here
that looks like it's related to a visual aspect I'll delegate that to him and anything that's
more text oriented and especially related to the the niche the brand and all that I'll probably
do that or I'll do that with him as a collaboration and that's what we'll do in the next section