In this video I'm going to demonstrate how I'm using ChatGPT to write unit tests for
our system in a consistent and predictable fashion.
I was curious if I could just take these scopes from our code.
Whether I could just go to ChatGPT and type in a message, can scopes be unit tested and
paste in the code and see what happens.
And ChatGPT has come up with a couple of unit tests, there should have been about five or six.
And when I looked through them they looked like they're close to what I need for unit tests.
But it has a little bit of code that I know if I tried to run it within our system would just
fail. The way it's worked with creating sample data for unit tests isn't using traits correctly.
And so what I did was give it a little bit of extra contextual information, letting it know
that I'm using sub-factories in the code. And from that it came up with better code just with
that little bit of extra information. Now this was just me training the bot a little bit,
but I thought I'd use it in anger. And so what I did is I went back to some of the code.
We had this scope. It's fairly complex. There's a few different ideas going on in the data.
And what I did with it was take a copy of it, go over to ChatGPT and I just said,
can you do a test for and then paste it in. Now the test that it came up with
semantically is right. It had information about four different shipments, three of which were
valid, one wasn't and gave the right expectations. But it didn't give enough logic in there.
And it had one serious flaw in that it took the idea of sub-factories to a level beyond what we
deal with. We only deal with two data specific sub-factories at a time. Usually after that when
you need more than two records, it's best to have more of a seed generation structure in place.
And so I just gave it two very simple pieces of training, one to start using create list
as a technique. And I taught it how we do our sample data systems. So when we do
simple traits or sample traits, I should say, they follow this pattern.
And I did that basically by taking a model called Shipment. I had a couple of usage specific
traits. I had the general sort of named traits that we use for consistent unit test. And then
sample was essentially a whole lot of data provided by Faker. And with just a little bit of
information, it was able to learn. So apologies for the misunderstanding. It was able to learn
how I work with sample data within the system. Now on one of the earlier examples with it,
I was able to get it to write a general close approximation of a unit test for needs PDF.
And I then manually just made a few slight alterations to it. And what happened was that
this worked and it covered every scenario that I could see in the logic. And I thought, okay,
this is pretty, pretty good unit testing for the code. Could I use it as the basis to train the bot
a little bit further? And so I just said for the following scope and I posted in the actual code.
And I told it, I wrote the following unit test and I gave it the pattern that it needed.
And then it was just a simple case of selecting the next scope on the list, going over and say,
can you write my unit test for scope and posted the code in. And what it did was write a unit test
which covered all scenarios and what the first time out, I didn't really have to change anything.
So I was pretty happy with that. And I thought, well, let's take it a bit further. And you might
be able to see here that there's a fair bit more complex scope going on here. There's a whole
lot of if else statements going on. So I just gave it that, that code that we're seeing with,
can you create a test for the following scope? And it ended up giving me a whole lot of code.
I think there were four or five tests going in here. And I knew there were one or two typos
in there. There should never have been a string like this. It should have been number. But I fixed
the couple of typos that were there and I ran it. And what was surprising about this
is that I had a bunch of unit tests. I think there were five and I focused in on just this
description. And three of them just worked off the bat. I checked the code and the code was
written well and I'm happy with that. Two of them failed. I haven't checked this one to see why it
failed. But when I checked this one, which it uncovered and it created a failure on, I thought,
okay, what has it done wrong with the unit test? Well, to my surprise and happiness in some respects,
because this is one of the things that we want to do with unit tests is it uncovered a bug in
the code itself. And the bugs seem to be related to a field that doesn't exist on the model. Now,
I'll probably do a little bit of further investigation to make sure that I'm not off.
But what's great about this is that the ability to uncover problems that we didn't even know about
is a powerful aspect of what we can do with the unit testing. And this has been quite simple to do
once you train the bot to create what you want. One of the areas that it probably would need further
training from my point of view is that I wouldn't usually set up data the way it's doing it here.
It works quite effectively, but it's not using probably good practices of RSpec around the use
of let blocks, context blocks, stuff like that. But the good thing is that can be trained as well
in a future bot. So you just you come up with the pattern that you want and you start seeding
it as information before generating new code. Now, I've been exploring a few different ways
of creating programming constructs that can define how code should come out of a system,
feeding it into chat GPT and getting code out the other end that's consistent.
One of the areas that I played around extensively with was with various languages,
Python, Ruby and JavaScript to build a mid journey bot that would just create image after image.
And the funny thing is that when you just use natural language to describe the problem and you
give it to chat GPT because it's not a complex problem, you get different code every time.
But through a little bit of pre training and a meta programming language or a
domain specific language, really, I was able to get chat GPT giving out consistent
code that followed patterns and practices that I would be happy to use within the system.