Have you become a fan of Claude Code? I certainly have, and in this video we're going
to look at a new capability that they've created, which is Claude Code in the web.
I'm AppyDave. Let's get into it.
On the weekend, I was at an AI meetup group and we were talking about Claude Code
on the web, and one of the people in the meetup group was actually using his phone
at the time and creating PRs on code with little requests to have agents do work
for him while we were in the meetup group. And what I thought I'd do is test out
Claude Code myself with a little problem that's plaguing me at the moment. It's to
do with the amount of documentation that I've created
And I thought this would be a great test to see what I can do with it.
So the positioned Claude Code as a new way of interacting on the web. And the way
it works is that if you've got a repo set up on your system and you've connected
it to Claude Code, it can create a pull request and start executing the prompt that
you give it. And the good thing is, if you have multiple tasks that you want to run,
They all exist in their own pull requests,
and they all get tested within isolated environments.
Now this stating here that it's flexible for every task will figure out whether that's
actually true or not. But it's concepts like answering questions should be easy to
do. Bug fixes that are done from well-defined
documentation should be easy. So we could use the BMAD method. Or we could do PRDs
or requirements documents, and just making basic back end changes that can also be
tested by unit tests. And the reason this will work is because it will spin up an
isolated environment and do all the integration or unit tests for you.
Now, they say, from a security first cloud execution point of view, that every task
is in an isolated sandbox environment.
I've already connected up all my GitHub repositories, and I have a lot of them across
multiple organizations coming through. So we've got little tutorial organizations
that I've had. I've got 88 repositories in one of my main organizations, and then
I've got stuff around AppyDave that I do right now. Now the one we're working with
today is going to be Support Signal.
And Support signal is a set of websites and cloud applications that have been put
together using vibe coding or really context engineering using the BMAD method. It's
got concepts like the ability to use AI to record incidents. We've got all these
users, multi-tenancy, security, all that sort of stuff going on. A little bit of
company management in the back end with the ability to update users, participants.
So it's a fairly complex application designed to allow people to enter in an incident
and have that incident enhanced with AI through asking different questions based
on whatever was said.
Now all of this application was done using Claude code and just using it from the
terminal. And if we were to start it up, it's relatively complex.
we've got three different servers that we run. One for the web, one for the convex
database,
and one for the log ingestion server. And under each of those, we've also got the
unit tests that we can run for each of those particular applications. So they're
going through at the moment
Now personally, I think Claude Code in the terminal is an incredible product. It's
been able to build that application,
that you were seeing, and it was all done using a context engineering framework called
the BMAD Method. But when you look at the code base, it's all, all the code, whether
it be the convex server, the web server, or the worker server,
the whole set of applications were built just using prompts. And all of those prompts
are all documented in the docs file. So within this docs file, we've got concept
like custom agents that I've built, analysis, we've got the API, the architecture.
Some of this came out of the BMAD method. It's been enhanced over time. We've got
design systems,
and then we've got this massive bulk of information, which is all the knowledge that's
been generated during the process.
So as the application was being built, there were many epics, there were many stories,
and everything was context engineered.
So that's an overview of all the code. I'm wondering personally how I can use
the web version. When you look at something like this screen where you've got three
different
web servers, you've got three different unit test systems, how can we work with it
from a web interface?
So what I thought we'd do is go into Claude Webb and point it at the repository,
also pointed at the particular docs folders and see if we can just get it to clean
everything up, analyze it, make it more readable than it is at the moment. Because
at the moment, after 3 or 4 months of coding an enterprise application, some of the
documentation is a little bit scattered and duplicated.
So I've come over to Claude Code AI code, and one of the things I've done is selected
the repository I want to work in, and I've just got a starting prompt. The user is
seeking a comprehensive audit of all documentation files in the system. We're looking
at the BMAD method. We want to see the early documentation created by BMAD like the
PRD and the architecture. We want to understand the epics and stories. This is the
working documentation that's being created. There's about 11 epics and many stories
in the system. And then I use a system called KDD Knowledge Driven Development, and
that's the area that I really want to get cleaned up as well. So what I think we'll
do is just kick it off and see what happens.
So it started writing a file for us. It's in the dots area. It's called an analysis
sub folder and documentation audit by type. And it's stating here,
it's completed the audit of all the documentation.
And this is how I felt it would be. We've got the BMAD method and the agents over
62 files. We've got all the technical guides, which are kind of the rules and
instructions that I've built along the way. We've got all the stories coming through.
We've got the patterns and practices. So I'm looking for architecture, coding patterns.
And there's a lot of stuff around error handling strategies and testing patterns.
The lessons learned, this is where we've got the antipatterns coming through.
platform constraints,
because the main system is around the incident analysis. There's a lot of documentation
going on there.
And also whenever I do a story, I have it create a story acceptance test, which is
just what either human need to go through
and test.
And these were actually written in a way that tools like Open AI's Atlas could actually
do the work for me.
So we can see a bit of a characteristics of the different documents going on and
what's it doing now.
So it looks like we've only got this one file. It's,
done a git add. We've got a commit message coming through here. And if we go and
have a look at my repositories and organizations, we'll go down to Support Signal
where we've got multiple repositories. The one we're interested in is the app support
signal. And look at that. It's created a pull request for us.
Now with this here, I could come up and press the create pull request within GitHub,
but I am aware that there's also a button directly in Claude code or Claude code
on the web. And let's try pressing that and see what happens.
So the click create PR, it looks like it's just doing the same thing,
just with a slightly different title to when I did it manually. So I don't think
it matters which way we go. We'll just go create pull request
and it's currently running through the CI pipeline down below. And if we click over
here, we can see the one file that's been changed.
If we go towards the bottom of that particular file, I think it might even have a
little bit of a plan of action or recommendations that we can move forward with.
So let's come back to Claude Code we could move forward. I noticed that we've got
a view PR I'm assuming it's going to take us to the same location it is. Looks like
CI has run. Let's just run the actions and see how
the continuous integration pipeline is working. We've got audit and categorized E
to E test, linting and testing and deploying the convex back end. That's the database
building the application. Also deploying the Next.js application to Cloudflare pages
seems to have all been working.
So we can just come back to Claude Code and execute our next prompt.
So I've let it run a little prompt. If the goal of the pool request is to clean up
five months worth of documentation and all we've got is the audit that we've built,
what would it prioritize? What order would it do things in? So it's talking about
removing the duplicates, which is an easy win. This is, I think, the first thing
that should happen next. We need to be able to find documents quickly, so getting
all the indexes up to date is really important. After that, it should be able to
archive or remove stale content. I don't know how it's going to go about that. I
know I have that folder. I don't think this is the right area for it, but we can
work on that when we get to it. I'm sure maybe the date timestamp of files will be
important. And then we can go into a consolidated,
documentation view. Now, one of the things I noticed is that unlike other chats systems,
if you did this a little bit incorrectly, you can't edit it and keep moving. And
this is the same in Claude code as well. Once you put information in, it's in the
context window and you can't fork it.
Now, the simple little prompt I'm running here is break it into four detailed tasks.
We're only going to work on one at a time, but
so like Claude Code, it just goes into its own internal TO-DO system. We're going
to update there.
If this was normal Claude Code in the terminal we'd have a command T which shows
or hides this sort of stuff.
we can't expect it to be working the same way as Claude Code right now. One of the
other things to notice if we look up in the top left hand corner, I'm not sure if
it's showing in the video, but I started off at $997 worth of credits. Currently
we're at $995 worth of credits, so it's a lot of work done,
but it could add up over time with a dollar here. $2 there.
Now, normally I would go deep and read this, but because it's just part of the video,
we're just going to work through them quickly. So we've got task one, remove duplicates,
we've got update the indexes. It's identified a lot of information here. Remove the
stale content.
in fact I should get it to remove anything from Gemini. I don't use Gemini CLI within
this application anymore. Consolidate related documentation.
say get going and see how long this actually takes. It's currently 9 a.m. in the
morning on a Sunday.
Now, funnily enough, we're only about a minute into this and it got to the GI commit,
but I was just looking at it on the phone and refreshed, and it talked about having,
enable notifications. So I'm going to turn that on.
press allow. I'm on an Android phone at the moment, and we can see hopefully on that.
You can see that task one is complete, but what we'll do is we'll bring it over to
the web interface and
it's working through things. We've got a bunch of code
removed. Let's click on this View PR button.
So it's come up to the audit and categorize or documentation files. We've now got
two commits, so let's click on this and see that something happened a minute ago.
So remove duplicate bmad command files. So we come in here.
Now, the interesting thing about this is that this could actually be a big mistake.
code base. I'm going to use Claude code from the terminal to check this. But essentially
what it's done is it's notice that BMAD is in two locations, which makes sense. It's
where it gets installed. BM a core, but it's also been embedded into the commands
directory. Now the thing is, this was done four or five months ago, so the version
of
BMAD that I'm using is not the same as it is today, and I know
whether it's been done in this area. So this is actually an area I'm going to do
some manual review on before I allow it through.
Now so far it's actually finished three of the tasks that it needed to do. I asked,
are there any more to do? There's a fourth one remaining. This is where the bulk
of the work is, and when I actually do this, I'm going to have to pay a lot of attention
to it. But the good thing is I should be able to run it all from my mobile phone
and check files that are being created. Now, there was one issue and I did ask it
to go and check into it.
and so if we go and have a look at my conversation with Claude code in the terminal,
I asked it whether there was an issue with deleting the particular agents that we
did because there's kind of clones of them. There's the original and there's one
in include code, and it said yes. This is a big problem. So what we're going to do
is copy all this information right here,
come back to our conversation and we're going to paste it in. Now, one of the things
I noticed this particular file that we also need, you can't drag files into the web
interface just yet.
So instead, I'm grabbing the file off Visual Studio and I'm just going to paste it
in directly and I'll let it go work through and come up with a plan of action to
reverse that, commit or reset the files, whatever it needs to do.
So it'll be working through the files that it lost. We've got a little bit of a corrected
architecture pattern here,
and it's making the changes. If we go and look at our pull requests, we've now got
seven commits and we're back to only eight files changed on the system.
So at the end of this session, what we've got is we've got a little bit of an update
around the clawed files. We've got our audit by type, which is documented. We can
use it in the future. We also know where we're at with the cleanup process.
It's backed up the old historical file. We've got new navigation updates and various
indexes in place.
we've also got a little bit of architecture updates.
So that brings us to the end of the session on Claude Code web. So far, I think it
has a lot of potential. I really loved hearing how other people at the AI meetup
group that I go to use it for just sitting in coffee shops or meetings like they
were on the day and just asking for new pull requests to be created. So what I think
I'll do now is go off and have a coffee and keep working on the documentation in
the background. I'm AppyDave I'll see you in the next video.